<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="dm_about_story_talk">
	<text>Those who have been walking the Zone for a long time, as far as I know, are interested in something beyond money, booze, and wish-fulfillers. Maybe I'm wrong, but I think I heard in the bar that among you there’s a trend for philosophical sayings. Care to tell an interesting parable?</text>
</string>

<string id="dm_about_story_end">
	<text>Thank you.</text>
</string>

<string id="dm_about_zonanews_end">
	<text>Thanks.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_story_1">
	<text>Well, how can I put it… there’s a trend among experienced stalkers. We take turns getting hooked on one thing or another. Listen. They say that once, King Mahmud outpaced his retinue. Riding at full speed along the river, he suddenly saw a small boy near the water, fishing with a net. The boy seemed very unhappy. The king sharply reined in his horse, approached the boy, and asked: 
   — My child, why do you look so sad? I have never met a person more sorrowful than you.
   The boy replied: 
   — Your Majesty, we are seven brothers. Our father has died, and we live in extreme poverty with our mother. To feed ourselves, I come to the river every day and cast my net. If I fail to catch a single fish during the day, I go to bed hungry.
   — My son, — said the king, — if you don’t mind, I will help you. The boy agreed, and King Mahmud himself cast the net, which, touched by the king’s hand, returned with a rich catch.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_story_2">
	<text>Heh, when you’ve been balancing between life and death for years, any fool eventually becomes a philosopher. So listen. A man went out to sow wheat in a field. The day was ending, and he hadn’t finished his work. He prayed: “Oh Lord, if only I had a helper, we could finish the sowing in no time…” 
   Suddenly, a bear emerged from the bushes and said: “Come on, man, I’ll help you. It’s more fun together.” 
   The man rejoiced and agreed. They sowed the field on time, and after embracing in farewell, parted ways. 
   When harvest time came… the man couldn’t gather the crops in time. Again, the familiar bear appeared and said: “Come on, man, I’ll help you; together it’s easier.” They worked together and harvested a crop larger than the man had ever seen.
   The man said to the bear: “Let’s go to my house, Misha. You helped me sow and reap… let’s sit at the table, drink, eat, talk…” 
   The bear agreed, pleased by the man’s generosity. They sat at the table, rejoicing, and the bear kept saying: “Man, if it weren’t for me, you wouldn’t have sown the whole field… if it weren’t for me, you wouldn’t have gathered such a harvest…” 
   The man thought: “He’s big and strong, he might take everything and break my bones… no wonder he brags like that…” 
   The man grabbed a pitchfork and stabbed the bear. The bear roared in pain and ran into the forest. 
   Time passed… and it was sowing season again. The man went to the field, but sowed only half without a helper. At harvest, he gathered only half the crop. 
   On his way home, the bear appeared from the bushes. The man reproached him: “Why didn’t you help me sow and reap, Misha? I gave you food and drink, and you?” 
   The bear, pointing to his chest, answered: “Here it hurts…” 
   The man examined the bear and said: “But it’s all healed, Misha!” The bear replied: “The wound healed… THE SOUL HURTS!!!”</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_story_3">
	<text>Well — we’re not exactly super philosophers. Just lovers of reading things that really have value. So here’s one. Once, an unknown poet came to a king and said: 
   — O King, unrivaled under the heavens! I have composed a hymn in your honor, and my creation outshines all the poems that other poets have ever made for you, like Sirius shines brighter than all stars in the night sky.
   With these words, he handed the king a sheet of paper with only the ruler’s name written on it. The king looked at the paper and got angry: 
   — And where are the verses? — he shouted. — Have you lost your mind? You didn’t extol our royal glory, didn’t praise our victories and deeds. You didn’t even say that I created this whole kingdom with my own hands! Do you dare mock me? 
   But the poet was not intimidated by the king’s wrath and replied with dignity: 
   — All the royal wisdom, mercy, and power, and all the warrior glory are contained in this name, and anyone who reads it will immediately imagine all the deeds done by the king. For the name is the symbol of your kingdom, and it alone surpasses the thickest book of praise. So I was right in calling what my hand wrote an incomparable hymn glorifying you and your deeds!</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_story_4">
	<text>Hmm, let me recall one of the last ones. Long ago, in the Middle Empire — that’s what China was called at the time — the best and mightiest fighters from all over the world gathered for a tournament. The contests were judged by a great Chinese sage. Finally, after thousands of fights, he chose the three greatest warriors and asked each of them how they trained.
   First, a huge, fierce-looking fighter stood up and said: — Every morning at sunrise I break trees, stones, planks — anything that comes in my way. Within a day’s radius of my dwelling, everything is turned to dust and desert. 
   — Excellent, — said the sage. — And how do you train? — he asked the second fighter. 
   A tall, lean man, more like a monk or ascetic, stood up. 
   — Every morning at sunrise, — he said, — I devote myself to meditation. I bring my body under the control of mind and will, making it light and swift as thought. 
   — Excellent, — said the sage. — And how do you train? — he asked the third warrior. 
   The most ordinary, unremarkable-looking man stood up. If it weren’t for the fact that he recently won a thousand duels, no one would have thought he was a warrior, let alone a great one. 
   — I don’t train at all, — said the third. — I just try to be present in everything I do.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_story_5">
	<text>Could it be that someone finally understood us? Well, there it is — enlightenment in life. So listen. There once lived a man named Godelo. He had a wife who constantly nagged him because his father interfered with their life, and Godelo couldn’t calm her. 
  Godelo’s father, hearing his wife’s shouts day after day, called his son and said: 
  — Son, I see I am disturbing your family’s happiness. Let me go live in the mountains... 
  — Godelo, at first refusing, had no choice... 
  The father began to get ready, then called his son again: 
  — I have only one problem: I can’t make it to the mountains myself. Let’s have you carry me in a basket on your shoulders, and I’ll manage from there. 
  — “Alright,” Godelo agreed. 
  He placed his father in the basket and carried him to the mountains. After setting him down, he was about to leave, when his father called: 
  — Wait, son, don’t forget to take your basket; your son might need it. 
  Godelo felt ashamed, realized his mistake, repented, put his father back in the basket, and carried him home. 
  ...And he drove the cruel wife out of the house.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_story_6">
	<text>Well, there’s a trend among experienced stalkers. We take turns getting hooked on one thing or another. Listen. A pilgrim walked thousands of steps to meet the Master and finally stood before him, asking to share the highest wisdom. 
  — Then take a sip from this stream and describe the taste of the water, — said the Master. 
  — I’ve already heard this and understand the Truth, — said the Seeker, a little disappointed. 
  — Tell me, what do you understand? — asked the Master. 
  — The taste of water cannot be described in words. Water must be drunk; one need not speak about it. The same goes for truth… 
  — Now imagine — I am sitting by the stream, and a crowd like you stands in line for me to describe the taste of water, although many of them have already heard this description from other Masters.</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_story_7">
	<text>Heh, after years of balancing between life and death, even a fool eventually becomes a philosopher. So listen. A girl was walking down the road, beautiful as a fairy. Suddenly she noticed a man following her. She turned and asked: 
  — Tell me, why are you following me? 
  The man replied: 
  — O mistress of my heart, your charms are so irresistible that they compel me to follow you. They say I play the lute wonderfully, am versed in the secrets of poetry, and can stir the pangs of love in women’s hearts. But I want to confess my love to you, for you have captured my heart! 
  The beauty silently watched him for a while, then said: 
  — How could you fall in love with me? My younger sister is far more beautiful and attractive than I am. She walks behind me, look at her. 
  The man stopped, then turned, but saw only an ugly old woman in a patched cloak. Then he quickened his steps to catch up with the girl. Lowering his eyes, he asked with a submissive tone: 
  — Tell me, how could a lie slip from your tongue? 
  She smiled and replied: 
  — You, my friend, also did not tell me the truth when you swore your love. You know all the rules of love perfectly and pretend your heart burns with love for me. How could you turn to look at another woman?</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_story_8">
	<text>Well — we’re not exactly super philosophers. Just lovers of reading things that really have value. So here’s one. A merchant sent his son to learn the Secret of Happiness from the wisest of all men. The young man walked for forty days across the desert and finally arrived at a beautiful castle on top of a mountain. There lived the sage he sought. But instead of meeting a wise man, he entered a hall bustling with activity: merchants coming and going, people talking in the corners, a small orchestra playing sweet melodies, and a table filled with the finest local delicacies. The sage spoke with many people, and the young man had to wait about two hours for his turn. 
  The sage listened carefully to the young man’s explanation of his purpose but replied that he had no time to reveal the Secret of Happiness. He suggested that the boy stroll through the palace and return in two hours. 
  — But I want to ask one favor, — added the sage, handing the boy a small spoon with two drops of oil. — Throughout your walk, keep this spoon in your hand so that the oil does not spill. 
  The boy climbed up and down the palace stairs, eyes fixed on the spoon. Two hours later, he returned to the sage. 
  — Well, — asked the sage, — did you see the Persian carpets in my dining room? Did you notice the park the head gardener took ten years to create? Did you see the beautiful scrolls in my library? 
  Embarrassed, the boy had to admit he had seen nothing. His only concern had been to keep the drops of oil from spilling. 
  — Now go again and explore the wonders of my Universe, — said the sage. — You cannot trust a person if you are not familiar with the house in which he lives. 
  Calmed, the boy took the spoon and walked through the palace again, this time paying attention to all the artworks on the walls and ceilings. He saw the gardens surrounded by mountains, the delicate flowers, and the care with which each piece of art had been placed exactly where it needed to be. 
  Returning to the sage, he described everything he had seen in detail. 
  — And what about the two drops of oil I entrusted to you? — asked the sage. 
  The boy looked at the spoon and saw that all the oil had spilled. 
  — This is the only advice I can give you: the Secret of Happiness is to observe all the wonders of the world while never forgetting the two drops of oil in your spoon.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_story_9">
	<text>Hmm, let me recall one of the last ones. Once, in an Indian kingdom-state, there lived an old monarch who had spent his life pondering a purely Eastern question: what is the essence of strength? He finally decided to find the strongest man in his realm to learn from him. As a reward, the winner would receive a horse from the royal stables of his choice: white if he wished, black if he preferred. To solve this difficult problem of eternal choice, he gathered the wisest men of his kingdom and sent them on inspections across towns and villages. 
  The monarch’s task proved extraordinarily difficult — the sages wore out countless pairs of sandals but could not find the strongest man. They arranged competitions and gave contestants many challenges, but none of the king’s subjects could claim the title of the strongest man in the kingdom. 
  The sages had almost given up when, passing through a small village, they noticed a giant man lying on a huge bed in the middle of a large garden surrounding his house. “What enormous strength is hidden in this man!” they exclaimed and decided to test him with three trials. 
  — Can you break a horseshoe with one hand? — asked the sages. He answered nothing and simply broke the horseshoe with his hand. — Can you uproot a tree? — they asked again. He took the ten-meter tree in both hands and pulled it from the ground. — Truly you are strong, man! But can you dam a river? — they asked a third time. The giant picked up a huge stone lying on the riverbank and threw it into the stream, stopping the flow. “Glory to the gods!” exclaimed the sages. “Truly you are the strongest man on earth! Choose any of the royal horses: black or white!” 
  Only when the giant raised his hand to scratch his head, ready to announce his choice, did a small frail woman in dark clothing appear at his doorstep. “Husband, I warn you: if you choose the white horse, you’ll regret it! I cannot vouch for myself!”</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_story_10">
	<text>Could it be that someone has actually started to understand us? Amazing. Enlightenment has finally come. So listen. Once, the wife of a prince approached Genghis Khan, asking him to free her relatives. 
  Genghis Khan said: 
  — Here stand your husband, your son, and your brother. I will release only one. Whom do you choose? 
  Without hesitation, she replied: 
  — My brother. 
  — Explain to me why? 
  The woman said: 
  — I can find a husband, I can bear a son, but I cannot create a brother. 
  After hearing this, Genghis Khan freed all three.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_story_11">
	<text>Well, after years of balancing between life and death, even a fool eventually becomes a philosopher. So listen. ...The gates of Zhongdu swung open, and into the richest city of the Celestial Empire, screaming wildly and brandishing weapons, the steppe warriors poured. 
  Li Kui, known in Zhongdu as Snub-nosed Li, a vagabond without family or clan, who had appeared in the city out of nowhere just before the invasion — frail and disheveled Li Kui, limping, ran through the alleys of the western outskirts, hoping for luck. 
  If great Guanyin would help him leave unharmed, he would become a shaven-headed Hashan monk in a saffron robe, living on alms and indifferent to worldly affairs — and let other fools give risky advice to the short-sighted Son of Heaven, the incompetent emperor, and let all those who wished, greedy ministers, filthy Mongols, and others, ravage the unfortunate Celestial Empire... 
  Before realizing that Guanyin was looking the other way that day, Snub-nosed Li suddenly stopped, hissed in pain from his injured knee, and raised a short staff three elbows long to his chest. 
  At the end of the alley, a tall Mongol in leather armor grinned, twirling a long spear with a crossbar under the spearhead. 
  The fallen commander Li Kui, called Snub-nosed Li in Zhongdu and Blue Tiger Hou in the capital, took a deep breath and slowly approached the grinning steppe warrior, forcing himself not to limp. 
  The Mongol waited until the frail fighter came close and lazily jabbed his spear forward. 
  In a moment, the weapon nearly flew out of his hands, but when the astonished warrior managed to leap back, holding the spear with the point up, a hollowed-out staff with a hidden Blue Tiger Hou sword inside flew into his face. 
  The city was already burning. Bitter smoke rolled through Zhongdu’s streets, preceding the looting warriors of the unstoppable Temujin Genghis Khan; smoke stung Li Kui’s throat painfully, and his leg ached unbearably, while the Mongol struck skillfully and fiercely, switching the spear tip and butt, moving constantly until Guanyin finally turned her benevolent gaze toward Zhongdu and the abandoned alley where Snub-nosed Li twice struck the Mongol’s wrist with his blade. 
  Now all that remained was to wait. Wait and not get skewered by the spear, whose movements grew uncertain and shaky. And when the moment came — put all remaining strength into the final leap. 
  ...He never released the spear, this unlucky fighter in light leather armor. Coughing and bent over, he sat against a wall, pressing the pierced side with his right hand, while his left still held the fallen spear. And above them, over the wounded Mongol and the powerless spear, stood Li Kui, former commander of the left wing Li, former Blue Tiger Hou, former Snub-nosed Li, future abbot of a monastery near Mount Wutai, a tired little man. 
  He stood and watched the Mongol’s face grow paler and the cut wrists bleed less and less. 
  The Mongol barely lifted his head — and their eyes met. 
  Li Kui sighed, tore his cloak into strips, sat next to the Mongol, and began tightly bandaging the hands of the invincible Genghis warrior. 
  Li did not know why he was doing this...</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_story_12">
	<text>Heh, after years of balancing between life and death, even a fool eventually becomes a philosopher. So listen. The king’s daughter, with beauty like the moon, enchanted all who ever caught a glimpse of her. One day, a dervish, about to take a bite of bread, saw her and froze in astonishment. His fingers relaxed, and the bread fell to the ground. As she passed by, the princess smiled at the dervish. Ecstasy shook his body, the bread lay in the dust, and he nearly lost consciousness. He remained in this state for seven years. His home became the street, his neighbors the stray dogs. The mad dervish bored the princess, and her guards decided to kill him. Then she summoned him and said: 
  — No union between us is possible. You must leave the city immediately, for my servants want to kill you. 
  The unfortunate lover replied: 
  — Since I saw you, life has no value to me. Innocent blood will be shed. But before I die, I beg you to fulfill my only wish, for you are the cause of my demise. Tell me, why did you then smile at me? 
  — Fool! — said the princess. — When I saw how ridiculous you made yourself, I smiled out of pity — nothing more. 
  And saying this, the princess disappeared.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_story_13">
	<text>Well — we’re not exactly super philosophers. Just lovers of reading things that really have value. So here’s one. Two wise men were conversing about love. One said: 
  — The nature of love is to always bring suffering and misfortune, and the lover always suffers and agonizes. 
  The other objected: 
  — Be silent, you have clearly never tasted the sweetness of reconciliation after a quarrel, nor the joy of union after separation. No one in the world is purer and gentler than those whose hearts are pure in love, and none are fouler than those who are far from thoughts of love. 
  In the beauty of a man’s heart — the reflection of the glow of love: 
  If the heart is ugly, it does not honor beauty! 
  Let the ignorant remember the saying of the wise: 
  Where breed honors breed, — the kinship of souls is established.</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_story_14">
	<text>Hm, let me recall one of the latest ones. Once lived a man, obsessed with mad love and exhausted by the pangs of desire. The beauty of the one he loved was unmatched, even compared to the beauty of heavenly maidens. People said of her that her beauty outshone both the Sun and the Moon. Moreover, her incomparable beauty was dangerous, not only because it could inflict deadly torments of love, but also because this beauty was both intelligent and merciless. 
  One day, the man, thinking himself alone, spoke to himself: 
  — My God! Her face is fairer than a rose, her form more slender than a cypress! Her whole appearance is brighter than a peacock, and her walk more graceful than a pheasant’s stride! 
  But it turned out that his beloved was nearby and had heard his words. She appeared before him and said: 
  — You probably meant to flatter me with your comparisons, but they only anger me, and I find them shameful. You compared my face to a rose, but where in roses have you seen such beautiful eyes and eyebrows as mine? You compared my form to a cypress, but does a cypress possess my mobility and spirit? You compared my whole appearance to a peacock, but has anyone ever burned with love observing a peacock? You compared my walk to that of a pheasant, but who in the world delights in recalling a walking pheasant? 
  — Forgive me! — cried the lover. — Out of my foolishness, I imagined that you could be described with words! 
  These words enraged the moon-faced woman even more, and in anger she said: 
  — For this foolishness of yours, I will torment you! 
  Then the lover fell at her feet, saying: 
  — O incomparable otherworldly Beauty! All my awkward words stem from my true and pure love for you. There is no malice, no reproach, not even a complaint, and if they seemed inappropriate to you, be kind and do not judge me harshly for this fault; consider it a sign of my ignorance and inexperience, and I shall perish from shame and disgrace! 
  And he sought and uttered words of repentance so long that the beauty calmed down and abandoned her intent to take revenge on the man who loved her.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_story_15">
	<text>Could it be that someone has actually started to understand us? Amazing. Enlightenment has finally come. So listen. In ancient times, there was a thief. One day he robbed the treasury of the padishah. The padishah immediately sent all his investigators after the thief. The thief was caught and the loot taken from him. Then the padishah asked his chief vizier: 
  — What should be done with this thief? 
  — Gather all the townspeople and, before everyone, execute the thief, — replied the vizier. 
  The padishah had a daughter. He asked her: 
  — Is what the vizier said correct? 
  — The vizier judged correctly, — replied the girl. 
  Then the padishah asked the middle vizier: 
  — What should be done with the thief? 
  — Gather plenty of wood, place the thief on it, and set it on fire. 
  Again the padishah asked his daughter: 
  — What do you think of the vizier’s words? 
  — Your vizier judged correctly, — she replied again. 
  Finally, the padishah asked the youngest vizier: 
  — What should be done with the thief? 
  — Dress the thief from head to toe, give him everything so that his stomach is always full, and release him. 
  The padishah asked his daughter again: 
  — What do you think of the vizier’s advice? 
  — Your vizier judged correctly, — the girl replied. 
  Then the padishah said: 
  — You said that each of the three viziers judged correctly. What do you mean, explain to us. 
  And the girl replied: 
  — The chief vizier, who said the thief must be killed, was probably born a butcher. Your middle vizier, evidently, was a brick-burner. And the youngest vizier is noble by his very nature. 
  The padishah checked, and the girl was right. The thief was treated according to the advice of the youngest vizier: he was well-fed, given money for expenses, and spared death. The youngest vizier was made chief vizier.</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_story_16">
	<text>Hm, let me put it this way: among experienced wanderers, there’s a tendency to get drawn to one thing or another. Listen. Once, a gang of robbers went on a raid. 
  After looting many items, they began to divide them among themselves. All shares were equal, except for a dress made of the finest threads—which was considered the worst share—and it was given to the weakest member of the gang. That weak man, upon receiving his share, became furious. He started shouting that he had been cheated. 
  When he went into the city to sell the dress he received, all the wealthy and noble merchants offered him large sums of money. What he alone had received turned out to be twice as valuable as the combined shares of all his comrades. 
  He then rejoiced and leaped with happiness. This is similar to ordinary people who give a small alms (part of their income) without knowing what reward it may bring. When they are reborn in heaven and experience immense bliss, they start to regret—they regret not giving more generously (their entire wealth). They are like the man who, receiving a great sum for the dress, rejoiced. With almsgiving, the same principle applies: great reward comes from small deeds. 
  That is why, alongside their joy, there arises regret for the incompleteness of what was done.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_story_17">
	<text>Heh, after years of balancing between life and death, any fool eventually becomes a philosopher. So listen. Once, there was a family: husband, wife, and daughter. The family was extremely poor, barely making ends meet. The husband and wife began to think about how to become wealthy. 
  — We live in poverty. Let’s find a rich man, settle near him, watch what he does, and imitate him in everything. 
  So they did. They demolished their hut and built a new house next to the rich seth?y’s home. The seth?y made his workers cultivate the fields and garden, then sent them to sell the harvest. The poor couple tried to imitate the seth?y wherever they could, working in the fields and selling part of their harvest at the market. Gradually, their affairs improved, and their wealth grew. 
  The husband and wife decided to thank the seth?y, from whom they had secretly learned the art of managing a household. The husband took a handful of gold and went to the wealthy man. 
  — Why have you brought me gold? — asked the seth?y, surprised. 
  — I was poor. My wife and I decided to demolish our hut, settle near your house, and imitate you in everything. Our affairs quickly prospered, the family grew wealthy, and now we offer you this gift in gratitude. 
  — Since you yourself believe you gained all your wealth thanks to me, then it is my wealth. You must give me all your property, and I will decide what share to allot to you. 
  — But I was not ungrateful and brought you gold. Had I known you would demand all my wealth, I would have brought nothing. 
  The seth?y and the former poor man argued at length. Finally, they turned to a judge. The judge could not resolve their dispute and led both to the king. The former poor man bowed and said: 
  — Your Majesty, I settled near the seth?y’s house, observed how he managed his affairs, how he sent his workers to cultivate and trade. I imitated the seth?y wherever I could and achieved prosperity and success. In gratitude, I brought gold to the seth?y, who helped me unknowingly, but now the seth?y demands all my property. I ask you, Your Majesty, to resolve this matter justly. 
  The king addressed the seth?y: 
  — Did this man recount the case correctly? 
  — Entirely correct, Your Majesty. 
  Understanding that the seth?y was overly greedy, the king said: 
  — Seth?y, do you have children? 
  — A son, Your Majesty. 
  — And you? — asked the king, turning to the former poor man. 
  — A daughter, Your Majesty. 
  — To prevent conflict between you, I decree that both families should be joined by marriage. Then there will be nothing to divide. 
  The seth?y and the former poor man bowed low to the king and departed, ready to follow the wise royal decision.</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_story_18">
	<text>Well — we’re not exactly super philosophers. We’re just lovers of reading what truly has value. So here’s one. There lived a hermit in the desert. Once, in his homeland, he had been a skilled carpenter. But life, by chance, cast him into the desert. A wealthy man learned about this master and sought him out, saying: 
  — I’ve heard you are a skilled craftsman. I want to order an oak table and chairs for my hall. I’ll come to pick up the order in a month and will pay well. 
  And he left. When the appointed time came, the wealthy man returned to the master and asked: 
  — Where are my table and chairs? 
  — Yes, I am a skilled master — but that alone is not enough. To fulfill your order, I also need wood and tools, which I do not have... 
  Desire alone is not enough: one also needs the means...</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_story_19">
	<text>Hm, let me recall one of the latest. In Shamil’s army, a letter was sent to a soldier informing him that his wife had died. Shamil himself received the letter. He decided to test the soldier and sent for him. When he arrived, Shamil said: 
  — You received a letter saying your father has died. 
  — In that case, the roof of our house has collapsed, and I need to go home, — replied the soldier. 
  — No, it was not your father, but your brother who died. 
  — Then a wall of the house has fallen; I must attend the funeral. 
  — It turns out it was not the brother, but your mother who died. 
  — Then the house is collapsing. I must go home. 
  — No, not your mother, but your sister has passed away. 
  — A flower has fallen from my heart — I must go home. 
  — I was testing you. Actually, your wife has died. 
  — If so, the whole house has collapsed, and nothing remains. Now there’s no need for me to go home.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_story_20">
	<text>Is it possible that someone has actually started to understand us? Incredible. Enlightenment has come, it seems. So listen. Two people were traveling towards each other. One was hurrying to help his benefactor, and the other was rushing to a celebration. They met on a narrow bridge and refused to give way to each other. They argued and finally turned to a judge. The judge could not resolve the matter and sent them both to the king. 
  The king asked: 
  — Explain to me why you did not want to yield to each other? 
  One of the disputants said: 
  — Your Majesty, I was hurrying to a celebration and met this man on the bridge, but he did not let me pass. 
  The other said: 
  — At one time, a man did me a great favor. Now he is in trouble, and I was hurrying to help him. That is why I did not yield. 
  The king delivered the following decision: 
  — The one who was hurrying to the celebration must compensate the one who was rushing to help his benefactor.</text>
</string>

<string id="dm_about_baiki_talk">
	<text>What interesting things can you tell me about life?</text>
</string>

<string id="dm_about_baiki_end">
	<text>Quite fascinating.</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_baiki_1">
	<text>The regiment I served in had a fairly large auxiliary farm: a sizable greenhouse, a pigsty, and even a horse named Bouquet.  
In the pigsty, a conscript soldier, a Gypsy by nationality, looked after the pigs. One winter, a sow farrowed. Everyone rejoiced, counted the piglets, and accounted for them, but at night one died… In the morning, the deputy commander came to check on the sow, and the Gypsy (I no longer remember his name) presented him with the newly deceased piglet. What could be done? They wrote one off.  
The Gypsy, not being a fool, didn’t throw the dead piglet away but hid it in a snowdrift. A day or two later, he took one live piglet for himself (over the years I forget whether he ate it with friends or sold it locally), and presented the deputy commander with the piglet he had hidden.  
Another piglet was written off. He tried the same trick again, but it failed.  
The regiment commander was very angry when he was informed about this. He personally went to the pigsty. For some reason, he especially disliked the radio receiver in the room where the Gypsy slept — a big, old wooden-cased radio. He made the soldier carry it from the pigsty to the parade ground, where the whole regiment was assembled, and then march around the parade ground with the radio. When the deputy commander asked, “How long?” he replied, “Until Nikolai Slichenko sings…”</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_2">
	<text>A large diesel submarine was at sea on a combat mission. According to the daily plan, so-called anti-emergency drills were conducted — actions meant to prevent actual emergencies later. In the central post, the deputy brigade commander was peacefully gnawing on a cracker. He was known for his rather fiery temperament, but that day he was leaving everyone alone.  
Among the submarine crew was a warrant officer named Pozhar, the kind of person everyone always needs. For some reason, that day he was needed by the deputy brigade commander. When it became clear that Warrant Officer Pozhar was not at his station, a command went out:  
— Report the compartment in which Warrant Officer Pozhar is!  
The command was given and quickly forgotten in the rush.  
Suddenly, from the diesel compartment, a report came over the loudspeaker:  
— Central post, Pozhar is in the fifth compartment! (But you can’t see capitalization in oral speech!)  
The central post reacted instantly. Short bells rang, followed by words that made even the thick-skinned flinch:  
— Emergency! Fire in the fifth compartment!  
It was a scare that made your soul tremble. There is plenty to burn in a diesel compartment…  
The boatswain shifted the horizontal rudders for surfacing, the acoustics operators listened intently to the horizon (hoping not to collide with anyone on the surface), and the hold crew prepared to deploy a very serious fire suppression system in the fifth compartment.  
The central post shouted:  
— Fifth! Fifth, report the situation! What is burning there?!  
The diesel crew replied calmly and embarrassedly:  
— Nothing is burning. We were simply ordered to report the compartment where Warrant Officer Pozhar was, and that’s what we did.  
After the emergency alarm was over, a debriefing took place using all naval terminology. Then the deputy brigade commander announced over the loudspeaker:  
— Attention, submariners! From now until the end of this deployment, this fellow’s last name will be Ivanov!</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_3">
	<text>In the early 2000s, I actively participated in organizing and preparing various charitable events, where the main advantage was the opportunity to meet serious people on an equal footing in a non-commercial setting. And, of course, to help children. At one such event, held at a departmental hotel, I helped a woman of the “I can do everything but want nothing for myself” type. In exchange for a massive amount of preparatory and fundraising work, I was promised several extremely valuable introductions to sponsors.  
In fact, at every large charitable event, there are four main groups of people — actual sponsors, event organizers along with various performers and “support staff,” children or other beneficiaries, and the category I want to focus on — the freeloaders. Not all freeloaders are complete freeloaders — some contribute a small amount to the children’s fund. But understand, if a banquet for sponsors costs $100 per person, you are not counting on 200 rubles from a lottery ticket.  
At the start of the event, I scanned the hall and noticed each of the four groups. There were not many freeloaders this time — control was in place — but they were present, as the tables were piled with food and drinks, and the program included star performances and other delights. The evening was split into two parts — the first featured stories of the beneficiaries, children’s performances, and a charity auction.  
The auction reveals the true freeloaders, as they never buy anything and try not to be seen by the active auctioneer, often slipping away quietly. One freeloader caught my attention immediately — a simple-looking man of about 30 with a small ponytail, completely rustic in appearance, looking like a child from a small Siberian town seeing the Kremlin for the first time. He didn’t even buy a lottery ticket, which completely astonished me.  
Since there was so much organizational work — all on my young shoulders (I was 22) — and it was important work (“these are children!” as the movie line goes), I gave it my all.  
During intermission, the woman I was helping kept her promise and introduced me to several very serious people from Russia and beyond. When I asked if anyone was really influential, she hesitated and said she couldn’t answer. The contacts I received were already enough for significant achievements, so I decided to let it be.  
During the second part, performers appeared — the ones I had helped organize. Somehow, everything aligned, and the event was a huge success — the sponsors were excited, I was sweating and hadn’t eaten all morning. The freeloader I had noticed earlier enjoyed himself like a child, clapping and eating heartily.  
After the event, guests were asked to donate to the collection. Most gave more than expected, but the freeloaders at best put in a small amount, and my rustic guest — nothing at all. The organizer was happy. As the guests left, she told me:  
— “Alright, you helped me a lot. I’ll show you ‘a hero of our time.’ But you must promise not to tell anyone about him or bother him — he is extremely shy and never shows off his help.  
This man financed the construction of new buildings for our orphanage for 300 children and the entire surrounding infrastructure, and even connected a gas pipeline from the nearest settlement. I gave my word.  
We left the hotel together, and she pointed to the rustic young man getting into a used Volga. Witnessing this construction firsthand was revolutionary for me. At that moment, I truly understood what it means to be a ‘serious person.’  
Since then, whenever I see freeloaders at events, I remember those innocent, loving, simple eyes and try to spot such people. Sometimes — I find them. And immediately, I understand everything.</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_baiki_4">
	<text>This happened a long time ago, at the very beginning of the 1990s. I was working as a young specialist at a well-known institute that developed OUR supercomputers. They didn’t pay much, so we had to moonlight.  
One time, we went to the city of Perm for some extra work. There, a cooperative had sold a batch of Chinese junk (players, toasters, a couple of TVs) to a local factory called NefteOrgSintez as employee rewards. Naturally, the defect rate was over 50%. So, the story goes:  
After stocking up on these technical wonders, we were sitting at the airport in bad weather, snow mixed with rain. The flight to Moscow was delayed for the second time. We were drinking in the restaurant. After a while, I realized I couldn’t drink anymore — I might die! I thought I’d walk in the cold to sober up a bit… and I ended up on the airfield. I saw some military transport being loaded.  
— Where are we flying? I asked.  
— To Moscow.  
— Take this with you.  
— Carry three bottles and get on board.  
— Gut!  
I dashed after the vodka, somehow with a bag containing a couple of pairs of underwear, and back. The flight was very fun. I think the crew was drinking with us too. (I vaguely remember a pilot shouting: “Takeoff is nothing! The main thing is to land!”) We landed in Zhukovsky. They transported us outside the airport in a UAZ covered with a tarp. Then I don’t remember. Around four a.m., I was sleeping in a soft bed at home. The phone rang. My wife reluctantly picked up. Through my sleep, I heard her trying to explain something for about five minutes… Finally, she shoved the phone to me with: “Tell him this!” — Hello, I said.  
— Who is this? Dimon, is that you?  
— Yes.  
Pause.  
— Holy crap! Bastard! Scoundrel!  
Etc.  
— We turned the entire Perm police upside down! A man with money disappeared! Traffic cops are checking cars leaving the city. The plane left without us (it was a regular flight)! And you, fool, are sleeping on a soft couch at home!  
Anyway, the next day I took a sick leave. Just in case…</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_5">
	<text>This was long ago, when planes flew drunk and there were no terrorists.  
We had a guy on watch, let’s call him Vasya. He’d spend one month at work drinking, one month at home fasting, because he couldn’t really party continuously. On the last day of his watch, the guys celebrated, and in autopilot mode, along with other unlucky fellows, he boarded a plane. At the bus collection point at the base, his backpack was lying there, and some good-natured pranksters, as always, slipped a valve into it.  
The valve is a thing 25 cm long, 8.3 cm in diameter, weighing about four kilos.  
All loaded, flight, reunion with his beloved wife, salary immediately confiscated, junk from the backpack went for laundry, and on the floor lay the metal piece.  
— Vasya, what’s this for?  
Who wants to admit that they got tricked and carried an unnecessary piece of metal for three thousand kilometers?  
— It’s a necessary item for the dacha, you go to the store.  
His wife went to the store. Vasya, hungover, looked at the device, and disgustedly threw it out the window. Steps in the hallway, and the item is placed on the table — by its knock, it reminds one of a medicinal concoction. Vasya opens his eyes.  
— Vasya, you carried a spare part so far, and I just came from the store, and look — there’s the same one under the window.  
On the table proudly stands Vasya’s valve…</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_6">
	<text>I served my country as a radio operator-radio mechanic at a backup command post “Zhilny” from 1978-1980. I had a habit of saluting officers without wearing my hat. We had a political officer major — I don’t remember his name, but he was a real jerk. Our commander, “Filipok,” Lieutenant Colonel Filippov, a commander from God, called me in. I entered the office and, as required, reported, raising my right hand to my temple. Since I was on combat duty, I hadn’t put on my garrison cap after removing my headset.  
With Filipok was the political officer. He said:  
— You don’t salute an empty head.  
I should have stayed silent, but the devil made me reply:  
— Sometimes a head in a peaked cap with an emblem sounds like an empty jug.  
Filipok smiled, and the political officer grimaced. I thought my lip was guaranteed to be in trouble.  
After hearing the order and replying:  
— Yes, permission to execute, — I left the office.  
I don’t know how other officers found out about this incident, but three hours later they started predicting I’d become a general.  
By the way, all officers, when meeting us conscripts after saluting, shook hands, but one political officer never offered his hand.</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_baiki_7">
	<text>An ordinary hose is just a long rubber tube. “Pretending to be a hose” for a Soviet soldier was like playing dumb, passively sabotaging orders from commanding officers. Sometimes this happened at the expense of fellow soldiers, so the “hardcore” — those who took service seriously and did everything to earn positive points in the eyes of the command — didn’t like hoses very much. Yet there were hoses who were legitimate, like the Russian spy Stierlitz: “Why bother catching him? He’ll get out of it anyway.” These were treated with affection.  

Few conscripts didn’t want to get home as soon as possible. Most quietly dreamed about it. Some tried to fake illness. In our unit, there was a legend about a young soldier who, upon entering the barracks for the first time, immediately sought out the heaviest weight, and upon finding it, began exercising his right arm. He did this every free minute and was encouraged for his zeal by the company commander. Just a month later, the young man went to the medical officer and declared:  
— Sir, my left arm is shrinking…  
The medical officer personally measured both biceps but recorded only the difference, as instructed.  
— Let’s check the trend, soldier, — said the major, slightly surprised. After a couple more weeks of intense workouts, the difference increased, and by the end of the month, the discharged soldier went home to Grodno…  
For some reason, he had no followers; even very dumb soldiers understood that an epidemic of shrinking arms would not go unnoticed.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_8">
	<text>This story happened when my uncle served in the Soviet army, around the 1980s.  
Two soldiers once brought sand to their military unit in a ZIL dump truck. A dump truck is very convenient: drive up to the spot, pull the lever, and the loose material falls in a neat pile according to gravity. But since it was late autumn with rain and frost, the sand in the bed had frozen slightly. It didn’t want to pour out properly. However, the driver and his partner, being models of indifference, reasoned that at the highest point, the sand would fall anyway like a punishment from heaven. Usually, that’s how it goes, but they didn’t account for the truck being on a slight incline. The unmoving sand significantly raised the truck’s center of gravity, causing the ZIL to tip over, finally releasing the sand. In the cabin, naturally, the soldiers fell on each other.  

The story is fairly ordinary — dump trucks tip over often. The most interesting part happens immediately after the fall: a crowd of soldiers, who were watching the unloading with interest, rushes to the truck cabin, smashing almost all the windows with boots and tools and pulling our two comrades out, grabbing anything they could. One ended up with a torn uniform, the other scratched on the face.  
It turned out the observing soldiers were scared of an explosion and decided heroically to rescue the drivers.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_9">
	<text>I don’t remember who told me this story, but it went like this. It took place in the Soviet army. In one region of our vast Motherland, there was a military unit; I don’t remember its specialization — infantry or artillery — but that doesn’t matter. Imagine a quiet, dark summer night, the whole unit sleeping a deep, strong sleep. In one of the barracks, as required, the duty sergeant (a senior conscript with just over a month left to discharge) and a young sentinel (fresh recruit) were on watch. The young man stood on a stool, fighting sleep with all his strength, while the sergeant dozed in the so-called “Lenin room.”  

Notably, the sentries and duty soldiers were equipped only with bayonets, strictly accounted for like any other weapon. At one point, the young soldier realizes that either his stomach isn’t used to army food or he caught an infection — or both. If he doesn’t act immediately, all the contents of his intestines will end up in his boots. Whispering in agony, so as not to wake the unit, he calls the duty soldier. The duty soldier, muttering and cursing all the “freshmen” who won’t let him finish his term peacefully, asks the reason for being disturbed. The young man quickly, clearly, and concisely explains his predicament as military regulations require. The sergeant, grumbling and cursing young men and their delicate stomachs, lets the duty soldier go to the toilet and takes the post himself.  

Civilization’s benefits like plumbing hadn’t reached this unit; there was a separate, very remote wooden toilet with three holes, no partitions. The young soldier runs to the toilet at breakneck speed, unfastening his uniform on the way, and positions himself over a hole. At the climax, the bayonet, issued for the defense of the Motherland, slips from his belt and falls mockingly into the hole. Realizing what happened, his urges intensify threefold. Scenes of being punished for losing his weapon flash through his mind, and worse — what the sergeant would do.  

Summoning all his courage, he trudges back to the barracks and tells the sergeant everything. Knowing he would be punished at least as much, maybe more, and his discharge delayed, the sergeant feels the urges in his own stomach. But a Russian soldier, as they say, is invincible and finds a way out. After a short thought, the sergeant finds what he considers the only solution: he dresses the young man in a full protective suit (for chemical weapon protection), a gas mask, and sends him back. “Go, dive, find a solution, and don’t come back without your bayonet.” The young soldier promptly carries out the order.  

But bad luck strikes: at that very moment, the duty officer, a Soviet army major, also needs to use the toilet. He goes to the same facility and positions himself calmly.  
Now imagine the major’s reaction when something in a gas mask, covered in excrement, with a bayonet in hand, emerges from the neighboring hole. According to the duty officer’s assistant, the major stormed into the duty room with wild eyes, one hand holding his unfastened pants, the other waving his service pistol, reeking of excrement and shouting something about saboteurs or evil spirits.  
The whole unit was raised on alert. After investigations, both soldiers received 15 days in the guardhouse, and the major was sent to calm his nerves.</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_baiki_10">
	<text>Here’s how it happened. In one military unit, training jumps were being conducted. The jump itself, with a standard airborne parachute (D-5), wasn’t particularly difficult. You roll out of the aircraft, count in your head: “501, 502, 503” — and after falling at least 60 meters, try to spot your deployed parachute canopy above your head. Once located, you land carefully. Everything usually went according to plan — jump, canopy opens, land safely.  

But one unlucky soldier had a problem. Yes, the canopy opened, but he didn’t reach the ground. A gust of wind carried him into the pines surrounding the drop zone. Picture it: hanging like a puppet in the branches of a massive pine, about 10 meters up. Reaching the trunk is impossible; climbing the lines is possible, but then comes the same problem — how to get down. Usually, you deploy the reserve parachute (on the chest) and use its lines to descend. Being young, several advisors immediately rushed to help. Enjoying the scene, everyone shouted in unison: “Pull the reserve!”  

What followed looked like a movie. The already frightened paratrooper grabbed a line cutter, cut the main canopy lines in one stroke, and, while falling, pulled the reserve parachute ripcord…  
P.S. I must note — the record for lowest-altitude parachute jumps was not set that day.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_11">
	<text>In my military department group, there was a student nicknamed “Yellow.” He had a unique talent for swearing, apparently from birth. And he ran into a typical student misfortune — during self-study, an officer caught him enthusiastically playing cards with another slacker…  

As punishment, they were made to stay after class, given a bucket of quick-dry paint, brushes, and ordered to paint all the desks and chairs that had been scribbled on by students. The work was completed, handed over to the duty officer, and brushes cleaned…  

The next morning, the cleaning lady came to mop the floors. The first thing she did was flip all the chairs onto the desks. Then she went to the teachers’ room, returned with the deputy head of the department, and showed him the familiar three-letter inscriptions on the unpainted sides of the chairs. That same day, the two mischievous painters appeared before the department head.  

— What on earth are you doing, students? — he mildly rebuked.  
Yellow suddenly stood at attention, clicked his heels, and reported:  
— Sorry, Colonel, it slipped out!  
— How many times did it slip out? — the colonel was astonished.  
— As many times as it slipped, I wrote it, — Yellow finished calmly.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_12">
	<text>Back then, I worked at an instrumentation institute in Moscow on Kutuzovsky Avenue, near the monument to the pilot Valentina Grizodubova — anyone passing by surely noticed the granite woman in a flight helmet. In the Soviet era, we developed airborne radar systems; after the USSR collapsed, we mostly switched to commercial orders — someone had to eat.  

Then we got an assignment from the Ministry of Defense to create a “black box,” the purpose of which I won’t reveal. During testing, we had to spend several hours in the technical compartment of an A-50 — not exactly sipping brandy in a Boeing seat, but that’s another story. The acceptance act required a test for airtightness. The enclosure had a tricky shape, but for simplicity, imagine a cube with a 1-meter edge. Soviet testing methods: the cube is lowered with a winch into a giant thick acrylic tank, about three meters deep. If bubbles appear, the item fails, including the electronics inside.  

The tank looked like an abandoned factory. The water was rusty and murky. The winch had been stolen long ago, so a worker had to submerge the cube manually. It’s a large, sealed aluminum cube. One man alone couldn’t do it. We engineers refused to help — our job was schematics, not playing with cubes. The soldiers, however, took over. Three of them rolled up their sleeves, climbed onto the ramp around the tank, and shouted, “One, two, three!” pushing the stubborn cube.  

They almost did it. At the last moment, the cube flipped onto its side; everyone except the cautious worker fell into the tank. Those nearby jumped back to avoid the dirty water, splashing everywhere. Chaos ensued: soldiers struggling, stepping on each other, a floating meter-long metal cube swinging and hitting anyone it could. Curses and cries filled the air. Half a minute, maybe more, until the fallen worker came to and helped the others.  

The soaked soldiers were taken away, presumably for 40-degree calming treatment, and the “presentation” ended. We smoked, discussed the events, and went back to work. Surprisingly, no one got in trouble. Later, the black box was accepted into service, even though some tests never got completed.  
P.S. Before the officials arrived, the device underwent all tests except the infamous tank dunking; that prototype may still fly on a Russian A-50 today.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_13">
	<text>Once I ended up in a hospital with a banal case of sciatica. I was around 25 then, a bit of a dandy, a ladies’ favorite, quite the Don Juan. To diagnose me properly, they decided to X-ray my spine. For this seemingly simple procedure, a pre-X-ray enema was required — to prevent intestinal contents from obstructing the view of any herniated discs.  

Armed with a large roll of toilet paper, I entered the designated room. A large room, with an elderly lady in a white coat. “Lie down here on your side,” she said. I complied. After administering the procedure, she left. I noticed a toilet in the corner — no partitions, just a solitary white fixture, inviting. Positioned on a pedestal, climbing it made one feel like a proud eagle on a cliff. And inside, the process was underway.  

I dashed to the door, searched for a lock — none. Peering into the corridor, I realized I wouldn’t reach the main men’s restroom. So, like a white-tailed eagle, I perched on the toilet.  

It turned out the hospital was full of female medical interns that day. The sight: a young eagle perched proudly on the porcelain, gripping the paper roll, while the spine preparation continued unabated. Every minute, a head popped in:  
— Is Mary-Ivanovna here? Oh!  
Another:  
— Mary-Ivanovna… oh!  

How many interns saw the proud bird, I don’t recall. Many, each prettier than the last. It didn’t exactly thrill me.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_14">
	<text>This happened in the Army. I studied at the Irkutsk Military Aviation School with my brother. We’re twins. Not identical, but hard to tell at a glance. Once, during exams, my brother ended up in the infirmary.  

How could he take the exam if he wasn’t released? I refused to take it for both of us, but lying in for him while he took it — why not? So I took the exam, rushed to the infirmary, swapped clothes with my brother. I’d never been in the infirmary and had no idea where anything was. My brother explained: go to the second floor, find room X, find bed Y in row Z — it’s yours. I found the bed, lay down, ready to rest.  

After about 5 minutes, a nurse entered: “G-ov, time for your shot!” I bolted, yelling: “What shot? I’m healthy!” She said: “I don’t know, I’m waiting in the Procedure Room.” I realized I was stuck — they were going to punish me for my brother. I thought to hide in the restroom.  

About 20 minutes later, I decided to leave. Crawled out, planning to sneak back to the bed. A lady in a coat saw me: “Oh, G-ov, carry these containers to the cafeteria.” I had no clue where it was, grabbed the containers, wandering hopefully. She hovered behind, pressuring me. Following the signs, I finally found the cafeteria. I dropped the containers and dashed back to the bed. Just as I settled, the nurse returned: “G-ov, how long do we wait? Come on.”  

And that was it. I received my dose of penicillin for my brother. We laughed about it for a long time, especially me.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_15">
	<text>This funny story took place in the glorious Soviet Army. Cadets were ordered to clean a howitzer. Everyone was bustling with the brush, running back and forth, the brush sprayed generously with a special cleaning solution containing SEVEN alkalis!  

Since this was happening in our country, the cadets cleaned the weapon without protective suits or even gloves. Suddenly, one of them needed to “take a pee.” He went, returned to formation, and started feeling increasingly uncomfortable! Looking down, he noticed that his member was swollen, red, and about four times its normal size!  

With no one around remotely familiar with medicine, the cadet was simply helped to wash the affected organ, wrapped clumsily in bandages, and sent to the infirmary.  

No doctor was present. Only a young nurse sat in the reception. Casting a stern glance at the wounded soldier, she asked:  
— What happened, serviceman?  
— Well… see for yourself…  

Embarrassed, the cadet showed his unzipped fly, from which the bandaged organ protruded.  
— My God! What did you do to it!? — the nurse exclaimed.  
— Cleaning the gun…  

He was cut off mid-sentence by the nurse’s wild laughter and the timely arrival of the doctor — the entire infirmary was paralyzed!</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_16">
	<text>I served in Germany. In Russia, one could sneak away on leave or absent oneself, but there, even if allowed, where would you go? Germans everywhere! One day we went on a field exercise. When we arrived, we heard via the grapevine that not far away was a lake with a nudist beach, something unimaginable in the mid-1980s — the mere thought of it was like five kilotons of Viagra.  

— Awesome! — I said to Igor, and began planning.  

The next evening, with the officers temporarily absent, we decided to seize the chance. Of those brave enough to go, only three remained — Igor, Musa, and me. The rest chickened out. As real scouts, we planned to reach the beach unnoticed, disguised as Germans. The lake was small; we swam around to the other side and intended to emerge naturally.  

On the opposite shore, we stripped off our cotton uniforms. Doubts crept in about remaining unnoticed.  

Musa, covered in body hair from head to toe, with tattoos and all sorts of soldier folklore, looked more like a Yeti than a German. But being sharp-sighted and hot-tempered, Musa, already glimpsing some female anatomy, refused to remove his blue cotton briefs initially. After some effort, we persuaded him.  

Musa was impressive. Midway across the lake, we swam like real Germans; the first naked figures and female voices appeared. Suppressing natural instincts, Igor and I reached the shore, lying on the sand as if nothing happened. Musa, however, remained waist-deep in water, mouth wide, eyes wide.  

Nearby Germans smiled. From Musa’s chest hair, a parachute with Cyrillic letters peeked, but Musa still believed he looked German. We signaled him to come out. He shook his head and replied in German: — Nein! After fifteen minutes standing frozen, he drew the attention of half the beach, causing laughter and encouraging German phrases, blushing under his body hair.  

We had to rescue him. Approaching from behind, we carefully pushed him onto the shore. Musa resisted, swearing in Russian, but finally fell onto his stomach. Already exposed, we dragged him onto the sand amid laughter and applause. He remained on his stomach, attracting local women’s attention. Igor and I later visited the nearby village a few more times, without Musa.  

P.S. Musa ran back into the water very quickly.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_17">
	<text>We had a pilot in our regiment famous for making forced landings in a jet with a dead engine four times. The fourth was the most entertaining.  

Here’s how it went. The airfield was on the Lena River. He took off normally, but at 600 meters the engine died.  

Jet planes without engine thrust fly like bricks thrown out a window. What to do? Below, the city; straight ahead, the Lena River, ice thick, winter — he put the plane into a dive straight for the river. He was heading to a range, bombs and rockets under the wings — quite a sight.  

He belly-landed, sliding on the ice — fast! About two kilometers, then opened the canopy and saw a man fishing, wrapped in a coat, oblivious. The pilot yells:  
— Hey, buddy, you’re in my hole!  

The fisherman turned, saw the jet, and ran so fast that even a jet afterburner wouldn’t catch him. Such was the story in our glorious Air Force, when fuel was plentiful...</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_18">
	<text>This actually happened to me in the Caucasus Mountains in the spring of ’95. I was studying journalism at the MESU (Kuban branch) in Krasnodar and often went hiking with a backpack, accompanied by other amateur (and overconfident) tourists. Gear: at best a few meters of rope, sometimes an ice axe. We were climbing Mount Achishkho, near the future Olympic sites. Twenty years ago, it was quite wild.  

The climb began on the second day after a night at a semi-derelict tourist base. The mountain itself wasn’t difficult; good for tourists, not mountaineers. The main challenge was the weather: late April, early May, snow thick on slopes and plateau, many deep cracks, avalanche risk, plus strong wet snow wind. I frostbit my left hand; my right hand, holding the ice axe, was fine. That’s the prelude.  

At one point, about 100 meters from the pass, the slope at 60°+ — I decided to climb left of the main group. Off I went, realized my mistake five meters later. Returning horizontally was dangerous; snow underfoot was wet, slippery. I slid downhill like a bobsled, no fear, just surreal detachment. Tried braking with the ice axe, then speed increased, bounced, hit my head — cap flew off, glasses — gone. My “eagle” eyesight of -7 meant near blindness. Tumbling, I slid about 200 meters.  

Finally, lying face down on a small plateau, I had to force myself to stand. Trembling, hands and legs numb, but not in pain. I understood the trip was over; without sight, only one way down — with a guide. Ten minutes later, Commander Gennady Ognev emerged from the mist.  

— Alive?  
— I think so…  
— Now…  

He went down a few meters, returned with my cap.  
— Here, don’t catch a cold.  

I asked, slurred, if he’d seen my glasses. Gennady laughed: I had dug snow like a tractor, dodging cracks like a slalom skier. Archaeologists would find my glasses in 25,000 years. Then the incredible: he bent down, pulled my GLASSES from under my left boot — intact!  

— Boy, you’ll live a hundred years.  

I’d never have believed such luck if it hadn’t happened to me. Thirty minutes later, on the pass, Svetlana fed us chocolate by hand, our own hands useless. That night, in an abandoned weather station near Achishkho, I saw a real ghost.</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_baiki_19">
	<text>Once we were celebrating a girl’s birthday. I, along with a few responsible lads, arrived on time, but the rest of the guests were late. For obvious reasons, nobody waited for the latecomers — the party was in full swing.  

Those who arrived were simply fined and welcomed into the group.  

By the time about 30% of the guests had gathered, everyone was quite drunk. The birthday girl went to the bathroom. A couple of minutes later, we heard screams from inside:  
— Open the door!!!  

As true gentlemen, we could not leave the lady in distress and, amid cheerful hooting, carefully removed the bathroom door from its hinges. The first words we heard from the girl sitting on the toilet in the proud eagle pose were:  
— IDIOTS! OPEN THE FRONT DOOR…</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_baiki_20">
	<text>This happened during the second campaign in the Chechen Republic. A group of heroes successfully completed a mission and reached Mozdok without losses (those who know understand) and were waiting for a flight at the airfield camp.  

At that time, the Mozdok airfield area had a transfer base, a large tent village (or a small tent town, depending on perspective) with streets, alleys, a headquarters (town hall), a canteen, etc. The heroes were assigned two tents on the edge of the village, but everyone piled into one (collective spirit). They bought some anti-stress medicine at the local pharmacy and went into nirvana (the flight was scheduled for the next morning).  

Among the heroes was a dog handler specializing in mine detection, with a female spaniel named Katya. At dawn, he discovered the dog was missing. Thinking she had gone on a dog business and needing to relieve himself, he stepped outside, calling softly at first, then louder — Katya, Katya, where are you? — and searched the nearby streets. No dog.  

Then a dreadful thought hit him (strengthened by lingering anti-stress medicine): the dog was lost! With the flight in a few hours, he could not cancel it — total disaster! Calling out in desperation — Katya, my girl! — he reached the main street near headquarters and the canteen.  

Suddenly, a girl’s head poked out of one tent, playfully saying — I’m here! At the same time, Katya appeared from a neighboring tent, guilty for the mischief (probably following the smell of food). A male tear welled up in the handler’s eye, relief, but the soul demanded revenge:  
— You little… bitch, sneaking into other tents!  

Within a second, the camp erupted in wild laughter. It turned out that coincidentally, the local serviceman was celebrating the birthday of a local soldier, Catherine, which lasted until morning. Nobody expected that a namesake would temporarily appear in camp and create this memorable mishap.</text>
</string>

<string id="dm_about_afgan_talk">
	<text>I’ve heard that some stalkers served in hotspots. Do you know anything about the Afghan and Chechen wars? Maybe some eyewitness stories?</text>
</string>

<string id="dm_about_afgan_end">
	<text>Thank you.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_1">
	<text>A friend recently told me a story. I’ll tell you too. The intelligence department of the 5th Directorate of HAD managed to insert an agent among the enemy. In Pakistan, he was recruited and sent back to Kabul with orders to blow up a school, carrying two kilograms of plastic explosive, about a meter of fuse, and two detonators. He brought it all to HAD and reported the assignment.  

KGB advisors asked me to examine it. I broke off a piece of the plastic explosive, lit a match — people jumped aside. The plastic ignited with bright flames. The fuse also burned properly. Quality excellent. To test the detonators, one had to be used, but advisors didn’t want extra noise. They pondered the next step. Blowing up the school was forbidden, but the agent had to be tested. The school, near the airport, was a two-story wooden structure, like a barn.  

I suggested:  
— Guys, give him to me. Imported explosives are for foreign operations. I’ll make a bomb from Soviet plastic explosive. The blast will be strong, windows everywhere, school unharmed.  

The senior advisor squinted cunningly:  
— Maybe you want it as a trophy?  
— Pff! — I left, offended.  

Next day, I first learned from Afghan colleagues about the night enemy sabotage. A patrol noticed someone tampering near the school cable manhole. The stranger fled. Soldiers leaned over the manhole; then the explosion occurred. Two soldiers injured. Power cable shorted, wooden school burned down.  

In the morning, I congratulated the advisors on the successful operation. They turned pale and ran to their subordinates. Reported to their chief. The chief philosophically remarked:  
— At least we successfully disguised our agent!</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_2">
	<text>I heard something. Our mentor at the Cordon told us by the campfire. Let me recall. Unarmed Khoshal approaches the gate of a villa where our hero is hiding. A jeep arrives. Khoshal is almost point-blank shot in the neck. Seeing him fall, a soldier fires an RPG-7 at the jeep. Two militants creep along the wall. Wounded and concussed by a nearby grenade, Khoshal grabs the pistol he was just shot at with and shoots the militants. Khoshal is carried away. The vehicle burns. They hide in the villa.  

Rashid’s friend appears, orders a grenadier to fire at the windows. Both grenades overshoot the roof, exploding somewhere in town. Rashid sends the driver with keys to his office. Under his couch are four disposable M-72 American grenade launchers (my gift). The driver returns. Rashid carefully fires each launcher at a window. Screams, smoke. The panicked prince in the basement calls the MGB, asks to stop the fire. Many dead. He surrenders.  

At Khoshal’s hospital bedside, two guards stand constantly — the prince had ordered his men to eliminate the operational regiment command along with advisors. He overreacted. We were innocent. But leadership sounded the alarm:  
— Forget a few advisors; worse if we lose Kandahar!  

The prince cannot be killed, must be calmed. He is flown to Sochi with two loyal wives, taking two bags — one of dollars, one of foreign trade cheques. The king publicly rebuked his foolish son. Returning from the Union, the prince went back to Kandahar. Relatives of killed militants pursued him. He fled across the border, later sending a tearful letter to a KGB advisor inviting him to… Pakistan.  

Khoshal recovered quickly. Remarkably, the 9mm Makarov round passed between his trachea and carotid artery without hitting vital nerves, vessels, or bones. Rashid ended up in the awkward role of the blood enemy of his former friend and drinking buddy. A showdown is inevitable.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_3">
	<text>The older guys used to tell stories by the campfire. Recently, one shared this one. A narrow path, with a small irrigation channel alongside. Thick bushes all around. Nothing visible beyond a few meters. The path twists and disappears around a corner. An ambush head-on!  

A 50-meter length of detonating cord, with a hand grenade tied every 5 meters — ten grenades in total. All this is placed in the water channel and camouflaged with grass. This time, we’ll detonate using an electric detonator. The grenade rings are pulled, their triggers held with string tied through the cord.  

Once the enemy lead guard approaches, the detonator presses the button. Explosion! How would a normal fighter react if it goes off half a meter from his feet? Naturally, he falls on the path. Even if the mujahideen quickly recover and look around, it’s too late — grenades lie all around.  

Crackling of grenades! Now our machine gunner must pin the remaining “spirits” to the ground with long bursts through the bushes while the detonator runs away.  

Since the lead guard in the “green zone” moves within visible distance (5–10 meters) from the column’s core, our grenade-mines are bound to hit 5–17 “spirits.” Trophies are unnecessary. Our goal is to strike hard so they won’t walk our street again. For training, we use RGD-5 grenades. In combat, we’d use F-1. F-1’s full blast radius is 3.7 meters; to be safe, we reduce it to 2.5 meters. So if a grenade goes off every 5 meters in an enemy column, even if prone — it’s no joke.  

Tests on the range showed detonating cord can throw F-1 grenades 0.5 to 15 meters.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_4">
	<text>Many didn’t like to recall this. From a seasoned soldier, I’ll share a tale. As the workload at the Paghman school increased, so did accidents. None fatal. A few times it happened to me too. The main cause was that we used only captured ammunition, often damaged in the enemy’s wet pits (no other supply).  

For example, every third or fourth 82mm mortar round didn’t fire. Imagine the nerve-wracking extraction! Chinese RPG-2 rounds caused trouble too — their black powder charges tended to get damp, so twice instead of firing, the powder burned slowly and grenades fell meters away. One, thankfully, didn’t explode. Another, exploding, injured three, including me. This was during my second mission.  

While showering at the villa, I noticed many small pimples scratching my palms. On closer inspection — tiny shrapnel. Had to pick them out with a needle. My bunkmate Alexander Ivanovich saw my green-stained stomach and said:  
— Go to the doctor, could cause sepsis!  
— Yeah, the doctor will report to the chief, I’ll get scolded and forbidden to work.  

A large fragment was stuck in a leather wallet in my pocket — it got stuck in a thick stack of Afghanis. Had it hit slightly to the right — disaster. Next day, advisor Vitaliy told a fresh joke:  
— Bek returns from a mission. His wife asks what gift he brought from Afghanistan. Sad Bek pulls a dried male organ on a string from his pocket.  

Another source of accidents: I was preparing “consumables” at the special forces school. The front required many trained fighters. They shouldn’t fear nearby explosions or whistling bullets. For comparison, two instructors from Moscow: in six months one prepared ten Afghans for a special lab. I trained over a hundred. Not that theirs was worse. Afghans observed: explosions scare either the totally ignorant or the highly professional. My students were in between — semi-professionals, fearless.  

Anything could happen in training. Once, someone shot under his feet with an AGS-17. Another time, a heavy 82mm mortar fell 20 meters away. A cadet accidentally loaded a hunting cartridge instead of a standard propellant.  

A nightmare: an OZM-72 bounding mine went off in an Afghan’s hands! If detonated, 2000 balls would mince us. Luckily, no detonator — it flew 20 meters, glanced his forehead, knocked him out, and everyone froze for a few seconds.  

Cadets often got scratches throwing RGD-5 and RKG-3m grenades. Two explosions occurred when collecting unexploded ordnance. Always wear protective goggles.  

One incident: teaching grenades to a special lab group. Many captured grenades. Divided by fuse type: instant and delayed. Instant: RKG-3 anti-tank, cumulative with parachute, RGO, RGN, and a defensive Egyptian grenade — cylindrical, enamelled, metal strip in middle, pierced by pin with lead seal. Pull pin, throw, spring unrolls, explodes on impact, shredding metal gears into nail-sized fragments.  

Delayed: F-1, RGD-5, RG-42, with UZRGM fuses, also English, American, Belgian, German, M-46.  

I explained grenade mechanisms to Afghan comrades and took them to the range. Instant grenades: throw high and far, hide immediately. Second class: can be handled less carefully. One fool mixed up — threw an Egyptian instant grenade nearby. Fell into mud, didn’t explode; spring didn’t fully unroll. I told the duty officer to destroy it; sergeant didn’t. Later, an Afghan lieutenant picked it up, spring snapped, he threw it aside. Explosion! Severed one leg to the knee.  

With M-46 in the 40th Army, a paratrooper lieutenant thought it was a smoke grenade. Pulled the pin, threw it in a smoking room. Result: a dozen dead. Officer shot himself.  

I averaged 1–2 accidents per month. My psychological state? Probably fatalism. What else could one do? Cadets must never see fear. Instructor must be fearless. Fatigue accumulates, not relieved by alcohol. Nervous breakdowns sometimes without reason.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_5">
	<text>Better not have reminded me — a sore topic. But I’ll tell one story. The operational regiment commander (our battalion had grown to a regiment) invited advisors to the “Kurban Bayram” celebration. Leadership, fearing incidents, forbade participation. Afghans were upset. The regimental logistics officer lamented:  
— We bought snacks for 20,000 Afghanis, and you didn’t come! A grave insult.  

Sergey, as a Muslim, tasked me to resolve it. At that time, I was on a provincial mission, so supposedly unrelated. I swore to partners the advisors were innocent, and we felt the incident too. Ready to make amends.  

Next day, the whole group visited the regiment. In the van — besides liters of cognac, vodka, champagne, and a box of dry wine — we carried several firearms. At the regimental range, we spread tents and laid out a German MG-42 (“Hitler’s saw”), PK, M-16, plus our RPK and AKS-74.  

Two translator-soldiers loaded belts. After three obligatory toasts, I announced a contest: a shot glass of alcohol for hitting the target! Afghans fired bursts. Gradually, everyone got competitive. Out of the corner of my eye, I noticed Din Mamad slowly backing away at the start of shooting. While everyone competed, he managed to knock over an extra glass, crawl back, and return to the firing line.  

We all liked the MG-42: 1300 rounds/minute, almost no dispersion — a burst hits a small target at 800 meters!  

After shooting and sipping champagne, hugging partners, we returned to headquarters. Incident resolved. Din Mamad — big, slightly stooped, from the commando unit, huge hands like rakes — whispered: let’s go to Kabul to see girls. He had a decent “chicken coop” there. But he only had the strength to reach his bunk. Collapsed, eyes open. I closed them:  
— Sleep peacefully, friend Din Mamad…</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_afgan_6">
	<text>A friend recently told me a story. As soon as we entered the sector controlled by Chechen fighters, she called over their commander and spoke at length, pointing at me. Then she said to me: “They considered you an FSB agent here, wanted to either shoot you or take you to the mountains, and I protected you.” Of course, I was full of gratitude, but thinking logically — who could have called me a security officer? Maybe they just didn’t believe her or didn’t have time to deal with me? Her son, Ruslan, after ’96, gladly helped me move around Ingushetia — first in his “Zhiguli,” then in a sporty Porsche. Talking to him wasn’t much about, except women, but very convenient for work. Still, he was an acquaintance. A “brother”...  

The day before October 4, when he offered to give me a ride to the checkpoint near Mozdok, one thing struck me. Ruslan mentioned having a beautiful girlfriend he visited almost every night, and then calmly added that he was married with two children. I asked: “Does your wife know? What does she say?” He calmly replied: “What can I tell her? She cries.” There was such cruelty in that calmness that it unsettled me.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_7">
	<text>I heard something. I’ll recount it from an eyewitness. On the morning of October 4, I overslept. Barely freshened up, I grabbed my things and went down to the hotel lobby. Ruslan was already there. I felt awkward that he had to wait; I fussed over checking out and paying for all phone calls. Neither while driving around Nazran, with Ruslan stopping at various addresses, nor on the Nazran–Malgobek road, did I remember the passport I left at the hotel front desk. Nor did I suspect anything. I would have reached Mozdok by noon and maybe even accredited at the federal forces press center preparing to enter Chechnya. With luck, I could have been in a forward unit by evening. With luck...  

Most likely, the idea to “sell” me arose in Ruslan’s mind only after returning to Nazran, when he started stopping at various addresses again. I can imagine a dialogue:  
“— There’s a journalist in my car… — Really? Who? — Seems from ‘Moscow News.’ — Alone? — Yes… — Wait… All right… Go to Magomed’s home, tell him everything, let him gather his men quickly. Got it? Then go to the hospital, find Said. He’ll settle with you. Decide where to meet…”  

Ruslan earned his money well — I hadn’t thought of any of this. The day was summer-warm and sunny, I filed one report, it went in the paper, and five more days of assignment were ahead — a chance to distinguish myself and do something notable for the newspaper. Mood was excellent...</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_8">
	<text>The older guys used to tell stories by the campfire. The following is from an eyewitness. The first days in captivity, I recalled the moment of capture with horror and pain. Stupid, bastard scum, greedy creatures thinking themselves supermen! Federal forces were already bombarding with full force, fully ready, and the situation didn’t allow for kidnapping — it wasn’t ’97 when bandits, feeling untouchable, were snatching journalists one by one! Federal troops, whatever their faults, were not the rabble called “presidential guard” or “state sharia security units” by Maskhadov! No matter the state of the Russian army, imagining officers themselves participating in abductions like the Chechen bandits of sovereign Ichkeria is impossible!  

Recalling that dreadful moment when the Judas left me alone in his car near the republican hospital while supposedly visiting his girlfriend, and a plain white “six” with Ingush plates stopped nearby, I realize this swift operation succeeded only because I froze for a split second. If I had shouted or started a fight, it would have gone differently. Not far away, around the corner, was a busy area — a bus stop, some shops. This relaxed me completely. When a blond man in military uniform, without insignia, peeked through the lowered car window: “Your documents! Passport check,” I thought nothing bad. I just got out and walked to the white “six”...</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_9">
	<text>Many didn’t want to recall this, but it happened. It’s our life. My former partner told me this story. Passing me into the back seat of his “six,” the bandits hissed in my ear: “Shut up, bitch! I’ll kill you!!!” and jabbed me in the side with pistols to convince me. Air in the plastic bag ran out fast, and I began suffocating, especially as I kept trying to shout. From this moment, time crumpled like paper.  

I remember the car racing through Nazran streets, someone’s strong hands tore off my belt bag with all documents, money, and wristwatches — a gift from my mother, in which I had dived in Crete in ’98. Someone pressed my head into their knees. Outside the bag, the bandits spoke in terse phrases in Chechen or Ingush. In shock, I yelled nonsense: “Basayev will kill you for me! Let me go or regret it! Don’t shoot! Then kill me, don’t take me anywhere!” The bandit jabbing me yelled: “One more word — I swear, I’ll shoot you like a dog right here!” and hit the gun butt above my ear. Not hard, but very painful.  

Soon I weakened from lack of air, begged for a breath. The car sped on asphalt. I rasped: “You’re Chechens! Better cut me than suffocate!” One bandit replied: “We’re not Chechens. We’re Arabs,” and all four laughed in disgusting, deliberate voices. They lifted the edge of the bag; the air inside, smelling of five sweaty men, felt refreshing like sea breeze.  

Then transferred to another car: “Get out fast, bitch, I’ll kill you! Here! Here!” — then to a third. Bandits switched cars. In the second, they were “kind” — lifted the bag so I could breathe, allowed smoking. Third car: “bad” again. I remember the soft ground under a fruit tree, lying face down, hands and shoulders stiff from ropes; two automatic riflemen forbade movement to ease the pain. After five minutes or an hour, a car approached, bandits kicked me up (with tied hands, standing was incredibly hard) and drove me like a sheep, shouting angrily. Dark when they brought me to the dungeon. My new home (for just two weeks, I later learned) was an unfinished garage among ruins and rubble. Hours before, I was free, planning steps and asserting rights. Now, I couldn’t believe I was a hostage — no longer quite human — and any bandit could do anything to me with impunity.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_10">
	<text>Better not have reminded me. A sore topic for many. Here’s what our commander told us. Now, after the wave of panic, pain, and constant tension subsided, I often think: could it have been different? All the circumstances leading to that fateful moment on October 4, 1999, around 3–4 p.m., when four bandits forcibly took me in their car, now seem a chaotic mix of coincidences and absurdities.  

If the day before I hadn’t suddenly decided to visit acquaintances in Nazran… If the “Assa” hotel clerks hadn’t been such kind, friendly girls, whom I didn’t want to offend (two days before capture, I jokingly but strictly asked: “Will my passport be safe with you?” Girls offered to return it; I said: “No, it’s safer with you — I always lose everything”)… If not for my cursed forgetfulness… If Ruslan, the Judas, had an old Zhiguli instead of a sporty two-seater Porsche, reaching Mozdok quickly and comfortably…  

These “ifs” make up any business trip — hot zone or safe country. But no matter how many assignments I had at Moscow News, circumstances always aligned perfectly. Perhaps luck had run out, and during that last trip to Ingushetia before a new big war, something bad was bound to happen. Lucky it was “just” a kidnapping. Lucky there remained a tiny hope, even in the darkest days.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_11">
	<text>A friend recently told me a story. Or rather, it’s a firsthand account. Thinking now of people who knew me since ’96, called me “nephew” and “brother,” and cold-bloodedly led bandits to me, I feel, besides dull anger, revenge, and hatred, a quiet, calm disappointment. Not so much in their integrity, but in their intelligence. How foolish and greedy must one be to deliver me into bandits’ hands without disguise or covering tracks!  

In the dungeon, I found only two explanations for such treachery — either they thought me a complete fool unable to make basic conclusions, or they were told I wouldn’t survive. The second explanation made me ill. I won’t name the “guides” — mother and son, though their surname appeared in Moscow News. This pair is now in a detention center; my kidnapping is just a minor episode of their family’s wild activity. Mother was already suspicious in ’96 — too businesslike, “mechanical,” with extensive connections in international humanitarian circles and among Chechen fighters. She claimed to have a selfless, noble nature, devoted to freeing Russian POWs, repeatedly facing death. To be fair, she wasn’t too afraid when we arrived March 7, ’96, in war-torn Grozny. At the time, I didn’t understand why she did it.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_12">
	<text>I heard something. More precisely, I read the last accounts of a former commander. Listen. April 4, around 3 p.m., the BMP gunner pushed us: “Get up, we’ll move soon!” Indeed, after 15 minutes, we moved… 600 meters to the road took an hour and a half. The “spirits” were above, shooting at us like a shooting range. From our company, 2nd and 3rd platoons went to the road, 1st and company HQ remained 200 meters back; 2nd and 6th companies flanked Goiskoye from the left.  

Our men decided to advance across the road, requested cover; my SVD didn’t fire — a grenade fragment in the bolt. I disassembled the rifle; found other metal fragments in the receiver. Checked all, tested rifle — worked.  

Our group moved to the road, throwing grenades at the spirits. Initially, a machine gunner-assault rifle team secured the spot. Under cover, the rest advanced. We drove the spirits from the position — about twenty. Retreating, they left five for cover — grenades shredded them. Dug foxholes didn’t help.  

We secured our position. Meanwhile, 6th and 2nd companies fought fiercely in the “green zone.” Eleven, including platoon leader filling company commander duties, fell there. Two weeks later, spirits requested bodies removed as decomposition progressed. Meanwhile, we blocked the right flank of 2nd and 6th companies. In one burrow, found a live “Czech,” who killed the boy who found him. Tried flushing him out — no luck. Poured kerosene, set fire, threw grenades — nothing. Apparently, the burrow path was angular, so he survived.  

While the fuss continued, main company forces arrived. They, having lost four men, failed to cross the field. Our platoon leader argued with company commander over late arrival. Commander shouted: “No clear orders from battalion commander!” Platoon leader: “Battalion commander was wasted. Had to decide myself!” While they argued, we inspected Chechen trenches, finished the wounded. Then ordered: “Fall back!” Absurd, of course. One draftee tried explaining on radio to hold position; no one convinced.  

Securing 6th company’s exit, we retreated. Self-propelled guns of 324 MSP shelled Goiskoye; we split into two groups. First withdrew with all gear, second covered. Withdrew normally, but incidents occurred. Last tank, number 420, covered everyone. During assault, spirits burned two BMPs — one ours, one 6th company’s. Tank hit burned BMPs for good measure. Then a gunner from “two” fired at it! Tankers said: “Not a big deal, but when your own hits you during retreat…” Shooter unknown.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_13">
	<text>The older guys used to tell stories by the campfire. One of them, a former soldier, shared this. Messy and boring — new recruits from some airborne brigade buzzing around. Three days with paratroopers, we turned Khankala into a fortress. Now a bit calmer. Spirits stopped silly night raids, we weren’t chased without reason. Timid generals allocated a whole Internal Troops brigade and an airborne battalion to guard tiny Khankala; a motor rifle regiment promised. Where would they be stationed? All rhetoric — nothing to do now.  

I go to the radio operators, need to know events, or war ends and I’ll be unaware.  
— Hi, “Broom.”  
— “Moscow,” got a smoke?  
— Anything new?  
— Marines, paratroopers, motor rifles, Sofrinets are active.  
For a moment, Dudaev, the asshole, doesn’t give up — life sucks, sun’s a damn lamp!  
— Heard news about our brigade?  
— Nothing specific, standing by, guarding “jackal” command…  

I try another wave on the radio; static breaks into “Chukchi” guttural speech, not Russian, whatever — we continue. I catch a motor rifle unit reporting they cornered “spirits” in a five-story building. No callsigns, pure swearing — some ensign Zinoviev had sexual relations with a BMP in an unimaginable spot…  

Good thing about booby traps — another spirit raid on our “Behemas” noticed in time. Fat “Broom,” during my radio interception, fell off chair while trying to put on body armor and grenade pouch, crashed to floor with loud noise. Would be funny, if not sad.  

In seconds, I rush to my vehicle, spot platoon leader behind rebar, enthusiastically firing at spirits foolish enough to appear in open. Either we’re truly capable soldiers, not a herd of deer as the commander claimed, or spirits were stupid, but we held Khankala well — almost no casualties. Two KIA in six days in January ’95 in Chechnya — not bad, though unfortunate they happened.  

After a few minutes, we assembled a combined platoon, swept the area — no spirits found nearby, placed a few traps and “lights,” nothing should roam without our knowledge. Another day in another war… Who needs all this…</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_afgan_14">
	<text>Many didn’t want to recall this. This is from an eyewitness. Having crossed the militants’ defensive lines in Grozny, we entered neighborhoods fully controlled by the “spirits.” Army camouflage and our unshaven, darkened faces with sunken cheeks gave us a chance to pass for militants in case of a sudden encounter with the “warriors of Ichkeria.” The militants’ mess was similar to the chaos in our own troops’ positions. Pass systems and passwords often didn’t work amid the general confusion, and shouting “Allahu Akbar” was sometimes enough to be accepted as one of them.  

Our goal was reconnaissance behind the militants’ battle lines and disrupting enemy communications by planting mines to create chaos and panic in their ranks. We moved only in the evening, but before dark. Nighttime movement through the city was dangerous, as both sides doubled their vigilance. At night, we hid in foul-smelling basements or abandoned houses in the private sector, selected after prior reconnaissance to have good views of all approaches to our hideout.  

Dusk was falling. We had been circling this district for two days, unable to find a passage to the neighboring area teeming with armed militants wearing green armbands. We had to wait out the night and move at dawn to the adjacent street. Earlier today, I noticed that the exit marked on our map had been turned by militants into a fortified position against Russian tanks, blocked with large debris — wrecked cars and a half-burned bus.  

A sixth sense told me the improvised barricade was surely guarded by “spirits,” so rushing in blindly was unwise. After setting guards and a lookout, we rested on a pile of broken bricks. The bricks dug into our backs, and inner tension prevented sleep. Turning onto my stomach, I lay on bent arms — uncomfortable, but forcing myself to sleep, as tomorrow would be hard.  

It wasn’t sleep. Closing my eyes, I fell into a trance of forgetfulness, somehow continuing to monitor the surroundings. I awoke suddenly. Silence. But my stomach felt cold and uneasy. Moments later, I simultaneously heard the crunch of debris, heavy footsteps, and a cautiously prowling flashlight beam.  

“Spotted! Where’s the lookout? Already with a slit throat?” — I was close to panic. I couldn’t hear my comrades’ breathing. They weren’t asleep, crouched like me in the brick pile. The flashlight carriers — surely a militant patrol — stopped near our hideout.  

A silence that felt like a lifetime. Heart in throat. “Calm down. This morning I read the Lord’s Prayer; God will protect me,” — this thought didn’t exactly calm me, but it helped overcome paralyzing, animal fear and prepare for action.  

Automatic rifle in hand. Fingers of the other hand found the cold, ridged surface of an F-1 grenade, meant for one purpose — not to be captured alive.  

Footsteps began to recede. “They didn’t find us.” Tension eased. Yet concern for the lookout comrades remained.  

A signal. “Our people!” Two shadowy figures slid to us. Militants had appeared suddenly from a basement we hadn’t noticed at first. At dawn, we cautiously left our hideout, leaving a few “presents” — two MON-50 mines. Exiting the basement and surveying the area, we found a barely noticeable passage into the basement, which turned out to be a throughway to the street we previously couldn’t access.  

After mining this passage, which militants might still attempt to use, our group slipped behind the “spirits” near the tram depot. Staying long was unwise; the depot and surrounding area teemed with militants as Makhadov’s headquarters was there, and they could stumble on our “presents” and realize intruders were in their territory. Collecting reconnaissance data visually, setting and camouflaging mines, we prepared to withdraw. The retreat route planned and approved by command was poor. Or rather, while behind enemy lines, the situation had changed. Contact lines had shifted; in some areas militants created new strongpoints. We had to recon further and find new retreat routes.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_15">
	<text>Better not have reminded me. A sore topic for many. Listen to an account from a veteran. Although our group included men who had lived in Grozny before all these events, navigating the ruined city was extremely difficult. In some areas, positions from five days ago might now be held by our troops, creating a high risk of coming under fire from federal forces. While there are no “smart” deaths, it’s still foolish to be shot by your own.  

To prevent this, constant reconnaissance of the terrain was necessary. I witnessed the consequences in January 1995, when our reconnaissance groups accidentally encountered our own forces. A similar group under Vadim ran into “Volgograd troops” (8th Army Corps under General Rokhlin) in Grozny. Lack of coordination proved tragic: Vadim’s group was mistaken for the enemy, and fire was opened. One member was killed. Vadim jumped from cover, shouting, “Don’t shoot! We’re friendly!” When detained by approaching troops, it turned out he had no documents. Vadim, attempting to explain, was brutally beaten and nearly executed. After investigation and requests for confirmation to higher command, he was taken in critical condition to the “Northern” hospital.  

I stood by his bed, pained listening to his broken, stammering words, repeating: “Y-y-you understand, I got c-c-concussion in A-A-Afghanistan, and h-h-here it’s the end…” Two hours later, he was transported by special helicopter to Mozdok, then to a hospital on the “mainland.”  

Running through a small park, through an arch, we entered a courtyard. It seemed from another life. The war had spared it so much that ruins on neighboring streets made the arch look like a gate between worlds. The silence was unusual.  

Yet the deceptiveness of silence in war became apparent within minutes. Trusting it, we made a mistake that nearly led to a tragic outcome. We violated fundamental rules of movement in enemy territory: “Trust neither eyes nor ears. Trust only instincts. Check seven times…” and other principles, never to relax.  

From a second-floor window of a neighboring house, someone called in Chechen. We froze. Not receiving an answer, fire was opened. Either poor shooters or our “animal instincts” kicked in — only one in our group received a light glancing wound in the side, as we quickly took cover behind high concrete slabs.  

To avoid wasting ammunition, we refrained from heavy firing at the enemy in the building. Under cover of the same slabs, replying with short bursts and single shots, we bought time to make the “only correct decision.”  

Through basement windows, we entered a three-story house behind us, one by one. Swearing at our carelessness, we first helped the wounded. Two went on reconnaissance; the rest took defensive positions. Recon returnees reported that Russian troops storming the city were nearby. Apparently, the proximity of federal forces prevented the militants who fired at us in the courtyard from taking further action against our group in the house. Or maybe it was an enemy group similar to ours, not meant for prolonged open combat. In any case, we quickly established communication with the command of federal units, and within an hour were sent on BTRs to the “Northern” sector.</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_afgan_16">
	<text>A friend recently told me a story. Now I’ll tell you too. The “ceasefire” turned into a bloody tragedy the very next morning. At 10 a.m. on Staropromyslovskoye Highway, militants detonated a remote-controlled mine planted on the roadside. Shrapnel from the exploded 152-mm howitzer shell (tank and howitzer shells were used by militants as improvised mines) pierced the armor of a BTR, instantly killing the driver. The uncontrollable BTR, moving at 70 km/h, jumped to the opposite side of the highway, knocked over a concrete lamp post, and stopped, covered in blood and brains of the 101st Internal Troops brigade soldiers on board.  

Four soldiers died instantly, the fifth, whose legs were blown off, died on the way to the hospital, the sixth died on the operating table. Nearby, an elderly Russian woman passed, covering her face with her cloak, unable to hide her tears. She had to hide them from the crowd of Chechen youth gathered at the intersection, cheerfully discussing the event.  

The same day, the Main Department of Internal Troops (GUOSH) received five militants captured at a checkpoint. Dressed in black clothing resembling uniforms, they carried weapons, half of which were equipped for silent firing. Leaving Shali after an operation by federal troops under General Shamanov in May 1996, this group attempted to infiltrate Grozny.  

The leader of the group, as revealed during investigation, was also the commander of a reconnaissance unit from Shamil Basayev’s detachment. The captured militants testified that they came to Grozny to carry out terrorist attacks. Evidence included a list of Chechen government officials with identifying features and office locations. Interrogations revealed they were also ordered to evacuate the families of militants fighting in the mountains by June 10. All this suggested that the “ceasefire” was being used by the militants for their own purposes, hardly peaceful. Tensions in Chechnya increased daily.  

The refusal of Russia’s military and political leadership to live by the rules of an undeclared, yet real war led to the tragic events in Grozny on August 6, 1996.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_17">
	<text>I’d heard a bit. This story comes to mind. It’s old. My company was called up to disarm a Chechen stronghold, while the “Vovans” (MVD Internal Troops special forces) did the main work and we only covered them. When the Vovan commander was brought the village elders, he demanded they hand over 24 AKs within two hours. One elder got cocky, acting like Lukashenko. He claimed the village had a legitimate self-defense unit but lacked rifles, so the federals had to immediately provide 20 more AKs. The Vovans were slightly taken aback, but we didn’t hesitate. The brazen elder received a burst to the bread cutter (machine gun) in front of everyone, and while his legs twitched, the others heard the delicate request: not 24, but 100 rifles, and not in two hours, but one. The Chechens complied in forty minutes, handing over exactly 100 rifles.  

The moral: politics and diplomacy work with partners within certain limits. With a partner who’s lost all restraint, a different set of tools is needed.  

I saw bus columns reeking so badly you couldn’t approach within 100 meters, packed with bodies of slaughtered Russians. Women cut evenly by chainsaws, children impaled on signposts, intestines artistically draped over fences. We Russians were wiped off our land like dirt under nails. And this was 1992 — two and a half years before the First Chechen War.  

Then it got even worse. Militants came to a stanitsa, cleaning out Russians. At night, cries of people being raped and killed in their own homes could be heard. No one came to help. Everyone was on their own. Some even tried to justify it ideologically: “my house, my fortress.” I heard that then — the man who said it is dead; his guts were draped over the fence of his own house. That’s how we, the cowardly and foolish, were killed individually. Tens of thousands of Russians were murdered, thousands enslaved or taken into Chechen harems, hundreds of thousands fled Chechnya in just their underwear.  

This is how the Vainakhs solved the “Russian question” in their republic. And they succeeded only because we were worthless, complete trash. We’re still trash now, though less liquid — steel grains are starting to appear among the filth. When these grains unite, Kondopogi happen. Few so far, but the Vainakhs are clever — real forest janitors. Their cultural mission gradually restores Russian people.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_18">
	<text>Yes, older guys used to tell stories around the fire. There were a couple of veterans. Listen. In the war, fate brought me together with a Jew — Lev Yakovlevich Rokhlin. Initially, we weren’t supposed to participate in the New Year assault. But when contact with the 131st Motorized Brigade and 81st Regiment was lost, we were sent to help. We broke into the 8th Army Corps’ positions under General Rokhlin and reached his headquarters. That was the first time I saw him personally. At first glance, he didn’t impress: hunched, cold, cracked glasses… Not a general, but a tired agronomist.  

He tasked us with gathering the scattered remnants of the Maikop brigade and the 81st regiment and bringing them to Rokhlin’s reconnaissance battalion. That’s what we did — collected scared troops from basements and brought them to Rokhlin’s scouts. About two companies in total. Initially, Rokhlin didn’t want to use them, but when all other groups retreated, the 8th Corps remained surrounded in the city center, against all militants. Then Rokhlin lined up these men opposite his troops and gave a speech. I’ll never forget it. The gentlest words he used were: “fucking monkeys” and “faggots.” At the end he said: “The militants outnumber us fifteen to one. No help is coming. If we are to die here, let each of us be found under a pile of enemy corpses. Let’s show how Russian soldiers and generals die! Don’t let me down, sons…”  

Lev Yakovlevich is long gone — taken care of without you. One less Jew, right?  

I told you about Rokhlin’s speech. What happened next I didn’t tell. Then came a terrifying fight — from my 19-man platoon, only six survived. When the Chechens broke into our positions and it came to grenades, realizing we were doomed, I saw real Russians. No fear, only a mix of furious calm and detachment. One thought: “Father asked us not to fail.” The wounded bandaged themselves, injected themselves with promidol, and kept fighting.  

Then we engaged the Vainakhs in hand-to-hand. They ran. That was the turning point in the battle for Grozny. It was a clash of characters — Caucasian versus Russian — and ours proved stronger. That’s when I realized we could do it. This inner strength exists; it just needs to be cleansed of the accumulated filth. In close combat we took prisoners. They didn’t whine — they screamed in terror. Then we intercepted a radio order from Dudayev: “Do not take 8th Corps scouts or VDV special forces alive or torture them; kill and bury them as warriors.” We were very proud of this order.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_afgan_19">
	<text>Many didn’t want to recall this. It was a tense time. Between Goyskoye and Komsomolskoye were orchards, and behind them the militants had ATGM positions. Their operator was excellent, hitting targets three versts away. He even tried to target the 324th regiment’s checkpoint, firing from four kilometers out. One day the commander assigned us to take out that ATGM. We assumed the position was well-guarded, so eliminating the operator had to be silent. We asked the commander to issue a VSS “Vintorez” sniper rifle. He did, but someone had to pick it up with the head of the missile-artillery service. We went to the regiment on a passing convoy.  

The situation in Goyskoye: the militants couldn’t break our resistance because we outmatched them in firepower, and we couldn’t take Goyskoye due to small numbers. Anyway, we pressured the militants, who warned that if any unit of the 245th Regiment approached Goyskoye, they would block the gorge.  

In Nizhniye Atagi, waiting for the convoy, it arrived at 1:30. The convoy included returning draftees and those leaving for family leave. (They weren’t accounted for, so casualty numbers were hard to determine later. One Ural with about 20 draftees burned after one “Shmel” hit — supplies inside, boys sitting on top, all burned…)  

I checked the convoy mail — none. Going back, I saw four “Nalivniks” in a row; one had my friend Arkasha. He was deputy platoon commander. Lucky! I asked, “Space in the cabin?” He said, “Come see.” I moved a vodka package and fit inside.  

Around 14:00 we moved. At 14:10, passing Chishki and entering the gorge, shots fired. Arkasha noted only women and children ahead. Previous intel: if men, women, children — safe; if only women — ambush.  

The convoy stretched along the serpentine. Trucks barely maneuvered. We joked along the way. Passed Yarishmardy, the lead was around the bend. Then explosions ahead — tank turret thrown, second blast elsewhere, third between us and lead truck. Hood torn off, windows shattered. I was concussed first time. Arkasha already out, I tangled in the doors, eventually fell out. Intense fire, but I managed 15 meters away. Found a ditch, lay low. A conscript soldier beside me. First shock passed, assessed situation — not good. Trucks stopped. Platoon fired all directions, enemy positions unclear. Arkasha fired at a militant under his truck.  

A grenade landed in a truck behind us, burning it. Estimated the blast would hit us — high danger. Saw someone 170 meters away, aiming new grenade — I shot him. Others firing from trench, one I shot but unsure if killed. Militant crawled uphill on all fours, first shot scared him, second flipped him over.  

Arkasha removed burning truck. Smoke obstructed aim; we decided to retreat. Covered sectors, I fired forward, he covered rear. Reached tree line. RPGs fired at rear tank — eight hits no effect. Eventually hit commander’s hatch, smoke emerged. Crew likely wounded, driver reversed through column, reached regiment.  

One hour since start. Fire dying down. I said, “Dima, let’s reach column end!” Under bridge, saw seven in Afghan hats, two corpses. Approached, one turned — black beard, hooked nose, wild eyes. I raised rifle… others were ours — contract soldier. A BMP crawled, collecting wounded. Hit in torsion, limping. Picked up wounded, moved to road; ammo vehicles burning around. Fighting almost ceased.  

Closer to Argun, men shouted about wounded. Jumped to help, found major — camouflage, Marine insignia, bullet wounds. I applied a tourniquet. They brought beer, cigarettes, juice. Dark approached, militants descending, artillery carefully fired on slopes, helicopters hit mountains. Reinforcements arrived: T-72, BMP, another tank. Tank aimed at us — we waved, tank fired at greenery, 20 meters away. Troops from 324th Recon crawled, fired. I directed them, ordered ten men forward. Counted over forty burned bodies. Some vehicles untouched, showing militants had intel. Delayed support — came two and a half hours later, battle already over.</text>
</string>

	<string id="stalker_afgan_20">
	<text>Bad idea to remind me. This is a painful topic for many. This was found in the diary of one of the fallen. Damn! If I get out, I’ll quit smoking, drinking, and that sort of thing — but later!  
Right now, I need to hold on! Where the hell is the BON!  
— Maljava, damn it, call reinforcements, they’ll tear us apart!  
— They told you ten times — not before an hour, unless they get burned on the way.  
— An hour from now we could be buried in a matchbox!  
— Well, ask the militants to stop shooting?  
— We need to retreat, the company commander is dead! BON is lost somewhere, the paratroopers are asleep too…  

Fed up! A few more such conversations and I’d lose it myself. Need to focus, distract myself as best I can in this hell.  

Then, as if on cue, fire from the militants ceased. Mines stopped whistling, ricochets died down, no “native” screams. Silence hung — worse than the mines’ whistling.  
— Did they run out of ammo?  
— Hell no, they’re plotting something, bastards.  

Then gunfire roared from the opposite side.  
— What is it?  
— No idea!  
— Guys, that’s the paratroopers! Definitely elite! No one else!  
— Hooray!  
— Go get the bastards!  

Without orders, everyone rose from the fortifications as one and rushed to the modest two-to-three story buildings. The militants quickly realized they were being attacked from two sides. Some tried to break out but were almost completely wiped out, the rest were finished off slowly. Clearing the buildings I remember vaguely (on the way to Khankala, slightly concussed).  

Then our long-awaited BON and paratrooper units arrived. Much later, a mini-brigade of “commanders’ fathers” showed up and… a quiet (as much as possible in Chechnya) winter evening. Sitting on the steps of the new headquarters, smoking, thinking that it’s finally over. We are Internal Troops — so basically cops, and our job is to guard cops. Means the paratroopers will hit Grozny, I’ve had enough fighting!  
Six days later, our brigade was sent to Grozny…</text>
</string>

<string id="dm_about_aneki_talk">
	<text>Will you tell a joke?</text>
</string>

<string id="dm_about_aneki_end">
	<text>Heh, it happens.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_1">
	<text>Listen. Male solidarity. One summer, my friend and I were sitting in a car, drinking beer. Windows open in nearby houses. Silence around, just our music. From the second floor came moans and groans, we turned down the music, listening, laughing. Suddenly the moans stopped and a girl shouted: — And that’s it? The guys didn’t even finish the song! My friend stuck his head out and yelled: — Don’t crush the guy, we paused it!</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_2">
	<text>Listen. In university, a psychology lecture. Professor: — Today we’ll study three initial stages of human psyche: surprise, irritation, and anger. He dials a random number. — Hello, is Vasya there? — No, he doesn’t live here. — See, — the professor smiles, — that’s mild surprise. He dials again. — Hello, Vasya didn’t answer? — No such person here. The professor rubs his hands, winks at the class, dials a third time. — So no Vasya? — Go to hell! — Well, hope the example is clear. A student from the front row stands. — Excuse me, professor, but you forgot the fourth stage. — Which one? — The stage of utter disbelief. He approaches, dials. — Hello, this is Vasya. No one called me?</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_3">
	<text>Listen. It was December 31, around 10 p.m. Going to celebrate New Year. Carrying three decent bags — you know what’s inside. Slightly drunk ourselves. Five minutes from the destination, anticipating fun, suddenly… a police car softly brakes about ten meters away. Sergeant gets out, heading straight for us. Thoughts — worst case, money extorted, New Year in the cell. Sergeant approaches: — Put the bags down! — we obey. I say to my friend: — Hands out. He spreads his hands. — A handful! — he places a handful in his hands. Sergeant reaches into his pocket, dumps a handful of candies into his hands, then turns to the car. From the car he calls back: — You’re expecting a New Year miracle, right!</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_4">
	<text>Listen. Morning assembly. Company commander’s grim gaze inspects the formation. Stops on a recruit without a belt. — Comrade soldier, where is your belt? Soldier, clearly from an educated family but learning army lingo, tries to explain: — Comrade Major, it was stolen. — “Stolen” doesn’t exist in the army, — replies the commander. Soldier blushes from freckles to ears. Then commander: — In the army, the word is “lost it.”</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_5">
	<text>Listen. After a battle, soldiers sit angry — many wounded, couldn’t drive Germans from heights. Discuss what to do if Hitler were caught. One: — Drown him in shit! Others: — No, too painful. Sergeant smokes. Second: — Quarter the bastard! All: — No, too fast. Sergeant smokes. Third: — Tie him in an anthill, let them eat him! — No, visibility bad. Sergeant finishes smoking: — Now listen, sons, what we’ll really do! Take an iron rail, heat one end, shove the other where it hurts! Grave silence. Youngest asks: — Sergeant, why cold? Should be the other way! Sergeant instructs: — So allies won’t pull him out!!!</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_6">
	<text>Listen. Traveling in an open carriage: Emperor Alexander III, Prince Golitsyn, Lieutenant Rzhevsky — on guard. Suddenly a bomb thrown by a revolutionary. Rzhevsky intercepts, throws into Neva. Emperor: — Lieutenant, I owe you my life — ask anything! — I ask for Princess Golitsyn’s hand. Emperor to Golitsyn: — Prince, you hear? He hesitates: — Your Majesty… — Prince, I understand. General Rzhevsky asks for your daughter’s hand. — But we are one of Russia’s oldest families… — Fine, Prince, I agree. General Rzhevsky asks. — Oh Majesty! Others may object! — I accept all conditions. General Rzhevsky asks. Golitsyn: — I agree. Rzhevsky shoves him aside, plops next to Emperor, pats Tsar on the knee: — Sanya, why do we need this princess? Look at all the women around!</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_7">
	<text>Listen. Young man in a cafe, coffee, notices a beautiful girl at the next table. Finally: — Can I join you? Girl shouts to the whole cafe: — I’m not sleeping with you! Everyone smiles. Young man blushes, returns to table. Girl joins him: — Sorry, I’m a psychologist writing a dissertation on “Behavior of different people in inadequate situations.” Young man, to whole cafe: — WHAT?! TWO HUNDRED BUCKS?! Girl runs outside. He calmly gathers himself, goes out, says: — Pleased to meet you, I’m a lawyer and I know how to make people feel guilty...</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_8">
	<text>Listen. Scientists created a unique AI computer with vast knowledge, speech processor, and emotion synthesizer. It should answer any question. Before showing it to the public, they asked a tricky question. — Can a man screw a woman? — asks a creator. — Can, but hitting a woman is immoral, — answers the computer. — How stupid he is! — creators laugh. — I won’t answer anything else, — says the computer. — Fuck off.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_9">
	<text>Listen. A priest was building a church. All was fine, but the bell tower kept falling. Built again, fell again. Angel appeared: “Wall in your wife in the foundation and your church will last forever.” Priest loved his young wife, but God too. Needed the church. He sadly walled her in. Bell tower still fell. Because structural mechanics cannot be fooled.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_10">
	<text>Listen. Two cars at an intersection: a 600 and a Kopiyka. Big guy exits 600, chains in hand, same from Kopiyka. 600 driver: — You hit a new car, same model! Other: — You hit it! — calls on mobile. An hour later, they bring a brand new zero Mercedes. Other: — Got a new one in an hour?! First, stunned: — Yeah… — Now YOU get me a NEW KOPIYKA! In an hour! Time starts!</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_11">
    <text>Well, listen. A guy tries to pick up a tipsy girl in a bar: "I bet 10 bucks I can impress you like never before without even touching you." "You’re an idiot, that’s impossible. Someone stop him!" They shake on it, he takes her home, and they spend the night chatting and playing games. In the morning, she wakes him and says: "That was really the best night of my life, but you kept joking around." "Take your ten bucks on the table," he mumbles in his sleep and turns to the wall.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_12">
    <text>Well, listen. A scary woman, with a face like a brick wall, enters a shopping center with her two sons, glaring at everyone and scolding the kids for the slightest thing. A shop assistant greets her: "Hello, welcome. What cute children! Twins?" "What nonsense are you talking, silly? One is 9, the other 8! Are you blind or just foolish?" "Neither, I just couldn’t believe someone dared to mess with you twice," she replies.</text>
</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_13">
        <text>Well, listen. At a resort, an unremarkable little man kept pestering a gorgeous lady about having sex with him. She just laughed at him, saying, “With your talents...” Then the man bet her that he could have sex with her twenty times in a row. The only condition was that everything had to take place in complete darkness and that he had to wash himself after each time. The bet was a car, and the woman agreed. Night fell, and the man got down to business... Once, twice, three times... after the seventeenth time, the woman couldn't take it anymore and begged: “That's it! I lost! I can't take it anymore, turn on the light!” The light came on, and she saw a completely unfamiliar, burly man standing in front of her. “Who are you?!” she screamed. “What are you doing here? Where's the short, skinny one?” “Oh, you mean the entertainer? He sells tickets at the entrance...”</text>
    </string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_14">
    <text>Well, listen. Attention! A new scam! Important to know! A group of young girls operates as follows: You leave the supermarket, approach your car, load your groceries, and get ready to leave. At that moment, two girls run up, asking for a ride to the subway, claiming their money was stolen and their mother is waiting. You agree. One sits in front, the other in back. Suddenly, while you’re distracted, they start creating chaos in the car. Questions many wonder: 1) Which supermarket should you watch? 2) What does the one in the back like to eat?</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_15">
    <text>Well, listen. A schoolgirl is getting ready for prom and asks her mother: "Mom, if I kiss a boy, can I get pregnant?" Mother (smiling): "No, of course not." "What if we kiss more passionately?" Mother (tense): "Also no." "What if I do more intimate things?" Mother (shocked): "No, you won’t get pregnant." "And what about other experiments?" Mother (fainting): "God, daughter, are you planning all this at prom?!" "No, mom, don’t worry. I’m just figuring things out."</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_16">
    <text>Well, listen. Grandpa, a WWII veteran, was sent to Germany on a tour by his children. At the embassy, he fills out a form: "Date of last visit to Germany." He writes: April–May 1945. "Mode of transport" (underline as appropriate)... options: plane, train, car… other. Grandpa skips everything and writes: "T-34 tank!"</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_17">
    <text>Well, listen. A prosecutor reports to the president: "Vasilyeva pointed to Serdyukov, Serdyukov to Chubais, Chubais to Surkov, Surkov to Medvedev, Medvedev to..." "Enough," interrupts Vladimir Vladimirovich, "it’s already quite clear that nobody is guilty of anything..."</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_18">
    <text>Well, listen. A clever insurance salesman: New soldiers were herded into a room. The insurer stepped onto the stage, smiled and said: "Guys, I know you don’t want to listen to nonsense, so I’ll explain insurance in one minute. Simple: if you don’t have it and die in battle, the government sends your family condolences. If you have it and die, the government sends your family $20,000." He paused, scanned the room, and asked: "So, who do you think will be sent to battle first?"</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_19">
    <text>Well, listen. A husband and wife go to bed. Husband, half-asleep, says: "Svet..." Wife slaps him hard on the forehead; he pops his eyes open: "For what?" "What Svet? I’m Galya!" "What Galya?! You fool! Turn off the light!"</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_aneki_20">
    <text>Well, listen. A man committed a crime. He was caught and brought before the king. The punishment was death, but the king offered him a choice: hanging or entering a large, black, steel door. The man chose hanging. As the noose was placed, he asked: "What’s behind that door?" The king laughed: "Funny thing, I offer this choice to everyone, and all choose the noose." "But what’s behind the door?" asked the man. "I won’t tell anyone," said the king. After a pause, he added: "Freedom. But people fear the unknown more than the rope!"</text>
</string>

	
<string id="dm_about_zonanews_talk">
    <text>Tell a story about the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_about_zonanewsend">
    <text>Interesting.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_1">
    <text>So we climbed into that hangar. Dust, cobwebs, the works—all the way to the roof; detectors went haywire, claiming there was no one around, not even us. We went to cover positions: Sanyok up front, the rest of us providing support… Then—CRASH! Huge rusty beams fell from the ceiling. Sanyok somehow dodged, but one beam landed exactly where he had been. He went down and started firing from the ground! The rest of us panicked and scattered. Sanyok started shouting about something in the corner. I looked—nothing there. It was chaos. We cautiously moved through the ruins for a few minutes, trying not to end up under another falling beam. Everyone started imagining things, firing at empty spaces. Two of the guys got unlucky: one fell into a hole in the floor, the other got hit by a falling door. We were sure some creature was messing with us. We activated psychic defense, threw gas grenades into the corners, and waited, guns ready. Turns out the creature was flying—it had been above the ceiling all along, having fun while we struggled below. Eventually, it brought down a few more beams onto us, flattening four guys. That’s when we got it. Sanyok heard rustling above and fired instinctively. We all joined in, hitting it however we could. Finally, the commander pulled us off before things got worse.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_10">
    <text>Have you heard of the Guide? The very first stalker. The first to venture into the Zone, and still alive. They say he can lead you anywhere. The problem is finding him—he doesn’t advertise, and he doesn’t take just anyone. He charges a lot, but if you find him and make a deal, he’ll take you exactly where you need to go. Now that’s someone worth talking to. He probably knows what’s behind the radar…</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_11">
    <text>Showing off and having money are two very different things. Do you think money here is given away for free? No way. Without thinking, you’re either going to be eaten by some creature or killed by another stalker. You need to be careful. Smart people survive, fools don’t last long. Once, the three of us—me, Sinyak, and Tsepa—were cutting through a yard. We saw a small deer dragging a bag, unnoticed. Sinyak whispered to check it out, but I said, "Watch where he’s going first." Suddenly, it fell into a hole. While waiting, Tsepa quietly approached and grabbed some loot. When we started searching, the trap went off, and I had to retreat fast. Came back a month later, everything gone. Then I ventured inside myself and found a hidden hatch with some treasures. Lucky me, I didn’t come back empty-handed.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_12">
    <text>They say there’s a group of guys—some call them shamans, some druids. They don’t carry electronics, closer to nature. They claim the Zone reacts violently to electronics and emits dangers if disturbed. A proper person can handle the Zone without fancy equipment. They do carry weapons, though. Their survival rate is about the same as ours. Most operate from the Belarusian side. Would be interesting to watch them and see how many artifacts they carry.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_13">
    <text>Anyone heard of the secret labs deep in the Zone? Supposedly still operational. It’s unclear how anyone survives there without supplies or energy. Maybe it’s not humans working there. I spoke to a guy who never saw a lab but intercepted strange communications at Yantra. Someone mentioned a lab, and another swore he saw a figure in advanced gear, half-transparent, telling him to leave. He panicked. Could be mutations, or energy-based entities. Hard to know.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_14">
    <text>You know what I’ll say? In this part of the Zone, it’s almost impossible to sleep. Some people get nightmares so severe they don’t wake up. I’ve heard of a trick: find an old bucket or large pot, put your head inside, and sleep like nothing exists. Lately, soldiers have been wandering around in new helmets—apparently with a wire mesh inside. They’re preparing approaches, maybe towards the Sarcophagus. Best be far from here when that happens.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_15">
    <text>Hey, guys, have you heard about the Interceptors? They’re specialists, trained soldiers. They operate differently from border guards—stationed in the Zone for months, with multiple bases and supply drops. Commander is called Gromov—or “Major” or “Grom.” They can detect monsters from 200 meters away. They even have people who can tame creatures. Artifacts? Plenty. The Duty faction knows about them, but they stay quiet.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_16">
    <text>Brothers, have you heard about a few intruders near the antennas? Monolith guided us, and the brothers spotted them just in time. One was destroyed immediately. Two ran away. Cowards. Only true faith leaves no room for fear. Monolith is wise; he let them live for a reason.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_17">
    <text>Brothers, Monolith called me at night. I spoke with him. His presence was magnificent. I almost blinded myself, but his light filled me with strength. I know his power is with all of us. He said only strong faith can defeat evil. His power will support the faithful. Our victory is near!</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_18">
    <text>I think… maybe this is all an experiment on humans. Maybe some little green men… Or maybe the Zone itself is a testing ground. Are they tracking how we react to artifacts? Or maybe it’s some sort of global experiment, scattered in labs for the rich to observe. Hard to know for sure… anyone who’s been near the radar can’t really say. Thoughts keep racing… It’s unsettling.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_19">
    <text>I was in the Dark Valley. Many unbelievers, as the Monolith’s power hasn’t reached there. We were guarding. At night, we were attacked. We fought fiercely. Monolith later gave the brothers a reward. For me, a trial. My weapon failed, but Monolith’s power guided me. Strong faith allowed me to defeat the enemies and come closer to him. I became a shadow, struck from behind, unseen. His power finished the rest. I am honored to serve, Perfect One!</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_2">
    <text>My partner and I had been watching that research facility for a while. Very remote, no animals, no mutants. Anyone who went there returned terrified, or never at all. We decided to scout it ourselves. Reached the edge of the forest at dawn, I climbed a tree to observe. Buildings were mostly intact, quiet, no movement. Suddenly, gunfire nearby. On a roof, a strange man was frantically shooting. Then… the chaos began. The man’s weapon flew from his hands as if it had wings. He screamed, wielded a knife. Another identical figure appeared, floating in the air. For five minutes, he was cut and thrown around like a rag. I was drenched in sweat. No creatures appeared in normal or infrared vision. When we returned to base, I was exhausted, and everyone stared at me like I’d gone mad.</text>
</string>
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_20">
    <text>Brothers, we were patrolling the outskirts of the Black Forest and came across a lone unbeliever. He began to show signs of turning, so we didn’t kill him, though he was still half in his animal state. I know the wise Monolith allowed this for all of us: he showed the true face of his enemies once more. Our faith is stronger than ever! Victory over the unbelievers approaches, brothers! Monolith will fulfill our deepest desires. The truly devoted will be brought closer to him, to his glory and greatness. We will dwell forever in his radiance!</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_3">
    <text>So my buddy told me this. He was woken up in the middle of the night by his superiors—rush to the lab, a shipment arrived. Half-asleep, he didn’t get it: what shipment? They said: “Have you been drinking government booze? There’s a fresh corpse on the table, dinner’s served!” He goes there, and what he sees… he’d seen lots of messed-up stalkers: torn, cooked, mutated—but here, something was in the stomach. At first glance, nearly human, but the head was a huge lumpy pumpkin, and the body was skin and bones. The mess was orange-red all over—blood, basically. Ammo had been used generously… searching for anomalies, you know. The body looked like a mix of a colander and a torn blanket, clearly played with by its “owners.” He spent the rest of the night and half the morning sorting it out. Apparently, this was the creature locals call the Illusionist: black cloths, visions for stalkers, a head nearly a meter around. The face looked like a tiny crown, eyes barely open, nose like a pin, huge mouth. It drags its head because it can’t hold it upright. And guess what it eats for dinner? Mushrooms! Yes, stalker mushrooms. And in a pouch on its side? Dried brains. And whose? Controller brains!</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_4">
    <text>We had a fool join us… We went for a five-minute rest, and he immediately relaxed. But when moving, he lagged behind. Eventually, a Controller caught him—straight for the brains. Newcomers, remember this: every sound matters. Even a rabbit—though rabbits here are dangerous. Be ready every second: magazines and grenades at hand, gun always ready. See something? Fire half a mag immediately. Something behind a bush? Shoot first, ask later. That’s the rookie’s course: don’t get fancy or they’ll devour you. As for Controllers, a separate story. Shoot at a sound? Drop immediately. They latch onto you if you’re in sight—they need focus. Listen for movement, click the magazine quietly, prep grenades… Count to three and move far away. Stay alert—only that way you survive.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_5">
    <text>I wonder… maybe everything here is an experiment on humans? Maybe some little green men… not a worse theory than others. If this is a testing ground, what exactly are they trying? Which artifacts make us drool most? Or maybe it’s bombs? Scattered worldwide to labs for the rich… fancy that! I’d love to get my hands on that! Bought some secret stuff, paid a fortune, bragged about it, and… it blows up spectacularly! Honestly, who knows what’s real. Anyone who went near the radar can’t really tell. Maybe they know, maybe not—they just drool. Thoughts keep racing… unsettling, really.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_6">
    <text>Someone asked why only our eggheads mess with the Zone while foreigners stay away, despite mountains of Nobel-worthy material here. Here’s the answer. First, why bother personally when you can fund ours and get everything delivered on a plate? Second, foreigners have been here, but in the last two years they avoid it after one major disaster. They now buy data and materials, pay well, many lone operatives and looters work for them. The story? Thirty top scientists from around the world, heavily funded, armed military squad for protection, three guides from our side. Loaded on armored BTRs, set off. Returned a week later—twelve people on a wrecked BTR. Ambushed at Rotten Forest by looters. Only three survived—two ours, one foreigner. The Zone claimed the rest. Heard of Town-32? That’s where it happened. Initially calm, they collected samples and took measurements. Then madness struck—mass psychosis. People tore at themselves, hit heads on walls, or shot themselves. Meanwhile, beasts attacked. Survivors barely escaped, dodging anomalies. From then on, Town-32 remains off-limits, and foreigners won’t enter even for big money.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_7">
    <text>So, here’s what I wanted to say. When Duty captured that Illusionist, I was nearby—actually by accident. My Niva’s right front wheel gave out, bolts sheared. No spare parts. I swore, then thought I’d check the factory for replacements—about half an hour round trip. I’d been there before. Suddenly, I saw Duty patrol—fifty of them! I dove into the bushes. If noticed, I’d be dead. I lay low, listening. Gunfire erupted—never heard volleys like that except during the First Base capture. After five minutes, quiet. I peeked with binoculars—Duties were carrying their blinded men and the Illusionist on a tarp, just scraps left. They disappeared into a ravine. Curious, I went inside. Nothing useful after Duty—just two mags, a gun pinned under a beam. Bolts? Forgot all about them. I returned to my car, salvaged what I could, and drove off cautiously. Had I arrived half an hour earlier… wow…</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_8">
    <text>Yes, I reached the outskirts of Pripyat. First thing, scout a high point—a big boiler with a chimney. Carefully entered, everything dusty, no signs of activity. Climbed inside the chimney via internal steps. Beautiful view, half the city visible! Binoculars out. About to descend, realized I hadn’t checked directly below—looked inside the courtyard: a dwarf wandering. Luckily, he didn’t see me. His AK was strapped on, I couldn’t aim well from the chimney. Using my Makarov was useless at that distance. I watched—he rummaged through debris, then froze. The pile started moving on its own! Dwarf jumped, covered his head, hands contorted. Debris flew from all directions, hitting him, yet he survived and walked away. I barely caught my breath. Suddenly smoke, fire below! I scrambled, used my forty-meter rep rope, secured it, wrapped a scarf, and descended, praying. Almost fell five meters short. Lucky, no major injuries, just scrapes and a pulled leg. Could’ve been worse.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_zonanews_9">
    <text>I couldn’t believe my eyes. Beautiful girls exist, sure—but this one… perfection. The world around her seemed black-and-white; she alone in color and sharpness. Her movements! Never seen anything like it. My throat tightened. What’s she doing here in the Zone? Evening, near the bus station, a nine-story building. Something moved in a first-floor window. I drew my AK, cautious. She emerged. I stared, didn’t hear a word. Blue jumpsuit, snug, not loose—fantastic figure. Only then did I realize I wasn’t listening at all—just smiling like an idiot. She was from a research team, working on Zone endemics, escaped the guards to come alone. I agreed to help fetch some things. Arrived two days later, almost got caught several times while collecting. All I could think about: seeing her again. She radiated from within…</text>
</string>

</string_table>
