<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
<string id="topi_b22_stalker_medic_need_health_care_0">
    <text>I need medical attention.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b22_stalker_medic_need_health_care_1">
    <text>Let me take a look...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b22_stalker_medic_need_health_care_11">
    <text>[continue...]</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b22_stalker_medic_need_health_care_111">
    <text>Alright, that’s it… You were worried for nothing, only your skirt got wrinkled. You can go.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b22_stalker_medic_need_health_care_2">
    <text>Let's see… With health like that? Well, I guess I need a ticket to the morgue...</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b1_trader_water_dialog_0">
    <text>I need to fill my canteen with drinking water. Can you help?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_trader_water_dialog_1">
    <text>No problem, my friend. Choose how much murky water you need.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_trader_water_dialog_2">
    <text>Fill it one-third. (100 rubles).</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_trader_water_dialog_3">
    <text>Only one-third? Are you out of your mind, buddy? Why so little? That’s barely enough for anything...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_trader_water_dialog_4">
    <text>That’s enough for now. Thanks.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_trader_water_dialog_21">
    <text>Fill it halfway. (200 rubles).</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_trader_water_dialog_31">
    <text>Here you go. Why so little? You don’t respect Vazgen at all, huh? Could’ve filled it completely. Julio here – just half. Oh, what kind of people these days…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_trader_water_dialog_41">
    <text>That’s fine for now. Thanks.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_trader_water_dialog_22">
    <text>Fill it completely. (300 rubles).</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_trader_water_dialog_32">
    <text>Here you go. Wow, you respected old Vazgen. Vazgen is feeling generous today. Can’t pour the chacha into another bottle. They brought me some amazing chacha – wow, it hits hard, just awesome...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_trader_water_dialog_42">
    <text>Sure, but later. Keep the chacha for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_trader_water_dialog_23">
    <text>Changed my mind. I’ll come back later, for now I’m fine.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_trader_water_dialog_24">
    <text>Damn. Don’t even have an extra hundred to buy drinking water.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b18_tainik_bandit_member_dialog_0">
    <text>So, idiot, hand over the cash or we’ll shoot you…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b18_tainik_bandit_member_dialog_1">
    <text>Cash? Why would a dead man need cash? He doesn’t, plus the gear and weapon too...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b18_tainik_bandit_member_dialog_2">
    <text>Hey you, jerk, don’t play smart. Pedal horse, empty your pockets. Last Chinese thing for you...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b18_tainik_bandit_member_dialog_3">
    <text>Let’s see how tough you really are...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b18_tainik_bandit_member_dialog_11">
    <text>Got the hint. I don’t need trouble. Take what’s here and let’s split.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b18_tainik_bandit_member_dialog_22">
    <text>Looks like you’ve got brains. Good. Don’t hang around too long. Better leave, these guys are edgy and might shoot…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b18_tainik_bandit_member_dialog_33">
    <text>Got it, I’m leaving now...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b18_tainik_bandit_member_dialog_111">
    <text>Go to hell, son of a bitch. Easier for me to just shoot you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b18_tainik_bandit_member_dialog_222">
    <text>What the hell? You’ve gone crazy, I see. Don’t worry, my guys and I will teach you some manners.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b18_tainik_bandit_member_dialog_333">
    <text>Go ahead and try...</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_hunter_dialog_0">
    <text>Alright. Tell me, what do you know about the "Clear Sky" faction?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_hunter_dialog_1">
    <text>Not much to tell. We’ve seen them around a couple of times. Once even a squad passed by. Though maybe it’s just rumors. What’s certain is they recently found a mutilated body in their uniform. Most likely killed by some local creatures.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_hunter_dialog_2">
    <text>The body is clear, but are you sure a whole squad was seen here?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_hunter_dialog_22">
    <text>A whole squad, you say. I doubt that. The body is clear, but the squad…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_hunter_dialog_3">
    <text>No way, like I said, probably just rumors. Maybe not. I don’t know, stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_hunter_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, thanks for that.</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_medic_dialog_0">
    <text>Listen, I wanted to ask you about the Clear Sky faction. Have you heard anything interesting about them?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_medic_dialog_1">
    <text>I’ve heard a bit. Rumor has it one of their agents was killed here. Don’t know who or how, but that’s what people say. Naturally, the Freedomers didn’t poke their beaks in – an agent is an agent, even in Africa. Our guys could have easily let it slide. But it seems to me that it wasn’t our people who took him out. Maybe mercenaries, bandits, or someone else.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_medic_dialog_2">
    <text>I see. This info helps connect some other facts. By the way, was that agent’s body found near the farm?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_medic_dialog_22">
    <text>Now that changes things a lot. The pieces of the puzzle are coming together. By the way, was that agent’s body found near the farm?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_medic_dialog_3">
    <text>Yeah, somewhere around there. And the strangest thing – our scouts found the body first and left it. Thought “whatever, he’s dead, that’s that.” So many stalkers die in the Zone. Later, they tried to bury it properly, but the body was gone. Vanished into thin air. Thought mutants dragged it off, but no body, no scraps of gear. Nothing. So now, who took him? That’s the question.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_medic_dialog_4">
    <text>I don’t know who took it, but I have an idea where it resurfaced... Thanks for the info.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_artefacter_dialog_0">
    <text>Now let’s talk about some information. Tell me, what do you know about the Clear Sky stalkers? I heard they were seen around here not long ago.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_artefacter_dialog_1">
    <text>Locals talk a lot. Recently, they said they found a clearing in the forest with bodies of Freedomers and Duty members. Doesn’t seem like they killed each other. Either all at once, or some first, then someone finished off the survivors. As for the Clear Sky, I can’t tell you much. There were also sightings of strange stalkers, looked like scientists, but who knows. Nowadays anyone with money can buy a lab suit.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_artefacter_dialog_2">
    <text>Wait. Forget about the Freedomers and others. Tell me more about the scientists – where, when, and how many?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_artefacter_dialog_22">
    <text>Hold on, forget Clear Sky for now. About the scientists – I need details. When were they seen, where exactly, and how many?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_artefacter_dialog_3">
    <text>Heh. You’re sharper than you seemed. Alright, since I promised info – here it is. About a week ago, in a dense part of the forest. A group of these “scientists” came from the east. About eight or nine, no one knows for sure. Scouts tried to track them the next day, but found nothing. Strange. Some say they were phantoms, others say no one was there. Personally, I think they just split up. Hard to track a group when everyone goes their own way. Our scouts are good, but not super-professional. That’s all I know, stalker. Believe me or not, your choice.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_artefacter_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright. Thanks for your help.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_artefacter_dialog_44">
    <text>Thanks. Your information helped me a lot.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_snab_dialog_0">
    <text>About Clear Sky. I want to know how many stalkers were seen and when. Was it a squad or just individuals?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_snab_dialog_1">
    <text>What I can say. A couple of people came here recently. Hung out at the bar, then left. Bought food and some ammo. Seemed like regular artifact hunters, nothing more. Standard stalker gear and weapons. Didn’t look like a combat group.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_snab_dialog_2">
    <text>Did they buy food and ammo just for themselves, or for a bigger group?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_snab_dialog_22">
    <text>And nothing else? Just food and ammo for themselves?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_snab_dialog_3">
    <text>I can’t get into that much detail. Ask Vazgen yourself… They looked like they only bought for themselves. Scouts saw them leave our territory toward Yantar.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_snab_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood. Thanks for the help.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_snab_dialog_44">
    <text>Got it. Thanks for the help, at least.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_radist_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, any rumors about Clear Sky showing up, or maybe scientist stalkers wandering around recently?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_radist_dialog_1">
    <text>Not that I heard. Freedomers were around recently, which is strange – far from their territory. Duty shows up often, though. Birds, I don’t recall.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_radist_dialog_2">
    <text>What about the scientists? Yantar’s nearby, maybe someone came through?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_radist_dialog_22">
    <text>We know about those. But the scientists – surely someone?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_radist_dialog_3">
    <text>No, as I said. If anyone came, I’d remember. No info on the radios either. If anyone went missing or needed help – I’d know. Ask locals, maybe someone heard something. I don’t trust rumors, only what I hear on the radio.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_radist_dialog_4">
    <text>Got it. Thanks.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_mechanic_dialog_0">
    <text>Help me with one thing. Have any scientist stalkers appeared at your base, or has anyone seen them nearby?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_mechanic_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah, a while back, about three months ago. They sometimes come from Yantar. But last couple of weeks, no one.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_mechanic_dialog_2">
    <text>Three months is a long time. So none in the last two weeks…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_mechanic_dialog_22">
    <text>Three months is too long. Maybe someone came later…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_mechanic_dialog_3">
    <text>Wait, I remember. Recently a stalker brought a torn, bloody lab suit. Obviously from a corpse. Asked me to fix it. Told him too damaged, impossible to restore. He left empty-handed. I bought it for parts for a thousand. Looks like the owner fell into some anomaly. That’s all I recall.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_mechanic_dialog_4">
    <text>Got it. Thanks, that really helps.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_trader_dialog_0">
    <text>Vazgen, help me out. Heard anything about Clear Sky or scientist stalkers? Seen them around here about a week ago?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_trader_dialog_1">
    <text>Sure, no problem. Seen them more than once. Don’t know how this info helps you. I know people like you – everyone comes here for something. And it’s not just artifacts and money.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_trader_dialog_2">
    <text>That’s not for you to decide. Just tell me what you know.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_trader_dialog_22">
    <text>Just tell me what you know. I’ll decide if it helps me.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_trader_dialog_3">
    <text>They were seen here. That’s all I can say for now. Look for more specific leads and you’ll find the clues.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_trader_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood. Thanks.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_lider_dialog_0">
    <text>Alright, let’s be specific. What can you tell me about my case?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_lider_dialog_1">
    <text>You’ve caused quite a stir here. Your contract is your business. But to me, it looks suspicious. Dirty work, Varg. Very. Since I promised help, I will. You’ve collected facts about Clear Sky and scientists. Pass them to the contact.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_lider_dialog_2">
    <text>When should I expect the contact?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_lider_dialog_22">
    <text>When should I expect the agent?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_lider_dialog_3">
    <text>Soon, my friend. Soon. Here’s what we know: Clear Sky squad here about a week ago. Our people saw a couple of them. One body found – likely their agent. The squad probably wiped out by mutants. Scientists seen around the same time. One body near an anomaly. Others unknown. Likely a hidden hideout in the forest. That’s the summary, collected from stalkers and scouts.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_lider_dialog_4">
    <text>Thanks for your help. I won’t forget this.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_zamlider_dialog_0">
    <text>Alright, let’s be specific. What can you tell me about my case?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_zamlider_dialog_1">
    <text>Your contract is your responsibility. But since you helped me, I’ll help you. You’ve collected facts about Clear Sky and scientists. Pass them to your contact. He’ll appear here soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_zamlider_dialog_2">
    <text>I see. So you have direct contact with Clear Sky?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_zamlider_dialog_22">
    <text>So you have direct contact with the Birds?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_zamlider_dialog_222">
    <text>Clear Sky contact? So you originally had direct access to the Birds?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_zamlider_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes. Here’s what we know: Clear Sky squad here about a week ago. A couple of them seen by our people. One body – likely their agent. Squad probably wiped out by mutants. Scientists seen at same time. One body near anomaly. Others unknown. Likely a hidden forest hideout. That’s all. Summary collected from stalkers and scouts.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_zamlider_dialog_4">
    <text>Thanks, Hasan. You really helped me, and I don’t regret choosing your side.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a1_main_suget_second_quest_zamlider_dialog_44">
    <text>Thanks. I hope I won’t regret choosing your side.</text>
</string>

	
	
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_0">
    <text>Greetings. Looking for some work. Need a hand with anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_1">
    <text>Well, there’s a small job. The main thing is your willingness to work. Though usually I take more trusted people — I rarely hire random newcomers from outside.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_2">
    <text>Uh, I don’t look like a random newcomer, do I? Or is your artifact business so serious you only take trusted hands? So, what’s the job exactly? Give me details.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_3">
    <text>All you freelance stalkers are the same. Girls at the bar sell their bodies, you sell your artifact-finding services. So tell me — what’s the difference? Enough talk. Everyone’s hungry, everyone wants profit… I need measurement results.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_4">
    <text>My name’s Varg and I’m no whore. Remember that, or I’ll shoot your hand. Measurements, you say? Will I need to set up any anomaly or artifact scanners?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_41">
    <text>No, you won’t be setting them up. They were installed long before you arrived. Some even paid with their lives. Your task is to collect them and bring them here so I can get the measurement results. That’ll help coordinate our search groups better, and they can work on safer, more profitable routes. The Zone’s not calm these days. Artifacts in usual spots are scarce. You gotta find the juicy bits. No walk, no catch...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_401">
    <text>What kind of scanners? Can you elaborate? They measure anomalous activity — so they’re near major anomalies?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_4011">
    <text>Just ordinary anomaly scanners. Their readings are needed by our techs to calibrate equipment. And for me, to prepare supplies and distribute everything among the groups.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_4012">
    <text>Got it. Better suit then. Send me the coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_4013">
    <text>Coordinates loaded. Suit is a good idea — take it. And don’t get cooked in anomalies.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_402">
    <text>Who installed them, and where do I have to go?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_4021">
    <text>Does it matter who placed them? Hassan’s people did it a few days ago — satisfied? Don’t think about that. Your job is to run to the marked points, grab the scanners, and return alive. Clear?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_4022">
    <text>Got it. Send coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_4023">
    <text>Coordinates loaded. Wear a better suit. And watch out in anomalies.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_5">
    <text>Anything else I need?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_51">
    <text>No, though later I might find a more serious job for you. First, you’ll need the measurement results from the installed anomaly scanners.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_52">
    <text>Hunting scanners in anomalies. Ha, fun prospect. Can’t survive long there without a good suit...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_53">
    <text>Got it. Lucky for you I’m generous today. Here, got it from the quartermaster for just such a case. Not bad, though worn. Coordinates loaded.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_531">
    <text>Did they at least clean the blood from it? Must be off some buddy’s corpse...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_5311">
    <text>Don’t start whining… You’re squeamish? My suit’s hardly fresh either. And I don’t ask what happened to its previous owner.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_5312">
    <text>Right not to ask. I’m off for the measurements. One more thing — more info, not really a request...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_5313">
    <text>Info, you say. Got it. Knew from the start you weren’t just some opportunist. Alright, talk when you return. Be careful — it’d be a waste if you die out there.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_532">
    <text>Understood. Heading out. By the way, one more thing — more info...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_5321">
    <text>Info, huh. Sure, why not. I guessed you didn’t just wander here for nothing. Info comes after the job. Be careful — wouldn’t want your effort wasted.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_6">
    <text>Alright, I’ll do what’s needed. Where to start?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_61">
    <text>Now that’s a proper business talk. Here’s the plan. First, find the anomaly scanners. Hassan’s people installed them. Coordinates sent. Later, maybe another job, can’t promise though.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_611">
    <text>Got it. I’ll get your scanners. About another job — don’t count on it. I’m more interested in some info, which you might have...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_6111">
    <text>Info, you say… why not. I suspected you didn’t come here for nothing. Talk when you return. Be careful. Don’t disappear in the anomalies.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_end_0">
    <text>Here are all your scanners. Honestly, didn’t expect you to handle this job. Usually it’s for techs or similar…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b6_scientist_tech_quest_anomalies_scaner_end_1">
    <text>Strange question — I oversee artifact collection groups. Naturally, I ensure they work better. Smart people only handle what matters, friend. I’m smart. I do what our techs do, and more… The info you’re after is probably confidential. You get the hint… Good job, stalker. I’ll process the measurements. New work comes later, maybe not at all… Meanwhile, ask anything you want.</text>
</string>

	
	<string id="topi_snab_quest_first_dialog_0">
    <text>I’m ready to keep working. What needs to be done now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Here’s the plan. We need to set up some backup caches for our clan fighters. It’s important work — the clan needs new stashes. And it’s time to set a little bait for our enemies as well.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_first_dialog_2">
    <text>By the way, did you manage to track down the previous looters? I’m interested in the specific culprits. Got a few ideas myself, and it’s good to know who you might run into.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_first_dialog_22">
    <text>By the way, did you manage to find the previous raiders? I want to know who exactly was involved. Good to know who you might face — if it’s just local thugs, that’s one thing, but if it’s pros, it changes everything.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Of course. It was one of the local punks. He pulled a little stunt, raiding one of our important caches. There was a lot of weaponry. We tracked the bastard to the nearest anomaly and, before taking him out, managed to learn that he raided the stash following someone’s tip. Hopefully now we’ll find out whose tip it was.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Bandits — that’s good in a way. They’re useless fighters. But here’s the thing. Info about these caches is only available to a select few for a short time, right? Eventually, the whole group will know, so what then?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Not quite. Though you’re close. You’re right that eventually everyone will know about the new caches. But for now, only the small circle you were told about has this info. No other leaks are possible. And my gut says the rat will show itself. And rest assured, silence and quality work will be generously rewarded.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Since it’s a delicate matter, I expect delicate payment. Some info, for example.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_first_dialog_656">
    <text>Delicate work deserves delicate payment. I hope you know what I mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_first_dialog_66">
    <text>Alright, I get it. I’ll do everything needed. But the payment will also need to be delicate…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_first_dialog_7">
    <text>We can work something out. For now, plant all the caches and come back here. Coordinates are already loaded for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_snab_quest_second_dialog_0">
    <text>All caches are planted at the spots you indicated. What’s next? I think your plan worked.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Next… you’ll need to fill them with essential supplies: first aid, some food, a few packs of ammo. The full list is already loaded for you. Some expensive items you’ll get right now. Wait — you said my plan worked? Explain.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_second_dialog_2">
    <text>A group of thugs tried to rob me near the southern checkpoint. They were right by the spot I told the collector about. The one I mentioned to… Mahir.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_second_dialog_22">
    <text>A group of bandits tried to attack me near the spot I told Mahir about.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_second_dialog_3">
    <text>See. That’s Mahir. Good, my friend. At least now we have a lead. He knew you’d be in that area and could direct the thugs to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_second_dialog_4">
    <text>So now we know who sent them. That’s what you needed — the whole cache setup was designed to find out who would attack me. Since you were the bait, let’s discuss payment and guarantees.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_second_dialog_44">
    <text>Now you know who could have directed them to this area. Since you were used as bait in this clever trap, let’s sort out payment and guarantees.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Don’t worry. Guarantees there will be. You’re alive, so all is well. Smart kid, I see — you caught the triple trick immediately. That’s good. Fewer questions later. Now go finish the job I hired you for, then we’ll talk about your matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Right. I’ll ask questions only on my own topic. And I hope your answers won’t leave me disappointed…</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_snab_quest_third_dialog_0">
    <text>All done. The caches are planted.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_third_dialog_1">
    <text>Good. Two birds with one stone. Caches help the stalkers, and I get my gain.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_third_dialog_2">
    <text>True. But I’m more interested in my third bird. You risked your life, after all… So I need info on any scientist stalker groups appearing here, as well as all Clear Sky members who visited in the past couple of weeks.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_third_dialog_22">
    <text>Birds are fine, but let’s get back to my matter. I need info on scientist groups appearing here, and all Clear Sky members who came in the last couple of weeks.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_third_dialog_3">
    <text>You risked your life for a reason. So that’s it — you’re after Clear Sky. Alright, let’s talk. Ask precise questions. Also, I’ll need to sort out the Mahir situation. Since you took this from the start, you’ll finish it. Come by when you’re ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_quest_third_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_radist_pred_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, brother. Listen, help me out. I’ve got a radio device lying around — a kind of direction finder. Maybe you’ll buy it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_pred_dialog_1">
    <text>Direction finder, you say. And how much are you asking?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_pred_dialog_2">
    <text>Three grand. Plus, you don’t ask where I got it from.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_pred_dialog_22">
    <text>I’ll give it for three K. Also, no unnecessary questions about its origin.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_pred_dialog_3">
    <text>Fair enough. Here you go. I wouldn’t ask anyway. Our clan’s stalkers don’t have such equipment, and the rest doesn’t interest me much. Even if you killed its previous owner.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_pred_dialog_4">
    <text>Thanks for not refusing.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_first_dialog_0">
    <text>By the way, do you have any work available?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Work… tricky question. Depends on what you can or can’t do, and why exactly you need the work.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_first_dialog_22">
    <text>Got it. I’ll come by later, can’t work for you just yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, I need work to earn. Whether I can do something depends on what you can offer. I’m a broad specialist, and I’ve been in the Zone for years. Worked a long time under Orest from Agroyantar.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Broad specialist, huh? Alright, we’ll see what you’re good for. Being from Orest’s clan tells me little. What matters is how well you handle a soldering iron, not hunting artifacts or killing mutants. The job I have for you is specific. If you handle it — good.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_first_dialog_4">
    <text>I’m listening. What exactly do you need me to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_first_dialog_44">
    <text>Let’s get to the point. What’s required from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_first_dialog_444">
    <text>Can we get straight to it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Briefly, here’s the thing. I’m in charge of radio communication and all related devices. I work closely with the technician and supply guy — but that’s another story. Here’s the matter: our clan has hidden radio stations here and on other locations. Don’t ask why. I think you already know. One of them seems down now. Unknown what happened. Your job — find out. Take some tools from me and get to it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright. I’ll handle it.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_second_dialog_0">
    <text>So, I checked the radio station. Things look pretty bad.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_second_dialog_1">
    <text>What happened? Probably a couple of boards fried during the emission? Happens more than once.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Not exactly. Here, your multimeter back. One board is fried, yes. But looks like someone did it on purpose. Not random bandits — they’d tear it apart. Other clans probably wouldn’t do it either. Seems like a pro worked on it and knew what and where to break.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_second_dialog_3">
    <text>On purpose, huh? Interesting. Who’d need to sabotage this radio? Well, I’ll inform Hasan. Let them handle the saboteur. Our job is to restore it ASAP. Take the soldering station, fix it, and move it to the point I sent. Place it somewhere discreet. Put the station in a special case so it doesn’t stand out.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright. What about the settings? Its coverage area will change, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_second_dialog_44">
    <text>And what about the settings? Won’t coverage be different?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Looks like you know your stuff. Good questions. Don’t worry about the settings. I’ll handle it later. The area is already covered via backup channels.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Got it. Understood.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_third_dialog_0">
    <text>Done. The radio station is repaired and installed in a new location. You can proceed with setup and connecting the backup channel.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_third_dialog_1">
    <text>Excellent, my friend. Just return the tools you borrowed. You’ll get proper payment. You did well, stalker. Not everyone would tackle this job. Good work. You’ll go far if you don’t ask unnecessary questions.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_third_dialog_2">
    <text>Life’s full of questions we try in vain to answer. Here’s your soldering station. By the way, your leadership? How did they react to the sabotage news? Any ideas who did it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_third_dialog_22">
    <text>Here’s your soldering station. By the way, how did your leadership react to the sabotage? Any idea who could’ve done it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_third_dialog_3">
    <text>Who knows. They decided to be more vigilant. Though honestly, it’s useless while Harold and Hasan run things here. Strictly between us, they’re decent stalkers. But suspicious things keep happening. They just seek personal gain — passing artifacts to outside suppliers without anyone knowing. I wouldn’t be surprised if one of them ordered the equipment sabotaged to blame the other.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_third_dialog_4">
    <text>Wow. Interesting conclusions. At first, you didn’t seem so concerned with clan affairs. Aren’t you afraid to tell me this? And a leader versus his deputy — is one trying to take the other’s place? They already run everything… No, something else is at play. You mentioned suspicious things — any specifics?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_third_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, nothing unusual happened, really. Just the Zone things. A few artifact dropper groups disappeared, later found dead. Recently, the Healer was killed — our first medic, a clan founder. Body found in jelly. Most think he drunkenly got there, but he didn’t drink that night. Thinking about it, the picture is quite complex…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_multimetr_quest_third_dialog_6">
    <text>Well… fine. Not my concern much. I have my work. But it seems events here won’t pass me by. We’ll talk later about one guy — might be connected to what you described.</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_init">
    <text>Hey, maybe you have some job for me? I’m new around here and looking for work. You’re a doctor, after all. Surely there’s something you need help with.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_about">
    <text>Honestly, I don’t have anything for you strictly related to my profession. But you can help with a personal matter — actually, two. Last time, I owe someone — need to return two artifacts to our dealer. Locals call him Vazgen. Central Asian guy… If you’ve ever dealt with this greed-driven bastard, you’ll know. I don’t like him, he doesn’t like me. Our characters… don’t mesh. Would have taken him out long ago, but the leadership and his, uh, “partners” would skin me for that. He can’t kick me out of the clan either… Central Asian tried, nasty piece, but failed. Recently the previous medic got eaten by the cold… there are no more doctors. That’s the story. The artifacts — that’s reality. Rare reality, like winning the lottery honestly — these aren’t lying around… And I’m a seeker like a frog is a ballerina. Maybe worse. So, if you find those artifacts — you’ll do me a solid. And yeah, buddy, a fancy detector will come in handy — I can hook you up. Free of charge. But I can offer another way to solve this. You’ll still have to do the same, but bigger risk. And pay will be higher. So, you in? Maybe later another task will pop up — more medical-related. Every day some greenhorn either flies into an anomaly or ends up on a boar’s tusks. Would be fine if they died, but no — they survive. So what do you do with these cripples afterwards?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_about1">
    <text>Alright, I’ll help as much as I can.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_nah">
    <text>No, I won’t work for you… at least not yet.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_medic_quest_var_2_arts_1">
    <text>And what’s the second way to solve this problem?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_var_2_arts_2">
    <text>Knew you’d be interested. Your job doesn’t change — still searching for artifacts. Just different ones, in another location. How I handle them next isn’t your concern.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_var_2_arts_3">
    <text>Alright. That works for me. Now, tell me specifically what to find?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_var_2_arts_4">
    <text>“Meat Chunk” and “Firefly.” Don’t look at me like that. Rare artifacts — I know. But I have little choice. Of two evils, pick the lesser. A friend, now gone, whispered one thing… A Griver appeared near the village. That Griver had those artifacts. The kid took care of the body, but the artifacts had to be hidden almost in the anomaly itself. Normal detectors used by our collectors can’t spot them. So, for now, they may still be there. If they are, grab them and bring them to me. Head to the thermal anomaly, I’ll figure out how to make the Central Asian take these, not other samples. Might even profit from it myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_var_2_arts_5">
    <text>Got it. I’m heading out. I’ll try to find everything you mentioned.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_start">
    <text>Ah, I love dealing with a serious person.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_start1">
    <text>And which artifacts are needed?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_start2">
    <text>“Paradise Apple” and “Sparkle.” Pick your jaw up off the table. Never heard of them, huh? And you’re already ready to take the job? Something tells me I jumped the gun with you, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_ok">
    <text>Wow! Yeah, “rare”… If you told me to deliver a red Ferrari right into the Zone, it would surprise me less… Though I remember a businessman from Kyiv did exactly that once. Anyway, my choice is limited. The artifacts will come. I’m curious how you managed to land on these specific ones…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_find">
    <text>Well, don’t look at me. I won’t drag you by the ear. I’ll wait… If you find them, bring them here. Better to hand over such goods immediately and not linger, or you’ll end up on the missing list. Don’t ask about how you got this contract — cheaper to shoot you right here. So, move it. Say hi to your Grigovovich. He’s probably cruising the Zone in his Lamborghini…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_where">
    <text>Hold up, buddy — why so fast? These artifacts are rare and valuable, not in the nearest ditch. You might be a seeker, but you probably didn’t sit idle on your post either. Any leads?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_hz">
    <text>Yeah, a bit. I checked with some knowledgeable folks… “Paradise Apple” — gravitational type, “Sparkle” — electric, both tricky. Artifacts here are a mess. They can appear almost anywhere. There is a system, but who will tell you, newbie? Life in the Zone isn’t easy without tricks. Search where there’s lots of radiation and gravitational clusters, or where “little lights” fly. Both are natural modifiers. As Jorah explained, they like not only their anomaly but others too. If our fat… sailor isn’t lying, “Apple” needs radiation, and “Shard” — chemistry stuff, like “Jelly” or “Burning Fur.” Got it? Best near the hamlet in radioactive piles. Go, and dive in.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_end">
    <text>Here’s to success. Farewell.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_find_begin">
    <text>I found something here…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_find_what">
    <text>Whoa… kid, looks like you’re not messing around.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_find_second_item">
    <text>Here you go — “Sparkle.” Took some effort to find it…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_find_first_item">
    <text>Yep. Only “Apple” so far. Halfway there, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_find_first_or_second_item">
    <text>Here’s both — “Apple” and “Sparkle.” If not for your lead, I’d have no chance. Take it, figure out the rest yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_find_end">
    <text>Well done! Not a chance most stalkers would not only find but deliver such artifacts. Solid. I’ll deal with Vazgen later, sort out the debt… For now, let’s get back to your question, agreed?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_find_nothing">
    <text>No results yet. Will continue searching, will signal if anything comes up.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_find_item_instr">
    <text>Good job, found “Sparkle”… Big deal. That’s only half the work. Once we get the “Apple,” we’ll tackle the other job.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_find_item_flash">
    <text>Very good. “Apple” is perfect, but without the “Shard,” my debt to the Central Asian isn’t cleared. Move your hooves, the evening won’t wait. The profit is yours, not mine. Move it, young one.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_sborki_find_item_all">
    <text>Excellent, both artifacts delivered. Now our conversation can proceed properly.</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_b30_owl_medic_quests_end_0">
    <text>Done, my friend. Artifacts are found. Here, take them.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b30_owl_medic_quests_end_1">
    <text>Thanks. Now I can call you a friend. Keep the detector — such a powerful device will surely come in handy. Consider it part of the payment. And take your share in cash. Now we can talk on a different note. Maybe even offer you a slightly different job.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b30_owl_medic_quests_end_2">
    <text>Thanks for that. That good detector will be useful. By the way, have you decided what to do about your debt? As I understand, you owed the dealer different artifacts. How will you handle that now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b30_owl_medic_quests_end_3">
    <text>We’ll sort it out. Like I said — this business is no longer your concern. Forget about the artifacts. Any other questions?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b30_owl_medic_quests_end_4">
    <text>Alright, let’s move on.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_medic_quest_peredacha_init_dialog_0">
    <text>So, enemy of Central Asia, what other job can you offer?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_peredacha_init_dialog_1">
    <text>Listen, stalker. No jokes now. I just got word from the Limping Squad. One of their scouts is seriously wounded. We don’t know exactly what happened, maybe a psi-strike. Could be a controller. Go to the village as fast as you can.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_peredacha_init_dialog_2">
    <text>And what should I do with this scout?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_peredacha_init_dialog_22">
    <text>So what are my orders? What should I do with this scout?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_peredacha_init_dialog_3">
    <text>What else — treat him, damn it. Listen, don’t push my buttons. I’d go myself, but Hasan, the second Central Asian, sent me on some urgent task. Long story short — someone’s dying, and he wants something done. You wanted work — here it is. Here’s a medkit with everything needed for first aid. Give it to the scout later.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_quest_peredacha_init_dialog_4">
    <text>Got it. Heading out.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b1_stalker_group_wounded_dialog_0">
    <text>Stalker, help… it’s in my head — I don’t know what it is… I can’t bear it anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_stalker_group_wounded_dialog_1">
    <text>Wait — don’t move. Let’s take a look…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_stalker_group_wounded_dialog_2">
    <text>Thanks… What was that? My brain felt like it was burning alive…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_stalker_group_wounded_dialog_3">
    <text>Not sure what kind of mess you stepped into. Looks like a psi-strike. Did you see a controller before it happened or anyone similar? Maybe an unknown psi-anomaly? What do you remember?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_stalker_group_wounded_dialog_4">
    <text>There were no anomalies. I only remember one person. A human. Some stalker. He passed by and went into the forest. Definitely not a controller.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_stalker_group_wounded_dialog_5">
    <text>Got it. Thanks for the info. Bye.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_0">
    <text>Good. I’m here on Elimey’s orders. Your man was wounded…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_1">
    <text>Greetings, wanderer. Why didn’t the medical guy come himself? I told him urgent help was needed. Are you some kind of top healer? And what happened to my man?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_2">
    <text>Your man died. Too severe injuries… I couldn’t help him in time. Take the medkit — unused.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_3">
    <text>I see. So why did I even need such a doctor? Maybe I should just finish you off too. Elimey, damn cunning rat — hides at base and sends some newbie instead, who can’t even reach the place…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_4">
    <text>Calm down, scout. I’m on my own here. This work for Elimey is a one-time thing. He warned your man might not survive — that’s why he sent me. Hasan, your deputy, delayed him anyway… No point in me getting into trouble.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_5">
    <text>So… Elimey says Hasan delayed him. I see. Your fault then is none. Alright. What else did that bastard ask to deliver? You say you worked for the doctor once. So, you don’t mind mercenary work. Not from the blue gang, are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_6">
    <text>Nothing else. I have no ties with the blue gang. I care more about the feathered ones. And what exactly happened to your man? I need detailed info.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_66">
    <text>I have no ties with mercenaries. I’m interested in the Clear Sky folks. And what exactly happened to your man? I need as much detail as possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_7">
    <text>Feathered, you say… Clear Sky influence here is minimal. We can discuss in detail. About the dead stalker — strange stuff. Maybe he stumbled into an anomaly or got hit by a controller or psi wave. But what worries me is…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_8">
    <text>Let’s talk in more detail…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_22">
    <text>Your fighter survived. I managed to save him. He told some strange things. Elimey didn’t come — Hasan detained him. Take the medkit. Might be useful for someone else. Elimey instructed you to deliver it later.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_33">
    <text>Hasan, huh. Alright… What exactly did the wounded tell you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_44">
    <text>He said he saw someone. I think it was a controller. His mind was under psi-attack. He might have seen something, or now remembers the illusion the mutant created in his head.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_55">
    <text>You think so, stalker? Maybe, but I’m not sure. Psi-types are often more dangerous than controllers, because you can’t tell them from humans. Likely it was him. We don’t need that mess here… Pray it was just a controller. And thanks for saving the kid’s life. If you want to work for our clan or just chat — I’m open.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_medic_peredachaquest_complete_dialog_676">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_first_dialog_0">
    <text>I’m new here. Don’t know much about your clan. As I understand, you’re the leader of the local scouts — not just any stalker. I’m mainly interested in work and the Clear Sky faction. Can you help me get started?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_first_dialog_1">
    <text>I can help. Just use the help wisely. Try to harm my clan — you die. Resist — you die slowly. Help — you’ll be well rewarded. I won’t discuss your feathered affairs, only info that won’t hurt the clan. About work — I have one risky job. Does that suit you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright. Let’s talk about your task. What exactly do I need to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_first_dialog_22">
    <text>Sure. Let’s start with your task. What do I need to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_first_dialog_3">
    <text>I like your approach, stalker. Good. Serious task, serious risk. Pay matches. You need to scout an area. Near us is an old farm. Not a key area, but usable for a base, or at least a forward point. Artifact hunters’ caravans pass through. Hasan doesn’t like the idea of occupying it. But at least scout properly. Recently, mercenaries were spotted. Not sure why they were there. Go check if anyone remains and if they left traps. Here, take the mine detector — be careful.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, clear on mine clearing. But if mercenaries are there? I can’t fight a whole brigade. Will you cover me somehow?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_first_dialog_5">
    <text>No brigade, just a few fighters. One of my men will be nearby, covering you. Don’t try to find him… He’ll reveal himself when ready. Farm is quiet, no traces of mercs. Even if someone is there, the two of you can handle it. Focus on clearing mines. Also, track signs of our blue friends. They won’t leave notes, but some traces will remain.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood. Will do.</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_second_dialog_0">
    <text>The mercenary friends left us a few surprises. The mine detector came in handy. Any group of free stalkers who got here before me would have surely blown up.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Understood. Good work, stalker. By the way, did your cover man spot anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_second_dialog_2">
    <text>No. You trained your scouts well. You won’t see them in the forest. But they could take you out without you knowing how or from where. These guys are professionals.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Scouts are the eyes and ears of our faction. Alright, moving on — did you find anything suspicious besides a couple of planted mines?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Nothing special. Some traces of a recent campfire, leftover food. Looks like they used this spot as a temporary stop.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright, stalker. I hate to disappoint you, but your work seems wasted. Hasan, that jackal, canceled the request to occupy the abandoned farms. Something’s off, my friend. And you, apparently, aren’t entirely honest with me… Better not move. Two of my best men have you in their sights. Reach for a weapon — you’ll get a bullet between the eyes. Got the hint?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_second_dialog_6">
    <text>More than clear…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_second_dialog_66">
    <text>Understood. What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_second_dialog_7">
    <text>You say the found campsite was temporary? Then how do you explain that mercenaries were spotted here repeatedly? And how do you explain that after you checked the farm, another of my men found a dead mercenary there? Think carefully before answering…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_1_quest_second_dialog_8">
    <text>I’ll answer your questions only if we survive this. Guns ready — a wave of creatures is coming…</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_radist_quest_first_dialog_0">
    <text>By the way, maybe you have another job for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Let me think… Not that, not that… I think this one will suit you. You handled the broken radio well, so I think this is within your skill. We got orders from HQ — enhancing vigilance. Working with radars, in short.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Radars, got it. I’ll take the job. But where did you get them from?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_first_dialog_3">
    <text>After that case and some others, the leaders decided to set up a special monitoring system using radar stations. I have no idea where our usual latecomers managed to get them. Radar "Credo-1E" — rings a bell? Unique military equipment brought to the Zone. Now we have to deal with it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_first_dialog_22">
    <text>Radars, huh? Not really in the mood for that right now. I’ll come later.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_first_dialog_222">
    <text>Nope, I’m not interested in messing with radar stations for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_first_dialog_4">
    <text>We’ll manage. Not my first time. What should I start with?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_first_dialog_44">
    <text>Alright, we’ll organize everything properly. Where do I start?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_first_dialog_5">
    <text>First, install the main radar modules at key points covering the main surveillance zones. The main module will be disguised as a simple wooden box, common in the Zone. I’ve configured the modules — battery, transceiver, primary processing unit, others. Each has configurable parameters. You fix them in place; I’ll connect remotely and check. If the signal works — fine. If not — we’ll troubleshoot.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Got it. Heading out.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_radist_quest_second_dialog_0">
    <text>I think I handled your task. Radars installed, modules in place. All done? Did you check their operation?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Checked. Two work fine. The third is problematic. Signal is off, like a settings glitch. Take the remote and go near that radar. Connect directly and adjust the input parameters.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_second_dialog_2">
    <text>You think this will help?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_second_dialog_22">
    <text>Are you sure this will work?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Any other ideas? Sure, you could disassemble a faulty unit, take it to the point, check modules against the working one… But that takes at least two days. So follow my instructions.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_radist_quest_third_dialog_0">
    <text>So, I reprogrammed it. Should give correct readings now. Check it. Here’s your configuration device.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_third_dialog_1">
    <text>Hold on, let me quickly restart the system… There! Works perfectly. Excellent job.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_third_dialog_2">
    <text>And what will you do with this system now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_third_dialog_22">
    <text>You set up a monitoring system like it’s a nuclear facility.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_third_dialog_222">
    <text>Not clear — why such an advanced monitoring system? Track swamp mutants or what?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_third_dialog_3">
    <text>Well… first, it’s not my whim. The boss said “do it” — I said “done”. We’re not poor or stingy. Huge money here — artifact hunting, mutant safaris… This is just a fraction. Harold makes money by the shovelful… And invests heavily in security. Equipment is like in private armies of Arab sheikhs. Cut corners — you’re dead. Show weakness — competitors crush you. And random bandits? Keep them in check too…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_radist_quest_third_dialog_4">
    <text>Got it. I understand. Doesn’t really concern me. I did my job, got my cut. Bye…</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_pred_dialog_0">
    <text>Phew, we held them off. Honestly, I didn’t expect that. Scout, don’t hold a grudge. You’re looking for enemies in the wrong place. I’m here for my own interests, and it’s not in my plans to harm your clan… Any questions? No problem, I’ll answer…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_pred_dialog_1">
    <text>Held them off… you can say that. Of course I have questions. I see you truly don’t want to harm my faction, at least for now. If you still wanted to — I can’t prove it yet. If you were a mercenary, you’d have killed me as soon as we got rid of the creatures. Not certain, but still… Alright, stalker. Answer this: why didn’t you mention the mercenary’s corpse?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_pred_dialog_2">
    <text>I told you — I have my own interest here, connected to the “Clear Sky” clan. Clues I find, I’ll use as I see fit. In that case, I have a counter-proposal… Help me investigate the disappearance of the Clear Sky group and the scientists in your area, and I’ll try to resolve your faction’s internal conflicts.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_pred_dialog_3">
    <text>Heh, you’re a clever one, stalker. Handling internal conflicts isn’t easy, huh? Well, fine. I can share some information. My guys tracked the Clear Sky members — they were here about a week ago. Where they are now — I don’t know. They left our controlled area, and we lost interest. Regarding the scientists, some will say they saw them, some won’t. Here’s what I tell you — my people didn’t see them. And if my scouts didn’t see them — they weren’t here. Interpret that as you wish…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_pred_dialog_4">
    <text>I see. Well, thank you for the information.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_pred_dialog_44">
    <text>Now that’s interesting. Thanks for the information.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_pred_dialog_5">
    <text>And one more thing. You’ll be surprised to learn that the mercenary corpse you found wasn’t actually a mercenary.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_pred_dialog_6">
    <text>Should I be surprised? Honestly — I haven’t decided yet… What’s going on here? Internal conflicts in your faction? Why is your Hasan, as you call him, “that damn bastard”? What are the mercenaries doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_pred_dialog_7">
    <text>Heh, my friend — that’s exactly what I want to find out. Hasan is our deputy. He and Harold founded this clan together. Lately, their paths started diverging. We suspect Hasan may be running a double game, selling artifacts through shady channels, bypassing Harold. We can’t prove it yet. The mercenaries we’ve been observing likely work for him. Plus, he has reliable people inside the clan. Our faction is splitting into two. My advice — don’t get involved, stalker. You’d just become another pawn, used and forgotten.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_pred_dialog_8">
    <text>Who knows. Maybe a pawn, maybe a queen. Either way, your internal conflict doesn’t concern me — at least until it crosses into my business.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_pred_dialog_88">
    <text>Even pawns can checkmate the king. Either way, your internal conflict doesn’t concern me — at least until it affects my interests.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_pred_dialog_9">
    <text>Remember — it’s in your interest that they don’t intersect. Though I suspect it’s inevitable. The corpse you found — one of the Clear Sky members, killed and disguised as a mercenary. I didn’t want to tell you. But you would’ve figured it out eventually. Since it’s neither a mercenary nor a stalker from our clan — you deal with it yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_pred_dialog_10">
    <text>Understood. Thanks. I’ll keep that in mind.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Alright, we’ll handle the main issues later. Need any more help from me? Nothing involving internal faction disputes. I’m fine with taking another job.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_first_dialog_1">
    <text>My group has two secondary tasks left. One involves measuring radiation at a newly emerged anomaly hotspot. The other is to measure activity of a chemical formation. If you want — you can take either.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I’ll take the radiation measurements.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_first_dialog_222">
    <text>Investigating the chemical anomaly suits me better.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_first_dialog_22">
    <text>Not interested in such work for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Good. Here’s a special radiometer. Handle it carefully — it’s rare and expensive here. Instructions are inside. Go to the designated area and complete the four measurements. Good luck.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_first_dialog_4">
    <text>On my way. Less risky than mine-clearing, thankfully.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_first_dialog_333">
    <text>Alright, then. Honestly, I hoped you’d take the radiation task — don’t want to risk extra doses ourselves. Here, take the good old VPHR. You know how to handle it. Take samples from one anomaly and return. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_first_dialog_444">
    <text>Understood. I’ll do it properly.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Task completed. Measurements done. Some spots have very high radiation. This anomaly should produce artifacts regularly.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Good work. Hand over the radiometer and the results. And again — take my advice. Things here are serious. Even too serious… Your investigation might take you too far, with no turning back.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Here’s the device and results. I know there might be no turning back. But I have no choice…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_second_dialog_122">
    <text>I have no choice. Either way, I’m already in this mess; I’ll try not to drown. Here are your results.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_second_dialog_3">
    <text>There’s always a choice, my friend. Remember that. If needed — you can count on my help. And beware of Hasan. Farewell…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_second_quest_second_dialog_4">
    <text>I’ll keep that in mind. Farewell…</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_b1_leader_third_quest_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Task completed. Samples taken. Quite a strange anomaly, but it should produce artifacts reliably.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_third_quest_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Good work. Hand over the VPHR and the samples. Still… take my advice. Things here are serious. Even too serious… Your investigation might take you too far… So far that there’ll be no turning back.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_third_quest_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Here’s the device and results. I understand there may be no way back. But I have no choice…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_third_quest_second_dialog_22">
    <text>I have no choice. Either way, I’m already in this mess; I’ll try not to drown. Here are your results.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_third_quest_second_dialog_3">
    <text>There’s always a choice, my friend. Remember that. If needed — you can count on my help. And remember — beware of Hasan. Farewell.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_third_quest_second_dialog_4">
    <text>I’ll keep that in mind. Farewell…</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_f1_freedom_patrol_lider_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, stalker… Hold up. No nonsense. We’ll talk and let you go. Who are you, which faction? And what brings you to these parts?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_patrol_lider_dialog_1">
    <text>Good to see you too, friend. Freedom member? And what are the fathers of anarchy doing in these remote lands, right next to Duty territory?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_patrol_lider_dialog_2">
    <text>Are you deaf? Or should I shoot your knee to make you hear? We ask the questions here. Answer if you want to live.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_patrol_lider_dialog_3">
    <text>Calm down, calm down. They call me Varg. From Agroyantar. Not tied to Duty. Don’t worry. I was in Orest’s faction. Then I came here, to the free life.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_patrol_lider_dialog_4">
    <text>On business here, or what?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_patrol_lider_dialog_5">
    <text>Just looking for artifacts, maybe find some work… But you clearly aren’t local. What brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_patrol_lider_dialog_6">
    <text>You’re too curious, stalker. We’re waiting for someone. But apparently, it’s not you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_patrol_lider_dialog_7">
    <text>Apparently? So you don’t even know who you’re waiting for? Heh, alright. By the way, tell me — where can I earn some money around here? Even if you’re not local, you’ve clearly been here longer than me.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_patrol_lider_dialog_77">
    <text>You don’t know who you’re waiting for? Funny. By the way, do you know where one can find work? You’ve been around longer than me, though not local.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_patrol_lider_dialog_8">
    <text>We can take you to our commander. Actually, that’s a good idea — maybe you’ll be useful to him if you don’t ask too many questions. Or you can play the role of the stalker we’re waiting for. Just a thought. I’ve already bored my guys standing here waiting. Just kidding, of course. If you want more serious work — you should head straight to the Free Stalkers’ base. They have everything — blackjack, girls. Everything, as it should be.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_patrol_lider_dialog_9">
    <text>Thanks, friend. I’ll probably see your commander first — maybe he can help.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_patrol_lider_dialog_10">
    <text>Good choice. He set up a camp nearby with his guys. Farewell, Varg…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_patrol_lider_dialog_11">
    <text>Farewell.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, Freedom. Passing by, thought I’d drop in…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_1">
    <text>Drop in, you say? Whose side are you on, stalker? What brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_2">
    <text>Easy there. Boss. I’m here on business. One important matter — if you know what I mean. Your patrol said you were here, so I came…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_3">
    <text>Patrol, huh. Got it. We were expecting you. Well, not everyone. The scout was with us. He told us to wait for you here — then left. It’s been three days since he’s been gone. Staying here is unsafe — not your home. Do the task and get out.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_4">
    <text>Two days you say? That’s bad. Any Duty members along the way?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_44">
    <text>Doesn’t seem like him to disappear that long. Duty? They haven’t tracked you, I hope?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_5">
    <text>No Duty along the way. Well, almost none. Two artifact collectors appeared here — we dealt with them and buried them under a tree. Don’t worry, no tails. So? Are you going to do what we’ve been waiting for, damn it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_6">
    <text>Your scout is needed. That’s one. Second — plans changed a bit. What’s the news on the “Clear Sky” faction?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_7">
    <text>What news could there be? And what does that have to do with this? Our task is…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_8">
    <text>Your task, fool, is to listen and follow orders. I said the tasks have changed. I won’t discuss them with you — only with your scout. Since he’s not here — answer my questions. Have you seen any Clear Sky stalkers in this area?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_9">
    <text>Yes, we have. But again… what does that have to do with our task?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_10">
    <text>Not your task, but mine. Did you try to find the scout? Maybe he’s lying nearby, guts ripped out, dying two steps from the camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_101">
    <text>Not yours, but mine. Did you try to find the scout?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_11">
    <text>He ordered not to search for him. To wait for you. Though, if you want — you can find him yourself. He’s your man after all…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_12">
    <text>When did he last contact you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_13">
    <text>Two days ago. Here, take the detector. I don’t like this… Find him yourself. This isn’t clean. Not according to plan. I won’t move from here with my people.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_freedom_scaut_lider_dialog_14">
    <text>Alright, sit tight, grow your rear. When I return, you’ll tell me everything you know about Clear Sky.</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_f1_dolg_squad_lider_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey there, folks. What happened here? Throwing a party or what? What’s the fight about?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_dolg_squad_lider_dialog_1">
    <text>None of your business, dog. This is Duty’s matter. Better leave while you’re still whole… Wait. Who are you and how did you find this place?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_dolg_squad_lider_dialog_2">
    <text>Got it. I’m not a fool, I’m leaving. I’m a local, called Varg. I was searching for artifacts nearby, heard gunfire, thought I’d check it out. Maybe someone needs help…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_dolg_squad_lider_dialog_3">
    <text>Local, you say? Searching for artifacts, you say? Local artifact collectors don’t roam alone. That’s the clan rule. So, who’s the commandant in your clan? If you’re local — you should know their name and what happened to them…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_dolg_squad_lider_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, I wander around — not just an artifact collector, you know. I’m not obliged to report to the first stranger I meet. As for the commandant — how should I know? First day I got my gear and was told: go, serve the motherland.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_dolg_squad_lider_dialog_5">
    <text>You’re right about one thing. No need to explain to every passerby. But regarding the commandant — see, here’s the thing — there is no commandant in your local clan. How do you explain that? We just took out some Freedom members, and you appeared here, at this spot…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_dolg_squad_lider_dialog_6">
    <text>Damn, lady luck has run out after all…</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey there, hunter. I heard you went alone after the controllers and came back alive? Is that true?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_1">
    <text>Maybe true, maybe not. Who knows what drunk folks babble. What’s it to you? Who are you anyway? Don’t recall seeing you around here.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_2">
    <text>I’m Varg. Stalker. Just a stalker. Recently arrived. Not in a clan, so you wouldn’t remember me.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_22">
    <text>I’m not local. Name’s Varg. Not in a clan. That’s why you don’t remember.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_3">
    <text>Varg, huh. So what do you need, Varg?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_4">
    <text>What else — money, women, honor, respect. Can anyone wish for anything else?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_5">
    <text>Everyone has desires. Not everyone wants what you mentioned. Money and women — plenty can get that with a gun. But honor and respect… Are you really so naive to think it’ll help you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_6">
    <text>Why not? It’ll bring even more women and money.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_7">
    <text>Heh, I’m starting to like you, Varg. And I assume you came here seeking all that?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_8">
    <text>Well, more or less, yes.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_88">
    <text>Exactly, my friend.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_9">
    <text>Remember this. Here you’ll find only trouble for your ass. But fine. Since you came, whether on your own or tipped off — choose. You can either destroy a swamp mutant nest or clear the area of more dangerous mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_10">
    <text>I’m more interested in the swamp mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_11">
    <text>I’ll take the more dangerous ones.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_12">
    <text>Good. Glad you’re not as foolish as I thought. Here’s the deal. Artifact collectors ran into unknown creatures. All the guys died. Scouts didn’t see it coming. And that’s not all. A few others recently disappeared in that area, all at night. One was apparently from Clear Sky. So who knows if you did the right thing. Don’t worry — you can go there not alone if you wish.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_13">
    <text>Wait. You said a Clear Sky member? I’ll handle this alone. Don’t need help.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_14">
    <text>Heh, I see you’re not only after women and glory… Fine, your choice, stalker. About the Clear Sky member — we’ll talk after the task. About help — I’d advise not refusing. Extra firepower won’t hurt. Anyway, my squad will be nearby. You’re going to them now. Their leader, Finist, will tell you more about the creatures and where they were seen. Take better gear. Off you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_15">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_112">
    <text>Boy, thought this through well? I think so. Won’t stop you — your choice. The creatures came here at night. Not at the base, but close. Three men missing by morning. Clear Sky members came recently too. One of theirs also disappeared the next night. Scouts tracked them, didn’t engage. Scouts rarely do. They gave approximate area of the creatures, which have some psi abilities. Be really careful.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_113">
    <text>Wait, you said Clear Sky?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_114">
    <text>Heh, see? You’re not only after women and fame… Fine, your right, stalker. About the Clear Sky member — we’ll talk after you finish the task, if you return. Others are heading to that area, so you’ll probably not be alone. Take better gear. Off you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_init_dialog_115">
    <text>Farewell.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_1_dialog_0">
    <text>You’re Finist? Zmeelov said to find you. You need to tell me more about the swamp mutant nest.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_1_dialog_1">
    <text>First — I owe no one anything. Heh, maybe my ex-wife. I don’t care what you say. I’ll do only what Zmeelov ordered.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_1_dialog_2">
    <text>And what did he order?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_1_dialog_22">
    <text>Exactly what he ordered?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_1_dialog_3">
    <text>He ordered to watch you. See if you can handle it. Said you wanted to do it all yourself. So me and my guys won’t interfere. Die if you die. But if you do it right — return, I’ll have a favor to ask. Oh, forgot — the nest is near an abandoned farmstead. Not far. Go and take out everything that moves.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_1_dialog_4">
    <text>Don’t worry, I’ll return…</text>
</string>

	<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_2_dialog_0">
    <text>The swamp creatures are eliminated.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_2_dialog_1">
    <text>Good job, stalker. What exactly were they?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_2_dialog_2">
    <text>Hell if I know… Some mutated half-lizards, half-fish. Never seen anything like them. And I doubt they’re exactly what we were looking for.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_2_dialog_3">
    <text>Unlikely. We’ve never seen fish-like lizards here. We’ll need to collect one of the bodies and send it to the scientists in Yantra. Also, you’re going back to Zmeelov anyway — give him this, I owe him.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_2_dialog_4">
    <text>Heh, didn’t you say you owe nothing to anyone?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_2_dialog_44">
    <text>I’ll deliver it. But you said you owe nothing, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_2_dialog_5">
    <text>I lied. Fine — that’s my business. Just deliver it. Goodbye.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_2_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright. Farewell.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_end_dialog_0">
    <text>Task completed. The creatures are dead. I didn’t need Finist’s help, just like I said.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_end_dialog_1">
    <text>Excellent, stalker, excellent. You’ll get a good reward. Enough for blackjack and women. Hmm… I’ll think of another job for you later. But we’ll see.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_end_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, I almost forgot. Finist asked me to give you his debt. Six thousand. By the way, what about the job? And my question about the Clear Sky member?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_end_dialog_22">
    <text>Ah, right. Finist asked me to pass you his debt — three thousand. What’s the work you wanted to offer? And my question?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_end_dialog_222">
    <text>What other job can you offer me? Ah, remembered — Finist asked to tell you he’ll repay the debt after his run. By the way, what about the Clear Sky member?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_end_dialog_3">
    <text>Debt is good. But Finist doesn’t owe me anything. What are you talking about? Did we nod heads in sync? Never mind. About the Clear Sky member — I’ll tell you what I know. The job — later. I need to decide if I can trust you with it. Did you really see Finist and his people?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_end_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, he was there. Talked to him just like now with you. So about the job later — fine. Though you could’ve given a hint of what to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_end_dialog_33">
    <text>Debt is good. But Finist doesn’t owe me anything. What are you talking about? Did we nod heads in sync? Never mind. About the Clear Sky member — I’ll tell you what I know. The job — later. I still need to decide if I can trust you. Did you really see Finist and his people?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_end_dialog_44">
    <text>Yes, he was there. Talked to him just like now. Job later — fine. Though you could’ve hinted at what to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_end_dialog_333">
    <text>Debt is good. But Finist doesn’t owe me anything. What are you talking about? Did we nod heads in sync? Never mind. About the Clear Sky member — I’ll tell you what I know. The job — later. I still need to decide if I can trust you. Did you really see Finist and his people?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_frog_end_dialog_444">
    <text>Yes, he was there. Talked to him just like now. Job later — fine. Though you could’ve hinted at what to do.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a7_hunter_bandit_member_dialog_01">
    <text>Hey, stalker. What are you doing here? You killed those creatures? That was our job.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a7_hunter_bandit_member_dialog_02">
    <text>Doesn’t concern me… First come, first served.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a7_hunter_bandit_member_dialog_0">
    <text>Doesn’t concern you, huh? We’ll tear your guts out then, dumbass. Give me what Zmeelov promised to pay, or else.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a7_hunter_bandit_member_dialog_11">
    <text>Easy, easy. Here, take it. Can’t even joke.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a7_hunter_bandit_member_dialog_22">
    <text>Good. Now get lost. Mention us to Zmeelov and you’re dead.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a7_hunter_bandit_member_dialog_33">
    <text>Got it. Leaving.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a7_hunter_bandit_member_dialog_1">
    <text>Don’t you get me, freak? I said in plain Russian — I don’t care. My job — my pay.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a7_hunter_bandit_member_dialog_2">
    <text>So you’re cheeky. Fine — I’ll teach you some manners.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a7_hunter_bandit_member_dialog_3">
    <text>Let’s see who teaches whom…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a7_hunter_bandit_member_dialog_111">
    <text>Screw you… Bastard. You think I’ll pay for you doing your job?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a7_hunter_bandit_member_dialog_222">
    <text>Don’t understand Russian? Fine, I’ll explain differently.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a7_hunter_bandit_member_dialog_333">
    <text>Go ahead, try…</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_polter_end_dialog_0">
    <text>Anyway, it’s done. Those creatures are destroyed. They were really dangerous, but I’ve encountered them once in the Agro-Yantra underground. No big issues.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_polter_end_dialog_1">
    <text>Good. You’ll get paid. Are you sure there were no problems? Nothing else to tell me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_polter_end_dialog_2">
    <text>Absolutely. Nothing more to tell. On the contrary, I hope you’ll tell me something about my topic.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_polter_end_dialog_22">
    <text>No problems. Nothing more to say. I hope you’ll give me some info on my subject.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_polter_end_dialog_3">
    <text>I will, don’t worry. Here’s the thing — one of my best groups disappeared in the area where you worked. No witnesses. I decided to shut down operations for a bit — all safaris close for entertainment. Did you notice anything unusual?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_first_quest_polter_end_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, exactly. I told you, didn’t see anyone — so I didn’t see anyone.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, friend. You a local mechanic? I’m Varg, a free stalker from Agro-Yantra. Looking for work before I settle. Got anything for a skilled and handy wanderer?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello. Skilled and experienced, you say? Good. Familiar with tech? Not a master of everything — just not clumsy. At least able to hold a screwdriver.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_first_dialog_2">
    <text>You flatter me, friend. Would I roam the Zone if I were clumsy? I’d have been buried in the nearest anomaly long ago.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Fine. Hope you’re honest. Doesn’t matter to me — someone else would do the job. But time is money. Or lives. The task: as a group technician, I need to prepare purchases for the clan — select equipment, supplies, etc. Currently deciding what gear to buy in bulk. Choose: test gas masks or test portable radios. Need results to decide which models to order.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_first_dialog_4">
    <text>I’ll test gas masks. More relevant to a regular stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_first_dialog_44">
    <text>I’ll work with radios. I studied communications in the military, so that’s my field.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_first_dialog_5">
    <text>As you wish. Plan: take necessary equipment from the nearby backpack. Prepare five test samples. Test in the designated tent — like army gas mask tests. Then bring results to me. Make sure to finish all five in time, or no pay.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Don’t worry. I’ll manage in time.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_first_dialog_55">
    <text>Fine. Task: five radio samples. Go to the area, check signal reception. Bring results to me. Our radio operator will monitor it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_first_dialog_66">
    <text>Alright, no problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_first_dialog_22">
    <text>Wow. Serious job. Maybe I’ll come back later.</text>
</string>

	
	
	<string id="topi_mechanic_razia_quest_end_dialog_0">
    <text>Task completed. That turned out to be pretty simple.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_razia_quest_end_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, that was all soft and easy for you. Some people can’t even handle such a simple task. Good job, kid. If another job comes up, I’ll let you know. By the way, have you thought about joining our clan? We need capable guys like you. I can put in a good word for you with the leadership.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_razia_quest_end_dialog_2">
    <text>Thought about it at first. But I need to sort out my own business first. After that — who knows.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_razia_quest_end_dialog_22">
    <text>Had a similar idea. But I need to handle my own business first. We’ll see after that.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_razia_quest_end_dialog_3">
    <text>Your own business? Maybe I can help. If you need technical assistance, don’t hesitate. Whatever’s needed — we’ll do it properly. By the way, if you want more work — come by at night, after three. If you’re interested, of course.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_razia_quest_end_dialog_4">
    <text>Thanks. I’ll keep that in mind.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Gas masks tested. Got the results. Is that all? That’s the entire job?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes. Isn’t that enough for you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, kind of. I was hoping for something bigger. Didn’t even have to leave the base much.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_second_dialog_22">
    <text>Yeah, always want more. And here, you barely had to leave the base.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Heh. You’re cheeky, stalker. Wanting more. Many would consider this work lucky — no risk to your own ass. If you like risk, join hunters, suppliers, or scouts. They’ll give you real adrenaline. I can only offer tasks like this. If more work interests you — come after three at night.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, don’t grumble like an old man. Got it.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_third_dialog_0">
    <text>Listen, friend. Got myself in trouble. Didn’t manage to test all the samples in time.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_third_dialog_1">
    <text>What, what? You got in trouble? Clumsy deer. I knew it. What kind of people are coming to the Zone now — I’m shocked. Complete idiots. And how are you still alive? And why are you just standing there blinking? Ah, son of a… Give me the equipment. You shouldn’t be trusted with anything.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_third_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, take it. Well, mistakes happen. I’ll fix it. Not everything works perfectly on the first try. Skill with tech is needed… I spent the last six months just shooting mutants and crawling through anomalies.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_third_dialog_3">
    <text>You’re still here? Fine — whatever. Maybe you’re skilled at something else. But don’t expect any more work from me. I wouldn’t even trust you to carry a dirty bucket.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_third_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright. Just don’t grumble.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_quest_third_dialog_44">
    <text>Fine. Just don’t complain.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_i1_anubis_yad_quest_dialog_0">
    <text>Damn, Freedom fighter… Where’s the medic? Who are you and where did you come from? Help…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_anubis_yad_quest_dialog_1">
    <text>Relax. Hold still, I’ll give you an injection. Struggle — and you’ll die in minutes. Barely made it to you. There… now it’s fine. Feeling better?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_anubis_yad_quest_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, better. Who are you anyway?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_anubis_yad_quest_dialog_3">
    <text>A stalker from the Freedom faction. That’s enough for now. Don’t worry — I don’t hold grudges over the skirmish with our groups and the debt groups. Otherwise, would I be saving you now? Didn’t you fail to crack a mercenary stash?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_anubis_yad_quest_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes. Wait, how did you know?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_anubis_yad_quest_dialog_44">
    <text>What? How did you find out?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_anubis_yad_quest_dialog_5">
    <text>I know a lot. You’re not the first to fall for their poisoned stash trick. They fill it with gas. No chance of surviving without special gear. But you survived. Thanks to me, of course.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_anubis_yad_quest_dialog_6">
    <text>Thank you. Name your reward — artifacts, money. I’ll give everything.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_anubis_yad_quest_dialog_7">
    <text>I’ll ask later. For now, go to the base and see the medic. Say you inhaled chemical anomaly gases. He’ll heal you. I’ll check in when needed. And no unnecessary questions for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_anubis_yad_quest_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_anubis_yad_quest_dialog_88">
    <text>As you say.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_i1_medic_yad_quest_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, I need your help. Got myself in a chemical anomaly. Inhaled all kinds of gases. Can you check me? Even with some meds, I still feel bad.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_medic_yad_quest_dialog_1">
    <text>In an anomaly, you say? Let’s take a look. Are you joking? Where did you find an anomaly that causes damage like a very curious HO? And you don’t really need treatment — you’ve already been healed. So where did this happen?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_medic_yad_quest_dialog_2">
    <text>I told you, I got into an anomaly.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_medic_yad_quest_dialog_22">
    <text>Why would I lie? First time seeing such an anomaly.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_medic_yad_quest_dialog_3">
    <text>Why are you hiding something? Let’s not lie to each other, okay? I’ve seen guys like you plenty. They’re usually dead by then. That’s mercenary methods, kid. Where did you see the blue ones?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_medic_yad_quest_dialog_4">
    <text>I didn’t see them. Found only one body. Had papers pointing to their stash. Found it, couldn’t open. Recently, while working on Vazgen, ran into bandits. One told me the stash and gave the code. The code worked. Then — you know. Surprise stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_medic_yad_quest_dialog_5">
    <text>Familiar situation. Mercenary stash. Bandits who attack our collectors have access. Friend, don’t you feel you’re meddling in things not yours? Dealing with forces that could kill you anytime?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_medic_yad_quest_dialog_6">
    <text>What are you talking about?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_medic_yad_quest_dialog_66">
    <text>What do you mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_medic_yad_quest_dialog_7">
    <text>Nothing. Just thinking aloud and giving advice. You’re smart, Varg, right? Don’t mess with mercenaries if you want to live. Got the hint or should I explain differently?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_medic_yad_quest_dialog_8">
    <text>Do you work for the syndicate?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_medic_yad_quest_dialog_9">
    <text>Think what I’d do if I worked for the syndicate and got caught? Probably shoot you now. But see — I’m talking to you. No, friend. I don’t work for them. But some of our people do business with them. I want to protect you. Varg, they’d eat you alive. Stop and mind your own business. You’ve been fishing for info on Clear Sky — keep doing that, don’t meddle here.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_i1_medic_yad_quest_dialog_10">
    <text>I can’t, friend. Everything’s connected. Pull one thread — the other follows. I’ll handle it myself. Thanks for your concern. I’ll manage if I’m lucky. Farewell.</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, Vazgen. I heard you’re looking for someone to handle a certain job. I can take it if it’s still relevant.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_first_dialog_1">
    <text>You, huh? Why not. Our guys, and many others, said you handle complex jobs pretty well. You did measurements, tested equipment. So I won’t give you simple tasks that anyone could handle. But I won’t throw you straight into serious work either — I have my trusted people for that. You may be a skilled specialist, but you still need to earn my trust.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_first_dialog_2">
    <text>So what now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_first_dialog_22">
    <text>I’ll come back later. Not in the mood for your nonsense. If it’s a concrete job — speak up. Don’t drag it out...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Nothing. You’ll work. Specifically — I’m interested in artifact delivery in this dump. Everything else doesn’t matter. Deliveries, and the people gathering artifacts — that’s our priority. Don’t be fooled by me acting as a simple trader. No artifacts — no trade. Experienced collectors are valuable. We train the young, but…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Listen, can you be more specific? What exactly do you need from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Heh, impatient, huh? Why interrupt Vazgen? He should tell you everything. Long story short — an experienced collector, with the clan since its founding, got killed. Two bastards — literally their own men — shot him in the back. Took all the loot and hid nearby. Rumor is, a few more joined them — forming a small gang. Scouts tracked them. The problem is taking them out. Quickly and cleanly. Otherwise, this small gang could give us big trouble. They won’t hit the base, but they know collector routes. If they join a bigger gang — total disaster. So, get moving. Only one of our combat groups will cover you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright, I’ll take this job gladly. I’ll tear those bastards apart.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b7_trader_quest_1_bandit_wounded_dialog_0">
    <text>Stalker, help… Got hit. Brother… medkit, I won’t forget this…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b7_trader_quest_1_bandit_wounded_dialog_1">
    <text>You think you’ll live another century, bastard? Tell me, how many of you were there?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b7_trader_quest_1_bandit_wounded_dialog_2">
    <text>Five of us. No one else. Me and my buddy tried to run when we heard the shooting. He wasn’t even a buddy — mercenary, I guess. He shot me on purpose and ran…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b7_trader_quest_1_bandit_wounded_dialog_3">
    <text>Where did he go? What exactly were you doing in this area?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b7_trader_quest_1_bandit_wounded_dialog_33">
    <text>Where did he head? What exactly were you doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b7_trader_quest_1_bandit_wounded_dialog_4">
    <text>There’s a stash nearby. He was supposed to pick up an order from there… Heading to the farm now. Stalker, help, please. I’ve told you everything I know…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b7_trader_quest_1_bandit_wounded_dialog_5">
    <text>I’m already helping you…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b7_trader_quest_1_bandit_wounded_dialog_11">
    <text>No, bastard. I’d rather watch you die.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b7_trader_quest_1_bandit_prisoner_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, you showed up, damn it. Ask your damn questions, let’s finish this fast…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b7_trader_quest_1_bandit_prisoner_dialog_1">
    <text>Can’t wait to die, huh? Don’t worry — won’t hurt you much. Our talk is short. But only if you answer quickly and clearly. Don’t talk — you’ll die slow. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b7_trader_quest_1_bandit_prisoner_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, stalker. I’m not a mercenary. But I started working for them. Used to be free, not in a clan. Joined this gang for money. And I have something to tell.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b7_trader_quest_1_bandit_prisoner_dialog_3">
    <text>Four questions. First — the stash you were going to for a job. I need the code. Second — how are the Blues connected to the local clan and whose body were they trying to pass as their dead fighter found on the farm? Third — what’s Hasan’s role? His name was in the documents I found. Last — is the Clear Sky clan connected to the mercenaries?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b7_trader_quest_1_bandit_prisoner_dialog_4">
    <text>You asked a lot. I’ll tell what I know. Code for the stash: 5683. We weren’t there to take an order, but payment for a job. Mercenaries hire their own. Blues connected to the local clan via Hasan. Our task was to kill a collector carrying a rare item. Hasan tipped the mercs. We were only executors. Mercs were intermediaries. Hasan may smuggle extra artifacts through them — just my guess. Don’t know about the corpse. Clear Sky — heard mercs say they killed one nearby, not sure if true. That’s all. Stalker — I know you’ll kill me, do it fast.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b7_trader_quest_1_bandit_prisoner_dialog_5">
    <text>Understood…</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Job done. Bandits and mercs eliminated. One former free stalker among them. I interrogated him.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_second_dialog_1">
    <text>And what did he say? Don’t keep me waiting.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Vazgen, you’re a strange guy. Not Russian, but when you want, you speak with no accent at all.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Don’t talk around me. Tell me what he said, damn it…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Nothing special. Said they agreed to take out one of your collectors who recently grabbed a stash with a rare artifact. A mercenary tipped them off.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_second_dialog_44">
    <text>Nothing noteworthy. They agreed to take out a collector who recently found a rare artifact. A mercenary tipped them.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright, listen. Forget what he told you. It’s better for everyone. I’ll pay extra for your silence. Don’t worry — not with bullets, though it’d be cheaper. I’ll need you for another job. Don’t cause trouble. Also, see our artifact specialist — he might have more work. Once that’s sorted, come back to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_1_quest_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Hope you weren’t lying.</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_0">
    <text>So, what’s the other job you wanted to offer me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Knew you’d be interested. You’re no simple man, Varg. This is basically a continuation of the matter you just handled.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Listening. What needs to be done now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_22">
    <text>Maybe I’ll take it later. Not in the mood right now…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Here’s the deal. Main rule for our business to thrive — security. When security is threatened, nothing else matters. You missed one of the gang members, Varg. Now wise Vazgen has to figure out how to cover our asses.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Missed? There were only five. The bandits themselves told me there were five.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_44">
    <text>Missed? There were five. You took down four. Your people got the fifth. The bandits themselves confirmed there were five of them.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_5">
    <text>You believed them? Don’t disappoint me, friend. My scout spotted six. The sixth left an hour before you arrived at their hideout. You dropped three, two headed for the stash. One shot the other to distract you and tried to escape to the farm. That’s where the combat team caught him. Sixth slipped away from our territory unnoticed.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_6">
    <text>And now you want me to chase that bastard halfway across the Zone? How could I know there were six?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_7">
    <text>You didn’t know. Now you do. And now you know that bastard knew the gang’s plans, maybe even was their leader. If he joins a bigger gang, we have big problems. The artifact our man found — the Devil’s Egg. Only three ever found in the Zone. Worth a couple million. Think the bandits will want it? Of course they will.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_8">
    <text>What a mess. Fine — what exactly should I do?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_88">
    <text>Unexpected twist. So, what now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_9">
    <text>That guy will likely meet renegade gangs. They’re reckless — no negotiations. Greedy, uncontrolled. We can redirect them. Take these documents and artifacts. Hide the documents in a stash — the info will reach the right ears. Deliver artifacts to another gang, say it’s from Vazgen. If they want more, they’ll contact Gogi. Then come back. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Do I need to know what’s in the documents?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_11">
    <text>No. But I’ll tell you. Guarantee you won’t run off with it — or we’ll kill you. Inside is a fake. One trusted gang member will be told the collector with the Devil’s Egg is on the swamps trying to sell via Clear Sky.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_12">
    <text>You’re setting up Clear Sky?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_13">
    <text>Yes. Nothing personal — purely business. Renegades will head to the swamps instead of here. They’ll make noise, find nothing, leave. All wins. I know you work for Clear Sky. Don’t worry. We help you in exchange. The gang you meet later is a decoy. Likely to try and kill you. Be ready to shoot back. We actually benefit if they attack you…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_14">
    <text>I don’t get why this meeting with the bandits is needed…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_141">
    <text>Not sure about your intentions…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_142">
    <text>Your logic is unclear. Why play all this out?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_15">
    <text>You don’t need to know why. Just play your part in the farce, that’s all.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_first_dialog_16">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a6_trader_quest_2_bandit_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, fool! Stop right there, runt. From Vazgen?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a6_trader_quest_2_bandit_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah, from him. And you lot — who are you with?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a6_trader_quest_2_bandit_dialog_2">
    <text>Listen, fool. You don’t need to care. Got it? Hand over the artifacts and run if you want to live.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a6_trader_quest_2_bandit_dialog_3">
    <text>Go… to hell. You’re all dead anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a6_trader_quest_2_bandit_dialog_4">
    <text>What did you say? You’re the dead one, runt. We’ll bring your head to Vazgen, got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a6_trader_quest_2_bandit_dialog_5">
    <text>Just try…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a6_trader_quest_2_bandit_dialog_33">
    <text>Here are the artifacts. Do I need to give something to Vazgen?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a6_trader_quest_2_bandit_dialog_44">
    <text>No, we’ll deliver your head ourselves.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a6_trader_quest_2_bandit_dialog_55">
    <text>Try it…</text>
</string>

	<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, fool, you worthless runt, what’s all this crap supposed to mean? Were these bandits just hired to kill me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Heh, you’re quick, I see. Well, nothing. Hope you realize you’ve learned too much unnecessary and dangerous info?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_second_dialog_2">
    <text>So you just decided to get rid of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_second_dialog_22">
    <text>You thought you could just dispose of me? Like that?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, you’re still alive, aren’t you? Because as soon as the bandits opened fire, someone took out two of them. Can you guess who or under whose guidance? No? Then shut up and listen. Not everything’s rosy here, stalker. You’ve stumbled into a huge mess, not easy to get out alive. So listen carefully…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_second_dialog_4">
    <text>So what exactly are you saying?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_second_dialog_5">
    <text>The clan founder, Harold, has a serious conflict with his deputy, Hasan. Hasan plays his own game and dreams of taking Harold’s place. Hasan is behind most of the strange things happening recently. He works with mercenaries, and they help him execute his plans. You’ve stumbled onto Hasan while investigating your Clear Sky assignment.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_second_dialog_6">
    <text>And what should I do? My main goal is to complete the assignment.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_second_dialog_7">
    <text>Two options. Since you survived the attempt, either help convince Harold that Hasan works only for himself, or offer your services to Hasan. You decide what fee to ask. Both can get you what you need. But understand the risk. Hasan won’t kill you publicly, and Harold can’t remove Hasan without proof.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_second_dialog_8">
    <text>Wait, how do you know all this?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_second_dialog_88">
    <text>And how do you know this?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_second_dialog_888">
    <text>How the hell did you find out about this?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_second_dialog_9">
    <text>Birds sing everywhere, my friend. You just need to know how to listen. Don’t worry about who Vazgen works for — just follow his advice. Next time, it won’t be simple bandits meeting you…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_2_quest_second_dialog_10">
    <text>Understood. Thanks. Good luck…</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Hasan. I need to have a business talk with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_1">
    <text>And hello to you. Come in, I’ve heard about your recent deeds. People here talk about nothing else.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I hope only good things?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_22">
    <text>At least good things, they say?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Maybe. I haven’t decided yet. They say you performed well working for the clan, and brought much benefit. But also that you started asking… risky questions. Questions that could bring trouble for both of us. They also say you survived opening a booby-trapped mercenary stash and easily dealt with some small gangs. You’re dangerous, Varg, and could be a valuable partner — or not. So, I’m listening…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Business partnership is good and essential. I’ve also heard a lot about you, Hasan. Some are unhappy you didn’t let them occupy local farms, and that you likely use this place as a meeting point with your mercenary allies. I also have documents confirming this. I’ve heard you hire small gang groups, guided by informers, to rob your own artifact collectors. This lets you sell artifacts bypassing the clan treasury. Dangerous business, isn’t it? Just thinking about what could happen if these rumors reach the wrong ears…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Now you start to please me… You know I can’t just kill you here. If you suddenly die, some stalker could give your documents to Harold — not good. Likewise, you can’t kill me. So, coming to me, you hope to ask for a higher price for your silence? Who hired you to work against me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_6">
    <text>You’re almost right. Except one thing. I wasn’t hired against you. I don’t care about your clan and its schemes. But I can work for you and provide some services. These dangerous things became available while completing my Clear Sky assignment. My client wants to know the fate of their missing squad and the stalker scientist group that appeared here shortly before. I can forget what I know, and silence those who know it in exchange for full info on my assignment…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_7">
    <text>I see. This could change everything… Fine, if it all goes smoothly, I lose nothing and might even gain. Pure blackmail on your part, but I’d rather not choose the other option — less benefit for both. Agreed. You help eliminate all unhappy parties, and I’ll give you full info on the missing scientists and arrange a meeting with the clan contact.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Agreed.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_88">
    <text>Fine. I agree.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_9">
    <text>How do you propose to proceed? From what I understand, the scout leader — Harold’s trusted man — is in the way. His death should raise no suspicion. I’ve considered various plans: poisoning, clash with mercenaries, or with a rare mutant. Poisoning seems optimal. It cleans loose ends.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Exactly. I know how to do it discreetly. Tell the scout to wait in the designated area — further instructions and equipment will come from me. Hint it’s for testing a new batch of gas masks at the anomaly cluster. Your supplier or mechanic should get me the necessary components.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_11">
    <text>My mechanic will prepare everything needed. I see you plan to poison using gas masks. I considered that, but traces may remain. My men will monitor the operation.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_12">
    <text>No traces, nobody will figure it out. If the prepped catalyst works perfectly. Prepare the info I need. When I return, we’ll discuss it.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi. From Hasan. You should know what I need.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_1">
    <text>Ah, I see. Well, yes — I’m aware. But I have some questions.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_2">
    <text>What questions?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_22">
    <text>Questions?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_3">
    <text>The gas masks are clear. Filters are available. But other components… I don’t fully understand their purpose. Special substances act as catalysts. Multiple components may serve as catalysts, depending on the task.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood. I need hydroquinone in a capsule for spraying.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_5">
    <text>Ah, I see. Clear now. Here you go. Regards to Hasan — tell him everything is done perfectly.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_6">
    <text>Will do.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_scaut_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, we meet again.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_scaut_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello. So, you’re working for Hasan now? Didn’t expect that. Any extra instructions?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_scaut_dialog_2">
    <text>Not much, just a one-time assignment. I’m a simple courier. Give them the new batch of gas masks, let them run through the anomaly cluster. They’ll buy a bigger batch later.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_scaut_dialog_3">
    <text>If that’s true, fine. I thought you became one of his trusted men. By the way, new info: remember the mercenary corpse? I told you it was a Clear Sky member. Indeed, Hasan’s people eliminated him. He was in the squad you searched for. Fate of the rest unknown.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_scaut_dialog_4">
    <text>Good. Thanks. Be careful in the anomalies. Better go to the chemical anomaly nearby.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_scaut_dialog_44">
    <text>Okay. Be careful in the anomalies. Better go to the chemical one nearby.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_scaut_dialog_5">
    <text>We’ll go there. Bye. Don’t get too close to Hasan. Harold already has some leads on him. Soon he’ll expose him, and heads will roll. Watch your own.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_scaut_dialog_6">
    <text>I’ll try. Bye.</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_0">
    <text>It’s done. The scout group is eliminated. Did your observers confirm it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, Varg. I’ve already received confirmation. Good job. I must admit, I didn’t expect such cold calculation from you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_2">
    <text>And what else didn’t you expect?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_22">
    <text>And what else could you not expect?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_3">
    <text>I didn’t expect that you’d come to me instead of going to Harold.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Yeah. And I thought you wouldn’t expect me to survive after opening the stash…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Not without reason. But we don’t choose another person’s path, we only guide them. Alright, let’s focus on your task. I’m eager to end this story once and for all.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes, let’s do it.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey. I have very important information that will interest you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello. I’ve heard about your recent deeds, Varg. You’ve provided serious assistance to our faction. I hope your information is truly important if you decided to contact me directly?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_2">
    <text>More than that. It concerns your deputy, Hasan. Most likely, he’s playing his own game here. He’s somehow involved with mercenaries recently spotted by your scouts. Most likely, he’s selling stolen artifacts through them. Additionally, under his leadership, several bandit groups operated, collecting these artifacts from your gatherers following Hasan’s orders. So mercenaries, bandits — all links in a chain leading to Hasan.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Hmm, stalker. I suspected something like this, but not this much. Hasan has indeed changed recently. Even without your words, we had suspicions he was involved in recent events. But that the “rat” was Hasan himself? Hard to believe. I need solid proof supporting your claims. I can’t just accuse him of betrayal and shoot him — it would split the clan and ruin our business. But with proof of his guilt, everything changes. Also, what’s in it for you? Why help me and expose your deputy?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Simple: a favor for a favor. I’m not here for your clan’s affairs. Recently, a group of scientists disappeared in your controlled area, along with the Clear Sky squad sent to find them. I need full info, and I think only you can provide it. About Hasan — I have some evidence. Some documents, and my conclusions are shared by your scout commander. He suspected Hasan colluded with mercenaries after being denied access to farms. Most likely he used them for his purposes. Later, I found a mercenary corpse there. I also interrogated a bandit who claimed a high-ranking clan member passed info on your gatherers’ movements.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_5">
    <text>You say the scout leader? Well, he can’t confirm any of your concerns anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Why is that?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_7">
    <text>He died with his group under very strange circumstances. Their whole team was found dead near an anomaly. They were testing new equipment — gas masks from the supply batch. We don’t know what killed them. Or rather, who — the Zone, or were humans involved? So, as you said, if the Cripple was in Hasan’s way, he might be involved in their deaths. Logical? I think yes. So we need to look for traces. Maybe a psi-blast, poison gas, or something else. Three skilled scouts couldn’t just die in a chemical anomaly.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright, I’ll take the investigation… I already have some ideas. I’ll need equipment. Which of your people can I rely on?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_9">
    <text>Go to the supplier then. He’s fully my man. Do everything properly, and then we’ll talk about the scientists and their feathered friends.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright. Bye.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_first_dialog_101">
    <text>Understood. Bye.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_snab_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello. I’m from Harold. He said you could assist me fully in a delicate matter. First, tell me where you gave the latest batch of gas masks? They were issued to the deceased scouts for field tests.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_snab_dialog_1">
    <text>To our technicians. They prepared them for distribution among clan fighters. Why? Does it matter?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_snab_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, it matters. Also, I need special equipment — a spectrometer. I know it’s rare, but still. You don’t sell artifacts cheaply here either.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_snab_dialog_3">
    <text>True. I have a spectrometer, but why do you need it? What are you planning to investigate?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_snab_dialog_4">
    <text>The place where your scouts died.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_snab_dialog_44">
    <text>The place where your scouts perished.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_snab_dialog_5">
    <text>Wait, so you think their death wasn’t an accident?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_snab_dialog_6">
    <text>I don’t think, I want to find out. Thanks for the equipment. I’ll return it intact to Harold. Bye.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey there, tech. You don’t want to tell me anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_1">
    <text>What’s with the attitude? I owe you nothing. Go away.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_2">
    <text>I think you will owe, and not a little. I’m from Harold. Now, tell me — did you give the scout leader the gas mask batch for testing?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, I did. What’s the problem? The batches are usually given to scouts for preliminary testing. What’s wrong?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_4">
    <text>The masks were contaminated with specific poisons, which reacted when stalkers approached the anomaly. Traces are minimal, but present. Another day and I’d be too late. But I can confirm you prepared the contaminated batch that killed the scouts. Decide: confess and name the contractor, and you die quickly. Act tough — I won’t envy you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_5">
    <text>I didn’t give them anything. I just checked filters and issued a spare set. Not to them directly, but to a local courier, just running errands.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_6">
    <text>Whose man is the courier — Hasan’s or Harold’s?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_66">
    <text>Wait, whose man was the courier?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_7">
    <text>He’s Hasan’s man. Listen, Varg — don’t kill me, I’ll tell everything. Hasan arranged it all. He wanted to eliminate the Cripple. He interfered too much. I’ll give up his accomplices in the clan. I swear.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_8">
    <text>What accomplices? Stalkers or who?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_9">
    <text>Stalkers. They have a meeting place. A shared stash with Hasan. I’ll give you the coordinates. Just don’t kill me.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_tehnik_dialog_10">
    <text>Fine, live. But you’ll breathe and work as I say. Tell Hasan I was here — you know the hint. Sit, scum, dry your pants.</text>
</string>

	
	<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_0">
    <text>So, I’ve managed to figure everything out.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, don’t keep me waiting. Speak up if you have something to say.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_2">
    <text>As you suspected, the scouts were killed. They were poisoned using rather rare chemical substances. Half of it was in the filters of their gas masks. The catalyst reacted near the anomaly. Within a day, all traces would have evaporated and no one would have found anything. I tracked that Hasan’s man handed the gas masks to the group. The technician swears he didn’t tamper with them — he’s lying. He gave up all of Hasan’s accomplices in the clan. When I tried approaching them, they opened fire. I had to eliminate them. I also uncovered their stash, and the records found there prove Hasan’s direct guilt.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Excellent news, Varg. That traitor got what he deserved. We can grab him by the collar and shoot him. The faction’s fighters won’t question anything anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_4">
    <text>What about the technician? He’s Hasan’s man. Possibly not the only one. Surely there are others involved in this scheme.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_44">
    <text>And what about the rest of his people? Should we deal with them as well?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_5">
    <text>That’s less important. The main thing is to decapitate the enemy. The other pawns can’t do much anymore. And I won’t find a new technician quickly, so let him live for now. If needed, he’ll follow Hasan. Alright, I need to give orders and prepare Hasan’s elimination. And I might still need you for that.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_variant_quest_1_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Good. But now it’s time to deal with my matter.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a3_suget_quest_3_svayznoy_dialog_0">
    <text>You’re my contact? May I ask why you’ve been out of touch for so long?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a3_suget_quest_3_svayznoy_dialog_1">
    <text>No, I’m a Monolith contact. Or do you see anyone else here? Why would I contact you? Have you found the scientists or our missing group? I don’t think so. So why should I listen to your whining?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a3_suget_quest_3_svayznoy_dialog_2">
    <text>I uncovered some information quite quickly... I needed to report it and hoped for new instructions.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a3_suget_quest_3_svayznoy_dialog_3">
    <text>New instructions? My friend, you’re not in the army. I’m not a sergeant, you’re not a conscript. You were given a task, you accepted it. The result is what matters, nothing more. No one will hold your hand or breathe down your neck. How you achieve it doesn’t matter to me. To our leadership — even less. Result. Period. You can bend the whole local stalker faction over if that’s what it takes — we don’t care. I need data, facts, preferably the specific people we’re looking for. Alive or dead — doesn’t matter. Result. Since you contacted me on behalf of someone, you have something. So spill what you’ve found.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a3_suget_quest_3_svayznoy_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright. I managed to find one of the missing scientists. He died in the anomaly. He had some documents that might interest you. Also, I tracked at least two people from your faction. One, probably an agent like me, died under mysterious circumstances — locals say eaten by unknown mutants. True or not — unknown. The other stalker, likely a fighter from the missing group, also died or was killed, most likely killed, either by locals or mercenaries under local orders. I might have mixed up who was the agent and who was the fighter. But both are dead — fact. Since they were here, the missing group likely didn’t leave the territory. I suspect it was entirely wiped out. Locals might be hiding something. Regarding the scientists, there’s a presumed area where they might still be if alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a3_suget_quest_3_svayznoy_dialog_5">
    <text>Understood. Overall, a satisfactory outcome for now. On dry land, even a crayfish is fish. You’re right about our “regular” agent. From your info, he’s dead. We feared this. He hadn’t contacted us for a long time. Last time, we learned he found one of the missing group fighters. The last thread to this group breaks with his death. Most likely, they all perished. That’s our conclusion, though grim. The fact that you know a more specific area for continuing the scientist search is encouraging. The fate of the scientists is crucial to us. Here’s what we’ll do: several of our groups will arrive soon. You’ve gained the trust of local stalkers. By any means necessary, convince them not to interfere with our squads. Then, you’ll indicate the search area to our teams. Understood? Alright, stay in touch. We’ll contact you when the squads are ready for operation.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a3_suget_quest_3_svayznoy_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood. Bye.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, hello, savior. Why did you need me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Don’t you have a clue yourself?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Probably to pay a debt. But I have nothing to give you now. I haven’t searched for artifacts much, my main stash with anything valuable is on Agroyantar...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_22">
    <text>I owe you, and now you decided to collect the debt… though I have no idea how I could repay it — no money or artifacts here. All the valuable stuff is in my Agroyantar stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Think about what I might need from you. Money, artifacts — fine, but I don’t need them. Working for me — that you can do. Handle a couple of jobs and consider the debt paid.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_4">
    <text>What exactly do you need from me? And whose interests will these jobs serve? You’re not a simple stalker, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Not simple, like you. Interests? Well… first, yours. Second — the Freedom faction. Third — you’ll decide yourself. Enough chit-chat. Here’s what I need: I recently got info about a large bandit squad here. Local stalkers somehow negotiated with them and let them into their territory. These bandits might be linked to mercenaries, who in turn may be linked to stalkers. The point: these bandits are a major nuisance. That’s all you need to know. And, as you guessed, your task is to eliminate them.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_6">
    <text>These bandits are likely linked to Hasan, the local deputy. Strange, Harold promised to eliminate him. Well, whatever. How many of them are there and where are they located?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Why assume only Hasan could be linked to the bandits? Good questions — I like that approach. But you’re jumping to conclusions. Their squad is no more than ten armed men. Soon they’ll settle near an abandoned local farm. You have a few hours to prepare a proper ambush. I’ll give you stash coordinates — there’s some equipment. Collect a couple of explosives and meet your guests appropriately. After this job, we’ll meet again and discuss more. I’m sure you’ll have questions.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Can’t we avoid questions? Also, I need to negotiate with locals...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_88">
    <text>We don’t need unnecessary questions. Solve this so that none arise. Also, I need to negotiate with locals…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_9">
    <text>About the Clear Sky faction — yes, I’m aware. Working for me won’t take much time. Also, you might reconsider some plans. As you see, my answer raises more questions. Questions always arise, my friend. What matters is whether it makes sense to ask them…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_10">
    <text>You think it won’t make sense?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_11">
    <text>I don’t think. What matters is what you think. Alright, bye. Once you finish the job, contact me again. Then we’ll see if you find meaning or I’ll have to point it out.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_first_dialog_12">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_0">
    <text>And what am I supposed to make of this, you damn fool? I’m dead now. I had a contract with these feathered stalkers. And you, bastard, just set me up...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Calm down. I told you questions would arise. And as I see it, you won’t be able to find the answers on your own...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_2">
    <text>What are you even talking about, damn it? Yes, I’m grateful you saved my life, but now you’re throwing me into the noose yourself... Freedom decided to ignite a conflict with the Clear Sky faction through my hands? For what? And what am I supposed to do now? I was almost done with my work for the feathered ones before you messed it up.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Think, my friend. Your head wasn’t given to you just to wear a gas mask. And I’m not shoving you into the noose — on the contrary, for the second time, I’m pulling you out. You just don’t see it yet. Tell me, do you really think your contract with the Clear Sky faction will be generously paid? Do you think they need extra witnesses to their affairs? You were hired for this task and will be removed as soon as it’s done. The Clear Sky folks don’t yet know their squad was eliminated by you — but they will. For now, we have time...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_4">
    <text>What? You think their contract is fake? There hasn’t been a single case where someone could doubt their reputation.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, you’re right. There hasn’t. And do you realize why? Because there was no one to tell. Stalker, I don’t wander this Zone for nothing. And we don’t run our affairs in vain. There’s always a hidden war between factions. And now you’re caught up to the hilt. So listen to what wise people say, if you don’t want to be out of the game. In it, you either win or die. There’s no third option. So decide what you really need.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Why should I trust you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_66">
    <text>Name at least one reason why I should trust you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_7">
    <text>Um, probably because you have no choice now. You destroyed a combat squad from one of the influential factions in the Zone. And now it’s up to me whether we solve this problem or not. But think about it. Clear Sky sends a free stalker off to God-knows-where to find their group of scientists. Haven’t you wondered what this group is, why they were attacked, and why a Clear Sky squad was sent after them? Or why now a whole combat squad of ruthless thugs is sent after you? By the way, I forgot to ask — how did it go? Did the ambush work?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_8">
    <text>The ambush worked. The scientists were working for Clear Sky. They were attacked by mercenaries, a clan combat squad tried to save them, but failed. Is this version not good enough for you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_9">
    <text>You see, life isn’t that simple. Let’s start with the fact that these stalker scientists never worked for Clear Sky. You’ve been deceived, my friend. Right from the start. I understand you’ll want proof… Go to the abandoned tower. A stalker will be there waiting. He’s not my man, and he shouldn’t know about me. But his info will confirm everything I said. Tell him you were looking for the missing group of scientists on behalf of Freedom. This stalker is well-known in the Zone. You won’t be able not to believe him. At least, I hope so. And I hope you won’t do anything stupid. Hurry. Time is short. Once you understand the situation, you’ll likely want to help me resolve it your way.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_10">
    <text>I hope you’re right...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_88">
    <text>The ambush failed. I screwed up with the explosives. The scientists worked for Clear Sky. They were attacked by mercenaries, a clan combat squad tried to save them, but apparently failed. Is this version not good enough for you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_99">
    <text>You see, life isn’t that simple. Let’s start with the fact that these stalker scientists never worked for Clear Sky. You’ve been deceived, my friend. Right from the start. I understand you’ll want proof… Go to the abandoned tower. A stalker will be there waiting. He’s not my man, and he shouldn’t know about me. But his info will confirm everything I said. Tell him you were looking for the missing group of scientists on behalf of Freedom. This stalker is well-known in the Zone. You won’t be able not to believe him. At least, I hope so. And I hope you won’t do anything stupid. Hurry. Time is short. Once you understand the situation, you’ll likely want to help me resolve it your way.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_suget_quest_4_second_dialog_1010">
    <text>I hope you’re right...</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_0">
    <text>Fang? And what are you doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_1">
    <text>Do we know each other? I recall you, but I don’t recognize you yet. Are you one of the locals?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_2">
    <text>No. I’m Varg, from Agroyantar. Your group, along with Strelok and Ghost, was there some time ago when I was still working for Orest...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_3">
    <text>Now I understand. But why are you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_4">
    <text>I’m looking for the missing group of stalker scientists on behalf of Freedom. They recently appeared here. Some mercenaries or bandits harassed them, and then they came here...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_5">
    <text>What? So we’re working on the same thing. Quite a surprise. How did you track me down? Tell me everything you know.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_6">
    <text>An old friend told me where to find you. I don’t know much. A Clear Sky squad was sent after them, probably to help. But they likely died here. I haven’t found any traces of the scientists yet. What do you know about this?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_7">
    <text>I know more than you, stalker. But I don’t want to fully fill you in yet. Though if you survive, you’ll uncover most of it yourself. Listen. The group of scientists left Yantra and were supposed to meet us, that is, Strelok. We arranged some equipment for their journey to the Zone’s center. We didn’t hand it over in Yantra — too many prying eyes and ears. The meeting was set on neutral ground. But the scientists never made it. Someone got wind of the deal and tried to stop us. And these someones were bastards from Clear Sky. They didn’t want anyone to cross the Burner and would do anything to stop us. They attacked the scientists, but something went wrong. Most of the group died, but those carrying the equipment escaped. The feathered ones aren’t great fighters and didn’t hire mercenaries. A Clear Sky combat squad was sent to find and destroy the remaining scientists and their equipment at all costs...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_8">
    <text>Wow, what a twist. I had info that the scientists actually worked for Clear Sky and that a squad was sent to help them...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_9">
    <text>Ha, that’s all lies. Trust me. Clear Sky are the ones responsible. They’d dig up the entire Zone to find the scientists’ equipment. But it’s already out of their reach. I recently took it and hid it safely. So Clear Sky ends up with nothing. I’m sorry we couldn’t get the scientists out. The feathered ones will kill them when they find them. But we must accept this for the greater good and stalker cause. Perhaps Freedom or Duty will reach them first.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_10">
    <text>And you’re not afraid to tell me all this?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_1010">
    <text>I don’t understand why you’re telling me all this.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_11">
    <text>What should I fear? The fate of the scientists no longer concerns me. They did their part — delivered the equipment. The feathered ones won’t get it anyway. Even if you’re their spy, it benefits me — you can’t kill me, and if you pass on the info I gave you, it gives the scientists a chance. Also, I might have lied to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_12">
    <text>Damn, this is complicated. What mess am I in... And yet I lied to you, Fang. I actually worked — and still work — for Clear Sky. They hired me to find the stalker scientists and their missing squad. Recently, Freedom people approached me. They hinted that Clear Sky would use me and kill me after the job. I didn’t believe it at first, but now you’ve fully confirmed it. Moreover, Freedom set it up so I killed several Clear Sky members I was supposed to work with. So I’m trapped in the gears, in a web of lies with no escape.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_13">
    <text>Yeah, stalker. Quite the story… Your situation is grim. You can’t return to the feathered ones — they’ll find out you killed their people. Freedom set you up… I wouldn’t trust them after this. And you lied to me at first too. Kid, this is a game. A dangerous game where you either survive or die. No third option.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_14">
    <text>I’ve heard this somewhere before...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_1414">
    <text>Familiar words you speak...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_15">
    <text>By the way, we ended up here and were indirectly connected earlier. Remember that stalker Vazgen? You delivered a document package from him to a stash. Well, I’m the one who took it and forwarded it to the bandits. That caused big problems for Clear Sky. Soon, dozens of renegades will flood the swamps. This might help us and Strelok and distract them while we prepare our mission. And here’s my advice — try to escape or flee to Duty. Not optimal, but at least they don’t betray their own. If Freedom offers reasonable cooperation, why not? They didn’t kill you. The main thing — you didn’t side with the feathered freaks. And that should be your main focus now. Decide for yourself. We can’t take you with us — we have our own path.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_16">
    <text>One Freedom member saved my life. Maybe the same person you worked with. I’ll try to escape first. If that fails, we’ll see.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_17">
    <text>Exactly. If you can’t escape, go to Freedom without hesitation. Alright, take care. And forget everything we discussed.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_stalker_fang_dialog_18">
    <text>Alright. Good luck to your group. Perhaps you’re the ones who will change the Zone’s history forever.</text>
</string>

	
	<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_0">
    <text>I don’t even know where to start. Fang completely turned my understanding of what’s happening upside down.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_1">
    <text>Upside down enough that you tried to run?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_2">
    <text>But you didn’t run...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_22">
    <text>After all, I’m still here...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_3">
    <text>Correct. The veil of lies that had clouded your eyes didn’t prevent you from thinking clearly. Had you ignored my message, you would already be dead.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_4">
    <text>I understand that. Alright, since we’re here — I’m still of use to you and you’re not going to kill me just yet. What should I do now in light of recent events? As I understand it, our main concern is the Clear Sky faction?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_5">
    <text>You understand correctly. Clear Sky is a big problem, and we need to deal with it. Officially, I represent Freedom. Unofficially — you’ll find out when the time comes. Or maybe not. That’s not important now. What matters is that you will work for me for the time being. You’ve proven yourself here — you’re smart and capable of manipulating faction affairs. I’ve been watching you for a long time — and you might have observed my actions, even without realizing it was me involved. So, here’s what we need to do. First, eliminate the Clear Sky members who came here after the stalker scientists. You’ve already taken out one group, but there are still informants and a major combat squad remaining. Second, we need to take care of the scientists themselves.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_6">
    <text>What exactly do you propose regarding the scientists?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_66">
    <text>How do you suggest we handle the scientists?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_7">
    <text>There are two options here. Either we eliminate them, or we use them further in our play against Clear Sky. Most likely we’ll need to eliminate them. Extracting them from here would be difficult. They’ve already completed their main task — delivering the equipment to Strelok’s group.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_8">
    <text>Your organization supports Strelok’s group?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_88">
    <text>Why does your organization support Strelok’s group?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_888">
    <text>What benefit do you gain from supporting Strelok and his stalkers?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_9">
    <text>Let’s say our organization currently benefits from Strelok and his team. They’re trying to penetrate the Zone’s center, where no normal human has stepped for a long time. Fine, let them try. As long as they remain a thorn in Clear Sky’s side, we’ll play hand in hand with them.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_10">
    <text>You said you’ve been watching me for a long time. And that you were involved in many of the events here...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_11">
    <text>Correct. I was the missing Freedom scout you tried to find upon arrival. At the same time, I was also an informant for Duty. In this way, I removed unnecessary participants from the game — not permanently, but for a time. And that time, it was you acting through my hands, even if you didn’t realize it. I also sabotaged one of the stalkers’ radio stations, nudged Hasan to cooperate with mercenaries, persuaded Vazgen to prepare significant evidence against Clear Sky. Much more, my friend. A big chess game started here, likely leading to a major clan war. As grim as it sounds, we need this war. And you have an important role in it, if you continue working as you do now.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_12">
    <text>Why did you send the renegades to the swamps? I don’t think it was just to cause trouble for Clear Sky.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_13">
    <text>Correct. I had much more far-reaching plans. We’ll talk about that later. For now, you need to finish things here. Go to the designated area first. There you’ll kill the Clear Sky agent. You’ve met him here before. Then go to the stalkers’ base. Find their radio operator and tell him the time for Operation “Retribution” has come. He’ll understand. That’s a signal for contacting the feathered squad. Afterwards, you eliminate them. Lastly… The group of scientists still alive is too large — six people. I’ll take three and lead them away, explaining why later. You’ll enter their hideout and eliminate the rest. Understood?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_1_dialog_14">
    <text>Understood. I’m on my way.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b1_radist_quest_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Valar Morghulis... Have you already forgotten me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_radist_quest_final_dialog_1">
    <text>Same to you. I thought you had decided to leave these lands. And you did.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_radist_quest_final_dialog_2">
    <text>I thought so too, but circumstances turned out differently... I have something for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_radist_quest_final_dialog_22">
    <text>Circumstances, my friend. You know they’re not always on our side. By the way, I have something for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_radist_quest_final_dialog_3">
    <text>What exactly?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_radist_quest_final_dialog_4">
    <text>A mutual friend asked me to pass along that the time for Operation “Retribution” has come. You understand what I mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_radist_quest_final_dialog_5">
    <text>Perfectly… When you see our mutual friend, tell him everything was executed perfectly.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_radist_quest_final_dialog_6">
    <text>Good. Farewell.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_0">
    <text>It’s done. The Clear Sky members who came here — all eliminated. Their informant, the combat squad — all gone. The scientists you didn’t extract have also been successfully dealt with.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_1">
    <text>Excellent. This round has ended in our favor for now. The feathered got what was coming, Strelok’s group is ready to head to the center for the Burner. Duty and Freedom each lost a squad, temporarily removing them from play. Local stalkers — we prevented the faction from collapsing, that’s also good. So what next? Now we need to play the next round, with much higher stakes.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_2">
    <text>So you’re not a Freedom member? Won’t you tell me who you really are?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_22">
    <text>Clearly not Freedom. Will you stop playing riddles and tell me who you work for?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_3">
    <text>Ah, my friend, I wouldn’t advise asking that again. Let’s say — I am someone who cares about what happens in this world...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_4">
    <text>Fine. As you wish. You saved my life, and I’m grateful for that. What happened to the scientists you extracted from here?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_5">
    <text>They will be taken care of properly. A mercenary agreed to escort them to safety. By the way, I’ll tell you a bit about my plans.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_6">
    <text>I’m listening carefully...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_66">
    <text>I’m listening...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_7">
    <text>The mercenary leading the remaining scientists isn’t an ordinary person. You share some similarities with him. His name is Scar. Perhaps you’ve heard the name. Like you, he doesn’t yet realize how or why he will be used in the upcoming game. But one day, he will play a key role. For now, it’s important that he reaches the swamps as quickly as possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_8">
    <text>What is he supposed to do in the swamps, especially with scientists that Clear Sky will just kill?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_9">
    <text>Who said the feathered will recognize whether those scientists are the right ones? Forget about the scientists entirely. They will all die. Once Scar reaches the swamps, there will be a strong and sudden emission. No one will survive except him. Don’t be surprised. Remember the scout injured by the psi-wave in the village? That was also my doing. Scar will end up with Clear Sky. He will be recruited, just like you were once. Lebedev’s goal will be the same — stop Strelok from reaching Pripyat and the Chernobyl NPP. And Scar will carry out their will. Initially, they’ll likely order him to clear the swamps of renegades you sent, then we’ll see… The important thing is, he will be one of them.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_10">
    <text>And then? He starts working for the feathered, tracking Strelok’s group. How does that benefit us?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_11">
    <text>Our benefit is that we’ll know the plans of both Clear Sky and Strelok’s group. Remember — our goal in the next round is to destroy Clear Sky completely. We’ll make Scar lure them out of their lair and eliminate them. Some we’ll kill, some we might spare and force to work for us. That doesn’t matter. The important thing is their faction must cease to exist. And that’s just one part of the plan.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_12">
    <text>Fine, and what’s my role?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_1212">
    <text>And what role is assigned to me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_13">
    <text>It’s simple, my friend. We’ll set the war in motion… Or rather, we’ll nudge the factions into action. New territories will open, clans will go there for new artifacts. Their patrons will try to negotiate, dividing spheres of influence. We’ll just add some spice… First, we deal with Duty and Freedom. That will be easiest. Especially since you’ve already taken the first steps here...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_1_suget_quest_final_2_dialog_14">
    <text>Fine. You’ve shown me another path for a deceived man. You can count on me — I won’t stray. But I didn’t say you’d be walking alongside me...</text>
</string>

	
	<!-- Anubis – Quest 1, Part 1 -->
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_anubis_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings. You wanted to see me? What happened and why do you need me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_anubis_dialog_1">
    <text>And my respects to you, old friend. It's not proper to forget who owes whom, and you owe me quite a lot — namely, your life. I called you here so that you could repay that debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_anubis_dialog_2">
    <text>Ask for whatever you wish — artifacts, money. I’ll give it. But right now I need to finish a task I committed to before our meeting. I’ll earn a little cash, so I can settle my debt to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_anubis_dialog_3">
    <text>Always about money. I don’t need your money. I need you to work for me. And breaking your contract with the Clear Sky faction will be the first thing you do for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_anubis_dialog_4">
    <text>What? I don’t understand.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_anubis_dialog_44">
    <text>Don’t understand? What do you mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_anubis_dialog_5">
    <text>Exactly what you heard. You will break your contract with the Feathered Stalkers while it’s not too late. You don’t know the whole truth, my friend. I will reveal it to you, and you must believe it. Your life depends on it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_anubis_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright, I’m listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_anubis_dialog_7">
    <text>Clear Sky hired you to find the missing group of scientists and their search team. But you never asked yourself who attacked these scientists and why a Clear Sky squad was sent after them. I’ll tell you — it was Clear Sky themselves. The so-called search team was actually a punitive unit tasked with tracking down the surviving scientists and eliminating them. They deceived you, Varg. You would find the scientists, report back to Clear Sky, and then be killed along with them.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_anubis_dialog_8">
    <text>These are terrible things you say. I don’t believe you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_anubis_dialog_88">
    <text>Complete nonsense. I don’t trust your words.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_anubis_dialog_9">
    <text>Your choice, Varg. Go meet your employers. They are expecting you. But think — would I have saved your life back then if I intended to lie to you now? Either way, if you change your mind — I’ll be nearby.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_anubis_dialog_10">
    <text>We’ll see.</text>
</string>

<!-- Svayznoy – Quest 1 -->
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_svayznoy_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello. Hasan said you’d be waiting. Why the delay in contact?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_svayznoy_dialog_1">
    <text>Why contact you before you found anything? Now that you have news — speak. We’ll pay you and go our separate ways.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_svayznoy_dialog_2">
    <text>Pay me? Already? The scientists haven’t even been found yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_svayznoy_dialog_22">
    <text>Why suddenly be so generous if the contract isn’t finished? The scientists aren’t found.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_svayznoy_dialog_3">
    <text>So should we leave? Why contact us then? Speak — what have you discovered?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_svayznoy_dialog_4">
    <text>I found that the scientists did reach territory controlled by local stalkers. Your squad followed but most likely perished. Several pieces of evidence confirm this. The bodies of deceased Clear Sky members were found. As for the scientists, an approximate location is determined. We can head there directly.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_svayznoy_dialog_5">
    <text>Good. Not much, but it’s something.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_svayznoy_dialog_6">
    <text>It seemed to me that the news of the area to search for your hideout isn’t exactly news anymore?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_svayznoy_dialog_7">
    <text>Right. This isn’t news. So I think we no longer need your services. You did well and earned your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_svayznoy_dialog_8">
    <text>One question — why, knowing exactly where to search, did you act only now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_svayznoy_dialog_88">
    <text>And why, knowing where they can be found, did you act only now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_svayznoy_dialog_9">
    <text>Ah, you’re sharp... We needed to make sure you would complete what remained, cover where needed, and then our need for you would vanish... Sorry, but that’s the truth. Best regards from Hasan...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_1_svayznoy_dialog_10">
    <text>Bastards...</text>
</string>

<!-- Anubis – Quest 2 -->
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_0">
    <text>You were right. Clear Sky deceived me and tried to kill me. And Hasan too...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_1">
    <text>What did I say? But you didn’t want to listen. No matter — you’re alive and can fix things. Your main mistake wasn’t trusting the Feathered, but interfering in the local stalker group’s internal conflict on the wrong side. Hasan is vile. You knew what he did and still chose to support him. He told Clear Sky everything you should have told. Your services became redundant and they decided to eliminate you before the scientists were even found. However, Hasan didn’t issue a direct order to kill you. So he influenced your fate indirectly. The same cannot be said about the faction’s fate. Soon he will kill Harold, if he hasn’t already, and will exert full control. We’ll deal with that later.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_2">
    <text>What do you suggest?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_22">
    <text>And how should we act in this case?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_3">
    <text>We must act, my friend. The situation can still be turned in our favor, despite your misstep.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_4">
    <text>Who do you really work for, and why did Clear Sky want to kill those scientists?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_5">
    <text>Officially, I work for Freedom. That’s enough for now. Unofficially, I work for a far more powerful organization. Consider yourself part of it. Refusing isn’t an option. For Clear Sky you are an enemy, for Freedom you will also be an enemy, as with Duty. Remember your arrival here — I was the Freedom scout you were looking for, and also an informant for Duty. I orchestrated their attack on Freedom. You already dealt with Duty. I can feed this info where needed. So, the choice is yours. I’m not scaring you — I want another skilled ally. You’ve proven yourself investigating. I’ve been watching your progress. The corpse for the mercs, the wounded psionic scout, the broken radio station — that’s just some of my work. So...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_6">
    <text>I’ve made my choice. I’m with you. But why did the Feathered need to kill the scientists?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_7">
    <text>Here’s the explanation. You know stalkers like Strelok, Fang, and Ghost? They’re near-legendary in the Zone. They could become greater when they execute their plan through the Exterminator to Pripyat and Chernobyl NPP. These scientists were to provide them equipment. But Strelok’s journey has enemies. Clear Sky is among them. They attacked the scientists to prevent the delivery. Something went wrong, and they didn’t kill them all. Some escaped here. They sent punitive units after them, but those perished. That’s the whole story.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_8">
    <text>No one has ever crossed the Exterminator.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_88">
    <text>But that’s impossible. No one has ever passed through the Exterminator.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_9">
    <text>Just because no one has yet doesn’t mean it’s impossible. Our organization benefits if Strelok and his team succeed. They’re also a thorn for our enemies. Enough talk — later I’ll answer your other questions. For now, here’s the plan: I know where the Feathered squad is stationed. Attacking them directly would be foolish. You go to the base, find Hasan, and tell him the mercs he worked with were killed by Clear Sky. He’ll send them to the village. Then they’ll handle it. You show up afterward to deal with the survivors. I’ll cover traces at the base and decide what to do with the scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_10">
    <text>What’s wrong with the faction base?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_11">
    <text>Hasan will be in charge now. That’s the problem. You’ve also been too exposed there — not good for upcoming operations. We’ll have to remove them.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_anubis_dialog_12">
    <text>Understood. I’ll do everything.</text>
</string>

	<!-- Zam – Quest 2 -->
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_zam_dialog_0">
    <text>Valar Morghulis. Thought you’d never see me again? Hoping Clear Sky would kill me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_zam_dialog_1">
    <text>What are you talking about? You’re not that easy to kill, stalker. And I see — the Feathered have stopped being your friends. Unexpected, huh? What brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_zam_dialog_2">
    <text>But they probably won’t be your friends either. I’ve learned something here that you’ll find interesting. Two mercenaries you were dealing with were recently killed. Don’t ask how I know — I just do. They were killed by Clear Sky, avenging the poor guy who was torn apart by the Blues and passed off as one of their own. The squad responsible stopped in the village today...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_zam_dialog_3">
    <text>Ha. And you think I’ll believe that? Planning to deal with your former friends with my own hands? No way, stalker...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_zam_dialog_4">
    <text>Tell me, what will your partners do when they learn you know why their men died but did nothing? They’ll likely be upset and question all agreements. Doing business with someone who keeps critical info secret — that’s bad, right? Not good, Hasan.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_zam_dialog_5">
    <text>I understand your hint. Fine, I’ll tell my mercenary friends that Clear Sky occupied the village. They’ll take care of them. How many times have you tried to make me look foolish? Be careful, stalker — my patience isn’t endless. Soon Harold will be gone, and no one will save you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_2_suget_quest_2_zam_dialog_6">
    <text>Don’t worry. That was the last time. I’m sure of it. Farewell.</text>
</string>

<!-- Anubis – Quest Final -->
<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_suget_quest_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Everything was done as you commanded. Mercenaries and Clear Sky members are dead. The stalker base destroyed, local clan gone. The scientists in the bunker are dead too. Now tell me — what was the point of this madness?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_suget_quest_final_dialog_1">
    <text>For our common good. Clear Sky deceived you and used you in their selfish plans, but they failed. Ours are now underway. While you dealt with Clear Sky, I extracted some scientists and handed them to a mercenary named Scar. He’ll lead three scientists to the Swamps, to the Clear Sky base. Allegedly, to pass them through Agroyantar. Those we no longer need will die along the way. The mercenary will infiltrate the Feathered as a Trojan horse.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_suget_quest_final_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood. You want to plant your man to undermine the faction internally, but wouldn’t sending renegades to the Swamps do it better?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_suget_quest_final_dialog_3">
    <text>Luring the renegades from their lair was a wise move with far-reaching consequences. They’ll weaken the Feathered for a time, but not destroy them. Relying on mere thieves is foolish — expendable material. Scar will likely first deal with renegades, then pursue Strelok’s group. Clear Sky must stop Strelok, and we must stop Clear Sky. We’ll exploit their mutual weaknesses.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_suget_quest_final_dialog_4">
    <text>What will my role be?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_suget_quest_final_dialog_44">
    <text>What will I need to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_suget_quest_final_dialog_5">
    <text>You’ll go with me. Before Scar reaches the Swamps, we’ll push the factions into a more overt war. You’ve proven yourself a skilled agent and can infiltrate Duty or Freedom ranks. Starting the conflict will be easy.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_suget_quest_final_dialog_6">
    <text>Why is this necessary?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_suget_quest_final_dialog_66">
    <text>And why exactly?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_suget_quest_final_dialog_7">
    <text>The Zone needs a shake-up. Many clans have gained power and influence, not all working for our organization. They need weakening.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_suget_quest_final_dialog_8">
    <text>You’re not telling everything...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_suget_quest_final_dialog_9">
    <text>Of course. But you don’t need to worry too much. I’ve briefed you on our plan. Other clans — don’t worry, they’ll clash among themselves. The main task — eliminate Clear Sky. Completely.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_suget_quest_final_dialog_10">
    <text>Understood… You can count on me. I guess we should leave this place.</text>
</string>

<!-- Patrol BES -->
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_bes_dialog_0">
    <text>Don’t you get tired of standing here all day?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_bes_dialog_1">
    <text>Heh, my friend, everyone in the clan has their job. Mine is to stand and guard the base from unwanted guests like you… If you have nothing concrete, better go your way and don’t interfere.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_bes_dialog_2">
    <text>Take it easy. I’m not from here, don’t know your rules. Just arrived. What can you tell me about this place?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_bes_dialog_3">
    <text>Stalker rules are the same everywhere. You’re not a rookie, and I see through any pretense. You didn’t come here just for money or artifacts. So I warn you — don’t cause trouble. If you do, you won’t live long.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_bes_dialog_4">
    <text>I’ve heard this before. Don’t threaten people without reason. They didn’t insult you. Though, you could tell a weary traveler something interesting — maybe a recent rumor or event.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_bes_dialog_5">
    <text>Did I threaten you? Call me friend again — I’ll slit your throat. That’s a threat. Notice the difference?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_bes_dialog_6">
    <text>More than enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_bes_dialog_66">
    <text>I think so.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_bes_dialog_7">
    <text>Good. Rarely come understanding people. Recently two arrived — from Duty and Freedom. Their squads found the remains nearby. Who convinced them — nobody knows. Security’s on edge. Better go and don’t ask questions.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_bes_dialog_8">
    <text>Heard anything else interesting besides Freedom-Duty clashes?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_bes_dialog_9">
    <text>You’re persistent. Fine, a story from wandering Military stalkers: a scientist’s corpse was found in the forests. How it got there — unknown. From the body, stalkers took a decent protective suit and approached dangerous anomalies. One anomaly held an artifact worth nearly half a million. What happened after — unknown. Those who found it disappeared. The stash they might have left is unfound. Running the forests alone? No takers. Likely the artifact’s in someone powerful’s hands now.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_bes_dialog_10">
    <text>Well, an informative chat. Pure nonsense, if not for the scientist’s corpse… Alright, I’m leaving. Good luck.</text>
</string>

	
	<!-- Patrol CEH -->
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey there. Why are you sitting around, slacking off? I’m Varg, by the way, just arrived here recently.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_1">
    <text>Call me Chekh. Just Chekh. I just finished my shift and took a seat to rest. Also, the boss gave me a task different from simple guard duty.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_2">
    <text>Got it. You been here long? And who do the patrols report to in the clan? Thinking about joining you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_3">
    <text>I’ve only been here a couple of weeks. Came on business, but got delayed. Needed work that’s not too messy. Harold recruits people for base security personally, so you can’t just walk in. Only through someone, or for a specific reason… Varg, you ask too many questions, drawing unwanted attention. Not professional, colleague.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_4">
    <text>Colleague? How did you know that…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_5">
    <text>Relax. This place is full of agents and people of different people. We’re all connected, so you can speak more openly than you originally intended. I assume your questions would have been about the fate of the missing Clear Sky squad and stalker scientists they were following? Locals know a bit about that. And they have contacts to your employers. But they won’t lift a finger without benefit. If you deliver them a benefit, they’ll hand you everything on a silver platter. Be careful. You’re watched not only by your employers and locals, but also by other clans. I can share more detailed info for a service. Your choice. I need help placing special equipment. Will you help me install a signal jammer or a radar blocker? So, ready for closer cooperation?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_6">
    <text>Why help me out of any love for mankind? Well, I lose nothing. Alright, I’ll help with the signal jammer. But I need details. And how do I know you’re not one of those representatives?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_7">
    <text>From nowhere. Believe if you want, don’t if you don’t. Simple. But take advice — don’t blindly trust some faction members you meet. Their motives aren’t always selfless. Especially some from Freedom. About the jammer — I need to secure the area for confidential meetings of some agents on the farm. The device is disguised as an old crate. Place it and return.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright, got it. You work for Duty?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_888">
    <text>So you work for the Duty faction?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_9">
    <text>No, I don’t. You won’t know who I work for until I choose to tell. For now, I just want to protect you from the web of a very skilled spider. He’s here now disguised as a Freedom member.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_10">
    <text>Even so — I don’t care. My business is with Clear Sky. The rest doesn’t concern me. Well, now it does — specifically the info you’re willing to share.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_11">
    <text>As you wish. But note, later may be too late.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_12">
    <text>Noted…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_66">
    <text>How do I know you’re not one of those representatives? Well, I lose nothing. Alright, I’ll help with the blocker — we’ll see. But I need details.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_77">
    <text>From nowhere. Believe or not. Simple. But take advice — don’t blindly trust faction members you meet. Their motives aren’t always selfless. Especially some Freedom members. About the blocker — someone might sabotage locals during clan negotiations. Secure the place against remote charges. The device is disguised as a wooden crate. Go to the village, place it in the attic, return.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_88">
    <text>Alright, now I get it. You work for Duty?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_99">
    <text>No, I don’t. You won’t know who I work for until I choose. For now, I just want to protect you from a very skilled spider, disguised as a Freedom member here.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_1010">
    <text>Even so — I don’t care. My business is Clear Sky. The rest doesn’t concern me. Well, now it does — the info you’re willing to share.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_1111">
    <text>As you wish. But remember, later may be too late.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_p1_patrol_ceh_dialog_1212">
    <text>Noted, farewell…</text>
</string>

<!-- CEH Quest 1 – Second Dialog -->
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_1_second_dialog_0">
    <text>I completed your task. The signal jammer is installed. Right after, a group of mercenaries attacked me. I neutralized the Blues, and it worries me. I don’t want to make the syndicate my enemy. So who did I actually help? Who are you, Chekh?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_1_second_dialog_1">
    <text>You did help, even without knowing who. I can assure you — no harm comes from it. Consider it a good deed, protecting good people from trouble. Mercenaries attacked? If you killed them, no traces remain — I’ll take care of that.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_1_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright, but let’s talk about the cost of this good deed. And your calmness surprises me. Don’t you see the syndicate as a serious threat?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_1_second_dialog_3">
    <text>You didn’t see Duty as a problem when killing those recon units, did you? Forget the mercenaries. About your payment — what have you heard about the Sin faction?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_1_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Nothing much. A clan of fanatic maniacs in the Dark Valley area. Mix of bandits and Monolith. What does that have to do with this?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_1_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Outdated info, my friend. The Sin clan everyone knew no longer exists. Survivors are under powerful mentors. Reorganized, joined by top specialists. Experts in reconnaissance and sabotage. Sin now is a group of elite undercover agents across the Zone. Smart, cunning, ruthless, deadly. Some may have extraordinary psi-abilities. No base, no insignias. Can be among Duty, Freedom, or loners. Secretly funded, influential. Conduct covert ops, pit clans against each other, intercept artifact shipments, block arms supply. Pros. Few know them, and those who do stay quiet. One agent may currently be here undercover as a Duty or Freedom member. Sin emissaries recruit experienced stalkers and agents from other factions expertly.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_1_second_dialog_6">
    <text>That’s quite info. Useful, but not really relevant to my interests or work.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_1_second_dialog_66">
    <text>Noted, but it doesn’t match my current interests.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_1_second_dialog_667">
    <text>Not sure this info helps me, but thanks anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_1_second_dialog_7">
    <text>Premature conclusions, my friend. Anyway, I warned you. Don’t become their next victim. Who knows where your investigation leads or who stands in your way. But you can rely on me. Also, help the local radio operator and hunter if needed — they’re good people.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_1_second_dialog_8">
    <text>Noted. Hopefully, I won’t need your help.</text>
</string>

	
	<!-- CEH Quest 2 – Second Dialog -->
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_2_second_dialog_0">
    <text>I completed your task. The signal blocker is installed. Right after, a group of controlled mutants attacked me. I doubt that’s a coincidence. So who did I actually help? Who are you, Chekh?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_2_second_dialog_1">
    <text>You did help, even without knowing who. I can assure you — no harm comes from it. Consider it a good deed, protecting good people from trouble. Mutants attacked you? And why do you think they were controlled?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_2_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Just seemed that way, and I rarely make mistakes. Now, let’s talk about the cost of this good deed. Don’t you see the psionic or controller as a serious threat?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_2_second_dialog_3">
    <text>You didn’t see Duty as a problem when killing their recon squads, did you? The psionic, if it’s really him, is a problem — but we’ll get to that. Now, about your payment. What have you heard about the Sin faction?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_2_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Nothing special. A clan of fanatic maniacs in the Dark Valley area. Mix of bandits and Monolith. How is that relevant?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_2_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Outdated info, my friend. The Sin clan everyone knew no longer exists. Survivors were taken under the wing of very influential people. Reorganized, joined by top specialists from the mainland. Experts in reconnaissance and sabotage. Sin now is a group of elite undercover agents across the Zone. Smart, cunning, ruthless, deadly. Some may have extraordinary psi-abilities. No base, no insignias. Can be among Duty, Freedom, or loners. Powerful backers, strong financing, growing influence. Conduct covert ops, pit clans against each other, intercept artifact shipments, block weapons supply. Pros. Few know them, those who do keep quiet. One agent may currently be here undercover as a Duty or Freedom member. Sin emissaries recruit experienced stalkers and agents from other factions masterfully.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_2_second_dialog_6">
    <text>That’s quite a lot. Useful knowledge, but not really relevant to my interests or work.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_2_second_dialog_66">
    <text>Noted, but this info doesn’t match my current interests.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_2_second_dialog_667">
    <text>Not sure this info will help me in my work, but thanks anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_2_second_dialog_7">
    <text>Premature conclusions, my friend. Anyway, I warned you. Don’t become their next victim. Who knows where your investigation leads or who stands in your way. But you can rely on me. Also, help the local radio operator and hunter if needed — they seem solid and you never know what might happen.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_ceh_quest_2_second_dialog_8">
    <text>Noted. Hopefully, I won’t need your help.</text>
</string>

<!-- Trader Flyaga Under Quest -->
<string id="topi_b10_trader_flyaga_under_quest_dialog_0">
    <text>My friend, I need help. A sip of water, if you please. I’ll pay you later.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b10_trader_flyaga_under_quest_dialog_1">
    <text>Looks like you’ve been through a lot — begging for a sip of water. Alright, we’re not beasts and we understand. Here, take the flask. Forget about payment. Consider it a goodwill gesture for future deals.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b10_trader_flyaga_under_quest_dialog_2">
    <text>And they will happen soon, my friend. I won’t forget your generosity.</text>
</string>

<!-- Zmeelov – Chimera Quest -->
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Listen, friend. What other work can you offer me? Surely there are unresolved problems here.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, there is one big problem, maybe more. The job is risky, and it must be done at night, which increases the danger. Come around three at night and we’ll sort it out.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_first_dialog_102">
    <text>Alright. I’ll be there at the designated time.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_first_dialog_101">
    <text>Time seems suitable. I’m ready to hear the details. What’s the matter?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_first_dialog_11">
    <text>We have uninvited nocturnal creatures — extremely dangerous and deadly. Several scavenger groups have perished. One hunter tracked them and reported them as chimeras. We need urgent action. Hunters are few, so I’d be glad if you help. You proved capable.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_first_dialog_22">
    <text>I’ll pass for now. Chimera is too dangerous. Hard to handle alone.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright, I agree. But I need preparation. Chimeras are no joke. I once killed one in Yantra. Luck mattered more than skill.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_first_dialog_3">
    <text>No time to prepare. Take a strong gun and plenty of grenades. My man is already waiting. He tracked a creature near the farm. Go there ASAP.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_first_dialog_4">
    <text>So I’ll have a partner?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_first_dialog_44">
    <text>Your man? What do you mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_first_dialog_5">
    <text>You’ll work with a partner. No discussion. Yakut — experienced hunter. Together you have a chance to kill it and survive. Or do you need an example of who they’ve eaten? Enough. Go now. Don’t risk the hunter too.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood. We’ll handle it as best we can.</text>
</string>

<!-- Hunter – Chimera Quest -->
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_first_dialog_0">
    <text>I’m from Zmeelov. So we’ll work together?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Looks like it. Couldn’t that dumb bastard find someone better than you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Apparently not. What now? Did you track the creature?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_first_dialog_3">
    <text>One tried before. I didn’t want to follow them to the afterlife. I observed. Two chimeras here. One is wounded, probably shot by our colleague before dying. Second is young.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Two creatures. This complicates things. How do we proceed?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_first_dialog_44">
    <text>Still two. And that’s a big problem. What’s our plan then?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_first_dialog_5">
    <text>First, secure the farm. I spotted the chimera in the forest behind it. We’ll handle it from there.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>

<!-- Hunter – Chimera Second Dialog -->
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_second_dialog_0">
    <text>We’re here. What’s next?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_second_dialog_1">
    <text>We’ll split up. You handle the wounded one, I’ll deal with the other. Plan’s not perfect, but we have no choice.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Are you sure there were only two?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_second_dialog_22">
    <text>I hope you were sure there were only two.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, absolutely. Don’t worry about these creatures. If you’ve dealt with them before, you’ll manage. Something else concerns me.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_second_dialog_4">
    <text>What? Don’t beat around the bush. Did you discover anything while observing the chimeras?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Not your concern. Your task is the chimera. Saw a strange figure in a cloak, didn’t seem fully human. Anyway, deal with your chimera and return. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_hunter_quest_himera_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes, understood. Good luck.</text>
</string>

	
<!-- Zmeelov – Chimera Quest Second Dialog -->
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Zmeelov, I killed the chimera. But there were complications.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_second_dialog_1">
    <text>What? What complications? Couldn’t you handle those nocturnal predators? Where’s Yakut?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_second_dialog_2">
    <text>He disappeared. How did you know there were multiple chimeras?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_second_dialog_3">
    <text>I’m asking the questions here. What do you mean disappeared? Are you insane? All competent hunters in the last two days have died. And you’re standing here trying to act all casual? Tell me what happened.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Yakut determined there were two chimeras. One was wounded. He suggested splitting up. I was to deal with the wounded one, Yakut took the healthy one. I handled my creature and returned to the meeting spot. Yakut wasn’t there. No sounds of shooting, fighting, or anything. No trace of the second chimera either. Whether it existed is only Yakut’s assumption. I didn’t risk searching alone at night and returned to base. Yakut disappeared — fact. Alive or dead, I won’t tell. But I completed my task. The chimera is dead.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_second_dialog_5">
    <text>The chimera is dead, that’s good. Consider the job done. But Yakut’s disappearance or death is concerning. The clan is losing experienced hunters, and we can’t replace them. We’ll have to plead with superiors to transfer some duties to scouts. But that’s not the scariest part. The unknown worries me. Yakut couldn’t just die to some stinking chimera. Even if it was there, he would have handled it. So it was something else. Did you notice anything suspicious?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Yakut mentioned a cloaked figure he saw in the area, but it didn’t look like a controller.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_second_dialog_66">
    <text>Yakut said something about a person in a cloak. And he wasn’t a controller.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_second_dialog_7">
    <text>A cloaked figure, you say? There’s a cemetery nearby. Not a friendly one. Who knows what horrors have risen from those graves. Compared to that, chimeras are harmless. But that’s just one theory. Alright, Varg. You did your job, now let the others work. Scouts will sweep the area. Farewell.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a5_zmeelov_quest_himera_second_dialog_8">
    <text>Farewell.</text>
</string>

<!-- Artefacter Quest – Selezcia First Dialog -->
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello. Your leadership said you can be trusted, and I can even approach you for extra work. Is that right?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that’s correct. Listen, Varg. It may sound silly, but believe me — I had nothing to do with the attack on you. I have no idea how they found out you’d be in that area.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright, forget about that attack. If your leadership vouches for you, then so be it. Now, what work can you offer me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Heard about artifact selection? If not, briefly: it changes their properties from negative to positive, or enhances existing traits. Now the task: I have several artifact samples for you to perform selection near an anomalous field. Not hard, but risky. High chance of getting fried. Will you take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_first_dialog_44">
    <text>No, I’ll pass. Don’t feel like diving into anomalies again.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, I agree. Now more details. Which anomalous field will I enter?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_first_dialog_5">
    <text>During your previous mission, you collected anomaly scanners. Analyzing results led to important conclusions. Remember the malachite spherical formations in the forest?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes, I remember those anomalies.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_first_dialog_66">
    <text>Of course I remember. First time seeing such things here.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Good. These anomalies have a strange field ideal for selection. Each of the three has a unique field. Here are three artifact samples and special equipment. Go to each anomaly and perform selection on one artifact in its field. Return when done. Clear?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Understood. I’ll do it.</text>
</string>

<!-- Artefacter Quest – Selezcia Second Dialog -->
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Task complete. Selection performed on all three artifact samples.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Good. Well done handling this task. Give me the artifact samples and equipment.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Here. Did you doubt I could handle it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Not really. I doubted how dangerous the anomalies might be while you were inside. These malachite formations are little studied.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_second_dialog_4">
    <text>So I was a guinea pig as well?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_second_dialog_44">
    <text>You used me as a test subject?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_second_dialog_5">
    <text>I didn’t say that. You drew that conclusion yourself. Either way, you completed the task. We’ll study the artifacts, and if selection samples have better traits, their value — and the fee for field access — will increase greatly. But that’s another story. You got your share. Farewell.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefacter_quest_seleczia_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright. Farewell.</text>
</string>

<!-- Radist Angel First Dialog -->
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello. Why do you need me? What happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Remember helping me set up Credo radiolocators? One detected something unusual. We sent a scout team there, but they went silent.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_first_dialog_22">
    <text>Oh no, my friend. Sorry, but I won’t run around finding out what happened to your scouts. Handle it yourselves. I helped place the systems, that’s enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_first_dialog_2">
    <text>What exactly did the radiolocator detect?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Hard to say. Something large, but not a mutant. Too static. Probably a new anomaly. I might be wrong. Adjustments to these radiolocators are ongoing. I changed a lot since you last worked with them.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Let’s skip the technical details this time. Where did this happen?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_first_dialog_44">
    <text>Be specific. Where exactly?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Not far from the village. The team got there quickly, and we lost contact immediately.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Could it be a strong anomalous field blocking their radios?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Anomalous field — don’t joke. Otherwise, radiolocators wouldn’t detect anything. They clearly spot a large object and several alive humans nearby. Radios are on, but no response. Investigate, carefully.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright, I’ll check it out.</text>
</string>

	<!-- Medic Angel First Dialog -->
<string id="topi_a45_medic_quest_angel_first_dialog_0">
    <text>What? What happened? Damn, how did I end up here?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_medic_quest_angel_first_dialog_1">
    <text>You got incredibly lucky. You’re tough, I’ll give you that. The second scout team sent after the missing ones found you barely alive. I managed to stabilize you, but your nervous system may not survive such a shock again. You were hit by a massive psychic strike. That’s the short version. What do you remember?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_medic_quest_angel_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I remember arriving at the place the radio operator indicated. There was a bloody anomaly. People around it, like in a trance… Then a strike, another strike. They started shooting, I returned fire, then nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_medic_quest_angel_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Those scouts were far less lucky than you. Their minds were completely destroyed by the psychic effect of an unknown anomaly. Not even sure it was truly an anomaly. Though, let’s say it’s rare. You probably haven’t heard of it yet, but soon everyone will. Go see our radio operator once you recover. He’ll explain the details. After all, it was his idea to send you basically to your death, so let him deal with it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_medic_quest_angel_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, you’re right. I’ll go. He’ll explain in detail what I faced. Thanks for saving my life.</text>
</string>

<!-- Radist Angel Second Dialog -->
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_second_dialog_0">
    <text>So what the hell was that? Trying to get me killed?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_second_dialog_1">
    <text>I’m as shocked as you are, Varg. Understand, this is the first time we’ve encountered something like this here. You surviving is a miracle, agreed. But you did survive. The scout team was lost — that’s the real tragedy. Harold was furious when he heard.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_second_dialog_2">
    <text>No wonder he was furious. What kind of anomaly was this? Why wasn’t this known? Or was it? If yes, why didn’t you warn?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Little is known. Here on our territory, it appeared for the first time. It was the “Black Angel.” Not fully, just its embryonic state. Heard of it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_second_dialog_4">
    <text>No, never. Psychic strikes, that was its effect? It felt like the anomaly worked like a controller. It destroyed the scouts from inside. They attacked me, I had to kill them all. Then the strike, and I woke up only at the doctor’s.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_second_dialog_5">
    <text>I know what happened on the road. Fellow stalkers who brought you here explained the details. You were doubly lucky they didn’t kill you themselves. As for the psychic strikes, that’s the mystery. The “Black Angel,” or rather its embryonic state, can’t produce such effects. Some of the most experienced runners believe the anomaly was just a cover.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_second_dialog_6">
    <text>So you’re saying it was the work of a powerful psionic who controlled the minds of experienced stalkers? And did he create the anomaly with his mind too?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_second_dialog_7">
    <text>It’s possible. The “Black Angel” anomaly is real. But it’s gone now. It was unstable and couldn’t progress into the next state as an amethyst vortex. Who applied the psychic influence under its cover is a mystery.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_second_dialog_8">
    <text>And what will you do? A powerful psionic with unclear motives attacks our stalkers. You won’t just leave it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_second_dialog_88">
    <text>What are your actions in this situation? You won’t just leave it? The death of the scout team due to a psionic isn’t a joke.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_second_dialog_9">
    <text>We won’t. But you won’t intervene either. We already owe you too much for everything you’ve done. So this time, we’ll handle it ourselves. I also tweaked the radiolocator settings. I’ll upload something to your PDA. Consider it payment for your risk. These settings let you monitor our systems. You’ll see stalker squads and some mutants. It’s still in test mode, but working. Only our clan stalkers and you will have access. This will really help us stay alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a45_radist_quest_angel_second_dialog_10">
    <text>If I’m not to interfere, then I won’t. As you say. Thanks for the bonus of a working radiolocation system — it’ll help avoid mutants when encounters are undesirable. Farewell.</text>
</string>

<!-- Technic PNV First Dialog -->
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_first_dialog_0">
    <text>So, what work can you offer and why at night specifically?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Hey. Work is work. Nothing special. Low risk, but it must be done. I need help testing night vision devices. Will you take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_first_dialog_22">
    <text>Maybe later, I’ll take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_first_dialog_2222">
    <text>Not interested. Won’t take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, of course. What exactly will the testing involve?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_first_dialog_222">
    <text>How will the testing procedure work exactly?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Here’s how. You’ll work with a local stalker, my second assistant. He’ll measure some parameters, you’ll test the devices. Three devices: “Contour,” “Dedal,” maybe you’ve heard of them. Test each, your partner records results, you return. That’s it. Clear?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Task is clear. How will the results affect anything? Planned purchase of a batch of gear again?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Preliminary plans only. Likely only one batch for our scouts. Others can order individually. Borders are restless now. Supplying quality gear is more difficult than before.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Got it. I’ll go then. Will ask you more later.</text>
</string>

<!-- Helper PNV Dialogs -->
<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_1_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey. I’m from the technician. About testing night vision devices. He said we’ll work together.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_1_dialog_1">
    <text>Greetings. Yes, we’ll work together. Your task: start the device, stay close, test it, I’ll record the necessary data. Got it? Here’s the first sample.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_1_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, got it. How exactly will you record the data?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_1_dialog_3">
    <text>God knows. I’m just helping like you. The technician gave the gear, explained buttons, the rest is up to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_1_dialog_4">
    <text>Fair enough.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_2_dialog_0">
    <text>All readings taken?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_2_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes. Here’s the second device. Do the same. This one seems slightly better.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_2_dialog_2">
    <text>Looks like it. Quality improves progressively. Haha, they’ll buy the cheapest crap anyway. What about the first one?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_2_dialog_3">
    <text>Return all devices to the technician at base. As for purchases, maybe you’re right, but quality equipment is bought here if needed. Serious business. Leadership handles money you wouldn’t imagine and wants the business to thrive.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_2_dialog_4">
    <text>Let’s hope you’re right.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_3_dialog_0">
    <text>Last device. Let’s finish and leave. Wonder how much Tokar will pay for this?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_3_dialog_1">
    <text>Who knows. The work is trivial, but Tokar seems fair, he won’t cheat.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_3_dialog_2">
    <text>True. How long have you been in their clan?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_3_dialog_3">
    <text>About four months. Getting used to the place. Relatively quiet. Mutants, yes — many, but other group stalkers are rare. That’s nice. At the dump, things are getting messy. Interests of Duty, Freedom, rogues, and bandits collide. Could turn into a serious fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_helper_quest_pnv_3_dialog_4">
    <text>True, but other factions have interests here too. But that’s another story.</text>
</string>

	
	<!-- Technic PNV Second Dialog -->
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_second_dialog_0">
    <text>So, my friend. The work is done, all readings are taken. My partner should have given you the results himself — he didn’t say anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Don’t worry about him. Payment is separate — each for their own work. Yours for yours, his for his. Hand me the samples, I’ll calculate your share.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Here you go. By the way, wouldn’t it have been easier for you to run these tests yourself? At least cheaper.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_second_dialog_22">
    <text>Take it. By the way — wouldn’t it have been easier for you to conduct these tests yourself?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_second_dialog_3">
    <text>And who would repair equipment and gear while doing that — you? Exactly. That’s why I offer people various jobs they can handle while I focus on my main duties here.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Got it. You mentioned recent problems with gear supply. Is it serious? What could be causing it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Hardly serious. Everyone’s sitting on a gold—or rather platinum—vein here. Military, stalkers, traders, middlemen — all profit from artifact sales. Officially, the Zone is dangerous and off-limits. In reality, it’s serious business run by serious people. Supply issues arise when either the military does something for show or someone disagrees about kickbacks. That’s about it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_technic_quest_pnv_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood. Farewell.</text>
</string>

<!-- Harold Kill Zam First Dialog -->
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello. Why did you call me? What exactly needs to be done?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Specifically — we need to settle the issue with Hasan once and for all. This man has done too much, it’s time to remove him.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_2">
    <text>And I suppose I’m the one who has to deal with him?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Exactly. It happens that you’re the best candidate for this task. Sorry to put you on a dirty job, but this bastard deserves no mercy. Plus, it needs to be done quietly.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Why such complications? Wouldn’t it be simpler to handle him directly, especially with the solid evidence you have?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_5">
    <text>He may still have loyal people in his faction. Not so much loyal as simply obedient. Even though Hasan is effectively a mercenary serving both his interests and those of his patrons. The clan’s stalkers might not accept us just shooting him in front of the base. So it must be done quietly and peacefully. There are already a few options for this.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_6">
    <text>And what are the options?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_66">
    <text>What are the options?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Well, you see. You could set up an ambush — lure him into the woods under some false pretext and deal with him there. The radio operator can fake a transmission, no problem. If you go this route, tell him it’s my personal order. Or deal with him here at the base. The second option is trickier — essentially, we do to him what he did to the scouts. I’ll ensure there’s a catalyst in his building, and you plant a chemically-triggered charge. No one will be hurt except him. So, choose wisely. The quartermaster will help with supplies and notify me if you go for the second method.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Understood. I’ll decide what’s best.</text>
</string>

<!-- Radist Kill Zam First Dialog -->
<string id="topi_b65_radist_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello. I need your help with a rather delicate matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_radist_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Depends how delicate.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_radist_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Very delicate. I need you to inform Hasan that a group of collectors reportedly found a rare artifact worth a fortune but fell into a bandit ambush and need urgent help. Make it convincing. The goal is to get Hasan to personally go to that area.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_radist_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Are you serious? Do you realize what you’re asking me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_radist_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Absolutely. This is Harold’s direct order. I’m executing it for him. Make sure Hasan moves immediately to that area.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_radist_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Understood. What about yourself?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_radist_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Delivering justice, my friend... Delivering justice.</text>
</string>

<!-- Harold Kill Zam Second Dialog -->
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Hasan is dead. I did everything necessary. Worked through the radio operator. Hasan and his men at the designated point — all eliminated.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Great, excellent work. Now we can stabilize the clan without that bastard.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_second_dialog_2">
    <text>What about his remaining loyal people? I asked about this when we discovered the technician’s involvement.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_second_dialog_3">
    <text>The obedient ones will find out and move on — they’re not dangerous. Those closely connected who remain alive — we’ll surveil them. If they cause trouble, same fate as Hasan.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Agreed. Wise approach.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_second_dialog_44">
    <text>Wise decision.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Exactly. Now about you. You’ve proven your worth to our faction. I understand you’re here for your own goals, but I don’t want to lose someone valuable like you. I propose you take Hasan’s place by my side. The only requirement — loyalty. You’ve seen what happens to those who betray me. Those who follow me rise to great heights. With your mind and foresight, we’ll strengthen our influence and earn a fortune.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Thanks for the trust. I’ll consider your offer. For now — I must settle my own affairs.</text>
</string>

<!-- Snab Kill Zam First Dialog -->
<string id="topi_b65_snab_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey. I need your help with a task.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_snab_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Speak plainly — what task?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_snab_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I work on Harold’s order. I need an explosive charge with a special chemical filler. I think you know what I mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_snab_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, I understand. So Hasan was indeed behind much of the recent chaos here?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_snab_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Not everything, but mostly he was involved. And all questions go to Harold. I just do my job, you do yours.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_snab_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Understood. I’ll tell Harold you’ll handle the chemical mine. Do it cleanly and carefully. The charge is set so no one gets hurt except Hasan.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_snab_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Everything will be as needed. Don’t worry.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_snab_quest_kill_zam_first_dialog_66">
    <text>Don’t worry. Everything will be perfect.</text>
</string>

	
<!-- Harold Kill Zam Third Dialog -->
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_third_dialog_0">
    <text>Hasan is dead. I did everything necessary. Worked through the quartermaster. Hasan was eliminated using the poison gas, as you advised.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_third_dialog_1">
    <text>Great, excellent work. Now we can stabilize the clan without that bastard.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_third_dialog_2">
    <text>What about his remaining loyal people? I asked about this when we discovered the technician’s involvement.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_third_dialog_3">
    <text>The obedient ones will hear of his death and move on. They’re not dangerous. Those closely connected who are still alive — we’ll surveil them. If they cause trouble, same fate as Hasan.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_third_dialog_4">
    <text>Agreed. Wise move.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_third_dialog_44">
    <text>Wise decision.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_third_dialog_5">
    <text>Exactly. Now about you. You’ve proven your value to our faction. I understand you’re here for your own goals, but I don’t want to lose someone valuable like you. Therefore, I propose you take Hasan’s place by my side. The only thing I’ll need is loyalty. You’ve seen what happens to those who betray me. Those who follow me will rise to unparalleled heights. With your mind and foresight, we’ll strengthen our influence and earn a fortune.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_harold_quest_kill_zam_third_dialog_6">
    <text>Thank you for your trust. I’ll consider your offer. For now — I must take care of my own affairs.</text>
</string>

<!-- Hasan Kill Lider First Dialog -->
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello. Why did you call me? What exactly needs to be done?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Specifically — we need to settle the issue with Harold once and for all. It’s time to act more decisively and take power into our own hands. Harold has outlived his usefulness. He’s a thing of the past.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_2">
    <text>And I suppose I’m the one who has to deal with him?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Exactly. It happens that you’re the best candidate for this task. Sorry to put you on a dirty job, but circumstances turned out this way. Plus, it must be done quietly.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Why such complications? Wouldn’t it be simpler to handle him directly? Especially since most in the clan also want change and would openly support us.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Harold’s influence is still too strong. An open revolt could cause unnecessary casualties. Most wouldn’t accept us just walking in and shooting him in front of the base. So it must be done quietly and peacefully. There are no other candidates for leadership — power will naturally come to me. Removing him is both wise and merciful. There are already a few possible ways to accomplish this.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_6">
    <text>And what are the options?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_66">
    <text>What options do we have?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Look. You could set up an ambush — lure him into the woods under some false pretext and deal with him there. The radio operator can fake a transmission — no problem. If you go this way, tell him it’s my personal order. Or handle him directly at the base. The second option is trickier — essentially, do to him what we did with the Lame group. I’ll ensure a catalyst is in his building, and you plant a chemically-triggered charge. No one will be hurt except him. Choose wisely. The quartermaster will assist with supplies and notify me if you go for the second method. Remember — in this case, the quartermaster will help, not the technician.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Understood. I’ll decide what’s best.</text>
</string>

<!-- Radist Kill Lider First Dialog -->
<string id="topi_a65_radist_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello. I need your help with a rather delicate matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_radist_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Depends how delicate.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_radist_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Very delicate. I need you to tell Harold that a collector group reportedly found a rare artifact worth a fortune but fell into a bandit ambush and need urgent help. Make it convincing. The goal is to get Harold to personally go to that area.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_radist_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Are you serious? Do you realize what you’re asking me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_radist_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Absolutely. This is Hasan’s direct order. I’m working for him now. He has undeniable proof that Harold himself was involved in attacks on collectors and connections with mercenaries. He just used everyone for his own gain. Make sure Harold moves immediately to that area.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_radist_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Understood. What about yourself?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_radist_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Delivering justice, my friend... Delivering justice.</text>
</string>

<!-- Hasan Kill Lider Second Dialog -->
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Harold is dead. I did everything necessary. Worked through the radio operator. The former clan leader was at the designated point with his men — all eliminated.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Great, excellent work. Now we can start the clan’s new life without this conservative.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_second_dialog_2">
    <text>What about his remaining loyal people?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_second_dialog_3">
    <text>The obedient ones will hear of his death and move on. They’re not dangerous. Those closely connected who are still alive — we’ll surveil them. If they cause trouble, same fate as Harold.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Agreed. That’s the right decision.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_second_dialog_44">
    <text>That’s the correct approach.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Now about you. You’ve proven both your resilience and your usefulness. First, forget all previous misunderstandings between us. Second — I propose you take an important role in the clan as an operative. The only requirement is your loyalty. With your mind and foresight, we’ll strengthen our influence in this difficult business.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Thank you for your trust. I’ll consider your offer. For now — I must take care of my own affairs.</text>
</string>

<!-- Snab Kill Lider First Dialog -->
<string id="topi_a65_snab_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey. I need your help with a task.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_snab_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Speak plainly — what task?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_snab_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I work on Hasan’s order. I need an explosive charge with a special chemical filler. I think you know what I mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_snab_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, I understand. So Harold was truly behind much of the recent chaos here?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_snab_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Not everything, but mostly he was personally involved. And all questions go to Hasan. I just do my job, you do yours.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_snab_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Understood. I’ll tell Hasan you handled the second method. Do it carefully and cleanly. The charge is set so no one is hurt except Harold himself.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_snab_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Everything will be as needed. Don’t worry.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_snab_quest_kill_lider_first_dialog_66">
    <text>Everything will be done perfectly.</text>
</string>

	
	<!-- Hasan Kill Lider Third Dialog -->
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_third_dialog_0">
    <text>Harold is dead. I did everything necessary. Worked through the quartermaster. The former leader was eliminated using poison gas, as you advised.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_third_dialog_1">
    <text>Great, excellent work. Now we can start the clan’s new life without this conservative.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_third_dialog_2">
    <text>What about his remaining loyal people?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_third_dialog_3">
    <text>The obedient ones will hear of his death and move on. They’re not dangerous. Those closely connected who are still alive — we’ll surveil them. If they cause trouble, same fate as Harold.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_third_dialog_4">
    <text>Agreed. That’s the right decision.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_third_dialog_5">
    <text>Now about you. You’ve proven both your resilience and your usefulness. First, forget all previous misunderstandings — that’s one. Second, I propose you take an important role in the clan as an operative. The only thing I’ll need is your loyalty. With your mind and foresight, we’ll strengthen our influence in this difficult business.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_hasan_quest_kill_lider_third_dialog_6">
    <text>Thank you for your trust. I’ll consider your offer. For now — I must take care of my own affairs.</text>
</string>

<!-- Artefact Quest Vozmezdie First Dialog -->
<string id="topi_a15_artefacter_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_0">
    <text>By the way, don’t you have any more work to offer?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_artefacter_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_1">
    <text>There are a couple of jobs. They’re not urgent, but it’s better to do them and forget. Quite risky, but surely you’ve encountered similar tasks during your stalker career. This is about retrieving rare artifacts on request. Currently, the faction has two unfulfilled contracts from the scientists in Yantra. First — to get the Black Soul artifact, second — to find the Dragon’s Eye. The artifacts are very rare, but we’ve learned to predict their possible appearances in certain anomalies. So the search area will be narrowed. If you’re interested, you can take one of these tasks. But keep in mind that Black Soul is dangerous. Without proper transport, it can harm humans. Of course, the payment will be higher.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_artefacter_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_222">
    <text>Maybe I’ll wait on artifact retrieval for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_artefacter_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I’ll take the Dragon’s Eye. I don’t have this artifact yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_artefacter_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_22">
    <text>I’ll take on the search for the Black Soul. I’ve encountered it once before.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_artefacter_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Wise choice. Dragon’s Eye doesn’t have the harmful effect of Black Soul. And it will count in your personal achievements.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_artefacter_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_4">
    <text>And it saves you effort. By the way, where should I look for it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_artefacter_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_404">
    <text>Plus, it will save you effort. Which area will the search cover?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_artefacter_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Can’t tell. Someone will have to fulfill the second contract anyway. There are plenty of people wanting to make money. Search area — south, near the checkpoint.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_artefacter_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, I’ll do it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_artefacter_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_33">
    <text>I hope you’ve thought this through and really know what you’re getting into. In pursuit of big money, many stalkers lost their souls.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_artefacter_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_44">
    <text>Don’t worry, I know. By the way, which area should I search?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_artefacter_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_55">
    <text>The search area — near the farm. It’s quite remote and dangerous; the cursed cemetery is nearby. So be doubly careful.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_artefacter_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_66">
    <text>Don’t worry, I’ll do everything properly. Prepare my share.</text>
</string>

<!-- Dolg Vozmezdie Leader Dialog -->
<string id="topi_a15_dolg_vozmezdie_lider_dialog_0">
    <text>Approach slowly and don’t even think about drawing your gun. So, punk, did you really think we wouldn’t find you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_dolg_vozmezdie_lider_dialog_1">
    <text>What are you talking about? I’m here on my own business, didn’t cross your way. Mistaken for someone else?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_dolg_vozmezdie_lider_dialog_2">
    <text>Don’t play dumb, Freeman scum. Remember the checkpoint? Our scouts you took out? Did you really think the zone’s most powerful clan would forget that?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_dolg_vozmezdie_lider_dialog_3">
    <text>I recall. They were in the wrong place at the wrong time, and mistook me for someone else. Just like you now.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_dolg_vozmezdie_lider_dialog_4">
    <text>Doesn’t matter. We always settle debts. More than fully.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_dolg_vozmezdie_lider_dialog_5">
    <text>And what are you planning to do...</text>
</string>

<!-- Freedom Vozmezdie Leader Dialog -->
<string id="topi_a15_freedom_vozmezdie_lider_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey punk, approach slowly and don’t even think about drawing your gun. So, brat, did you think we wouldn’t find you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_freedom_vozmezdie_lider_dialog_1">
    <text>What are you talking about, Freedom junkie? I’m here on my own business, didn’t cross your way. Mistaken for someone?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_freedom_vozmezdie_lider_dialog_2">
    <text>Don’t play dumb, Dolg scum. Remember the checkpoint? Our scouts you took out? Did you really think the zone’s most powerful clan would forget that?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_freedom_vozmezdie_lider_dialog_3">
    <text>I recall. They were in the wrong place at the wrong time. And I didn’t take them out — your Dolg friends did. But I did take care of the others — my work.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_freedom_vozmezdie_lider_dialog_4">
    <text>And you think we’ll believe that crap? Maybe we should give you a medal too? Although… maybe not.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_freedom_vozmezdie_lider_dialog_5">
    <text>And what are you planning to do...</text>
</string>

<!-- Zam Quest Vozmezdie First Dialog -->
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hasan, I urgently need your help. Can you hear me out?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Speak, since you started, but quickly. I don’t have time to waste on nonsense.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_2">
    <text>It won’t take long. In short — I have serious conflicts with the Freedom faction and need support to resolve this.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Why should I wipe your tears and risk the clan’s reputation protecting an enemy of Freedom? Freemen are cruel and powerful. I have no desire to quarrel for some vagabond.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_4">
    <text>What if I tell you these Freemen will threaten your clan’s interests — would that change your response? I’m not just some vagabond. You probably remember the Freemen and Dolg squad was recently wiped out at your border. Everyone thought it was mutual, but it wasn’t. I was there and played a direct role.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Go on...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_6">
    <text>The Freemen just discovered me and declared a hunt. I survived their brutal game, but they won’t stop. The deceased Freemen and Dolg planned to start sabotage against your clan...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Don’t exaggerate. I don’t think Dolg and Freedom came here in sync just to profit. But they are unwanted guests. Alright, stalker, consider yourself heard. I’ll probably help you, and myself mostly. Come to me at night. We’ll find a solution. Consider this payment for future work. After their game, you’ll need to recover some gear. Now — leave.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_22">
    <text>It won’t take long. In short — I have serious conflicts with the Dolg faction and need support to resolve this.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_33">
    <text>Why should I wipe your tears and risk the clan’s reputation protecting a Dolg enemy? They are cruel and powerful. I have no desire to quarrel for some vagabond.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_44">
    <text>What if I tell you these Dolg will threaten your clan’s interests — would that change our conversation? I’m not just a vagabond. You probably remember the Freemen and Dolg squad was recently wiped out at your border. Everyone thought it was mutual, but it wasn’t. I was there and involved directly.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_55">
    <text>Go on...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_66">
    <text>The Dolg just discovered me and declared a hunt. I survived, but they won’t stop. The deceased Freemen and Dolg planned sabotage against your clan...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_77">
    <text>Don’t exaggerate. I don’t think Dolg and Freedom came here in sync just to profit. But they are unwanted guests. Alright, stalker, consider yourself heard. I’ll probably help you, and myself mostly. Come to me at night. We’ll find a solution. Consider this payment for future work. After their game, you’ll need to recover some gear. Now — leave.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_88">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
</string>


	<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Harold, I need your help. Urgently. Can you hear me out?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Greetings. Speak, since you’ve started. I hope this is something serious if you came to me directly.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_2">
    <text>This won’t take long. In short — I’ve run into serious conflicts with the Freedom faction and need support to resolve it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Why would you think I’d wipe your nose for you and risk the clan’s reputation covering an enemy of Freedom? The Freemen are a ruthless and powerful group. I have no desire to quarrel with them over some simple stalker. Sorry, but the interests of the clan come first for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_4">
    <text>What if I told you that these very Freedom fighters could threaten your clan’s interests — would that steer our conversation in the right direction? Besides, I’m not just any simple stalker. Surely you remember the Freemen and Duty squads that were recently wiped out on the border of your territories. Everyone assumed they killed each other. That’s not true. I was there personally involved.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_5">
    <text>I see. So you’re the Rambo who wiped out squads of Duty and Freedom. Naturally, they were pissed and came after you. And now you crawl to me, whining and tail tucked, asking for help. Right? I’d gladly hand you over to them myself, but I understand as well as you that their presence here wasn’t accidental and certainly not because of you. So, I think we can work something out.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_6">
    <text>The Freemen only just tracked me down and declared a hunt. I survived their brutal game, but I’m sure they won’t stop. The fallen Freedom and Duty members had indeed planned to sabotage your clan, and now all evidence of my words is in their hands.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Careful, stalker, don’t overdo it. I don’t think Duty and Freedom came here in perfect sync just for easy profit. But they are definitely uninvited guests and clearly out of place in this little party of life. Alright, consider yourself heard. I’ll probably help you, and the clan as well — mostly the clan. Come to me at night. We’ll find a solution to your problem. And by the way — consider this payment for future work. After their game, you’ll need to restore some of your gear. Now — go.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_22">
    <text>This won’t take long. In short — I’ve run into serious conflicts with the Duty faction and need support to resolve it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_33">
    <text>Why would you think I’d wipe your nose for you and risk the clan’s reputation covering an enemy of Duty? They’re a ruthless and powerful faction. I have no desire to quarrel with them over some simple stalker. Sorry, but the clan’s interests come first for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_44">
    <text>What if I told you that these Duty fighters could threaten your clan’s interests — would that change the course of our conversation? Besides, I’m not just any simple stalker. Surely you remember the Freemen and Duty squads that were recently wiped out on the border of your territories. Everyone assumed they killed each other. That’s not true. I was there personally involved.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_55">
    <text>I see. So you’re the Rambo who wiped out squads of Duty and Freedom. Naturally, they were pissed and came after you. And now you crawl to me, whining and tail tucked, asking for help. Right? I’d gladly hand you over to them myself, but I understand as well as you that their presence here wasn’t accidental and certainly not because of you. So, I think we can work something out.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_66">
    <text>The Duty fighters only just tracked me down and declared a hunt. I survived their brutal game, but I’m sure they won’t stop. The fallen Freedom and Duty members had indeed planned to sabotage your clan, and now all evidence of my words is in their hands.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_77">
    <text>Careful, stalker, don’t overdo it. I don’t think Duty and Freedom came here in perfect sync just for easy profit. But they are definitely uninvited guests and clearly out of place in this little party of life. Alright, consider yourself heard. I’ll probably help you, and the clan as well — mostly the clan. Come to me at night. We’ll find a solution to your problem. And by the way — consider this payment for future work. After their game, you’ll need to restore some of your gear. Now — go.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_88">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, looks like the time is right. So, what’s the plan? What exactly are you thinking?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Don’t rush. You’ll know soon enough. My people double-checked everything, compared the facts with your words. A few questions came up. How exactly did you eliminate those Duty and Freedom scout groups? And most importantly — why? Think carefully before answering.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Here’s what happened. I ended up on your territory, and the first people I ran into were a Freedom patrol. As it turned out, it wasn’t even a patrol, but part of their recon squad. They offered me a small job — I agreed. When I came back, the Freedom squad had already been wiped out. The Duty fighters tracked and eliminated them. They mistook me for another Freedom member and opened fire. I returned fire. And I got lucky…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_3">
    <text>I see. So in fact, you only took out the Duty fighters. Interesting. Noted.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, essentially. Though the Freedom hunters just opened season on me. So, what now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Simple. We kill those in your way. More precisely, you will. My people arranged for your enemies to occupy one of our temporary checkpoints. You go there and eliminate everyone present. Then you come back to me, and we’ll discuss the proper cover story. The rest will be handled by others. Remember — my primary loyalty is to the clan. I don’t need roaming scouts from other factions here.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright, I’ll take care of it.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_44">
    <text>Yes, essentially. And the Duty fighters have opened season on me now. So, what do we do now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_55">
    <text>Simple. We kill those in your way. More precisely, you will. My people arranged for your enemies to occupy one of our temporary checkpoints. You go there and eliminate everyone present. Then you return to me, and we’ll discuss the proper cover story. The rest will be handled by others. Remember — my primary loyalty is to the clan. I don’t need roaming scouts from other factions here.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_66">
    <text>Alright, I’ll take care of it.</text>
</string>

	
	<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Hasan, everything that depended on me — has been successfully done.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Excellent. I hope that now both my problem and yours will be resolved. The guys are finishing up covering the tracks the way we need.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_second_dialog_2">
    <text>And how exactly do you need it? You also mentioned a follow-up story.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_second_dialog_3">
    <text>We’ll skip the fine details. I’ll tell you only what you need to know. Here’s the deal. Through my channels, I arranged with the Duty fighters to smooth over the possible conflict. Remember this about the first day, when both Duty and Freedom squads were killed: you were not at that checkpoint, you didn’t see the Freedom fighters and you didn’t work for them. You didn’t witness the Duty fighters arriving and killing their enemies. You appeared there later with my scouts and only found the bodies left behind. The attack by the Duty squad on you was a mistake — they thought you were a Freedom agent, but I convinced their leadership otherwise. Got it? Forget this story and never mention it again if you want to stay alive a little longer. And about your elimination of the second Duty squad — don’t bother thanking me, but if you ever face a critical choice, remember that Hasan once saved your ass. Now, disappear from sight.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_second_dialog_4">
    <text>I understand. Thanks anyway. Goodbye.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_second_dialog_22">
    <text>And how exactly do you need it? You also mentioned a follow-up story.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_second_dialog_33">
    <text>We’ll skip the fine details. I’ll tell you only what you need to know. Here’s the deal. Through my channels, I arranged with the Freedom fighters to smooth over the possible conflict. Remember this about the first day, when both Duty and Freedom squads were killed: you were not at that checkpoint, you didn’t see the Freedom fighters and you didn’t work for them. You didn’t witness the Duty fighters arriving and killing their enemies. You appeared there later with my scouts and only found the bodies left behind. The attack by the Freedom squad on you was a mistake — they thought you were a Duty agent, but I convinced their leadership otherwise. Got it? Forget this story and never mention it again if you want to stay alive a little longer. And about your elimination of the second Freedom squad — don’t bother thanking me, but if you ever face a critical choice, remember that Hasan once saved your ass. Now, disappear from sight.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_zam_quest_vozmezdie_second_dialog_44">
    <text>I understand. Thanks anyway. Goodbye.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, seems like the time is right. So, what’s the plan? What exactly have you decided to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Don’t rush. You’ll find out soon enough. My people double-checked everything, comparing facts with your words. A few questions came up. How exactly did you eliminate those Duty and Freedom scout groups? And most importantly — why? Think carefully before answering.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Here’s what happened. I ended up on your territory, and the first people I ran into were a Freedom patrol. As it turned out, it wasn’t even a patrol, but part of their recon squad. They offered me a small job — I agreed. On my way back, the Freedom squad had already been wiped out. The Duty fighters tracked and eliminated them. They mistook me for another Freedom member and opened fire. I returned fire. And I got lucky...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_3">
    <text>I see. So, in fact, you only took out the Duty fighters. Interesting information. That changes a lot, but don’t worry — it’s manageable.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, essentially. Though the Freedom hunters just opened season on me. So, what now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Simple. We kill those in your way. More precisely, you will. My people arranged for your enemies to occupy one of our temporary checkpoints. You go there and eliminate everyone present. Then you return to me, and we’ll discuss the proper cover story. The rest will be handled by others. Remember — I help my clan first. I don’t need roaming scouts from other factions here.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright, I’ll take care of it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_44">
    <text>Yes, essentially. And the Duty fighters have opened season on me now. So, what do we do now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_55">
    <text>Simple. We kill those in your way. More precisely, you will. My people arranged for your enemies to occupy one of our temporary checkpoints. You go there and eliminate everyone present. Then return to me, and we’ll discuss the proper cover story. The rest will be handled by others. Remember — I help my clan first. I don’t need roaming scouts from other factions here.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_first_dialog_66">
    <text>Alright, I’ll take care of it.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Harold, everything that depended on me — has been successfully done.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Excellent. I hope that now both my problem and yours will be resolved. The guys are finishing up covering the tracks the way we need.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_second_dialog_2">
    <text>And how exactly do you need it? You also mentioned a follow-up story.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_second_dialog_3">
    <text>We’ll skip the fine details. I’ll tell you only what you need to know. Here’s the deal. Through my channels, I arranged with the Duty fighters to smooth over the possible conflict. Remember this about the first day, when both Duty and Freedom squads were killed: you were not at that checkpoint, you didn’t see the Freedom fighters and you didn’t work for them. You didn’t witness the Duty fighters arriving and killing their enemies. You appeared there later with my scouts and only found the bodies left behind. The attack by the Duty squad on you was a mistake — they thought you were a Freedom agent, but I convinced their leadership otherwise. Got it? Forget this story and never mention it again if you want to stay alive a little longer. And about your elimination of the second Duty squad — don’t bother thanking me, but if you ever face a critical choice, remember that Harold once saved your ass. Now, disappear from sight.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b15_lider_quest_vozmezdie_second_dialog_4">
    <text>I understand. Thanks anyway. Goodbye.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Good day. I’m looking for work. Do you need any help? Maybe I could be of use for some task?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_first_dialog_1">
    <text>And the same to you, stalker. Honestly, everyone’s fully loaded right now — supplies, couriers… you know how it is. It all requires skill and experience. And you’re new here. But I think I have a suitable job for you. Precisely because you’re new, that’s what we’ll use.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_first_dialog_22">
    <text>Maybe I’ll come back later.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I’m willing to work. But for now, it’s not clear what I’ll actually be doing. Can you be more specific?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Of course. You’ll be carrying out several tasks aimed at benefiting the clan. That’s the official cover for everyone else. Don’t be surprised. In reality, you’ll be primarily involved in an investigation initiated by the clan leader Harold, aimed at identifying artifact collectors who have started working against the faction. Recently, there have been increasing cases of artifacts being sold to outsiders, attacks on certain collector groups, and other sabotage. For example, some faction caches were recently looted. And it’s believed all these events are somehow connected. So we need to figure it out — and, most importantly, we need a new person to handle part of the work.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Sounds like an interesting job. I like it. But tell me, why did you decide that artifact collectors are involved?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_first_dialog_5">
    <text>They are involved. Rest assured. You’re right that there’s no clear leader among them, but there are definitely link nodes. Perhaps there’s a leader too. Our scouts have already caught and interrogated ordinary bandits. Some clearly acted on orders and had supervisors. But who gives instructions to those supervisors is a big question. Someone from inside is informing them. We need to figure out who. We’ll start with the collectors — or rather, their coordinators. Each collector group has a coordinator who manages several groups, issues current routes, other info, and collects the most valuable artifacts. We have three coordinators. They deliver the best items either to me or to our artifact specialist. We’ll begin by checking these coordinators.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_first_dialog_6">
    <text>And how exactly?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_first_dialog_7">
    <text>You’ll become my personal courier. I’ve arranged with Jorah to inform them of your authority. You’ll go to each of them and collect the artifacts they were supposed to deliver. Try to get them talking, act like a naive rookie who can’t keep a secret. Then bring up the recent cache looting and say you’ve been assigned to restore them. Give each collector coordinates of a new cache — I’ll provide them to you now.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_first_dialog_8">
    <text>So the key is to give each of them slightly different info? And you think they’ll fall for it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_first_dialog_9">
    <text>Whether they fall for it or not — I don’t know. But we have to start somewhere. Do what I ask first, then we’ll see if I was right.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>


<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_1_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey. I’m the new courier from Isai. He said you’d be informed when I arrived.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_1_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah. I was told. Well, there aren’t many artifacts at the moment, but I’ll hand over whatever there is.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_1_dialog_2">
    <text>Good. By the way, have you heard anything about the looted faction caches? Rumor has it some scavengers found them. Now I’ll have to hide a new one near the abandoned farmstead. What a pain.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_1_dialog_3">
    <text>No, haven’t heard. I get it, you’ll be running back and forth. But hang in there — everyone’s got their own patch.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_1_dialog_4">
    <text>True. Noticed anything unusual, by the way?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_1_dialog_5">
    <text>All quiet so far. Everyone’s completing their tasks. Mutants as usual, countless. Just the usual grind. We’re expecting a shipment of new gear soon, so push Isai a bit.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_1_dialog_6">
    <text>Will do. Take care.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_2_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi. I’m the new courier from Isai. He should have informed you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_2_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah. I was told you’d be arriving. I’ll hand over the artifacts collected. Anything else needed? Any additional instructions?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_2_dialog_2">
    <text>Good. By the way, have you heard about the looted faction caches? Rumor says some bandits found them. Now I’ll have to stash a new one near the central outpost. What a hassle.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_2_dialog_3">
    <text>No, haven’t heard. The guys haven’t mentioned anything either. I’d know if something like that happened in our area.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_2_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright. Noticed anything else unusual? Any clues could be important.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_2_dialog_5">
    <text>Only one odd mutant. Looks like a controller. Our scouts spotted it north of the village. They reported it — now we wait to see what they decide. Pass this to Isai. No telling what this freak really is. A controller would attack, but this one left, which is suspicious.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_2_dialog_6">
    <text>Will do. Take care.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_3_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello. I’m the new courier from Isai. You should’ve been informed about my arrival.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_3_dialog_1">
    <text>Correct — I was told. I’ve prepared everything needed. The guys have some requests too. Deliver them along with the artifacts. Supposedly, new gear shipments were planned a while ago, but Isai’s dragging his feet. The guys are frustrated — no proper binoculars, detectors, or night vision. What a mess. He better stop loafing and get to work.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_3_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright, I’ll pass your requests to him. By the way, heard anything about the looted faction caches? Rumor says some bandits found them. Now I’ll have to stash a new one near the southern outpost. What a headache.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_3_dialog_3">
    <text>No, haven’t heard. Not surprising. With slackers like Isai, it’s a miracle anything still holds together. Long overdue to kick that lazy bastard. I wouldn’t be surprised if he drunkenly blabbed where the caches were.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_3_dialog_4">
    <text>Sure, that’s your opinion — but I haven’t noticed anything like that from him.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_3_dialog_5">
    <text>Heh, you’re green here, barely a week in. My advice — stop serving Isai. Go to Tokar instead. One of the few worthy people in the clan. Even the leadership respects him. Especially Hasan. Not like this under-supplied fool.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_freedom_sborshik_member_3_dialog_6">
    <text>I’ll think about your suggestion. Take care.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_second_dialog_0">
    <text>I did everything as you told me. Took the artifacts, had a few talks, planted the new cache locations with each of them. Now I think I understand why it was needed.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Glad you got it. We told one collector the cache would be near the farmstead, another in the center, the third near the southern outpost. Now we wait to see which cache gets looted — that’ll reveal the bastard.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Let’s hope they make their move. By the way, one of the collectors or coordinators was rather aggressive.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Who exactly?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Some Mahir. He’s extremely unhappy with your work. Thinks you’re incompetent. The groups have been waiting for new gear for ages but can’t get it. He blames you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_second_dialog_5">
    <text>I see. Good to know. Thanks. That’s an important observation. I have an idea now — just need to check if it’s correct. When you’re ready for the next step, come see me. We’ll check the floats.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m1_snab_quest_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_0">
    <text>I’m ready to handle the artifact collector Mahir.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Good. Here’s the plan — I consulted leadership and we decided to eliminate him.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_2">
    <text>What? He’s probably an important link in the chain! His job was just passing tips, surely someone is above him. Shouldn’t he be interrogated?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_3">
    <text>True, he should. But I warned you not to ask unnecessary questions. Interrogation changes nothing. He’s not the type you can crack. Besides, we already suspect his connections. Confirming that again is pointless.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Don’t get me wrong. It’s foolish to remove a valuable witness just like that. But fine. It’s your mess in the clan to clean up. I don’t really care.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_5">
    <text>His death will serve as a warning to anyone thinking of betraying the clan. Consider it a message delivered via Mahir’s corpse. Those behind him aren’t fools — they’ll know we’re aware and can act anytime. Don’t overthink it. Deliver this package to Mahir — looks like a simple gun, but it’s no ordinary piece.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Your will. I’ll do what’s needed.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_66">
    <text>All will be done as required.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings. I’m here from Isai again. This time it’s about you personally.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Really? And he’s sending his little monkey to me again. What’s he lacking? The courage to handle delicate matters himself? When can we expect his damned shipments?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I don’t know what you’re talking about. I don’t care about your relationship with Isai. Here’s the deal — he asked me to give this to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_3">
    <text>And what’s this junk? Why would I need a simple gun? I don’t care about toys, I need proper gear for my guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_4">
    <text>He asks you to forgive him. The equipment shipment is delayed. This gun is a personal gift — also a sample of the quality of weapons that will be given to some collectors later.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Fine, I’ll wait. But my people won’t. Isai or Jorah won’t get valuable artifacts until proper gear arrives. Tell these bastards that. And next time, don’t scare me with threats — I couldn’t care less.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Don’t worry, I’ll pass it on. And I assure you — they won’t threaten you again.</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_222">
    <text>Mahir, I’ve got bad news. Isai decided to take you out. Can’t say more for now, but I don’t agree with him. That’s why I warned you. If you’ve got an alternate route off clan-controlled territory, now’s the time to use it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_333">
    <text>So that’s how it is. The little monkey’s getting smarter by the day. And I take it you’re expecting a generous reward? Fine, I hope you’re telling the truth. We’ll head to the northern outpost using a hidden route. If all goes well — I vanish, and I pay you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_444">
    <text>Go on, but we need to move fast.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_44">
    <text>I don’t give a damn. I was ordered to kill you. But I won’t. Isai is wrong. Dead wrong. I’ll save your life and get you out through the southern outpost, but you’ll answer my questions.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_55">
    <text>What a turn of events. Didn’t expect that. I guess I have no choice — I’ll answer your questions. One thing though — why the southern outpost? Wouldn’t the northern one be safer? I’ve got a better chance of leaving unnoticed there.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_first_dialog_66">
    <text>Didn’t you get me, damn it? You go through the southern outpost. Argue, and I’ll put you down on the spot. Move.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_fake_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, kid. Slow and steady, come closer. Reach for your gun… yeah, you know what I mean.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_fake_dialog_1">
    <text>Have you lost it? I just saved your life.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_fake_dialog_2">
    <text>I appreciate your noble act. But your greed for cash backfired on you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_fake_dialog_3">
    <text>So that’s how you repay someone who helped you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_fake_dialog_5">
    <text>This is the payback, my friend. You exposed me to Isai. Now I have to flee this place and find a better deal. Consider us square. These temporary troubles I’ll survive, unlike you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_fake_dialog_6">
    <text>I don’t think so...</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Alright, I think we’re here. From here, you’re on your own.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_1">
    <text>I don’t know why you decided to spare my life, but thanks.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_2">
    <text>For selfish reasons. Don’t think I’m some saint. Dead men are useless, but a live one can still be of profit. Tell me — you set up the attack on me when I was talking about the caches?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, I set it up. I was ordered to conduct several sabotages within the faction. Loot some caches, organize attacks on collector groups supervised by other coordinators. The actual attackers were just bandits — I only passed along information from one person.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_4">
    <text>And who is this person? Think carefully, or I might reconsider sparing you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_44">
    <text>Who is this person? Think before answering me.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_5">
    <text>This person is one of the mercenaries, but well-connected with someone high in our clan. I don’t know exactly who. Maybe your Isai — since he decided to eliminate me. Makes sense. I slipped up, and he wants me gone. Who knows now. The main point — someone in the clan has arrangements with the mercenaries. Why the sabotages were needed — I don’t know.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_mahir_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Fine. Get out of here.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_fouth_dialog_0">
    <text>Mahir’s dead. There were some complications, but it got done.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_fouth_dialog_1">
    <text>Complications, huh? What kind?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_fouth_dialog_2">
    <text>He somehow realized I was coming to kill him and resisted. There was a firefight, and he died in it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_fouth_dialog_22">
    <text>Seems he realized they wanted him gone and tried to fight back. He died in the firefight.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_fouth_dialog_3">
    <text>Was anyone else with him?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_fouth_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, a few. As far as I know, they were a team of collectors he supervised. Shame. They died needlessly. Foolish to lose your life for others’ sins.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_fouth_dialog_5">
    <text>No pity. They surely knew Mahir’s business. But fine, it’s a lesson for the rest. You did well and proved yourself. Keep it up, and you could do well in our clan. Good working with a competent man. Take care.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_fouth_dialog_6">
    <text>Take care.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_third_dialog_0">
    <text>Mahir’s dead. Some complications arose, but it got done.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_third_dialog_1">
    <text>Complications? What happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_third_dialog_2">
    <text>He somehow guessed I was coming to eliminate him and tried to flee. Threw a grenade at me and bolted. But he didn’t get far — hit a trap, and his guts and bones were scattered around.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_third_dialog_3">
    <text>He’s dead, that’s what matters. Anyone else with him?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_third_dialog_4">
    <text>No, he was alone. He expected me where you said. What now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_third_dialog_44">
    <text>He was alone. What now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_third_dialog_5">
    <text>Nothing now. You did well and proved yourself. Keep it up, and you could do well in our clan. Good working with a competent man. Take care.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_third_dialog_6">
    <text>Take care.</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Mahir’s dead. Everything went smoothly.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_1">
    <text>No complications at all?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_2">
    <text>None. I handed him your package and started leaving. A small directional charge went off and sent Mahir to his ancestors.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Good. Was anyone else with him? Any witnesses?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_4">
    <text>No one. He waited for me exactly where you said. What now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_44">
    <text>No one was with him. What now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Nothing now. You did well and proved yourself. Keep it up, and you could make a good place for yourself in our clan. It was a pleasure working with a competent man. Take care.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c17_snab_quest_licvidation_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Take care.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_pred_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey. I’m looking for work. Can you help me out?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_pred_dialog_1">
    <text>I could. But I won’t. You’re new here, and I don’t know if you’re trustworthy. Talk to our radio guy. Sometimes he gives work to newcomers. Work for him first, then you can come to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_pred_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_trader_pred_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings. I’m interested in work. Got anything for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_pred_dialog_1">
    <text>Work, huh? Not with just anyone, my friend. Prove your worth to our group first, then I’ll deal with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_trader_pred_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_snab_pred_dialog_0">
    <text>My respects. Listen, friend, I need a favor. I’m looking for work. Can you offer anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_pred_dialog_1">
    <text>You’re an outsider, right? Sorry, can’t help yet. Well, maybe I can. But I need to know if I can do business with you. Our artifact specialist usually works with outsiders. If you handle his tasks, you can come to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_snab_pred_dialog_2">
    <text>Got it. Thanks.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_hasan_pred_dialog_0">
    <text>My respects. I’m new here. Looking for work. Can you help?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hasan_pred_dialog_1">
    <text>Who are you? New? Go bother the collectors and scouts instead. They’ve taken in degenerates... Show yourself first, then come back — then we’ll talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hasan_pred_dialog_2">
    <text>On my way.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_harold_pred_dialog_0">
    <text>My respects. Looking for work. I’m new here. Can you help?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_harold_pred_dialog_1">
    <text>New, and you’re coming straight to the clan leader? If you’re not some super-Rambo, sorry — nothing to discuss. Work for the people in the clan first, then come back if you prove yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_harold_pred_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_hunter_pred_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey friend. Looking for work. Got anything in mind?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_pred_dialog_1">
    <text>New, and straight to the hunter? Tired of life already? Go help the guys out first. Patrols, for example... Then come back to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_hunter_pred_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_var_1_suget_quest_final_harold_dialog_0">
    <text>About your offer to join the clan — is it still on?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_1_suget_quest_final_harold_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, why? You’ve settled your business and decided to stay?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_1_suget_quest_final_harold_dialog_2">
    <text>Something like that. The Clear Sky problem’s solved and I have nowhere else to go. Paths to Freedom or Duty are closed, even though the conflict there is sorted. Becoming a marauder or a hired gun isn’t for me. I’m an outcast, tossed around. I just want peace.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_1_suget_quest_final_harold_dialog_3">
    <text>Outcast, huh? Don’t exaggerate. You haven’t even seen what it means to be truly exiled. I stand by my words — people like you are needed in our clan. I have big plans for expansion. We need to strengthen influence in key areas and consider pushing toward the northern territories.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_1_suget_quest_final_harold_dialog_4">
    <text>Promising idea. I could start establishing contacts up north. I’ve been stuck in your swamps too long...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_1_suget_quest_final_harold_dialog_5">
    <text>Don’t rush. First, tell me exactly what you’ve been doing here. I know you worked for Clear Sky, but as I understand it, your paths diverged and your last contract caused problems. I need to know — will you bring those problems into the clan? Did you resolve everything? What exactly happened after your meeting with the Clear Sky agent?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_1_suget_quest_final_harold_dialog_6">
    <text>As I said — the Clear Sky problem’s resolved. The issue with the stalker scientists too. Everything else doesn’t matter. I’m here and ready to work. Nothing else matters...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_1_suget_quest_final_harold_dialog_7">
    <text>Fine. We’ll go with your word. Still, I’ll check what you call “everything else.” You’re free for now. Rest. I’ll call you when the northern expansion plan is ready. Go...</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_var_1_suget_quest_final_harold_dialog_8">
    <text>I’ll be waiting. Take care...</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_d5_radist_third_end_quest_2_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey. I’m from Chekh. Got a job. You know what I mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_radist_third_end_quest_2_dialog_1">
    <text>Uh, from Chekh? Sorry, not really… What exactly do you need from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_radist_third_end_quest_2_dialog_2">
    <text>I need you to contact the Clear Sky agent and set up a meeting with him immediately.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_radist_third_end_quest_2_dialog_3">
    <text>Ah, right… Chekh, the Clear Sky agent. Got it. No problem. I’ll handle it. You can head to that area already.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_radist_third_end_quest_2_dialog_4">
    <text>Thanks. By the way, how do you know Chekh?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_radist_third_end_quest_2_dialog_44">
    <text>How do you know Chekh?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_radist_third_end_quest_2_dialog_5">
    <text>From the same place as you. He worked here for a while, then left. Varg, why the extra question? You know how it works — everyone looks out for themselves or follows the money. I helped him with some of his special tasks before you showed up, and also after.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_radist_third_end_quest_2_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood. Alright, take care.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_0">
    <text>My respects. Finally, we meet. Situation is clearer now, but some complications arose.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_1">
    <text>What kind? Why didn’t you contact us sooner? What did you find out?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_2">
    <text>Didn’t contact sooner because there was no precise info on the task. I managed to find details about your missing group. Found traces. Several bodies. Most likely the whole group is dead…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_3">
    <text>Understood. We didn’t expect a happy ending, but hope, as you know, dies last. What about the scientists? Did you find traces of them?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_4">
    <text>I did, but here’s the tricky part. I know where they are hiding now, where they’ve been hiding from you, and that you still want them. I need guarantees that after I hand them over, nobody will put a bullet in my head…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_5">
    <text>Smart one, huh… Figured they were hiding from us. But maybe someone tipped you off? Anyway, not important now. Guarantees, you say — alright, what’s your proposal?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_6">
    <text>Old farms. No more than three of you. I come alone with the scientists. You hand over the promised money, we part ways. My sniper covers the site to keep anyone from breaking the deal. If that’s acceptable, let’s discuss the time…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_7">
    <text>Kid, aren’t you afraid? Setting conditions for Clear Sky? Do you even know what we could do to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_8">
    <text>When I got here — suddenly a Duty squad and a small Freedom unit blocked me. Heard of them, probably. See? I’m still alive, two recon squads are dead. After that, do you think I’m afraid to set conditions for some pitiful Southern Marsh clan that couldn’t even hire proper mercs?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_9">
    <text>Yeah, we underestimated you. We’ll fix that. Don’t get cocky, luck is fickle. Many want your head — don’t make us your enemies.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_10">
    <text>Better to be a living enemy than a dead pawn… So, you accept my terms?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_1010">
    <text>One enemy more, one less. Doesn’t matter now. So, do you accept my terms?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_11">
    <text>What guarantees can you give? Why should we trust you? Where’s the proof that the scientists are still alive?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_12">
    <text>Only three scientists left. You wanted to kill them after they delivered something valuable to Strelok’s group. Enough proof for you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_13">
    <text>Fine. We’ll be in touch…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_csky_svayznoy_quest_2_dialog_14">
    <text>You’ve been deceiving me from the start. I hope you don’t make that mistake this time. I’ll be waiting for our next meeting.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_0">
    <text>I’m here. What’s the rush? What’s so urgent?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_1">
    <text>Still asking? We found a Sinner agent. Remember I told you about them? Your so-called friend working for Freedom is actually a Sinner agent undercover. His real motives aren’t clear, but his plans regarding you are.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_2">
    <text>What plans?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_222">
    <text>Which plans exactly?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_3">
    <text>Sinners recruit more agents. You proved smart and capable — not just a shooter or artifact scavenger. He nearly recruited you.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_4">
    <text>Aren’t you doing the same thing?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_5">
    <text>No. I only want to protect you from him and his clan. Sinners are evil, a curse of the Zone. Treacherous soulless creatures that must be destroyed. I’ll do whatever it takes.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright. Suppose he’s a Sinner. What proof do you have?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_7">
    <text>Remember when you worked for Karim and Zmeelov? First time you faced an unknown anomaly with a psionic covering. Second time — Yakut the Hunter disappeared. All done by Anubis.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_8">
    <text>Psionic, huh. Probably the same one who attacked a scout from Khromy’s group.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_9">
    <text>Exactly. Finally, you’re understanding. We need to stop him at any cost.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_10">
    <text>But we don’t know what he wants…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_11">
    <text>I know what he wanted from you and how it ended. Most likely the Sinner’s interests match your current operations. You were supposed to meet Clear Sky agents regarding your task, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_12">
    <text>Supposed to. So?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_13">
    <text>Nothing good will come of it. I’ve learned more. We need to piece together how everything connects. Clear Sky tricked you — hired you to find a missing team and scientists. That team wasn’t for search — it was a strike team meant to kill those scientists. First attempt failed. Scientists fled here; I’ve tracked them.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_14">
    <text>Another twist. What a day… So they’re enemies too? Then who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_15">
    <text>Politics. No friends here, only players working for certain people. Clear Sky lied from the start. Hired you and others to find the missing team and scientists — they wanted them dead because they crossed Clear Sky. First attempt failed, scientists fled here, I tracked them.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_16">
    <text>Wait. So I wasn’t supposed to save them, but lead Clear Sky to them so they could kill them? Damn… Why did these scientists anger Clear Sky so much?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_17">
    <text>They were to deliver secret equipment to a stalker named Strelok. He planned a trip to the Zone Center at Chernobyl and Pripyat; without it, he couldn’t pass the Burner. Clear Sky wants to block him. So they decided to eliminate anyone helping him. They attacked the scientists, but don’t know if the gear reached Strelok’s group. That’s why they needed you. After you do your part — they’d kill you as an extra witness.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_18">
    <text>Hm, even more shocking. Even learning Anubis is a Sinner agent didn’t surprise me that much. What’s in it for you?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_19">
    <text>Simple. Investment in the future. Pure business. Nobody can imagine what wealth the Zone Center holds — anomalies, mutants, artifacts. Millions. So I want Strelok’s mission to succeed. We need to figure out the Sinner’s goal and stop Clear Sky. I know what to do about the second, Anubis is trickier.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_20">
    <text>How do we handle it?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_21">
    <text>Here’s the plan: You deal with Clear Sky for now. I’ll find out the Sinner’s exact goal. Don’t contact him. Forget him. Go through Karim; he sets up your meeting with the Sinner agent. Tell them you found the scientists, but won’t hand them over for free. Trick them, make them accept your terms. Exchange for payment and guarantees. You might need to eliminate them. Then I’ll contact you with further instructions.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_d5_killer_ceh_quest_1_dialog_22">
    <text>Alright. Hope I made the right choice.</text>
</string>

	
	<string id="topi_m2_killer_ceh_quest_5_dialog_0">
    <text>The Clear Sky problem is sorted. You were right. They would’ve killed me if I’d just handed over the scientists’ location. By the way, I never found them, did I? Got any info on that? And did you learn anything about the Sinner’s plans?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m2_killer_ceh_quest_5_dialog_1">
    <text>I found the scientists. Even before meeting you. But I didn’t get the chance to lead them out. They told me the full story — how Clear Sky attacked them and why. Luckily, they managed to deliver the necessary equipment to Strelok’s people. After that, I went searching for Anubis, but when I returned, I only found bodies. He beat me to it.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m2_killer_ceh_quest_5_dialog_2">
    <text>That’s bad. So, what now?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m2_killer_ceh_quest_5_dialog_3">
    <text>Now we know for sure the Sinner agent is also on this. He cares about Strelok’s mission to the Zone center. What he hopes to gain is still unclear. Also, I only found three scientist bodies. There were six when I met them. Where the rest went, I don’t know. But that’s not the worst part.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m2_killer_ceh_quest_5_dialog_4">
    <text>What else happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m2_killer_ceh_quest_5_dialog_5">
    <text>Hasan. That bastard. The Syndicate bet on this freak in vain. Should’ve worked with Harold. Though probably the same outcome. Anyway — the locals found out you wiped out the Clear Sky squad. When you clashed with Duty and Freedom, they covered your ass. With the birds, it’s much worse. Probably the Sinner helped. They’ve put a bounty on you. So, base access is blocked.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m2_killer_ceh_quest_5_dialog_6">
    <text>Great. And now what do you want me to do this time?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m2_killer_ceh_quest_5_dialog_7">
    <text>Nothing. We’ll cover our tracks and head north. Hasan failed us. Time to end this game. Yes, we’ll lose a lot, but that’s the price for the mess we’ve made here.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m2_killer_ceh_quest_5_dialog_8">
    <text>So I have to eliminate all the stalkers at the base?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m2_killer_ceh_quest_5_dialog_9">
    <text>Yes. No choice. I’ll provide the gear you need. They’re under the Sinner’s influence. No other explanation. We take them out and leave. We’ll monitor Strelok’s mission. To hell with Anubis — nothing more for us here.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_m2_killer_ceh_quest_5_dialog_10">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_k9_freedom_anubis_quest_6_dialog_0">
    <text>Just so you know, I’ve got nothing to lose. I know what you’re capable of — make a move.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_freedom_anubis_quest_6_dialog_1">
    <text>Relax. I won’t kill you — don’t even have a gun on me. Could’ve, many times — but didn’t…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_freedom_anubis_quest_6_dialog_2">
    <text>Speak your piece, then we part ways.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_freedom_anubis_quest_6_dialog_3">
    <text>Curious — what made you side with that fool Chekh? You know, there’s little difference between us Sinners and mercs. Everyone wants their slice of the Zone. Methods are almost the same — so why mercs?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_freedom_anubis_quest_6_dialog_4">
    <text>Their goals are clearer to me. I’m a merc too, agreed to work for Clear Sky. But your aims remain a mystery. Care to enlighten me?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_freedom_anubis_quest_6_dialog_5">
    <text>Why not. Simple. I need to open a path to the Zone center and block those who oppose it. In this case — Clear Sky. See? My goals align with mercs’…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_freedom_anubis_quest_6_dialog_6">
    <text>Got it. Strelok’s mission is important to you, but why exactly?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_freedom_anubis_quest_6_dialog_7">
    <text>You’ll find out soon, my friend. The mechanism’s in motion, unstoppable. Wonder where the other three scientists Chekh found went? I’ll tell you — they’re being led to the swamps, into the hands of those they tried to escape. But not by you, as planned — another merc. He’ll play a key role in the next act. Strelok starts his mission, the man follows. Many will die, the Zone will shake, but it’s the fair price… Everything resolves near Pripyat.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_freedom_anubis_quest_6_dialog_8">
    <text>What are you even talking about? Which merc, damn it? Pripyat?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_freedom_anubis_quest_6_dialog_9">
    <text>The real Pripyat. Anyway, I rambled. Hope you understood your role in this play. Part’s done, the second part’s the setup for act two. And remember — you’re like me. We’re alike. Thanks for that…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_freedom_anubis_quest_6_dialog_10">
    <text>What?</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_k9_killer_ceh_quest_6_dialog_0">
    <text>I met Anubis. We talked, but now he’s dead. You won’t believe what happened…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_killer_ceh_quest_6_dialog_1">
    <text>What? How? Tell me.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_killer_ceh_quest_6_dialog_2">
    <text>I cleared the clan base of stalkers. Then the Sinner contacted me and suggested a meeting. I knew it was a trap but went to end it. I was wrong. He didn’t intend to kill me — we talked, then he shot himself…</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_killer_ceh_quest_6_dialog_3">
    <text>Shot himself? Wait… What did you learn?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_killer_ceh_quest_6_dialog_4">
    <text>Just like that, he shot himself. Said his role is done, mine is just starting. Then — a bullet to the chin. He also told me what happened to the scientists he took from under your nose — sent them with some merc to the swamps. Why exactly — unclear. But our suspicion about Strelok’s group was right.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_killer_ceh_quest_6_dialog_5">
    <text>So that’s how it is. Clear enough then.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_killer_ceh_quest_6_dialog_6">
    <text>What exactly is clear?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_killer_ceh_quest_6_dialog_7">
    <text>Everything. We need to get out of here fast. Head north. I need to contact my command. Did he mention Pripyat?</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_killer_ceh_quest_6_dialog_8">
    <text>Yeah, he mentioned it, but the meaning was lost.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_killer_ceh_quest_6_dialog_9">
    <text>You think that. In reality, it’s clear. Big shocks are coming to the Zone. And we’re meant to be at the center… Let’s go, I’ll explain on the way.</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_k9_killer_ceh_quest_6_dialog_10">
    <text>As you say…</text>
</string>

	
</string_table>
