<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="topi_quest_medic_container_name">
    <text>ULM CASE 1 Emergency Medical Kit</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_quest_medic_container_desc">
    <text>ULM CASE I Circulation III Emergency Medical Kit (WM 5302, included). Aluminum case with plastic interior coating, dimensions 52.6?40?17 cm, weight 7 kg, compartments for accessories, 48 ampoule slots. Contents: Blood pressure monitor, Stethoscope, Pupil-check flashlight, Neurological hammer, Tourniquet, Tweezers 145?2 mm, Tweezers 145?3.2 mm, Scissors, Multi-purpose scissors, Spatula, Curved clamp, Disposable scalpels, Infusion system with manometer.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_spec_anomaly_scanner_1_name">
    <text>Anomaly Scanner</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_spec_anomaly_scanner_1_descr">
    <text>Special artifact scanner developed by a group of scientists from Yantar. An indispensable tool for simplified artifact detection, helping determine their presence within various anomalies. There are different modifications of this scanner with customized operating parameters. For example — scanners for acidic anomalies, gravitational, electrostatic anomalies, etc.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_example_taynik_item_name">
    <text>Military Backpack</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_example_taynik_item_descr">
    <text>Tactical backpack made of durable cordura with water-repellent coating and polyurethane lining. This model was originally developed for U.S. military special forces. Compact yet offers good storage capacity.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_topi_main_quest_document_1_name">
    <text>Scientist’s Notes</text>
</string>
<string id="st_topi_main_quest_document_1_descr">
    <text>Notes of a deceased scientist. "...We really shouldn’t have gotten involved in this. Really shouldn’t. We trusted the honesty of our partners. Smart scientists turned fools. They tricked us like children with three candies. You could say we sentenced ourselves and dug our own grave. That stalker isn’t going to survive anyway. He’ll be killed sooner or later, whether he reaches the Barrier or not. Only we won’t find out..."</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_components_1_name">
    <text>Component No. 1</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_components_1_desc">
    <text>The first component required to create an explosive device.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_components_2_name">
    <text>Component No. 2</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_components_2_desc">
    <text>The second component required to create an explosive device.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_components_3_name">
    <text>Component No. 3</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_components_3_desc">
    <text>The third component required to create an explosive device.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_name">
    <text>Explosive Device</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b9_anubis_fugas_desc">
    <text>An explosive device assembled from anti-personnel mines with preset fuse time and target sensor length.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_topi_anubis_fugascreate_device_name">
    <text>Explosive Device Crafting Equipment</text>
</string>
<string id="st_topi_anubis_fugascreate_device_descr">
    <text>Special kit required for safely dismantling anti-personnel mines and subsequently creating an explosive device from them.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a6_trader_documents_name">
    <text>Folder of Documents</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a6_trader_documents_desc">
    <text>Documents handed to you by a local trader. Contain information that would interest bandit groups in the Dump and other territories under their control. Exact contents are unknown.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_topi_mechanic_proto_device_1_name">
    <text>Gas Mask Assembly Device</text>
</string>
<string id="st_topi_mechanic_proto_device_1_descr">
    <text>Special portable device for preparing gas masks for field testing with various filters.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_topi_mechanic_proto_device_2_name">
    <text>Gas Mask Testing System Model 8020M</text>
</string>
<string id="st_topi_mechanic_proto_device_2_descr">
    <text>A portable system for testing gas mask protection against CBRN (chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear) threats. Evaluates the fit of a gas mask on an individual soldier. Results are displayed as a numerical fit coefficient. This tester does not require aerosol test chambers or tear gas chambers for mask evaluation. It can be used almost anywhere — at gas mask issuance points, training facilities, and even in the field.</text>
</string>

	
	<string id="topi_b1_leader_radiotion_item_name">
    <text>Dosimeter-Radiometer "MKS-07N (DKG-07BS)"</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_radiotion_item_desc">
    <text>The dosimeter is used for operational radiation monitoring, creating radiation maps of areas, and studying radiation anomalies. It can check contamination levels of clothing, equipment, buildings, and other objects. Can be used as a portable device (MKS-07N) or as a stationary/onboard measuring instrument (DKG-07BS).</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b1_leader_radiotion_doc_name">
    <text>Measurement Results</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_radiotion_doc_desc">
    <text>Media containing results measured by the dosimeter.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_item_name">
    <text>Radar Station "Kredo-1E"</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_item_descr">
    <text>The unified Kredo-1E radar station is designed for detecting moving ground targets (individuals, groups, vehicles) and for supporting artillery fire at any time of day or year, including in conditions of limited visibility (fog, dust, or smoke).</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_akum_1_name">
    <text>Battery</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_akum_1_descr">
    <text>One of the components of the radar complex.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_kabel_name">
    <text>Connection Cables</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_kabel_descr">
    <text>One of the components of the radar complex.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_naved_name">
    <text>Guidance Device</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_naved_descr">
    <text>One of the components of the radar complex.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_pered_name">
    <text>Transceiver Unit</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_pered_descr">
    <text>One of the components of the radar complex.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_blok_name">
    <text>Primary Processing Unit</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_blok_descr">
    <text>One of the components of the radar complex.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_comp_name">
    <text>Control Panel Unit</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_barsuk_taynik_1_comp_descr">
    <text>One of the components of the radar complex.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_1_name">
    <text>Filter VK 320</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_1_descr">
    <text>VK 320 filter, model A1B1E1K1R3, designed to purify inhaled air from organic vapors with boiling points above 65°C (cyclohexane, benzene, xylene, toluene, gasoline, kerosene, halogenated organics like chloropicrin, chloroacetophenone, etc.), nitro compounds of benzene and homologs, acetonitrile, aniline, ketones, tetraethyllead, etc.; inorganic gases and vapors (hydrogen cyanide, hydrogen sulfide, chlorine, fluorine, bromine, arsines, phosphine, etc.) excluding carbon monoxide; acidic gases and vapors (sulfur dioxide, hydrogen chloride, hydrogen fluoride, hydrogen bromide, sulfuric acid vapor, acetic acid vapor, formic acid vapor, nitric acid vapor, phosphoric acid vapor, etc.); ammonia and its organic derivatives; specific hazardous chemicals (chlorocyan, sarin, soman, phosgene, etc.); and aerosols in gas mask use during continuous or periodic operation, as well as for emergency exit from hazardous zones.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_2_name">
    <text>Filter VK 600</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_2_descr">
    <text>VK 600 filter, model A2B2E2K2R3, designed to purify inhaled air from organic gases and vapors with boiling points above 65°C (cyclohexane, benzene, xylene, toluene, gasoline, kerosene, halogenated organics, nitro compounds, acetonitrile, aniline, ketones, tetraethyllead, etc.); inorganic gases and vapors (hydrogen cyanide, hydrogen sulfide, chlorine, fluorine, bromine, arsines, phosphine, etc., excluding carbon monoxide); acidic gases and vapors; ammonia and organic derivatives; specific hazardous chemicals; and aerosols during continuous or periodic gas mask use, as well as emergency exits.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_3_name">
    <text>Filter VK 450</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_3_descr">
    <text>VK 450 filter designed to purify inhaled air from organic gases and vapors, inorganic gases, acidic gases, ammonia, specific hazardous chemicals, and aerosols in gas mask use during continuous or periodic operation, as well as for emergency exits from hazardous areas.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_4_name">
    <text>DPG-3</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_4_descr">
    <text>Additional DPG-3 cartridge for civilian gas masks GP-7, GP-7V, and children’s masks PDF-2D, PDF-2Sh to extend their operational range. Provides protection against toxic agents, radioactive dust, biological aerosols, and emergency chemical hazards such as ammonia, chlorine, dimethylamine, nitrobenzene, carbon disulfide, tetraethyllead, phenol, furfural, ethyl mercaptan, etc.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_5_name">
    <text>Filter DOT 460</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_filtr_5_descr">
    <text>DOT 460 filter provides respiratory protection in the PFMG-96 gas mask against hazardous chemicals. Gas masks with DOT 460 A2B2E2AX filters are used with a minimum of 17% oxygen in the air and harmful substance concentration not exceeding 0.5% by volume, in temperatures from -40°C to +40°C.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_1_name">
    <text>Gas Mask</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_1_descr">
    <text>Type 1 gas mask.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_2_name">
    <text>Gas Mask</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_2_descr">
    <text>Type 1 gas mask.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_3_name">
    <text>Gas Mask</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_3_descr">
    <text>Type 1 gas mask.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_4_name">
    <text>Gas Mask</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_4_descr">
    <text>Type 1 gas mask.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_5_name">
    <text>Gas Mask</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_maska_5_descr">
    <text>Type 1 gas mask.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_dathik_name">
    <text>Gas Mask Sensor</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_proto_dathik_descr">
    <text>Special sensor from the 8020M system for measuring parameters of the tested gas mask.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_1_name">
    <text>Type 1 Gas Mask</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_1_descr">
    <text>Tested variant RSh4 gas mask.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_2_name">
    <text>Type 1 Gas Mask</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_2_descr">
    <text>Tested variant PMK1 gas mask.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_3_name">
    <text>Type 1 Gas Mask</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_3_descr">
    <text>Tested variant PMK3 gas mask.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_4_name">
    <text>Type 1 Gas Mask</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_4_descr">
    <text>Tested variant PMG2 gas mask.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_5_name">
    <text>Type 1 Gas Mask</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_mechanic_protivogaz_5_descr">
    <text>Tested variant IP4 gas mask.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b11_radiostation_name">
    <text>Radio Station R-168-5KDNE</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b11_radiostation_descr">
    <text>The R-168-5KDNE radio station provides open and encrypted communication in HF/VHF bands for tactical control networks under harsh conditions, including frequency hopping operation. Manufactured by Yaroslavl Radio Plant.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b11_plata_1_name">
    <text>System Board No. 1</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b11_plata_1_descr">
    <text>One of the main system modules of the radio station.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b11_plata_2_name">
    <text>System Board No. 2</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b11_plata_2_descr">
    <text>One of the main system modules of the radio station.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b11_plata_3_name">
    <text>System Board No. 3</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b11_plata_3_descr">
    <text>One of the main system modules of the radio station.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b11_plata_4_name">
    <text>System Board No. 4</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b11_plata_4_descr">
    <text>One of the main system modules of the radio station.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b11_plata_3_paika_name">
    <text>System Board No. 3</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b11_plata_3_paika_descr">
    <text>One of the main system modules of the radio station.</text>
</string>

	<string id="topi_b11_multimetr_name">
    <text>Multimeter AM-1083</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b11_multimetr_descr">
    <text>Aktakom AM-1083 multimeters are designed to measure DC and AC currents (40–400 Hz) up to 20 A, voltage, resistance, capacitance, test diodes, and check circuit continuity.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b11_payalnik_name">
    <text>Soldering Station Lukey-852D+</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b11_payalnik_descr">
    <text>Digital hot air soldering station with soldering iron. Digital temperature display ensures precise control of hot air flow. Wide working temperature range allows use in various conditions.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b11_components_1_name">
    <text>Capacitor</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b11_components_1_descr">
    <text>Miniature aluminum electrolytic capacitor. ECAP (K50-35 mini), 0.1 µF, 50 V, 4?7 mm.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b11_components_2_name">
    <text>Transistor</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b11_components_2_descr">
    <text>KT117B, single-junction N-base low-power transistor [metal].</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b11_components_3_name">
    <text>Diode</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b11_components_3_descr">
    <text>1.5KE12(A), protective diode, 1500 W, 12 V, [DO-201].</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b11_zaglushka_name">
    <text>Resistor</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b11_zaglushka_descr">
    <text>CF-100 (C1-4), 1 W, 1.6 ?, 5%, carbon resistor.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b1_leader_vphr_item_name">
    <text>Military Chemical Recon Device</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_vphr_item_desc">
    <text>Device for detecting battlefield toxic agents in air, on terrain, and on equipment — sarin, soman, mustard gas, phosgene, diphosgene, hydrogen cyanide, chlorocyan, and V-series gas vapors. Works by passing air through indicator tubes which change color to estimate concentration of toxic agents.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b1_leader_vphr_doc_name">
    <text>Measurement Results</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b1_leader_vphr_doc_desc">
    <text>Media containing results obtained by the military chemical reconnaissance device.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_1_name">
    <text>Radio Station "Barmitsa-RS"</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_1_desc">
    <text>The Barmitsa-RS radio station provides open and encrypted phone communication with similar radios, as well as with R-159 and R-163/R-168 systems. Built-in speech scrambler. Designed for harsh field conditions. Lightweight, durable (parachute-capable), compact, with sealed metal dust- and water-resistant casing. Manufacturer: NPO "Rif", Voronezh, Russia.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_2_name">
    <text>CB Radio "Berkut-801MK"</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_2_desc">
    <text>The radio combines all advantages of the "Berkut" series: effective threshold noise suppressor (0.05–0.07 µV), high receiver sensitivity and selectivity, very high efficiency (80% transmitter efficiency with standard flexible antenna), ultra-low power reception mode, compact size and weight, high reliability in all weather and temperature conditions.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_3_name">
    <text>Radio "Tulip" (22RTP-2-CM)</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_3_desc">
    <text>Portable single-channel simplex VHF transistor radio "Tulip" (22RTP-2-CM) for non-search, automatic phone communication with similar radios and the 140–174 MHz range systems. Used in construction, railway, automotive, agriculture, for distances up to 1–2 km.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_4_name">
    <text>Radio "Erika-302"</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_4_desc">
    <text>Professional radio for extreme conditions. Metal and impact-resistant plastic body protects against shocks and drops. High-quality imported components ensure operation in extreme temperatures. Features 16 channels, two scan priorities, LED mode indicators. Manufacturer: JSC "Ural Radios", Izhevsk.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_5_name">
    <text>Radio "Granit 2R-44"</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a105_razia_type_5_desc">
    <text>Modern professional Russian radio. Supports simplex and half-duplex (can use a repeater). Available in two versions: basic 10-channel model and 100-channel model with scanning in three modes.</text>
</string>

	
	<string id="topi_zam_protocrafter_name">
    <text>Equipment for Crafting Poisoned Gas Mask</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_protocrafter_descr">
    <text>Special kit required to assemble a gas mask with a modified filter.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_zam_protivogaz_1_name">
    <text>Gas Mask IP4</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_protivogaz_1_descr">
    <text>Test batch version of the IP4 gas mask.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_zam_maska_1_name">
    <text>Gas Mask Facepiece</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_maska_1_descr">
    <text>Facepiece for the IP4 gas mask.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_zam_proto_filtr_1_name">
    <text>Filter VK 600</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_proto_filtr_1_descr">
    <text>VK 600 A2B2E2K2P3 filter designed to clean inhaled air from organic gases and vapors with boiling points above 65°C (cyclohexane, benzene, xylene, toluene, gasoline, kerosene, halogenated organics like chloropicrin, chloroacetophenone, etc.), nitro compounds of benzene and homologs, acetonitrile, aniline, ketones, tetraethyllead; inorganic gases and vapors (hydrogen cyanide, hydrogen sulfide, chlorine, fluorine, bromine, arsines, phosphine, etc., except carbon monoxide); acidic gases and vapors; ammonia and its organic derivatives; specific toxic chemicals (chlorcyan, sarin, soman, phosgene, etc.); and aerosols in continuous or periodic use, as well as for emergency evacuation from hazardous areas.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_zam_yad_1_name">
    <text>Capsule with CW</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_yad_1_descr">
    <text>Capsule containing chemical warfare agent based on sarin. Requires a special catalyst for activation.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_zam_katalizator_1_name">
    <text>Chemical Catalyst</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_zam_katalizator_1_descr">
    <text>Special catalyst needed to activate the poisonous agent.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b12_key_1_name">
    <text>First Container Key</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b12_key_1_descr">
    <text>One of two keys for the stash organized by Hassan’s people.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b12_key_2_name">
    <text>Second Container Key</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b12_key_2_descr">
    <text>One of two keys for the stash organized by Hassan’s people.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_lider_copromat_1_name">
    <text>Folder with Documents</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_copromat_1_desc">
    <text>Documents containing significant kompromat on Hassan. Includes smuggling schemes for artifacts, contacts with mercenaries, and a list of unwanted clan stalkers, some already eliminated.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_lider_spectrometr_1_name">
    <text>Portable Spectrometer "Responder RCI"</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_lider_spectrometr_1_descr">
    <text>Lightweight portable Raman spectrometer, ideal for identifying unknown liquids and powders. Analysis can be done by inserting a sample tube or remotely using a module to detect chemical composition in IR-transparent containers. Results in under 30 seconds.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_anubis_ukazanie_1_name">
    <text>Folder with Documents</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_ukazanie_1_desc">
    <text>Additional instructions from Anubis: "The situation with the scientists is clarified. This group cannot be extracted — too late. Prepare to eliminate them after dealing with the local stalkers."</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_bomba_name">
    <text>Explosive Device</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_anubis_var_2_bomba_descr">
    <text>Explosive device with preset detonation time and lethal elements in the form of chemical agents.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_detector_mine">
    <text>IMP-2</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector_mine_descr">
    <text>Induction mine detector, semiconductor, for individual use. Designed to find anti-tank and anti-personnel mines buried in soil or snow, with metal cases or fuses. Detects mines in bushes, grass, and shallow water. Developed in the 1970s by Tomsk Research Institute "Project", produced by Tomsk Measurement Equipment Factory. Improved version of IMP detector, used in Afghanistan war and still in army service.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_killer_ukazanie_1_name">
    <text>Folder with Documents</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_killer_ukazanie_1_desc">
    <text>Documents of a syndicate mercenary. Contains information about a "data drop" location, possibly in nearby caves or a village. Likely a stash or something similar.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_killer_ukazanie_2_name">
    <text>Folder with Documents</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_killer_ukazanie_2_desc">
    <text>Documents of syndicate mercenaries. Some contain artifact delivery estimates, mentioning the deputy leader of the free stalkers clan.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_f1_radioscaner_name">
    <text>Handheld Direction Finder "ARK-RP3"</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_f1_radioscaner_descr">
    <text>Used for radio monitoring, evaluating EM field intensity and signal parameters, locating radio sources, and recording radio signals and transmissions.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b41_seleczia_device_name">
    <text>Artifact Selection Device</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_seleczia_device_descr">
    <text>Prototype device developed by scientists in the Zone to alter artifact properties in anomalous formations.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b41_artefact_1_name">
    <text>Modified Artifact Type 1</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefact_1_descr">
    <text>Artifact with altered properties.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b41_artefact_2_name">
    <text>Modified Artifact Type 1</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefact_2_descr">
    <text>Artifact with altered properties.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b41_artefact_3_name">
    <text>Modified Artifact Type 1</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b41_artefact_3_descr">
    <text>Artifact with altered properties.</text>
</string>

	
<string id="topi_b19_quest_pnv_1_used_name">
    <text>Portable Night Vision Device "TNK-7"</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_quest_pnv_1_used_descr">
    <text>TNK-7 — multifunctional night vision device for observing, detecting, and identifying objects, including camouflaged ones, in dark or adverse conditions (fog, smoke, complete darkness). Features two channels: thermal imaging (384x288 microbolometer) and night vision (Gen 2++). Channels share a single eyepiece and can be switched or combined, overlaying thermal image on night vision.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b19_quest_pnv_2_used_name">
    <text>Night Vision Device "Kontur SP-301/303"</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_quest_pnv_2_used_descr">
    <text>Compact night vision devices for surveillance, reconnaissance, and security. Equipped with high-power optics and IR illuminators, they allow observation and recording at distances up to 500 m.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b19_quest_pnv_3_used_name">
    <text>Night Vision Device "Dedal-370-DK3"</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b19_quest_pnv_3_used_descr">
    <text>Lightweight, versatile night vision tool. Suitable for night observation, security, search, hunting, or night photo/video. Can be used as a monocular, attached to optics, cameras, or headgear. Two units can be combined into binoculars. Interchangeable lenses allow up to 9.6x zoom.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_c7_quest_device_1_name">
    <text>Jamming Generator "Druid D-06"</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_quest_device_1_descr">
    <text>Secure communication system for up to 6 users (12 with 2 devices). Protects against all known eavesdropping: radio microphones, stethoscopes, recorders, passive resonators, wired microphones, etc.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_c7_quest_device_2_name">
    <text>Electronic Protection Suite "Pelena-7K"</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_c7_quest_device_2_descr">
    <text>Protects against remote-controlled explosives and secures technical data. Can operate in stationary or portable modes.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_b65_zam_bomba_name">
    <text>Explosive Device</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_b65_zam_bomba_descr">
    <text>Directed explosive with preset detonation time, containing chemical warfare agent.</text>
</string>

<string id="topi_a65_zam_bomba_name">
    <text>Explosive Device</text>
</string>
<string id="topi_a65_zam_bomba_descr">
    <text>Directed explosive with preset detonation time, containing chemical warfare agent.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_topi_a2_main_tainik_title">
    <text>Stalker’s Backpack</text>
</string>
<string id="st_topi_a2_main_tainik_descr">
    <text>Backpack used as a stash, where a free stalker hid some supplies.</text>
</string>


</string_table>
