<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
<!--Buttons & Hint-->
<string id="st_ui_weapon_enciklopedia_item_name">
	<text>Encyclopedia of weapons.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_weapon_enciklopedia_item_descr">
	<text>Data on some models of small arms were collected. It is broken into five large chapters, according to their type.</text>
</string>
<string id="notepad_btn_sound_play">
	<text>Play Record</text>
</string>
<string id="notepad_btn_sound_stop">
	<text>Stop recording</text>
</string>
<string id="notepad_list_none">
	<text>Nothing selected</text>
</string>
<string id="notepad_list_empty">
	<text>the list is empty</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_notepad_button_weapons_use_1">
	<text>Assault rifles:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_notepad_button_weapons_use_2">
	<text>Sniper / Shotgun:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_notepad_button_weapons_use_3">
	<text>Pistols:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_notepad_button_weapons_use_4">
	<text>Other weapons:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_notepad_button_weapons_use_5">
	<text>Ammunition:</text>
</string>
<string id="notepad_btn_weapons_use_1_hint">
	<text>Section with information about assault rifles and assault rifles.</text>
</string>
<string id="notepad_btn_weapons_use_2_hint">
	<text>Section with information about sniper rifles and shotguns.</text>
</string>
<string id="notepad_btn_weapons_use_3_hint">
	<text>Section with information about pistols and n-machine guns.</text>
</string>
<string id="notepad_btn_weapons_use_4_hint">
	<text>Section with information about other weapons.</text>
</string>
<string id="notepad_btn_weapons_use_5_hint">
	<text>Section with information about ammunition.</text>
</string>
<!--/Buttons & Hint-->

<!--/Weapons & Guns-->

<string id="ui_notepad_button_weapons_use_1">
	<text>Assault rifles:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_notepad_button_weapons_use_2">
	<text>Sniper:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_notepad_button_weapons_use_3">
	<text>Pistols:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_notepad_button_weapons_use_4">
	<text>Melee:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_notepad_button_weapons_use_5">
	<text>Other weapons:</text>
</string>
<string id="notepad_btn_weapons_use_1_hint">
	<text>Section with information about assault rifles and assault rifles.</text>
</string>
<string id="notepad_btn_weapons_use_2_hint">
	<text>Section with information about sniper rifles.</text>
</string>
<string id="notepad_btn_weapons_use_3_hint">
	<text>Section with information about the pistols.</text>
</string>
<string id="notepad_btn_weapons_use_4_hint">
	<text>Section with information about shotgun p-machine guns.</text>
</string>
<string id="notepad_btn_weapons_use_5_hint">
	<text>Section with information about other weapons.</text>
</string>

<!-- Rifle -->
<string id="rifle1">
	<text>Akm 74/2U</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle1">
	<text>The shortened AK-74U automatic was developed in the late 1970s as part of the Modern program on the basis of the AK-74 full-time machine (in the AKS-74 version with a folding butt) specifically for arming the crews of combat vehicles, guns and other army personnel , For which the AK-74 state machine is too large. In addition to the army, Aks-74U is widely used in the Ministry of Internal Affairs, since it is compact and convenient when moving in a car and when operating in rooms. For the same reason, and also because it is easy to hide in a bag or under clothing, AKS-74U is popular among various security services for high-ranking government officials, as well as among bandits. \n In terms of its dimensions and weight, as well as the tactical niche, the AKS-74U is close to submachine guns, but due to the intermediate cartridge used and the mechanism of the staff automatic machine it is still a shortened automatic machine, not a PP. The advantages of AKS-74U include high mobility in cramped conditions (rooms, car salon), the possibility of concealed carrying, a rather high punching ability of the cartridge. Disadvantages - a small targeting range of fire (with a rather large slaughter range of the bullet), low bullet stopping effect, a tendency to rapid overheating when firing. \n AKS-74U is created with the maximum unification by nodes and details with AK-74 / AKS-74 automatic machines. It differs from the AKS-74:2 times the shortened barrel with correspondingly peredvinutoj ago gas kamoroj, shortened gas piston rod; a special muzzle, an employee of the expansion Chamber (for reliable operation of gas engine automatics) and flame; the receiver cover pivotally attached to the receiver in the front part of it; rear sight changeover, with installations on the 200 and 400 meters, is enshrined on the cover of the receiver. All mechanisms, controls and general device AKS-74U are similar to the device of the automatic device AKC-74.</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle2">
	<text>Akm 74/2</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle2">
	<text>AKS 74 - version AK 74 with a side-folding metal butt of pentagonal shape. It was created for use in airborne troops (an automatic machine with a non-folding butt can not be conveniently and safely placed in a suspended parachute system).</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle3">
	<text>AK-74M</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle3">
	<text>AK-74M - AK-74 modernized. Equipped with a folding sideways plastic butt and a universal mount (dovetail bar) for attaching sights, both optical and night, to the left side of the receiver. Thus, AK74M replaced four models at once: AK74, AKS74, AK74N and AKS74N. The coven and the barrel of the gas tube are made of impact-resistant glass-filled polyamide AG-4B. The changes also affected the muzzle brake, which received open cameras, which allows it to be cleaned without removing it. To reduce the probability of mechanical damage to the cover of the receiver, the latter was significantly strengthened. In the design of the guide rod of the return spring there was a lock, which allows to shoot from the grenade launcher GP-25 or GP-30 without using an additional fastening of the cover of the receiver, which is necessary in such cases for AK74. With the new automatic machines, it is possible to use the collimator sights PC-A and PC-01. In 1991, AK 74M was adopted and started its serial production at the Izhevsk Machine-Building Plant.</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle4">
	<text>AK-101</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle4">
	<text>The AK-101 Kalashnikov assault rifle is an export modification of the AK-74M full-time automaton of the Russian Army. The main (and in fact the only) difference between the AK-101 and the AK-74M is the caliber of the &quot;hundredth&quot; series. It uses cartridges of 5.56mm (5.56x45 NATO) caliber and the corresponding stores, while the other machines are identical.</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle5">
	<text>AK-103</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle5">
	<text>The AK-103 Kalashnikov assault rifle is an export modification of the AK-74M full-time automaton of the Russian Army. The main (and actually the only) difference between the AK-103 and the AK-74M is the caliber - this &quot;hundredth&quot; automatic machine uses cartridges of the caliber of 7.62mm (7.62x39 M43) and corresponding stores (compatible with the stores of older AK / AKMs), the rest Automata are identical. In 2006, a significant number of AK-103 assault rifles (100,000 pieces) were purchased in Izhevsk for the Armed Forces of Venezuela.</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle6">
	<text>AK-105</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle6">
	<text>Compact Kalashnikov assault rifle &quot;hundredth series&quot; caliber 5.45. It is based on full-size automatic devices of the same series, based on the standard automatic machine of the Russian Army AK-74M. The main differences from the &quot;full-sized&quot; brethren were a truncated barrel (314 mm) with a special blower-flame suppressor and a modified aiming bar, having a marking only up to 500 meters (for full-size 1000 samples). The machine has a foldable sideways plastic butt and a standard bar located on the left side of the receiver for the installation of optical or night sights. Constructively, it is completely analogous to the AK-74M.</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle7">
	<text>AK-107</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle7">
	<text>AK-107 and AK-108 assault rifles were developed at the Izhevsk Machine-Building Plant (IZHMASH) on the basis of earlier models created to participate in the competitive program &quot;Abakan&quot;. The main creators of new automata are Yu. K. Alexandrov and V. N. Paranin, and the design of these automata was based on the experimental Izhevsk AL-4 automata (developed back in the late 1960s) and AL-7 (later development). Both of these machines featured a so-called &quot;balanced&quot; automation, which in its idea is similar to that used in the AEK-971 automatic machine of the Kovrov Mechanical Plant. Such automation can significantly improve the performance of weapons when firing bursts of any length, in comparison with traditional Kalashnikovs, on the basis of which both AL-4 and AL-7 and AK-107/108 were developed. \n In fact, the main difference between the 5.45mm 5.45mm AK-107 and the 5.56mm AK-108 automatic rifles from the AK-74M and AK-101 Kalashnikov assault rifles, respectively, is the changed design of the automation, which received the second gas piston with anti-mass mounted on its stem and synchronizing Device located between the shutter frame and the balance bar. There are a number of differences, in particular, the modified design of the cover of the receiver, but they are less significant. AK-107 and AK-108 automatic machines differ from each other only by the used cartridges. Automation is built on a gas-discharge circuit with a long stroke of the gas piston and an additional balancer with its own, second gas piston moving in the opposite direction. Synchronization of the shutter frame and the balance bar is carried out by means of a gear located vertically between them. In addition, the original part is introduced into the design, excluding the rebound of moving parts when they come to the extreme position, corresponding to the front position of the shutter frame (at the end of the recharge cycle). The barrel is locked by a rotary bolt, similar in design to the Kalashnikov AK-74 automatic shutter.</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle8">
	<text>AKM</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle8">
	<text>AKM - Kalashnikov assault rifle Modernized. The machine, which replaced in 1959 in the armament of the Soviet Army AK and is its further development. The main differences between the AKM and its predecessor. Increased sighting range (from 800 m to 1000 m). New stamped receiver, which allowed to reduce the weight of the machine. A raised butt, which brought the fence to the firing line. Added trigger delay trigger, allowing the bolt frame to stabilize in the forward front position before another shot to increase the stability of the machine and increase the accuracy of combat. Increased stability in the horizontal plane by transferring the point of impact of the shutter frame in the front position from the right side to the left. A muzzle compensator that increased the accuracy of firing from unstable positions (on the move, standing, from the knee). Instead of it, a PBS or a nozzle for firing with empty cartridges can be mounted on the thread. A short (150 mm blade) detachable bayonet-knife was introduced, which was more economic and domestic than a combat mission. Instead of the second blade, he received a saw, and in combination with a sheath could be used to cut barbed wire fences.</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle9">
	<text>AKMS</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle9">
	<text>AKMS is a variant of AKM with a folding butt. The buttstock fastening system was changed with respect to the AKS (folded down-forward, under the receiver). The modification is specially designed for paratroopers.</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle10">
	<text>AK-94 &quot;Abakan&quot;</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle10">
	<text>In 1978, the Ministry of Defense of the USSR announced a tender for the creation of automatic weapons, superior to the combat qualities of the AK-74. The main requirement was to increase the effectiveness of shooting, including from uncomfortable positions: on the move, from the knee, without an emphasis. As a result of the preliminary study, a scheme with a shift in the recoil momentum was adopted for further development. \n
In 1981, the &quot;Abakan&quot; contest was announced, in which twelve models participated. According to the results of the competition, the automatic device AS (automatic with a biased recoil momentum), developed by Gennady Nikonov, was recognized as the most promising. By 1986, the Nikonov automatic was modified and named &quot;AFM&quot; (automatic with a shifted impulse, modernized). \n
In 1991, AFM passed state tests in the Taman Division, showing, in comparison with the AK-74, a significant increase in the accuracy of firing in fixed queues, even from inconvenient provisions. According to the test results, he was recommended for adoption. However, the process dragged on. In 1997, AFM under the official name &quot;5.45-mm automatic Nikonov arr. 1994. (AN-94) &quot;was adopted by the Russian Army, and the machine was given the name of the competition in which he defeated Abakan, although the initial plans (in the 1980s) assumed full rearmament of the army with new automatic weapons, modifications to the Kalashnikov assault rifle The role was played, both the complexity of the machine and the economic reasons. \n
The machine is characterized by high accuracy and accuracy of fire: when firing bursts of two rounds at a distance of 100 m, a good shooter hits two bullets at one point in the target. The high rate of the first two shots positively affects both the accuracy and effectiveness of shooting (compared to single shooting, the killer, stopping action and armor penetration increase significantly, the probability of hitting defended targets increases). Return on firing in fixed queues practically does not affect the accuracy of the fire, it is possible to fire the aimed fire without the assault of the submachine gun in the shoulder. However, it should be borne in mind that the displacement of the recoil momentum makes it possible to compensate for the recoil only from the first two shots. When firing long bursts, the effect of recoil compensation is practically absent, and the AN-94 proves to be accurate and scattered bullets at the same level as the AK-74.
</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle11">
	<text>OC-12 Tiss</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle11">
	<text>The compact automatic device OTS-12 &quot;Tiss&quot; was developed in the early 1990&apos;s in the Tula Central Design Bureau of Sport and Hunting Weapons (TsKIB SOO). This machine was intended for arming the personnel of the Ministry of Internal Affairs. A small batch of OTs-12 submachine guns was released in 1993 at the TsKIB SOO, but serial production was not deployed that way. At present, a small number of OTs-12 automatic machines are still in service with a number of units of the Ministry of Internal Affairs of Russia. On the device the compact automatic device OTS-12 &quot;Tiss&quot; completely repeats the Kalashnikov AK-74U automatic machine, differing only from the barrel with the muzzle device (muzzle brake-compensator), the dimensions of the shutter mirror and the magazine (for cartridges 9x39 SP-5 and SP-6) .</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle12">
	<text>AKS-74UB-6S1 &quot;Canary&quot;</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle12">
	<text>Silent grenade launcher Canaryka: BS-1M grenade launcher on AKS-74UB automatic machine with PBS-4 silencer. The leather lining on the front of the machine serves to cover the bracket for installing the grenade launcher on the forearm when the grenade discharger is removed from the weapon. The machine is equipped with a rare magazine for 20 rounds, the grenade launcher sight is complicated. \n In connection with the adoption of a new complex of small arms for the Soviet troops and a massive supply of 5.45mm ammunition, a need arose to adapt a noiseless underbarrel grenade launcher to a new weapon. Since the acceptable results when firing 5.45 US silencers with ammunition were achieved only on shortened AK-74U (UB) automatic guns, a new version of the complex, designated 6C1 &quot;Canary&quot;, was designed specifically for this machine. While maintaining the overall design of the grenade launcher and grenade and their general appearance, the CNII TOCHMASH designers were able to increase both the efficiency of the grenade&apos;s combat part and the range of fire from the grenade launcher, while special blank cartridges of caliber of 5.45x39 instead of the empty cartridge of the caliber of 7.62x39 mm were used. \n Approximately from the beginning of the eighties a noiseless 30mm grenade launcher complex 6C1 &quot;Canaryka&quot; consisting of: a grenade launcher BS-1M, an AKS-74UB automatic rifle and a PBS-4 muffler began to enter the units of the special forces of the Soviet Army.</text> 
</string>
<string id="rifle13">
	<text>AEK-971</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle13">
	<text>The AEK 971 automatic was developed in the 1980s at the Kovrov Machine-Building Plant (KMZ) under the direction of SI Koksharov within the framework of the &quot;Abakan&quot; competition program. The design feature of AEK971 is a scheme with balanced automatics based on a gas engine (similar to the AK-107/108). \n In this scenario, additional gas piston that is associated with the protivomassoj, moves synchronously with the main transferring bolt frame, but to meet him, thereby compensating the pulses that occur when moving the bolt group and when it blows back and forward position (it is not a secret that one of the features of the design avtmatov Kalashnikova, providing high reliability of weapons — the coming of automation moving parts in an extreme situation with considerable speed, and hence in moments the movement of the bolt group automatic gets significant and multidirectional movement impul&apos;zy, adversely affecting accuracy of automatic fire). As a result, the shooter feels only the impulse from kickbacks at the shots, and the machine does not twitch when shooting the bursts, but as it sticks to the shoulder. Thus, in the automatic device AEK971 it was possible to achieve the accuracy of automatic firing in 2 or more times better than that of AKM or AK-74 guns (when firing from AEK973 caliber 7.62 mm and AEK 971 caliber 5.45 mm respectively).</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle14">
	<text>AEK-973C</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle14">
	<text>AEK-973C - version AEK-973, with retractable telescopic butt, modified shape and angle of inclination of the pistol grip. Cartridge 7.62h39 mm, frame stock is not folded, but moves into the receiver, the flag of the fuse - the translator of the fire on the right side of the receiver. The shape of the pistol grip was changed. For convenient retention of the machine with a retracted butt.</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle15">
	<text>OTS-14-4A-01 &quot;Groza-4&quot;</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle15">
	<text>The OZ-14 automatic-grenade launcher complex was developed in Tula, in the TsKIB SOO, and was produced in small batches at the Tula Arms Plant in the mid-1990s. The development of the automatic-grenade launcher complex for close combat was started in 1992 by designers Valery Teles (developer of 40mm grenade launchers GP-25 and GP-30) and Yuri Lebedev, and in 1994 the first prototypes were ready. The main idea of ??creating a specialized complex was that the traditional installation of a grenade launcher for a regular automatic weapon (whether AK-74 or M16A2) greatly worsens the balance of weapons, and therefore it is necessary to design weapons from the outset, taking into account the installation of a grenade launcher. In addition, due to the modular design of the weapon, it was supposed to achieve great flexibility in its application. \n Initially, this machine-grenade launcher complex was created for special forces of the Ministry of Internal Affairs for special 9mm rounds of SP-5 and SP-6. The variant &quot;Groza-1&quot; (another designation - TKB-0239) was created for the army special forces under the widely used cartridge 7.62x39. The automatic device OTs-14 &quot;Groza&quot; was created on the basis of the receiver and the mechanisms of the automatic device AKC-74U. The main changes concerned adaptation of the shutter to another cartridge with a large diameter of the bottom of the cartridge case and a shock-trigger mechanism. In addition, OC-14 is arranged according to the bullpup scheme, so that the pistol grip of the fire control is moved forward, in front of the magazine, and the butt of the butt is attached directly to the rear of the receiver. Sparkle the OC-14 — variable configuration: base machine can be used in the assault carbine, submachine gun variants (with extended nadul&apos;nikom and the front auxiliary handle to hold), silent submachine gun (silencer), trial-grenade launchers (native fire control handle and handguards are replaced by fire control handle with trigger switch &quot;automatic-Launcher&quot; and a 40 mm underbarrel grenade launcher). The OTs-14 automatic machine was tested in the course of the anti-terrorist operation in Chechnya, but it did not find much popularity and did not get into mass production.</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle16">
	<text>AS &quot;VAL&quot;</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle16">
	<text>AS &quot;Val&quot; (Automatic Special) - a silent automatic machine developed in Klimovsk Central Research Institute of Mechanical Engineering by designers P. Serdyukov and V. Krasnikov in the second half of the 1980s, together with the silent rifle sniper rifle and the armament of special purpose units of Russia. &quot;Val&quot; and &quot;Vintorez&quot; are unified by 70%, which positively affects production and operation. The machine is designed for special units of the state security and internal affairs agencies. \n
The automaton is built on the basis of a gas operated automatic system with a long working stroke of a gas piston. The application is a tubular folding left metal, strong enough for use in close combat, when folded, it does not prevent shooting. Pistol grip, fore and two-row shops - plastic. The integrated silencer also plays the role of a flame arrestor. Thanks to him and the cartridges with subsonic speed, the sound pressure level at the shot is 130 dB. The fire mode interpreter is located at the back of the trigger guard, and the fuse and the recharge handle are on the right. \n
It uses special 9-mm subsonic cartridges SP-5 and SP-6. The bullet of the sniper cartridge SP-5 (with a steel core) breaks the bulletproof vests of the 2nd class or the 6-mm steel sheet at a range of 100 m, and the 2-mm - at the entire distance of aiming, while retaining sufficient energy to defeat the hiding enemy. Armor-piercing cartridge SP-6 with an enlarged core of hardened steel is able to disable a car and even lightly armored vehicles. It punches an 8-mm steel sheet at a range of 100 m, and a 5-mm steel sheet or bulletproof vests of the third class - at the entire distance of aiming. These indicators are comparable with those of standard cartridges of 5.56 mm, 5.45 mm caliber, which have at times greater muzzle energy. \n
Disassembled on the main units (receiver with trunk, automatics, USM and forearm, silencer with impact devices, butt), the machine is transported in a special case along with sights and shops. The assembly takes from 30 to 60 seconds depending on the preparation of the arrow.
</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle17">
	<text>WZ-96 «Beryl»</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle17">
	<text>The design and operation principle of the Kbs wz.96 Beryl automatic machine are the same as in the wz.88 Tantal automaton, the main changes were made to the design of a longer barrel (457 mm long, the barrel had 6 right rifling in 228 mm steps), a new slotted muzzle brake- A flame arrester, a receiver, a forehead, sighting devices, a magazine, as well as a butt. The metal butt, which flips to the right toward the receiver, received a more robust frame-type construction, borrowed from the Belgian FNC assault rifle. The back of the butt was equipped with a rubber lining, which helped to partially quench a powerful kickback when fired from a grenade launcher. \n
The trigger and trigger mechanism with two-way controls remained the same, designed to handle a single, fixed by three shots and automatic fire. To stabilize the weapon when firing automatic fire, a light metal bipod falcon is used, which is put on the trunk of the machine. &quot;BERIL&quot; can be equipped with a 40-mm grenade launcher Kbk-g wz.1974 Pallad and his sight. The flame arrester is designed to fire rifle grenades in the NATO standard. \n
The trunk box was slightly different from the receiver box of the kbk wz.88. The gun received a new plastic forearm and a gas chamber trim. However, the shape and execution of the forehead changed. Unlike the fore-end used in the machine Kbk wz.88 Tantal, it has acquired a different shape and has received diagonal ribs, for better retention of the weapon. \n 
On the Kbs wz.96 Beryl master lid, a special quick-release lath can be installed to mount a variety of sights: night IR PCS-6, collimator SK-3, optical LKA-4 or laser target designator CWL-1. Power is provided from 30-charge upgraded stores from KA wz.90. A blade knife is included in the kit for 5.56 mm Kbs wz.96 Beryl.
</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle18">
	<text>Steyr AUG A2</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle18">
	<text>Steyr AUG (Armee Universal Gewehr - army universal rifle) - a small arms complex, issued in 1977 by the Austrian company Steyr-Daimler-Puch. Adopted by such countries as Austria, New Zealand, Luxembourg and Ireland. In Australia, the rifle is manufactured under license under the brand F88. It has exchangeable trunks of different lengths: the main one is 508 mm, as well as truncated trunks 350 mm and 407 mm and heavy trunk 621 mm. In this rifle, the &quot;Bull-pop&quot; layout scheme is applied, in which the magazine and the shutter assembly are located behind the fire control handle and trigger. There are two modes of fire: fire with single shots and automatic fire. It is also possible to upgrade to fire single and with a cutoff of 3 rounds. There is no translator for fire regimes. The choice of modes is carried out by the depth of depression. A weak depression results in a single shot. Pressing to the stop causes automatic fire by an arbitrary burst. The rifle can be equipped with an American 40 mm grenade launcher M203 \n
Steyr AUG A2 differs from the basic model with the presence of a universal attachment for the NATO standard sights (Wiver bar) and a folding front handle.
</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle19">
	<text>Colt M16A2</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle19">
	<text>M16A2 - version of the rifle M16A1, adapted for the cartridge SS109 / M855. Differences from the M16A1: strengthened by hard trunk with rifling pitch 1:7, improved sights, spaced up to 800 m, a new handguard and Buttstock made of impact resistant polyamide, replacement of continuous fire mode with the queue after 3-x shots (in service with the Marine Corps enrolled version of the M16A2 with the possibility of conducting continuous fire), the new Flash Hider with slots only at the top (thereby offset by disposal of arms upwards). The new rifle began to be equipped with light plastic stores for 30 rounds. In the modification M16A2, a reflector appeared, which allows the shooter to fire from the left shoulder, without fear of hitting the shells in the face. The rifle can be fitted with a 40 mm M203 underbarrel grenade launcher.</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle20">
	<text>Colt M16A4</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle20">
	<text>The assault rifle Colt M16A4 was adopted by the United States armed forces in 1994 together with the M16A3. The M16A4 rifle differs from the A2 by the presence of the Picatinny bar on the receiver for attaching any types of sighting devices.</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle21">
	<text>Colt M4A1</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle21">
	<text>In 1996, by order of special operations forces based on the M16A3 rifle, a similar M4A1 carbine was developed, featuring a return to fully automatic fire instead of a 3-shot fire. Modification M4A1, in addition to a short trunk and a telescopic butt, received a replaceable handle for carrying and accordingly a replaceable sight (optical, collimating or night sights can be installed). \n
At the same time, for the carbines M4 and M4A1, a basic version was adopted with a removable carrying handle mounted on an integral rail of the Picatinny rail type. Based on the M4A1 carbine, the US Navy&apos;s Ground Operations Center developed a special set of components called the SOPMOD M4 kit. The set has a M4A1 carbine as a core with an RIS (RIS) rail interface system. On the Picatinny to the receiver carbine, and guides on RIS foregrip can be different elements of the package: sights-optical 4 x ACOG, collimator (&quot;red dot&quot;) ACOG, outdoor detachable rear sight; Laser designators of visible and infrared range; night sights; flashlights; front handle; a modified 40-mm grenade launcher М203 with short barrel and improved sight. In addition, the kit includes a quick-detachable silencer, which is worn directly on the standard flame arrester of the carbine.\n
The new carbine model was also adopted by the special operations forces of the United States. From a technical point of view, the M4 and M4A1 models hardly differ from the corresponding versions of the M16A2 and M16A3 rifles.
</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle22">
	<text>FAMAS F1</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle22">
<text>The FAMAS rifle in all versions has a bullpup configuration (the magazine and chamber are located behind the trigger and the pistol grip of the fire control). FAMAS uses a rather rare scheme of automation with a free gate, which has a retarder of opening in the form of a lever. The shutter group FAMAS consists of two parts - an easier shutter itself and a heavier shutter frame. The double-armed lever is mounted on the shutter, its lower arm at the front (closed) position of the bolt rests against a special transverse pin in the receiver, and the upper one - into the shutter frame. When shot, the powder gases pressurize the bottom of the cartridge case, forcing it to move back in the chamber, and press on the shutter mirror. In this case, the lower arm of the lever rests against a stationary pin, and the upper arm transfers motion to the massive bolt frame. Due to the difference in the shoulders at the first moment after the shot, the shutter itself moves slowly, and the bolt frame is mostly accelerated. By the time the pressure in the chamber drops to a safe, the retarder lever disengages from the pin, and further the shutter with the bolt frame moves together, at the same speed, compressing the return spring. At the same time, the fired sleeve is ejected and thrown out, and a new cartridge is supplied on the reverse course of the bolt group. The retarder also serves as a fuse against a shot when the shutter is not open, as it swings back from the starting position and retracts the hammer and blocks it before the bolt group is placed in the closed position. \n
	Another feature of the FAMAS shutter is that it has two symmetrical sockets for the extractor, and the extractor itself can be rearranged to the right or left after partial disassembly. In combination with a spring-loaded plunger ejector located along the axis of the bolt below the drummer and two windows for ejecting cartridge cases on both sides of the gun, this allows you to quickly remake the FAMAS to extract the sleeves to either side. The currently unused window for ejecting the sleeves is closed with a removable plastic cover, which also serves as a stop for the cheek on the butt. The loading handle looks like a hook and is located above the barrel, in the opening of the handle for carrying. When firing, the load handle is stationary. The trunk of FAMAS is unusual in that it has only 3 right cuts with a pitch of one turn of 228 millimeters, which makes it possible to use practically any cartridges of 5.56mm caliber - old ones with a light bullet, such as the American M193, and newer ones with a heavier bullet, type 5.56 Mm NATO / M855 / SS109. \n
	The flame arrester can be used to throw rifle grenades directly from the barrel. The chamber has longitudinal grooves (the so-called Revelly grooves), facilitating the extraction of shells in systems with a semi-free closure. The trigger-trigger mechanism FAMAS - hammer, is made in the form of a separate quick-detachable module. A flasher fuse-fire translator is located inside the trigger guard, in front of the trigger. The main modes are &quot;fuse&quot;, &quot;single shots&quot;, &quot;automatic fire&quot;. Additionally, on the body of the USM behind the magazine there is a switch that turns on or off the additional shooting mechanism with bursts of 3 rounds. The FAMAS trunk box is compact enough, most of the weapons body parts, including fore-end, butt, USM body and carrying handle, are made of plastic. \n
	Sights in the form of a fly and dioptric head are installed on the barrel on special racks hidden in the handle for carrying. A guide for optical sights can be attached to the carrying handle, and folding lightweight bipod from aluminum is available at the front. FAMAS rifles are equipped with a strap for carrying and bayonet knife, in addition, they can be installed 40mm grenade launcher M203. \n
</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle23">
	<text>HK 416 D10RS</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle23">
	<text>HK416 - automatic rifle, created by the German firm Heckler Koch on the basis of the carbine M4. Initially, the new weapon was to be a plug-in module for installation on any lower part of the receiver from M4 or M16 rifles, but later there were full-automatic machines. The name HK416 symbolizes continuity from the M4 and M16. The HK416 is available in four different versions with only the barrel length and the corresponding mass: - HK416 D20RS - with a barrel length of 505 mm. - HK416 D16.5RS - with a barrel length of 419 mm. - HK416 D14.5RS - with a barrel length of 368 mm. - HK416 D10RS - with a barrel length of 264 mm. \n
The direct gas discharge system M16 has been replaced with the scheme used in the HK G36 with a short stroke of the gas piston, more reliable and resistant to pollution. Improvements to the gas exhaust engine also helped to eliminate the problems with overheating when firing bursts, typical for the M4. The shutter and the return mechanism were also improved. The gate delay mechanism and the traditional T-shaped shutter cocking handle were retained. Three-position fuse-translator of shooting modes allows to fire with single shots and continuous bursts. The barrel of increased survivability is made by the method of cold forging and withstands more than 20,000 shots. The barrel box is made of aluminum alloy, the shops are made of steel (standard stores for M16 can also be used). The trunk is hung in the fore arm. The machine has Picatinny slats on the upper plane of the receiver, as well as on four sides of the fore-end, thus enabling the use of a wide range of accessories. The multiposition telescopic butt is similar in design to that of M4.
</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle24">
	<text>HK 417 «Assaulter Model»</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle24">
	<text>Based on the experience gained by the troops of the international coalition in Afghanistan and Iraq, where in certain conditions a 5.56x45 mm gun showed insufficient effective range and insufficient penetration and stopping action, Heckler-Koch in early 2005 started developing a new 7.62x51 weapon Mm. \n
The new 7.62 mm automatic rifle developed by Heckler-Koch, under the designation HK417, is based on an automatic HK416 rifle of 5.56 mm caliber of the same company. \n
In 2007, the rifles of the NK 417 series were launched into batch production and offered for arming the army and police forces. \n
The HK417 rifle, similar to the HK416, has a modular design that largely resembles the design of the American M16 rifle, with one important difference: the German HK417 rifle has a modified gas control automatic system using a conventional gas piston with a short stroke. There are a number of other differences, however, all the main controls and the method of disassembling and assembling weapons are inherited from the M16, which is primarily due to the fact that one of the main sales markets for the HK417 was originally intended by the US. \n
</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle25">
	<text>Colt Commando Model 933</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle25">
	<text>After adopting the M16A3 and M16A4 assault rifles in the 1990s, the Colt Commando Model 933 was developed based on their principle, which received a new receiver with a universal rail instead of an integral carrying handle, and the possibility of installing additional guides instead of forearm. \n
From a technical point of view, the compact automatic model Colt Commando almost does not differ from the corresponding versions of the M16 rifle. \n
The machine has the same aluminum aluminum alloy box, consisting of two parts, the same automation with a direct discharge of powder gases to the shutter frame and a rotary valve with 8 arms. \n
The return spring is in the butt, and therefore all variants of the Commando are equipped not folding sideways or down, but with telescopic butts. \n
Depending on the model, Colt Commando can have a fully automatic fire mode or fire with a 3-round turnout (in addition to the mandatory single-shot mode).\n
Various versions of the Colt Commando were adopted by the US Special Forces, as well as supplied to other countries, including Israel and the Philippines \n
</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle26">
	<text>SIG 716 Tactical Patrol</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle26">
	<text>In 2010, the American division of the international arms concern SIG-Sauer offered a whole family of self-loading rifles SIG 716 caliber 7.62 mm NATO. \n
In addition to the SIG 716 Tactical Patrol and SIG 716 Patrol assault rifles, the SIG 716 also included the SIG 716 Precision Sniper sniper rifle. \n
The entire family of SIG 716 rifles was created in the same scheme and in the same design as the SIG 516 of the 5.56 NATO caliber, with the exception of changes associated with the use of the cartridge 7.62x51 mm. In this case, the sniper rifle differs from the automatic rifles (assault rifles) with only longer trunks manufactured with greater accuracy, and with a regulated butt. \n
In fact, this weapon, like the SIG 516, is an attempt to improve the AR-15 / M16 rifle system, which has become popular in the US, by abandoning the most controversial element of this design - a direct gas outlet inside the bolt frame, and also offering weapons of the newly gaining caliber 7.62 mm NATO. \n
By design, the SIG 716 rifle is similar to the SIG 516 and repeats the AR-15 / M16 system. \n
Automation SIG 716 - gas discharge, however, instead of a long gas tube above the barrel a separate gas piston with a short working stroke is installed, through a special rod transmitting impulse to the gate frame. A three-position manual gas regulator is provided in the design of the gas outlet. The rotary shutter is made standard for systems of the AR-15 / M16 type, however, taking into account the increased caliber. \n
The upper and lower halves of the receiver are similar to the base platform and are made of aluminum alloy, corrected for larger sizes. \n
	</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle27">
	<text>Magpul Masada ACR</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle27">
	<text>The Magpul Masada is one of the variants of the Magpul Masada ACWS (Adaptive Combat Weapon System) system, which allows you to change the caliber and class of weapons in minimum time and without using tools. So a compact rifle can at will of an arrow become a &quot;full-size&quot; machine gun or a tactical sniper rifle. \n
The Magpul Masada ACWS system consists of the following main weapons options: \n
- Carbine - a carbine, with a barrel length of 14.5 inches (368 mm). The application is combinable, foldable and adjustable in length. The appliance is provided with a two-position adjustable cheek. \n
- CQB - rifle for melee, with a barrel length of 10.5 inches (267 mm). It is supplied with a shortened version of fore-end, with additional guides. \n
- SPR - sniper version, with a barrel length of 18 inches (457 mm). It is equipped with the butt of PRS (manufactured by Magpul). Sniper&apos;s butt - adjustable in length and height. \n
- AK - Masada rifle, but under the caliber of 7.62x39 mm (the cartridge used in the AK-47 Kalashnikov assault rifle). In addition to the barrel and the shutter group in the AK, the lower receiver also changes.\n
The rifle consists of 6 main modules: a receiver (from 2 parts, upper and lower receiver), a gate frame with a bolt, a barrel with a gas removal mechanism, butt and a barrel. \n
The upper part of the receiver (the so-called upper receiver) is stamped from aluminum. Inside it are installed guides for the shutter frame, made of steel in the form of one piece. On the top of the receiver, along its entire length, the Picatinny guide is installed, allowing the installation of various sighting devices. The lower receiver (the lower part of the receiver) is made of high-strength polymer with a single pistol grip and a magazine receiver.
</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle28">
	<text>FN-F2000 «Tactical»</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle28">
	<text>
	F2000 Tactical - is similar to the standard model, however it lacks an optical sight, instead of which an additional guide of the Planck Picatinny type is installed, as well as open sighting devices. \n
Automation F2000 operates due to the removal of powder gases, locking the barrel by turning the shutter. The layout is bullpup. Thanks to the patented scheme of frontal extraction of shot cartridges (the sleeves fall out almost at the muzzle), the main problem of the weapon of such a layout is solved - the impossibility of using the weapon by a left-handed shooter due to the hit of cartridge cases in the face. In this case, the weapon can be used by both left-handers and right-handers without alterations, in contrast to Steyr AUG or FAMAS. The location of the two-way fuse / interpreter of the fire modes under the trigger guard also ensures the &quot;two-sidedness&quot; of the system. \n
The materials of the case are polymers, fore-plastic, easily removable, in the place of which can be installed various additional modules: laser target designator, flashlight, 40-mm grenade launcher, &quot;non-lethal&quot; module M303, intended for shooting capsules containing paint or tear gas. In the future, other modules can be installed at the request of the customer. The standard sight is an optical multiplicity of 1.6X with a wide field of view. It can be quickly replaced by any other sight with appropriate attachments, for example, a special computerized fire control module. \n
This module includes a laser rangefinder and a ballistic computer that places a sighting mark of the sight both for firing from the machine itself and from the grenade launcher (if it is installed), based on data on the range to the target. With this module F2000 can be considered as a cheaper analogue of the American system OICW. \n
	</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle29">
	<text>Heckler-Koch XM8</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle29">
	<text>The modular XM8 rifle practically does not differ from the German rifle Heckler-Koch G36, based on which it was created. XM8 has the same scheme of automation with a short stroke of the gas piston located above the barrel and locking the barrel by turning the bolt, which has 7 fighting stops. The trunk box, fore-end, butt are made of high-strength plastic. Barrels XM8 quick change, it is assumed that, depending on the desired configuration, the following types of barrels will be used: length 318 mm in the base version; Length of 229 mm in the version Compact / PDW; 508 mm in the version of the sniper rifle and 508 mm weighted - in the Automatic Rifle version, that is, the machine gun. \n
	The attachments are also easily changeable, the five-position telescopic butt, which is adjustable in length, is considered to be the main one. Instead of the standard forehead, it is possible to install a 40mm single-shot grenade launcher XM320 (modified Heckler-Koch AG36) with a standard trunk, or fore-end with an integrated bipod with a machine gun barrel. Carrying handle - also removable, has attachments for various sights. \n
	As the main sight, a collimating sight of the &quot;red dot&quot; type with battery backlighting is assumed, and various other sights are also possible. A two-way translator - the fuse is located above the pistol grip and provides firing by single shots and bursts, fire with a cutoff of the queue for 2 or 3 shots is not planned. The shutter handle is located above the receiver, type G36, and is available for both hands. The supply of cartridges is carried out from detachable box magazines for 30 cartridges or, in the machine gun version, also from 100-cartridge drums.
	</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle30">
	<text>FN Mk.16 SCAR-L</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle30">
	<text>Fabrique Nationale Mk.16 FN SCAR-L (Light) is a 5.56 NATO automatic machine. The basis of SCAR automatics is a gas engine with a short stroke of a gas piston separate from the shutter frame. The upper half of the receiver is made of aluminum, the lower one is made of polymer. Replacement trunks are attached to the upper half by two transverse bolts. The fuse-translator of the shooting modes is displayed on both sides of the weapon, the shooting modes are single and continuous bursts. On both sides of the top of the receiver there are cutouts for installing the cocking cock. The lock button on the magazine is also duplicated. The plastic butt is folded sideways, and is also adjustable in length. In addition, a 40 mm grenade launcher or front handle can be installed.</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle31">
	<text>Heckler-Koch G36KE</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle31">
	<text>G36K (Kurz) - a shortened version, the automatic with a barrel length of 318 mm G-36 is built on the basis of automation with a gas engine with a short stroke of the gas piston. The rotary shutter, with 7 radial arms, is located in the slide frame, which moves along one guide rod, on which a return spring is fitted. On the upper surface of the shutter frame there is a cocking handle protruding above the upper surface of the receiver. In the marching position, the cocking handle is located along the axis of the weapon and is held in this position by a spring, and for cocking it can be bent to either side by approximately 90 degrees. When firing, the handle moves with the bolt frame. The barrel is made of plastic with steel inserts, the USM is made as a single unit with a pistol grip and trigger guard, and is attached to the receiver with transverse pins. Shock-trigger mechanism can be supplied in several versions - with or without a shooting mode with cutoffs of 2 or 3 cartridges. The plastic fore-end is also attached to the receiver with pins, so that only a cartridge or other object suitable for pushing the pins out of the holes is required for incomplete disassembly. \n
The rifle at the G36 has a collapsible sidewall, made of plastic. On the upper surface of the receiver there is a large carrying handle, in the back of which there are sighting devices. The standard G36 rifle for the Bundeswehr has two scopes - an optical multiplicity of 3.5X, and a collimating sight (&quot;red dot&quot;) positioned above it, intended for use at short distances. The export version of the G36E rifle and the shortened &quot;carbine&quot; G-36K have only one optical sight with a multiplicity of 1.5X. An even shorter version of the G36C (C stands for Compact or Commando) instead of the handle for carrying has universal guides such as Picatinny for attaching any type of sight. \n
Power G36 is made from transparent plastic stores with 30 rounds, having special fasteners for combining stores into &quot;packages&quot; to speed up recharging. Since the store receiver on the G-36 is designed in accordance with NATO standards, the G-36 can use any standard stores, including the Beta-C double drum shops for 100 rounds. \n
</text>
</string>
<string id="rifle32">
	<text>FN FAL «Paratrooper»</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_automatic_rifle32">
	<text>FN FAL 50.63 (FN &quot;Paratrooper&quot;) - option for airborne troops (truncated barrel and folding metal butt). The FAL rifle is an automatic weapon built on the basis of gas automatic control. The rifle uses a scheme with a short stroke of the gas piston, similar to those used in SAFN-49 and SVT-40 rifles. The gas piston is located above the barrel and has its own return spring. The gas chamber is equipped with a gas regulator, which allows to adjust the automatics to the existing conditions of the weapon operation or to completely cut off the gas escape line, which is necessary for starting from the barrel of rifle grenades. Locking the barrel is made by skewing the back of the shutter down, behind a special ledge in the bottom of the receiver. The shutter is mounted in a massive bolt-on frame, after firing a short powerful thrust from the gas piston and then moving along the inertia, compressing the return spring. In versions with a fixed butt, the return spring is located in the butt and the slide frame interacts with the spring with a special long narrow shank. In the variant with folding stock, the return spring is located in the cover of the receiver and acts directly on a specially modified bolt frame. The trigger mechanism (USM), together with the pistol grip and the backplate of the receiver, is made as a separate unit hinged to the receiver from below, behind the magazine receiver. \n
	To access the knots and mechanisms of the rifle, this unit flips down - forward after releasing a special latch located behind on the left side of the receiver. The fuse-fire translator is located on the left on the USM case, above the trigger, and interacts with the whip of the trigger USM. Sights usually include a fly in the namushnik on the gas chamber and a diopter adjustable rear sight in the back of the receiver. Depending on the country of production, the details of the structure and the marking of the whole can be different. In England, part of the L1A1 rifles was equipped with a 4X optical sight SUIT (Sighting Unit, Infantry, Trilux) with a luminous sighting mark. Practically all variants of FAL rifles are equipped with a combined muzzle device - a flame arrester, also used as a guide for throwing rifle grenades. For FAL rifles, stores with 20 cartridges are used, in some countries (for example, Canada) for variants with a weighted barrel (C2) used as hand-held machine guns, modified stores are used from Bren L4 machine guns of 7.62mm NATO size for 30 cartridges. It should be noted that shops from rifles produced in countries with a metric system can be used in rifles of countries with an imperial (inch) system, but the reverse is false (that is, the English rifle L1A1 or Canadian C1 can use stores from the Belgian FAL or Austrian Stg. 58, but on the contrary it will not work). Fittings (material butt, fore-end, pistol grip) from FAL rifles of different countries and years of production may also differ - they can be made of wood, plastic, metal. \n
	Rifles can have bipods of various designs, sometimes in a folded form replacing the missing forearm (as on the Canadian manual machine gun C2). Almost all variants of rifles have fastenings for a rifle belt, and the majority - and also fastening for bayonet-knife under a trunk.
</text>
</string>

<string id="sniper6">
	<text>Vintar BC</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_long_sniper6">
	<text>VSS (Rifle Sniper Special) &quot;Vintorez&quot; was created for carrying out special operations that require low-noise weapons. The rifle was developed in the Central Research Institute of Precision Engineering (TSNIITOCHMASH) in the city of Klimovsk under the leadership of Peter Serdyukov. Together with the rifle, special ammunition with subsonic speed of bullets designed to reliably hit targets at ranges up to 400 meters was also developed. These ammunition were cartridges 9x39mm SP-5 (with a conventional bullet) and SP-6 (with armor-piercing bullet), created on the basis of cartridge case 7.62x39 obr 1943. The initial velocity of bullets of cartridges of the PSP-5 and SP-6 is about 280 m / s, the mass of the bullets is about 16 grams. \n The armament of ARIA consists of the late 1980s. The VSS rifle is widely and successfully used by various special forces units in the power structures of Russia, including in Chechnya. The VSS rifle is built on the basis of automation with a gas engine and a rotary valve. The gas piston is located above the barrel and rigidly fixed to the bolt frame. The rotary bolt has 6 warheads. Trunk box - milled of steel, To increase the strength of the structure. The shutter handle and the fuse are of the Kalashnikov type, but the fire mode interpreter is a transverse button located behind the trigger hook. The trigger mechanism is also very different from the AKM AK, and has a shock structure. The barrel in the front part (after the gas chamber) has several rows of holes, the Leading part of the powder gases from the bottom of the rifling to the rear of the integrated muffler. In the front, before the muzzle of the barrel, the muffler has a row of steel diaphragms with a bullet hole that inhibits the powder gases inside the muffler. \n For cleaning and compact storage, the muffler can be removed from the gun, but it is forbidden to fire without a silencer. VSS sighting devices include a side bar for securing optical or night sights, as well as a reserve open sight fixed to the muffler casing and consisting of a track adjustable up to a distance of 400 meters and flies. The standard optical sight for VSS is a 4X multiple PSO-1, marked for ballistics of the cartridge 9x39 SP-5. The rifle of the BSS rifle is wooden, of a skeletal design. If necessary, can be easily removed from the weapon for storage in the minimum dimensions.</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper5">
	<text>SVU-AS (OC-03AS)</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_long_sniper5">
	<text>The OC-03 rifle was offered by the Russian Interior Ministry as a weapon for combat operations in the city, where the increased maneuverability of the short rifle is an absolute plus. The rifle was adopted by the Ministry of Internal Affairs under the designation of the IED (Sniper Rifle Shortened), but at the request of the same Ministry of Internal Affairs in Tula, its OTs-03A version was developed (SVU-A after taking it into service), which was capable of conducting automatic fire. The most recent version of the OC-03 line was the OC-03AS version (SVU-AS), which differs from the VCA-A only by the presence of a foldable two-legged bipod installed under the barrel on a special bracket. It should be noted that automatic fire from SVU-A and SVU-AU rifles should be kept only in emergency cases, since a light trunk and a small capacity of the magazine do not allow to conduct from it any intense fire with bursts. From the point of view of accuracy of firing by single shots, according to available data at small and medium ranges, the rifles of the IED series are approximately similar in characteristics to the DragunovSVD rifle. Sniper rifle IED uses the basic mechanisms and a modified receiver from a sniper rifle SVD. The IED maintains a gas-evacuation mechanism with a regulator and a short stroke of the gas piston, as well as locking by turning the bolt from the SVD. The changes affected the shock-trigger mechanism, which received a long pull connecting it with the trigger triggered forward. In SVU-A and SVU-AS rifles, the impact trigger is modified to provide automatic fire. The choice of the fire mode is carried out by the degree of pulling the trigger - a short press causes single shots, a long (until it stops) - automatic fire. To ensure only automatic shooting, there is a special translator, when turned on and limiting the working stroke of the trigger. The barrel of the rifle is equipped with a special muzzle device that combines the functions of a flame arrester and a muzzle brake. Sights include a fly and dioptric bead placed on foldable bases. The target has adjustments in range from 100 to 1300 meters. On the left side of the rifle is a bar for mounting brackets for optical sights. Usually the IED is used with the PSO-1 fixed 4X sight. The SVU-AS rifle differs in that it is equipped with a folding bipod placed on a special bracket under the barrel. The bracket is attached to the receiver to unload the barrel from the influence of the mass of bipods and all weapons (when firing from the stop).</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper4">
	<text>SVD</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_long_sniper4">
	<text>In 1958, the GRAU (Main Rocket and Artillery Directorate) of the General Staff of the Soviet Army announced a contest for the creation of a self-loading sniper rifle for the Soviet Army. The competition was won by the team headed by E. Dragunov, and in 1963 SVD (Sniper Rifle Dragunov) was adopted by the SA. Specially for SVD, a &quot;sniper&quot; cartridge with a steel core bullet was created, but the rifle can use the entire range of domestic cartridges 7.62х54R. The SVD rifle is a self-loading weapon with a gas venting automatics, with a short stroke not connected rigidly with the gas-piston frame (to reduce the mass of the moving parts of the automatics). A two-position gas regulator is provided in the design of the gas outlet. Locking the barrel - turning the bolt, which has 3 fighting stops. The trunk box is milled from steel. USM is unregulated, executed on a separate basis. All variants of the rifle are equipped with removable open sighting devices in the form of a fly in the puff and adjustable head located in front of the receiver cover. The bracket for the optical sight is attached to the receiver on the left. In addition to the main optical sight PSO-1 (fixed multiplicity 4X) on the SVD can be installed night-sighted scopes NSPU-3 or NSPUM. In the early versions of the rifle, the fore and stock of the frame structure were made of wood, in more modern versions the forehead is made of plastic, the frame stock can be both wooden and plastic. The SVD-C rifles have a separate plastic pistol grip and a folding metal butt. The rifle is equipped with a rifle strap for carrying. One of the characteristic features of the SVD is the presence on the barrel of the tide for the installation of a bayonet knife.</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper3">
	<text>KSVK</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_long_sniper3">
	<text>The rifle of the KSVK was developed by the Degtyarev Plant (ZID) located in Kovrov, Russia, on the basis of the earlier SVN-98 rifle. Initially, the rifle was called ASVK. The rifle is designed to defeat unarmored and lightly armored equipment and equipment of the enemy at ranges up to 1000 meters, as well as enemy manpower at ranges up to 1500 meters. The latter, however, is actually difficult due to the lack of special 12.7x108 mm sniper cartridges, since standard machine-gun cartridges are specially manufactured in such a way as to give some dispersion during firing. The manufacturer claims an average range of about 16 cm at a range of 300 meters for SWRCC, with the use of special sniper cartridges this feature is certain to improve. According to some reports, the KSVK rifles are successfully used in a counter-terrorist company in Chechnya. \n Rifle KSVK is not self-loading shop large-caliber weapons, arranged according to the scheme bullpup. Locking of the barrel is carried out longitudinally by sliding pivoting shutter, food - from a detachable box magazine for 5 rounds. The rifle is equipped with a standard lateral bar for attaching the sights and can be equipped with various day and night sights. In addition, the rifle has open sighting devices as a reserve. Folding bipods are located under the trunk on a special bracket, a powerful muzzle brake-compensator is located on the trunk, the butt is equipped with a wooden lining under the cheek and a rubber pad-shock absorber. </text>
</string>
<string id="sniper7">
	<text>M99-2</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_long_sniper7">
	<text>The large-caliber sniper / anti-material rifle M99 is developed in China and is offered for export. It is also assumed that it goes into service with the Chinese People&apos;s Liberation Army or special police forces. The rifle is produced in two externally and structurally identical variants, differing only in the used cartridge - Soviet 12.7x108 (M99-I) or &quot;western&quot; 12.7x99 /.50BMG (M99-II). There are no reliable data on the accuracy of the shooting of this rifle, however, the available information allows us to assume the accuracy of about 2MEA (angular minutes), which is more or less sufficient to defeat light vehicles and to fight lightly fortified firing points at medium ranges (sniper positions, machine gun nests and Etc.). Automation of the rifle uses a gas outlet mechanism and locking by a curved gate. To reduce the perceived impact on the barrel a muzzle brake is installed, and the butt is equipped with a rubber pad-shock absorber. The rifle is equipped with a folding two-legged bipod and additional adjustable support under the butt. To install the aiming devices a guide like Picatinny rail is used. The rifle can be completed with various optical (day) and electron-optical (night) sights.</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper2">
	<text>Accuracy International L96A1</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_long_sniper2">
	<text>In the early 1980s, the British Army announced a competition to replace the obsolete sniper rifles Enfield L42. The main participants of the competition were English companies Parker-Hale with a rifle &quot;model 82&quot;, and Accuracy International with a rifle &quot;model RM&quot;. The rifle of the Republic of Moldova was the winner in this contest, and in the mid-1980s it was adopted by the British Army under the designation L96. The main distinguishing feature of this rifle was a bed of an unusual kind and design: the base of the box is an aluminum beam that runs along the entire length of the box to which the barrel with the receiver is attached, the trigger and all other parts of the rifle, including the box itself consisting of 2 plastic Half - left and right. In addition, the L96 rifles are equipped with open sighting devices in addition to the mandatory optical sight. In the siege of the 1980s, the Swedish army is also beginning to search for a new sniper rifle, suitable for use in severe northern weather. Accuracy International offers Swedes a modified variant of the L96 rifle called Arctic Warfare, and in 1988 the Swedish army takes it into service under the designation PSG.90. The British army, in turn, also adopts the Arctic Warfare rifles (new designation L96A1). The main model of the series AW is designed as an army weapon, besides it four more base models are produced: Police (AWP), Suppressed (AWS), Folding (AWF) and Super Magnum (AW SM). The name of the series (Arctic Warfare = Arctic fighting) comes from the fact that the rifles have special design features that allow them to be used in Arctic conditions (at temperatures up to -40 degrees Celsius). Models AW, AWP and АWS are produced only for the cartridge 7,62mmNATO, and model SM - for cartridges.338 Lapua Magnum, .300 Winchester Magnum and 7mm Remington Magnum. The trunk of the AW model has a length of 660mm, the AWP model has a length of 609mm. The trunks of the AW SM model can have a length from 609mm to 686mm. The AWS model is equipped for use with a silencer and subsonic ammunition. The accuracy of the base model AW is such that at a distance of 550 meters a series of 5 shots fits in a circle of less than 50mm in diameter! The rifles are equipped with Smidt 3-12X variable magnification scopes or Leupold Mark 4 constant multiplicity 10X, as well as a foldable removable bipod.</text>
</string>
<string id="sniper1">
	<text>L115A3 Long Range Rifle</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_long_sniper1">
	<text>In November 2007, it was adopted as the L115A3 Long Range Rifle. Soon the first rifles were transferred to the British contingents in Iraq and Afghanistan. On November 15, 2007, the British Ministry of Defense published information on the conclusion of a contract with the company Accraracy International Limited for the supply of 580 rifles L115A3 for 4 million British pounds (5.04 million euros). The L115A3 rifle is a completely traditional design with manual recharging by means of a longitudinally sliding with a turn of the bolt. The basis of the design is a system made of high-quality steel and firmly connected to the aluminum frame. The stem of the bolt is made by injection molding, it has a diameter of 20 mm. The larva of the shutter is permanently equipped with six arms placed in two rows, the angle of unlocking the shutter is only 60 degrees.</text>
</string>
<string id="pistol1">
	<text>PMSh</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_light_pistol1">
	<text>In the early 90s, the quality of PM tried to increase - primarily due to the introduction of a new, reinforced (high-impulse) cartridge 9x18 PMM (57N181SM). Makarov&apos;s modernized pistol (PMM, GRAU-56-A-125M) was developed on the basis of the PM (Makarov pistol) for a more powerful cartridge. Modernization of the pistol was carried out by the designers BM Pletskiy and RG Shigapov, the serial pistol was manufactured since 1994 by the Izhevsk Mechanical Plant. Outwardly it is distinguished by an enlarged plastic handle of a more convenient shape. On the back end of the handle is a notch for more reliable retention. PMM can be completed with a single-row magazine on 8 or two-row magazine with 12 rounds. The smooth transition of the two-row store in the upper part to the single-row neck allowed not to alter the magazine socket and the bolt. Three chambered grooves are provided on the walls of the chamber. The pressure of the gases presses the walls of the sleeve into the grooves, increasing the resistance to its movement backward. As the staff cartridge develops less pressure, the grooves do not interfere with the use of standard cartridges. The maximum pressure in the barrel of the gun barrel with a new cartridge increased by 15%. Thus, the cartridge of power and damaging action approached 9x19 Parabellum. Due to the greater gas pressure on the muzzle, the acoustic load increased by 20% when the new cartridge was fired. The magazine cover slightly protrudes forward, which gives the palm rest and can somewhat accelerate the recharge. The change in the retention organs can significantly improve the accuracy of the pistol shooting.</text>
</string>
<string id="pistol2">
	<text>FN Browning HP Mk.3</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_light_pistol2">
	<text>In January 1989, the company &quot;FN&quot; introduced another modification, which received the designation High Power Mk III. This model was designed specifically to replace the failed Mk II. The High Power Mk III gun was manufactured to a higher standard. Equipment with electronic program control has significantly increased the quality of processing of parts. To make the structure more durable, the dimensions of the frame and the casing-casing were increased. The shape of the window for ejecting the shells and the design of the handle cheeks changed. The sighting device was now fixed to the shutter-case with the help of a &quot;swallowtail&quot;, which allowed, if necessary, to replace it with a target for target shooting and use not only a removable rear sight, but also a fly. The HP Mk III was originally intended for use in the army, and was soon followed by a modification of the High Power Mk III S. The High Power Mk III S pistol equipped with an automatic drummer blocker that did not allow the latter to move forward until the trigger was fully squeezed was intended for police and commercial sale.</text>
</string>
<string id="pistol4">
	<text>Beretta 92FS</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_light_pistol4">
	<text>Beretta 92FS (1989) - modification of the Beretta 92F pistol, which has an increased head of the trigger axis, which prevents the back of the shutter from being torn from the guides when it is destroyed. It differs from the 92F model with a small disc on the head of the trigger axis and a groove along the lower left edge of the shutter. The disk serves as an additional guide protrusion when the shutter moves and prevents the rear of the shutter from leaving the guides when the shutter is broken. \n
Damage to the shutter occurred on the early 92F pistols after 4,000 rounds, failing to fire heavy ammunition (9x19 mm + P + or 9x19 mm NATO) when firing, to a guaranteed 5000 rounds. In 1987, after the suspension of the contract with the United States, the strength of the metal for the manufacture of the bolt was increased and the destruction of the bolt was not revealed, but additions were made and the model 92FS appeared. \n
From commercial pistols is marked and external trim. It is one of the most common and recognizable pistols in the world. It is used by the armies, police and special forces of many countries, enjoys great popularity in the civilian arms market. The annual production of 92 series pistols of various modifications in Italy and licensed production in other countries is more than 100,000 units \n
</text>
</string>
<string id="pistol3">
	<text>Colt Government M1911</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_light_pistol3">
	<text>The pistol, most commonly known as M1911 (the commercial designation of the company Colt - Government model = Government Model), was developed in the US by John Moses Browning in the early twentieth century, and in 1911 it was adopted by the US Army. \n
In 1926, the pistol was partially upgraded, and from then until the mid-1980s, he remained on active duty under the designation M1911A1, thus becoming the longest-lived army pistol. In the US Army, he was replaced by a Beretta 92 pistol (military designation M9), but to this day the M1911 remains one of the most popular pistols in the US. \n
Key features of the M1911 design: \n
- scheme of automation with a short stroke of the barrel; Locking with two warheads at the top of the barrel and on the inner surface of the bolt in front of the window for sleeve extraction; Tripping of the barrel and the shutter is carried out by lowering the trunk due to a steel earring connecting the breech block and the pistol frame \n
- Single-action homing single-hammer ACM \n
- inertial drummer, held in the rear position by its own spring \n
- non-automatic fuse on the frame, blocking the shutter and trigger (both in the cocked and in the deflated position) \n
- automatic fuse - key on the back side of the handle, switched off with a tight grip of the handle \n
- Single-row shop in the handle; Lock the store in the form of a button located next to the trigger guard</text>
</string>
<string id="pistol5">
	<text>SIG-Sauer P220 SAO</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_light_pistol5">
	<text>The P220 gun uses recoil energy for recharging with a short stroke of the barrel. Locking the barrel is carried out by a modified Browning scheme of locking, one massive ledge on the breech block of the trunk outside the window for ejecting the shells. Reduction of the barrel for unlocking is carried out by the interaction of the figured notch in the tide under the breech section of the trunk with the steel frame liner. The very frame of the gun is made of aluminum alloy, the pistols of the latest releases can also have a heavier frame made of stainless steel. The shutter casing is made of steel sheet stamping, in its rear part there is a massive steel insert - a bolt rigidly fixed with a transverse pin. The trigger-trigger mechanism is self-cocking, with an open trigger and automatic blocking of the impactor when the trigger is not pressed. There are also variants with only a self-cocking shock-trigger mechanism (self-cocking for each shot). Since 2006, specifically for the US market are also available versions of the P220SAO pistol with non-self-powered USM (single-action). These pistols have, instead of the trigger for the safe trigger release, a two-sided hand fuse on the frame, locking the USM when the trigger is cocked. The gun does not have automatic fuses, on the left side of the frame behind the trigger on the pistols with the basic USM there is a lever for the safe release of the trigger from the combat platoon. Sights open, on service options - unregulated, with white or luminous inserts. The telescope is mounted on the gate in a transverse slot such as &quot;swallowtail&quot;. The store latch on the &quot;European&quot; models was placed at the bottom of the handle, on models for the American market, the store latch is shaped like a button located at the bottom of the trigger guard.</text>
</string>
<string id="pistol6">
	<text>IMI Desert Eagle</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_light_pistol6">
	<text>The Desert Eagle uses a very infrequent automatic pistol for the pistols, locking the barrel with a rotary bolt and using the energy of the powder gases removed from the barrel for recharging. The shutter has 4 fences, which engage with the breech part of the trunk. The removal of powder gases is carried out through an opening near the chamber, after which gases are sent to the gas piston in the front part of the gun under the barrel with a short working stroke. Trigger trigger trigger mechanism, single action (not self-amenable). The fuse is double-sided, located on the bolt. Stores are single-row, with capacity from 7 to 9 rounds, depending on the caliber, non-interchangeable between calibers. Sights are usually open, unregulated, although it is also possible to install adjustable micrometric lobbies. The upper surface of the barrel of modern pistols has a special shape, allowing a direct mounting on the barrel of rings for optical sights.</text>
</string>
<string id="pistol7">
	<text>Five-seveN</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_light_pistol7">
	<text>The Fiv-Seven pistol (just so, and not Five-Seven!), Designed by the Belgian company Fabrik Nacional, Gerstal, as a companion weapon for the P90 submachine gun of the same firm. The key features of both the Five-Seven and the P90 are the new, specially designed SS-190 cartridge of 5.7mm caliber with a pointed bullet that develops muzzle velocity above 650 m / s when firing from Fiv-Seven and about 700 m / s - when firing from P90. The main task of such weapons is to fight against the enemy, protected by bulletproof vests. The Fives-Seven pistol is constructed in a semi-free shutter pattern, and has a polymer frame with under-barrel guides for fixing a tactical flashlight or a laser target designator. The shock-trigger mechanism is shock-struck, with integrated blocking of the impactor until the trigger is fully depressed. Currently, Five-seveN is available in two versions: standard, with USM only dual-action, without a non-automatic fuse, and Tactical - with a single-action USM, with a two-sided manual fuse located on the frame above the trigger guard. The standard version of Five-seveN is intended primarily for the military as a weapon of last chance, and the Tactical variant is for the police, where often the pistol is the main weapon. A shorter stroke of the trigger with a lower descent rate provides a more targeted fire.</text>
</string>
<string id="pistol8">
	<text>HK USP Tactical</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_light_pistol8">
	<text>The development of a new promising pistol, primarily aimed at the American market (both civil and police) was launched at Heckler und Koch in mid-1989. The concept envisaged the creation of a sufficiently versatile weapon, which has various options for the USM in accordance with the requirements of various customers, as well as high performance. The name of the new project - USP, stands for Universal Selbstlade Pistole, that is a universal self-loading pistol. The serial production of the first USP version was started in 1993, and already in 1995 a 9-millimeter version of the USP modified to the requirements of the Bundeswehr was adopted by the Armed Forces of the FRG under the designation P8 (Pistole 8). In the same year there was a variant of the USP pistol under the American caliber .45 ASR. Unlike pistols caliber 9mm and .40 version .45 caliber had elongated by 5 millimeters trunk and bolt. In 1996, a compact version of the USP Compact was built, with a truncated barrel, a bolt and a handle, and in 1997 a 9 mm version of the USP Compact was approved as a police weapon of the FRG and received the official designation P10. USP Match, USP Expert, USP Elite and others, as well as special variants with an extended barrel and adjustable sight, designed for use with a silencer - USP Tactical caliber.45 ASP and USP 9SD were also created on the basis of USP pistols. Caliber 9mm.</text>
</string>
<string id="pistol9">
	<text>OC-33 Pernach</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_light_pistol9">
	<text>The OC-33 pistol was developed in the mid-1990s at the TsKIB SOO (Central Design Bureau of Sporting and Hunting Weapons) under the leadership of I. Ya. Stechkin to replace the obsolete and long-discontinued APS gun of the same author&apos;s design. At present, in connection with the inclusion of TsKIB SOO in the Tula Instrument Design Bureau, the OC-33 is engaged in the production and promotion of the PCU. In small quantities, OC-33 is armed with various units of the Ministry of Internal Affairs of the Russian Federation. Compared to the Stechkin pistol, the OPS-33 APS has a much simpler design and a smaller rate of fire, OC-33 is more convenient to handle. \n
OC-33 pistol is an automatic weapon built on the basis of automatic with a free shutter. To reduce the perceived return, the barrel of the gun is movable. At the end of the rollback cycle, the bolt is picked up by a massive barrel, and due to its inertia, the shutter is pre-braked before it collides with the frame in the extreme rear position. Such a decision not only reduces the impact, but also reduces the rate of automatic shooting, which allowed to abandon the use of the mechanism of forced reduction in the rate of fire, which was in the gun of the APS. The return spring is located under the barrel. The weapon is almost entirely made of steel, the plastic handle cheeks. The fuse-translator of the fire modes is located on both sides of the shutter and ensures the maintenance of a single (middle position) and automatic fire (lower position). \n
In the upper fixed position, the fuse locks the hammer, trigger and shutter. The transfer of the fuse-translator lever to the position above the &quot;fuse&quot; position causes the trigger to be released safely from the combat platoon, after which the fuse automatically returns to the upper fixed position. The pistol is powered from standard two-row magazines with a capacity of 18 cartridges or from extended magazines with a capacity of 27 cartridges. For manual automatic fire, the gun is equipped with a removable collapsible shoulder stop (butt) made of steel and worn in a separate belt cover. Under the barrel on the frame of the gun, guides are provided for fixing a torch or laser pointer. The gun is also equipped with a soft carrying case and pouches for spare shops.
</text>
</string>
<string id="drobash1">
	<text>Remington 870</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_near_drobash1">
	<text>Shotgun (smoothbore gun) Remington 870 &quot;Wingmaster&quot; was introduced by Remington in 1950, and since then is the best-selling US pump gun. Initially created as a universal hunting weapon, Remington 870 was produced and produced in dozens of modifications in various calibers. Technically, the Remington 870 is a store gun with manual recharging with the help of a movable back-forward forearm (&quot;pump&quot; gun). Locking is carried out by a swinging combat larva located in the gate, behind the breech block of the trunk. The barrel is steel. The drive of the bogie frame - two pulls, for reliability. The barrels are replaceable, of different length and are drilled. The shop is tubular, it is equipped through a special window in the bottom of the receiver with one cartridge. Depending on the model and the caliber, the capacity of the magazine can vary from 3 to 8 cartridges. Sights can also vary depending on the modification of the gun and its purpose.</text>
</string>
<string id="drobash2">
	<text>Benelli M4</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_near_drobash2">
	<text>Technically, the Benelli M4 Super90 is a self-loading magazine gun. Drive automation - the removal of gases in two symmetrically located under the barrel of the gas cylinder, with two gas pistons and rods, for greater reliability. Locking the barrel - turning the bolt, for 2 combat stops. The chamber is designed for 3-inch (76 mm) cartridges, but the rifle is designed to work reliably with cartridges of 2.75 in. (70 mm) length without any adjustment. \n
Incomplete disassembly and assembly of the gun is carried out without an additional tool. Standard gun is equipped with a telescopic sliding butt, which, if necessary, can be replaced with a pistol grip or a conventional unshaped butt. A sight - with a dioptric wholly and a conventional rifle of a rifle type. In addition, on top of the receiver we installed a universal rail (weaver rail) for the installation of various sights (night, collimator) and other devices. The coatings of all metal surfaces, both external and internal, are matte, not reflecting light, and have increased resistance to corrosion and wear. The barrel is replaceable, can be replaced with a shortened, 355 mm long. The trunk is equipped with screwed chokes for greater univerality.
</text>
</string>
<string id="drobash3">
	<text>Mossberg 590</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_near_drobash3">
	<text>Smoothbore rifle Mossberg 590 was created by the American firm F.F.Mossberg \u0026 sons in the mid-1970s as a &quot;paramilitary&quot; modification of their popular Mossberg 500 gun. Militarization included hardening of a number of parts of the weapon, a mounting cover for the protection of hands from burns, fixing for a standard bayonet knife M9, a more resistant matte coating of external surfaces to protect against wear and corrosion, metal trigger guard - the base of the USM block. Smoothbore rifle Mossberg 590 consists of weapons of the Navy and the Marine Corps of the US, many police departments of the United States; It is also sold in the civil market. Mossberg 590 is a shop shotgun. Recharging with a movable forearm (pump), the tube shop is not replaceable, located under the barrel. Locking the barrel - installed on the back of the swinging larva behind the breech block of the trunk. The barrel is made of aluminum alloy. The fuse is located on top of the back of the receiver and is equally convenient for both right-handed and left-handed users.</text>
</string>
<string id="drobash4">
	<text>Saiga-12K</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_near_drobash4">
	<text>Saiga-12 is a self-loading rifle developed at the Izhevsk machine-building plant on the basis of Kalashnikov assault rifle and intended for commercial and amateur hunting for small, medium-sized beasts and poultry in areas with any climatic conditions. A family of weapons called &quot;Saiga&quot; was developed during the collapse of the USSR at the Izhevsk Machine-Building Plant. &quot;Saiga-12K&quot;, shortened self-loading rifle - &quot;smoothbore carbine&quot;. The application and pistol grip (and in some designs and forearm) are borrowed from the Kalashnikov assault rifle. In the design, a locking mechanism is introduced, which does not allow removing the weapon from the fuse until the butt is thrown back. The length of the trunk is 430 mm. Sights of hunting or &quot;automatic&quot; type.</text>
</string>
<string id="drobash5">
	<text>Vepr-12</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_near_drobash5">
	<text>The Vepr-12 rifle is based on the time-tested design of the Kalashnikov Kalashnikov machine gun, however, when it is created, the wishes of the shooters-athletes are taken into account, and additional elements are added to the design of the rifle that make handling it more convenient: a two-way fuse, a magazine shaft, .P. Currently, the Vepr-12 series guns are produced in three versions, differing in length of the trunk - in the basic version, the trunk is the shortest, in versions 01 and 02, the trunks are longer. Smoothbore rifles Vepr-12 inherited the general layout and construction of the Kalashnikov assault rifle (manual machine gun), with a gas venting mechanism and locking by the shutter. Naturally, the shutter group and the receiver were reconstructed taking into account the use of hunting cartridges, the trigger mechanism lost its self-timer, the self-adjusting self-adjusting gas venting mechanism and allows to shoot cartridges with both 70mm and 76mm cores (Magnum) without additional adjustments. Sights like the Kalashnikov assault rifle, with an adjustable whole and a fly mounted on the gas chamber. The receiver&apos;s cover is not detachable, but folds up and down, like the AK-74U automatic. In addition, a Picatinny rail type guide is provided on the receiver cover allowing quick and convenient installation of various additional sights on the respective brackets. The ammunition is supplied from plastic single-row stores with the capacity of 8 rounds, a bolt delay is introduced into the weapon design, which blocks the bolt with the open position to consume all the cartridges in the magazine (to speed up recharging). The metal is applied, the skeleton structure is foldable sideways. Outside, the butt is covered with plastic to increase the comfort of shooting in frost or heat. On the fore and under the gas chamber there are additional guides such as Picatinny rail for the installation of laser target designators, tactical lights or other accessories. </text>
</string>
<string id="drobash6">
	<text>HK MP-5N</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_near_drobash6">
	<text>The development of a new submachine gun (PG) was started by the German firm Heckler und Koch in about 1964. The first prototypes, designated as NK MP-54 (sometimes referred to simply as NK-54), appeared at the same time, and already in 1966 the police and the border guards of the Federal Republic of Germany adopted this PP under the designation MR-5 in two versions: MR-5 - with a fixed butt, and MP-5A1 - with a telescopic telescopic butt. In the future, the MP-5 is purchased by a variety of police and army forces in Europe and other continents. \n
Structurally, the MP-5 is nothing more than a replica of the German Heckler-Koch G3 rifle under the pistol cartridge. He inherited from the G3 and a steel stamped box with a folding down and detachable shock module (USM), and a semi-free shutter with retardation retardation using a pair of rollers. Fire from the MP-5 is always conducted with a closed shutter, which increases the accuracy and accuracy of fire, but increases the probability of self-ignition of the cartridge in the barrel when the weapon overheats.\n
 HK MP-5N. A modern version, developed specifically for the US Navy. It differs with a folding butt of configuration A3, all-plastic case USM with a two-way translator of fire regimes and designations in the form of &quot;icons&quot;. In addition, the muzzle of the barrel is threaded to install removable silencers of American design.
</text>
</string>
<string id="drobash7">
	<text>AEK-919K &quot;Chestnut&quot;</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_near_drobash7">
	<text>The AEK-919K &quot;Kashtan&quot; submachine gun was developed at the Korovsky Mechanical Plant in the mid-1990s. Initially, the Austrian PP Steyr MPi-69 was taken as a model, but after the release of a small trial lot, a number of shortcomings were discovered, and &quot;Chestnut&quot; was reworked. The updated sample received the AEK-919K index, and is being actively advertised for arming the crews of combat vehicles and aircraft. As well as for special forces of the Ministry of Internal Affairs and the army. &quot;Chestnut&quot; is built on the basis of automatic with a free shutter. The fire is fired from the open bolt, the fire mode switch (which is also a fuse) is located on the left above the trigger guard. The barrel box is stamped out of steel, the pistol grip with the trigger guard and the fore-end are cast of plastic. The trunk of &quot;Chestnut&quot; has a polygonal cut and can be equipped with a removable silencer. The standard sighting devices consist of a fly and a fly-away head for two distances - 50 and 100 meters, in addition, the latest versions of &quot;Chestnut&quot; can be equipped with detachable collimating sights (&quot;red dot&quot;). The AEK-919K retractable attachment, made of metal, can be rotated 180 degrees downward for a more comfortable attachment when pulled out. In general, &quot;Chestnut&quot; is described as an accurate and reliable weapon, which has small dimensions. In my opinion, the main disadvantage of PP AEK-919K is the location of the translator / fuse - to remove the weapon from the fuse with the right hand, without rotating the weapon in the palm of your hand, it is almost impossible even for a person with long fingers. If it is impossible to use the second hand, this drawback may cost the shooter extra seconds of time, and maybe life. The collimator sight, advertised together with &quot;Kashtan&quot; at present, is quite large, and is intended rather for use in police operations, since it considerably facilitates the aiming at the expense of increasing inconvenience when carrying a weapon. However, it is possible to install more modern and compact sights.</text>
</string>
<string id="drobash8">
	<text>FN-P90</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_near_drobash8">
	<text>FN P90 - Belgian submachine gun (personal self-defense weapon), developed in 1986-1987 by FN Herstal. It was developed, first of all, for tankmen and drivers of military vehicles. Has a progressive and convenient ergonomic design. Specially for the P90, a 5.7 ? 28 mm SS190 cartridge was developed, which has a high breakdown power and a low ricochet. The bullet of this cartridge develops a muzzle velocity up to 715 m / s and is capable of penetrating a titanium / Kevlar bulletproof vest that meets the requirements of NATO CRISAT from 200 meters. The magazine is installed on top of the receiver and its capacity is 50 cartridges, while the cartridges are horizontally perpendicular to the trunk and unfolded 90 degrees before being fed into the chamber. It is made of transparent plastic, which allows the shooter at any time to know the number of cartridges in it. The store is filled in the usual way. The shell cases are thrown down, through the hollow handle of the fire control. FN P90 is equipped with a built-in collimating sight with a multiplicity of 1X with an aiming grid in the form of the letter T. The aiming grid has an automatically adjustable backlight depending on the ambient light; Also, the weapon is equipped with a laser target designator, located at the bottom. In addition, a silencer is attached to it, but its operation is possible only if cartridges with subsonic speed are used. At the same time, one of the main tasks was the maximum reduction in the weight of weapons and ammunition. The Belgian designers followed the path of creating a small-caliber cartridge with a high initial velocity of the bullet and developed a munition corresponding to the requirements that had been set up, which also had a flat trajectory of the bullet&apos;s flight and yielded a small amount of return, which facilitated fire and defeat of the enemy for inexperienced soldiers with weak fire training. Such a weapon-cartridge complex was intended in the future to replace pistols and submachine guns in the operating armies of NATO countries with a traditional 9 mm Parabellum cartridge.</text>
</string>
<string id="drobash9">
	<text>HK MP7A1</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_near_drobash9">
	<text>The Heckler - Koch HK MP7 submachine gun, developed in the late 1990s by the German firm Hekler and Koch, belongs to the new class of small arms, the Personal Defense Weapon (PDW), in the western classification, and is intended for the arming of servicemen who The state does not have a full-fledged assault rifle (assault rifle), that is, crews of military equipment, gun calculations, etc. From a technical standpoint, the HK MP7A1-automatic weapons under specially designed cartridge calibre 4.6 mm (cartridge designation 4.6 h30mm, Chuck recalls reduced cartridge 5.56 mm NATO). HK MP7A1 is organized by type of compact pistol-machine gun shop is inserted into the grip, collapsible stock, telescopic front has an extra foldable handle for two-handed weapons retention. Automation HK MP7A1 built on a scheme with a gas engine with a short stroke of the gas piston, locking - turning the bolt. In general, the automation and USMHK MP7A1 strongly resemble the corresponding elements of the G36 rifle of the same company. The case of HKMP7A1 is made of plastic, on the top of the case guides are provided for fixing various sighting devices. Fire modes - single shots and and turns, the fire mode switch also serves as a fuse and is controlled from both sides of the weapon. The cocking handle is located on the rear side of the body above the butt, has a T-shape (like the handle of the M16 rifle) and is stationary when firing. The fire is conducted from a closed shutter.</text>
</string>
<string id="drobash10">
	<text>TDI Kriss Super 5</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_near_drobash10">
	<text>When creating this submachine gun, the goal was to maximize the accuracy of shooting with automatic fire, while maintaining small dimensions and weight of weapons and using sufficiently powerful ammunition.45 ACP, which are distinguished by high stopping action at short distances. The Kriss Super V submachine gun uses a rather unusual automatic scheme with a semi-free shutter and redirection of the momentum of the moving parts moving down. The lightweight shutter of the submachine gun has side protrusions that enter the inclined grooves of the massive rocker moving inside the hull of the gun up and down. When a shot is fired, the movement of the shutter is converted back into a vertical movement of the balance beam downward, while at the expense of the variable angle of the groove along which the shutter protrusions slide, an early retraction of the shutter slows it. The shooting is carried out with a closed shutter, the trigger trigger is located above the axis of the barrel. The cocking cocking handle is foldable, is located on the left on the body of the weapon and remains stationary while shooting. The fire mode interpreter is located on the trigger box approximately in the middle of the weapon&apos;s length, and provides fire control by single shots and bursts. A separate fuse is located above the pistol grip. To enhance the sustainability of weapons and further reduce podbrosa barrel while shooting without using a pistol grip stock is raised relative to the axis of the barrel so that the recoil shoulder towards the retention arms hand minimum (such a decision before it was used in the Soviet Olympic-calibre pistol MC-3, also known as &quot;Sheptarskogo frame&quot;). The store receiver is located in front of the fire control handle. Currently, 13-charging magazines are used from Glock 21 pistols, but in the future it is planned to develop own stores of greater capacity. To increase the accuracy of the shooting, the Kriss Super V submachine gun is equipped with a foldable side butt and a removable front handle.</text>
</string>
<string id="drobash11">
	<text>PP-19 &quot;Bizon-2-01&quot;</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_near_drobash11">
	<text>Sub-machine gun PP-19 Bison was designed in the early 1990&apos;s. At the Izhevsk Machine-Building Plant with the aim of arming the MVD with modern small-sized automatic small arms instead of AKS-74U. In this case, the PP-19 itself was designed and manufactured with a large volume of Kalashnikov AK-74 assault rifles. Such details include a shortened AK-74 receiver with a pistol grip for controlling fire and a trigger mechanism, as well as a metal folding butt, borrowed from the AK-74 automatic. Submachine gun PP-19 Bison differs from its original screw magazine with a capacity of 64 cartridges for PP-19 Bizon-2 for the cartridge 9x18 PM and 53 cartridges for PP-19 Bizon-2-01 for the cartridge 9x19 Parabellum. This store was created in part based on the American Calico pistol. At the same shop PP-19 is placed on the gun with great convenience for the shooter and combines the function of the forehead. The store is located under the trunk, does not increase the size of the submachine gun and performs the function of foremost to retain weapons when firing. For convenience of carrying and transportation, the submachine gun has a folding butt. Two variants of the stock are possible: a frame stock, folded to the left side or an upper butt that folds onto the receiver&apos;s lid. The design of the submachine gun allows you to fire with a folded butt. Bison is perfectly adaptable for use in conjunction with silent shooting devices and modern fire control equipment. There is a side bar for installation of collimating, optical and night sights.</text>
</string>
<string id="drobash12">
	<text>PP-2000</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_near_drobash12">
	<text>The PP-2000 submachine gun was developed at the Design Instrument Design Bureau in the city of Tula, Russia, and was first shown in public in 2004, although a patent for its design was registered back in 2001. PP-2000 is obviously intended for the role of either self-defense weapons of the military (PDW), or as a melee weapon for special operations forces, both army and police / police, primarily for action in the city. PP-2000 is extremely compact and light, with a minimum number of parts and a simple design, which ensure simple operation and low cost. The ability to use 7N21 and 7N31 armor-piercing ammunition, originally developed for the GSh-18 pistol, makes it possible to use the PP-2000 to fight opponents in individual means of protection (helmets, body armor) and effectively hit targets inside the vehicles. In comparison with the small-caliber analogues produced in Western countries, such as Belgian 5.7mm FN P90 or German 4.6mm HK MP-7, the PP-2000 thanks to the use of 9mm bullets provides greater efficiency against targets not protected by bulletproof vests. At present, the PP-2000 is already in series production and is being used by the Russian Ministry of Internal Affairs. The submachine gun PP-2000 is built on the basis of automation with a free shutter. Fire from the PP-2000 is carried out with a closed shutter, trigger trigger mechanism trigger. The body of the submachine gun is made of plastic with a pistol grip and an enlarged trigger guard, providing, if necessary, holding the weapon with both hands. The bolt protrudes from the body above the barrel, in its front part there is a leaning arm to the right or to the left. The magazine is inserted into the pistol grip, the store latch button is located at the base of the trigger guard. The fuse interpreter is located on the left side of the gun, above the pistol grip, and provides firing both single shots and bursts. A distinctive feature of the PP-2000, protected by a patent - in the back of its housing is a nest for a spare store. When inserted in this jack store, it can be used as a rudimentary shoulder stop.</text>
</string>
<string id="drobash13">
	<text>PP-19-01 &quot;Vityaz-SN&quot;</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_near_drobash13">
	<text>Submachine gun PP-19-01 &quot;Vityaz&quot; is a further development of the submachine gun PP-19 &quot;Bison&quot;. &quot;Vityaz&quot; was developed by the IZHMASH concern specially for the demands of the detachment of the special forces of the Ministry of the Interior of Russia &quot;Vityaz&quot;, from where it got its name. Currently, the submachine gun PP-19-01 &quot;Vityaz&quot; is in mass production and is already being supplied to the units of the Ministry of Internal Affairs of Russia. Like its predecessor, the AK-74U automatic machine is based on the design of the PP-19-01, or the newer AK-104, the unification of the &quot;Vityaz&quot; with which the details are about 70%. The knight is produced in two versions - the basic PP-19-01 issp.10 and the modified PP-19-01 mod.20 &quot;Vityaz-SN&quot;. The second option has improved ergonomics (due to the removal of the fuse and the handle of the shutter on the left side), as well as an additional guide such as Picatinny rail on the cover of the receiver, which allows the installation of various additional sighting devices. Submachine gun PP-19-01 &quot;Vityaz&quot; can use the majority of commercial and army versions of the cartridge 9x19, produced in the world, including domestic cartridges 9mm 7N21 with armor-piercing bullet. PP-19-01 can be equipped with silencer sound shot. Pistol-machine gun PP-19-01 &quot;Vityaz&quot; uses automatic with a free shutter. The fire is conducted from the closed shutter, the trigger and safety mechanisms along with the receiver are completely borrowed from the AK-74U automatic. From the bottom to the receiver there is a shaft for box-type double-row stores, designed specifically for PP-19-01. If necessary, stores can be stapled in pairs using a special staple supplied with the weapon, providing an accelerated recharge of weapons in battle. Frame, metal, folding sideways. On the left side of the barrel a standard for the domestic weapon is used for fixing the brackets for optical sights. The sight is sectoral, open, adjustable in range.</text>
</string>
<string id="other1">
	<text>Machine gun M249</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_some_other1">
	<text>The Minimi machine gun was developed by the Belgian company FN Herstal in the mid-late 1970s and early 1980s and has been in serial production since about 1981. It is used by many countries, including Belgium itself, the USA (under the designation M249 SAW), Canada (designated C9), Australia (designated F-89) and many others. The machine gun is deservedly popular for its high mobility in combination with firepower, which considerably exceeds the firepower of such machine guns as RPK-74, L86A1 and others, built on the basis of automatic weapons, and not created from scratch as machine guns. A distinctive feature of the Minimi is the ability to use both metal tape (standard method) and NATO standard rifles (from the M16 rifle, the backup version) without any changes in the design (similar to the Czech manual VZ.52 machine gun created by the 30 Years earlier). Minimi machine guns are used to increase the firepower of infantry units, providing effective fire at ranges up to 600-800 meters, combined with high mobility. Minimi - light (manual) machine gun, built on the basis of gas venting automatics, locking the barrel by turning the bolt. Power - metal loose tape or box magazines (the magazine receiver is located on the left side of the weapon under the receiver for the tape, the store is inserted at an angle of about 45 degrees down from the horizontal). When using the tape, the receiver window for stores is covered with a dust cover, when the magazine is inserted (with the tape removed), the open curtain overlaps the feed path of the tape. When using a tape, part of the energy of the gas engine is used to drag the tape, so the rate of fire with the tape is lower than when the magazine is powered. The tape is usually fed from plastic boxes or canvas bags on a metal frame attached to a machine gun from below, with a capacity of 100 or 200 cartridges. The barrel of the machine gun is quick-change, equipped with a flame arrester and a folding handle for carrying. The trunks of three basic sizes are produced: the standard length is 465 mm, the &quot;landing&quot; length is 349 mm and the &quot;special purpose&quot; is 406 mm long. Folding bipod, located under the barrel on the gas pipe. Depending on the country of manufacture and modification, the Minimi can have attachments and foreheads of various designs, mountings for optical and night sights, etc. Fire control - with the help of a pistol grip with a trigger, the fire mode is only automatic. </text>
</string>
<string id="other2">
	<text>PKM</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_some_other2">
	<text>The PKM machine guns are highly reliable and enjoy a well-deserved popularity among the troops, despite the slightly over-complicated two-stage system of supplying cartridges from the tape to the trunk. Kalashnikov&apos;s machine gun uses gas-operated automation with a gas piston under the barrel with a long working stroke. The barrel is quick-change, has a handle for carrying, also used to replace the hot trunk. The gas outlet is equipped with a manual gas regulator. The barrel is locked by turning the bolt. Feeding cartridges - from an unassembled metal tape with a closed link. Tapes are assembled from pieces of 50 links with the help of a cartridge. The nominal capacity of the tapes is 100 (in manual version) or 200 (in the machine tool) cartridges. The tape feed direction is from right to left, the feed and exit windows of the tape are equipped with dust covers, as well as the window for ejecting the cartridge cases. Feeding cartridges from the tape two-stage - first a special grip when pulling back the original frame pulls the cartridge out of the tape back, after which the cartridge goes down to the line of delivery and at the back of the bolt is sent to the barrel. Shooting is carried out with an open bolt, only with automatic fire. Standard controls in the infantry version include a pistol grip, trigger, manual guard and frame stock. In armored vehicles, it is possible to install a special seatplate with paired handles and a trigger key instead of a butt, in the tank - an electric remote trigger mechanism is used. In the infantry version, the machine gun is equipped with a foldable two-legged bipod, the machine tool is additionally equipped with a universal tripod with an adapter for anti-aircraft shooting. The standard sighting devices were open, infantry versions were also produced with a side bracket for the installation of night sights.</text>
</string>
<string id="other3">
	<text>RPCM</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_some_other3">
	<text>In the mid-1950s, the Soviet Army launched a program to develop a new complex of small arms designed to replace the AK Kalashnikov assault rifle, the SCS carbine and the RAP hand-gun. The structure of the complex was to include an automatic machine and a maximum unified with it a manual machine gun (support weapons of the department), both for the cartridge 7.62x39 M43. According to the results of the competition in 1961, a modified AK Kalashnikov assault rifle and a Kalashnikov-made manual caliber RPK, unified with it in design and stores, were put into service with the SA. The PKK remained the main weapon of support for the department until 1974, when it was replaced by its analog for the 5.45x39 cartridge - the RPK-74 hand-gun. \n
The Kalashnikov Kalashnikov machine gun uses the same automation scheme and basic design solutions as the AKM Kalashnikov assault rifle, that is, the gas-operated automation with locking the barrel by turning the bolt. The barrel box is stamped from steel sheet, more durable than the AKM box for increasing the resource. The trunk is longer than the AKM, there is no possibility of replacing it in case of overheating. Shock-trigger mechanism is completely analogous to that of AKM, allows firing single shots and bursts, shooting is conducted from a closed shutter. Feeding cartridges - from detachable stores, compatible with AK / AKM. For the PKK, two types of high-capacity magazines were developed and put into service: a boxed (carob) magazine for 40 cartridges and a drum magazine for 75 cartridges. Early versions of box-shaped stores were made of steel, later - from plastic. The drum shops had a steel structure and were distinguished by the high cost and slowness of the cartridges. The PKK was equipped with a folding two-legged bipod installed under the barrel, butt of a special shape and a sight with the possibility of introducing lateral corrections. The RPCS variant, developed for the airborne troops, had a folding side stock. In addition, versions of RPKN and RSKSN were produced with a bar mounted on the receiver for fixing the night sights. \n
At present, the RPKM-7M machine gun is manufactured for the cartridge 7.62x39, intended primarily for export. It should be noted that as a handgun, the RPK had significant shortcomings - a small capacity of the power system, the inability to conduct intense automatic fire due to the non-replaceable trunk and firing from the closed shutter. Its main advantage was a high degree of unification with a standard AKM automatic machine, and somewhat larger in comparison with the range and accuracy of shooting (due to a longer and slightly heavier barrel).
</text>
</string>
<string id="other4">
	<text>RPG-7V1</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_some_other4">
	<text>RPG-7V1, hand-held anti-tank grenade launcher. It is designed to combat tanks, self-propelled artillery systems. The grenade launcher is based on the scheme of recoilless starting device of reusable application and a shot with an over-caliber warhead. The grenade launcher has a broadening of the barrel in its middle part - a charging chamber - for more complete utilization of the propellant energy, and a bell in the breech part - to ensure the smoothness of the complex. In addition to the mechanical sight, the grenade launcher has an optical sight. The constant development of new rounds of grenades with grenades of various striking actions, the improvement of sighting devices significantly expands the capabilities of the grenade launcher, making it multi-purpose.</text>
</string>
<string id="other5">
	<text>РГ-6Г30</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_some_other5">
	<text>The RG-6 grenade launcher (GRAU index 6G30) was developed in a hurry in 1993 at the TsKIB SOO (TsentralnoyKB Sport and Hunting weapons, Tula) to arm the troops that operated against the separatists in Chechnya. The small-scale production of the RG-6 was started in 1994 at the Tula Arms Factory, and the grenade launcher almost immediately began to arrive in the troops and some units of the Ministry of Internal Affairs. Due to the speed of development of the grenade launchers of early issues, there were some problems, in particular, the unreliable operation of USM. The RG-6 grenade launcher was created under the undoubted influence of the Milkor MGL South African grenade launcher, but due to the fact that the RG-6 uses fundamentally different ammunition with the departing sleeve, there are a number of notable differences in its design. \n
The RG-6 grenade launcher has a revolver circuit, the drum chambers are formed by six rifled muzzle-charge barrels from the GP-25 grenade launchers. Accordingly, the equipment of the drum is carried out from the front, after folding the front part of the grenade launcher with the false trunk sideways and upwards. In the chambers grenades are held by special spring clips. Rotation of the drum is carried out by a spring that is manually cocked during recharging. The rotation of the drum after each shot occurs at the release of the ratchet at the time of release of the trigger, which excludes the attempt of repeated injection of a misfiring grenade. In addition, in the event of a protracted shot, the pomegranate immediately &quot;leaves&quot; from the trunk, and the author knows at least one case when a protracted shot at the RG-6 led to the destruction of the weapon (fortunately, the shooter threw the grenade launcher aside in time and nobody was hurt ). The shock-trigger mechanism is self-cocking, mostly borrowed from the GP-25 grenade launcher. The grenade launcher is equipped with a false trunk, which has a smooth (not cut) channel and serves only for fixing the front handle and sight. Sights folding, step type. The telescopic telescopic application has a rubber cushioning pad.
</text>
</string>
<string id="other6">
	<text>RGD-5 grenade</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_some_other6">
	<text>RGD-5 (hand grenade, remote, GRAU index - 57-G-717) - Soviet offensive hand grenade, refers to the anti-personnel fragmentation grenades of offensive offensive type. This means that it is designed to defeat the enemy&apos;s personnel with shell fragments during its explosion. The goal of the pomegranate is achieved by throwing a hand. Remote action - means that the grenade will explode after a certain time (3.2-4.2 seconds) after it is released, regardless of other conditions. Offensive type - means that the grenade fragments have a small mass and fly at a range less than the possible range of the throw. \n
Externally, the pomegranate has an oval body made of thin steel. The streamlined body is assembled from the top and bottom parts, each of which includes an outer shell and a liner. The hole for the fuse during storage is closed with a plastic stopper. The mass of a grenade with a fuse of 310 g. The charge of an explosive is TNT with a mass of 110 grams. Range of fragmentation is 30 meters. \n
The fuse of the grenade is universal, suitable also for grenades RG-42 and F-1. The fuse brand: UZRG, UZRGM (from the second half of the 1950s), or UZRGM-2. All these fuses are interchangeable.</text>
</string>
<string id="other7">
	<text>F1 grenade</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_some_other7">
	<text>F-1 (GRAU-57-G-721 index) is a hand-held anti-personnel defense grenade. It is designed to defeat manpower in a defensive battle. Due to the considerable radius of the fragmentation, it is possible to throw it only because of cover, from an armored personnel carrier or from a tank. \n
The names &quot;F-1&quot; and slang &quot;limonka&quot; came from the French fragmentation grenade F-1 model of 1915 with a mass of 572 grams and the English grenade of the Lemon system, which were supplied to Russia during the First World War. Another version of the origin of the slang name is its shape resembling a lemon. \n
Initially, the F-1 grenades were equipped with the fuse of FV Koveshnikov. In 1941, Ye. M. Vitseny and AA Bednyakov developed a universal UZRG fuse, after the war it was finalized and serves to this day under the name UZRGM (universal firing of hand grenades modernized).</text>
</string>
<string id="other8">
	<text>Grenade MK3A2</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_some_other8">
	<text>A modern American hand grenade, commonly referred to as a concussion grenade, is designed to inflict damage primarily on the strength of the explosion. It also affects the fragments, but they play a secondary role here. \n
The main task of this grenade is the production of destruction (damage to unarmored or lightly armored vehicles, small structures (dugouts, cracks, rooms, fuel tanks, containers with property) and disabling enemy soldiers in confined spaces (in cars, shelters, dugouts, Premises). \n
A significant explosive effect is achieved due to a large charge of explosive (TNT) in garnet - 227 grams with a total mass of garnet of 443 grams. The length of the grenade is 13.8 cm. The diameter is about 5 cm. According to the American standards, the radius of death of a person with a shock wave is 2 meters. Fragments of a grenade can fly up to 200 meters. The radius of safe removal of their soldiers is 235 meters. \n
Applicable fuses M206A1 or M206A2. Grenade of remote action, i.e. The explosion occurs 4-6 seconds after the release of the clamping lever. Before the throw, the soldier presses the lever to the body of the grenade, pulls out the safety ring and throws the grenade at the target. You can throw a grenade only because of shelter. \n
The maximum range of the average soldier&apos;s throw is 40 meters. The pomegranate is painted black. The marking is yellow on the side surface of the grenade. This grenade became very popular during the Vietnam War in the sixties, when with their help, American soldiers destroyed Vietnamese people who were hiding in underground passages. It was not possible to do this with conventional grenades. Grenade can have a certain effectiveness in street fighting, mountain conditions. In the usual field battle, its effectiveness is questionable.</text>
</string>
<string id="other9">
	<text>Grenade M68</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_some_other9">
	<text>The offensive grenade M33 was designed as a grenade, which would be convenient for an accurate throw. The grenade has a spherical body with an internal notch. As a charge M33 is equipped with composition &quot;B&quot;. When a grenade explodes, about 400 fragments form. The M33 grenade used the M204 series fuse. Based on the M33 grenade, its modification was developed - a grenade M67, which differed from the M67 only used fuse. In the M67 grenade, the M213 ignitor is used, which differs from the standard one by the presence of two safety devices - a conventional check with a ring and a wire loop wrapped around the fuse and holding the lever. Thanks to the reliable protection, which allows to carry a grenade, having hooked the lever of the fuse behind the equipment belt, and also to small dimensions with high density of fragments in the affected area, the grenades M67 were popular with paratroopers, marines and special forces. \n
	A further modification was the M68 grenade similar to the M59, which was supplied with a M217 fuse, but using a wire loop wrapped around the fuse and holding the lever in order to increase safety. To learn the rules of use is an imitation grenade M69, repeating the shape and weight of the grenade M67. In South Korea, under the designation K400, a copy of the M67 grenade with a modified fuse design is produced.</text>
</string>

</string_table>