<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>


	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- (ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists) -->
	<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_1_name">
    <text>Scientific Donor</text>
</string>
<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_1_text">
    <text>Professor Tenyakov is very busy conducting a series of experiments using tissue samples from the Zone's fauna. At least, he was busy until all available materials ran out.\nNow he needs any help he can get to provide the necessary samples.\n\nI agreed to help him solve this problem. "You" will need to find and deliver it in good condition as soon as possible, while the sample still retains its freshness. Otherwise, Professor Tenyakov will not accept it.\n\nNow, all that remains is to find a donor who can provide this sample...</text>
</string>
<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_1_about">
    <text>I am experiencing a severe shortage of necessary animal materials, and I urgently need an experienced hunter to gather certain samples. Can I count on you?</text>
</string>
<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_1_fetch_about">
    <text>I have been conducting a series of especially important experiments in my lab related to the properties of certain fauna species.\nUnfortunately, I miscalculated my sample supplies needed in case of unexpected circumstances and experiment branches—I have exhausted the last available material I had.\n\nThese experiments are of great importance to the scientific community and to me personally, so I need to replenish the necessary materials. I require "You".\n\nI must emphasize that I am not interested in the details of obtaining the samples. You are free to go hunting, buy them from traders, or even other stalkers. The only thing I require is the timely delivery and freshness of the materials. They will be useless in the experiment if they lose their freshness.\nOnce you gather everything I need, you must return here as soon as possible. Will you agree?</text>
</string>
<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_1_fetch_finish">
    <text>Look at that! The samples have preserved their freshness as much as possible! I am very grateful, young man. Simply excellent work. I will immediately continue my experiments.</text>
</string>

<!-- Collect New Artefact Task -->
<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_2_name">
    <text>Scientific Progress</text>
</string>
<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_2_text">
    <text>Professor Tenyakov is conducting a series of important research related to artifacts.\n\nUnfortunately, the professor had a case where he completely exhausted the material necessary for high data accuracy. Because of this, he was forced to suspend his research.\n\nHe asked to find and provide him with the artifact "You". He promised a good payment for its delivery.</text>
</string>
<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_2_about">
    <text>Will you help me with the research, young man? A monetary reward will not be far behind.</text>
</string>
<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_2_fetch_about">
    <text>Excellent! You can't imagine the good you can do for humanity!\n\nAt the moment, I am conducting important laboratory research, but I have run out of all available material for the necessary sample! Without it, the data accuracy and selection are worthless!\n\nPlease, I urgently need the artifact "You" so I can resume my research immediately.</text>
</string>
<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_2_fetch_finish">
    <text>Young man, your eagerness to lend a helping hand to science in a difficult time is invaluable. How I wish there were more people like you here! The scientific laboratory and I personally thank you for your help.</text>
</string>

<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_4_name">
    <text>In the World of Mutant Animals</text>
</string>
<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_4_about">
    <text>You see, our zoologist colleagues installed tracking devices on some representatives of the local fauna so that we could get a full set of data on them: their movements, behavior, habits, daily life, and so on. Unfortunately, I regret to inform you that after one of the recent anomalies, a couple of these beacons stopped functioning properly—they still transmit coordinates, but... alas, that's all. No other data can be retrieved. So, you will need to find the target and extract the device manually, after which you will deliver it here. There is no other way, unfortunately. On the other hand, you can help the Zone's inhabitants eliminate a possible problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_4_stage_0">
    <text>According to Professor Tenyakov, zoologists were studying the lifestyle of several mutants by attaching tracking devices to them. However, a recent anomaly seems to have damaged them—now, instead of all the data, scientists are only receiving the current coordinates of the creature. The data is still recorded on the beacon's storage, but the only way to retrieve it is to find the mutant, eliminate it, and take the device.</text>
</string>
<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_4_stage_1">
    <text>Pick up the data device fallen from the mutant</text>
</string>
<string id="ano_smart_terrain_3_1_scientists_task_4_stage_2">
    <text>Return the device to Professor Tenyakov</text>
</string>


</string_table>
