<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<!-- rosf_isg_tech -->
	<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_1_name">
	<text>Find %s for Sergeant Malarki</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_1_text">
	<text>You need to bring tools to Sergeant Malarki so that he can carry out equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_1_about">
	<text>You know, buddy, I’m actually a pretty good technician. I can repair weapons and armor, and I even do some upgrades! Well, I would, if I had the right tools. But where the hell can you get those around here? Maybe you can help me get a simple set of tools?</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>I need a set of tools for heavy-duty work. It should include tools and oils for working with weapons. If you can get it for me, I’ll be grateful, and I’ll even pay you... Probably.</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Great, dude! Oh, sorry, I don’t have anything to pay you with. But I can give you a good discount!</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_2_name">
	<text>Find %s for Sergeant Malarki</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_2_text">
	<text>You need to bring Sergeant Malarki tools for fine work. He needs a more complete set to carry out more complex equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_2_about">
	<text>Hey, dude, if you agree to get me a more complete set, I’ll give you an even bigger discount. Will you help me out, buddy?</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_2_fetch_about">
	<text>I need tools for fine work. It should have everything I need. You’ll be like a brother to me if you get it for me!</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_2_fetch_finish">
	<text>Wow, thanks, bro! Now I’m definitely going to get rich. Damn, I’ll actually become successful!.. Unless I mess this one up too. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_3_name">
	<text>Find %s for Sergeant Malarki</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_3_text">
	<text>You need to bring Sergeant Malarki %s. He needs a unique set to carry out even more complex equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_3_about">
	<text>Hey, buddy, if you find something valuable—I’ll give you a discount!</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_3_fetch_about">
	<text>I need tools for calibration. They should have everything I need. You’ll be like a brother to me if you get them for me!</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_tech_task_3_fetch_finish">
	<text>No way...! Damn, thanks, bro! Now I’m definitely going to get rich. Damn, I’m actually going to become successful!.. Unless, of course, I mess this chance up too. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>




	<!-- rosf_isg_medic -->
	<string id="rosf_isg_medic_task_1_name">
	<text>%s for Lieutenant Martin</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_medic_task_1_text">
	<text>You need to find a medical kit and bring it to Medic Lieutenant Martin.</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_medic_task_1_about">
	<text>I need a good medical kit. I can quickly patch up minor wounds, but for something more serious than a simple scalpel, I need better tools.</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_medic_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>I need a good medical kit. I can quickly patch up minor wounds, but for something more serious than a simple scalpel, I need better tools.</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_isg_medic_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Thank you, my friend! These tools will save many lives. Thanks again for bringing them.</text>
</string>

<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
<!-- (Ecog Trader) -->
<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_1_name">
	<text>Scientific Donor</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_1_text">
	<text>Makarev is very busy conducting a series of experiments using tissue samples from Zone fauna. At least, he was busy until all the available materials ran out. Now, he needs any help that can provide him with the necessary samples. \nI agreed to help him solve this issue. The "%s" needs to be found and delivered in good condition as soon as possible, before the sample loses its freshness. Otherwise, Makarev will not accept it.\n\nNow, we just need to find a donor who can provide this sample...</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_1_about">
	<text>I am experiencing a critical shortage of necessary animal materials, so I urgently need an experienced hunter to collect specific samples. Can I count on you?</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>I’ve been conducting a series of important experiments in my lab, related to the properties of some of the fauna.\nUnfortunately, I miscalculated the stock of samples I had, and as a result, I’ve run out of the materials I needed.\n\nThese experiments are of immense significance to the scientific community and myself, so I urgently need to replenish my supply of necessary materials. I require the "%s".\n\nLet me be clear, I’m not interested in the details of how you obtain the samples. You are free to go hunting, buy them from traders, or get them from other stalkers. The only thing I require is timely delivery and freshness. They will be useless for the experiment if they lose their freshness.\nOnce you gather everything I need, return here as soon as possible. Are you willing to help?</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Just look at that! The samples have retained their freshness as much as possible! I am most grateful to you, young man. Simply magnificent work. I will immediately continue my experiments.</text>
</string>

	
	<!-- Collect New Artefact Task -->
	<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_2_name">
	<text>Scientific Progress</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_2_text">
	<text>Makarev is conducting a series of, in his words, important studies related to artifacts.\n\nUnfortunately, the professor had a case where he completely exhausted the material required for highly accurate data. Because of this, he was forced to pause the research.\n\nHe has asked to find and provide him with the artifact %s. He promised a good payment for its delivery.</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_2_about">
	<text>Could you help me with the research, young man? A monetary reward will not be long in coming.</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_2_fetch_about">
	<text>Simply excellent! You can't imagine what good you might do for humanity!\n\nRight now, I am conducting a series of important laboratory studies, but I have exhausted all available supplies of the required sample material! Without it, the accuracy of the data and the corresponding sample are just useless!\n\nI ask you, I urgently need the artifact %s so I can immediately return to my research and continue it.</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_2_fetch_finish">
	<text>Young man, your eagerness to lend a hand to science in a difficult hour is simply invaluable. How I wish there were more people like you around here! The scientific laboratory and I personally thank you for your assistance.</text>
</string>

<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_4_name">
	<text>In the World of Mutant Animals</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_4_about">
	<text>You see, our zoologist colleagues have installed tracking devices on several local fauna representatives so that we can gather a complete set of data on them: their movements, behavior, habits, daily life, and so on. Unfortunately, I regret to inform you that after one of the recent emissions, a couple of these beacons stopped working properly – they still transmit coordinates, but... alas, only those. The rest of the data cannot be retrieved. So, you will need to find the target, extract the device manually, and bring it here – unfortunately, there is no other way. On the bright side, you can help the inhabitants of the Zone get rid of a potential problem as well.</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_4_stage_0">
	<text>According to Makarev, the zoologist scientists were studying the behavior of several mutants using tracking devices attached to them. However, a recent emission seems to have damaged them – instead of all the data, the scientists only receive the creature's current coordinates. The data is still recorded on the beacon's storage, but the only way to read it is to find the mutant, eliminate it, and take the device.</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_4_stage_1">
	<text>Retrieve the device with data from the mutant</text>
</string>
<string id="rosf_eco_tunnel_scientists_task_4_stage_2">
	<text>Return the device to Makarev</text>
</string>


</string_table>
