<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>



	<!-- ASSAULT TERRITORY FOR GREH TASK -->
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_1_name">
		<text>Destroy the Enemies of Greh</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_1_text">
		<text>You need to suppress the territorial threat in this zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_1_about">
		<text>I have an important mission for you, brother. You must destroy the camp of the heretics so that our brothers can establish themselves better in this place. Are you ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_1_finish">
		<text>Task completed? Good. Greh appreciates good work.</text>
	</string>

<!-- ASSASSINATION FOR GREH TASK -->
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_2_name">
		<text>Kill the Heretic</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_2_text">
		<text>A stalker wants to attack us. Kill him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_2_about">
		<text>A stalker wants to attack us. Find and kill this heretic.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_2_finish">
		<text>You did well. The brothers are proud of you.</text>
	</string>

<!-- FIND WEAPON FOR GREH TASK -->
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_3_name">
		<text>Find Weapon: %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_3_text">
		<text>Veles is looking for new weapons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_3_about">
		<text>We are growing stronger every day. We need more weapons to achieve our goals. You must find new weapons for us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>%s is what we currently lack. Bring it when you find it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>That's good. The brothers are proud of you.</text>
	</string>

<!-- FIND MUTANT MEAT FOR GREH TASK -->
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_4_name">
		<text>Meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_4_text">
		<text>Hunt %s. Give the meat to Veles - he can cook it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_4_about">
		<text>Our supplies are running low. You need to go into the Zone and hunt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_4_fetch_about">
		<text>Here, %s is what we need. Remember, these creatures are a gift from the Zone. Kill them swiftly and with gratitude.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_4_fetch_finish">
		<text>You have succeeded. Well done.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- FIND SUPPLIES FOR GREH TASK -->
<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_5_name">
		<text>Find %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_5_text">
		<text>Find %s. Return to Veles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_5_about">
		<text>You must provide more supplies for us so we can continue our great work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_5_fetch_about">
		<text>The search target is %s. Retrieve it and return.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_5_fetch_finish">
		<text>Greh appreciates good work.</text>
	</string>

<!-- FIND ARTEFACT FOR GREH TASK -->
<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_6_name">
		<text>Find the Artefact %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_6_text">
		<text>Find the artefact %s and bring it to Veles so he can prepare it as a sacrifice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_6_about">
		<text>We need an artefact to offer as a sacrifice. Are you ready to serve Greh and find it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_6_fetch_about">
		<text>Here, %s is what we need. Bring it to me so we can conduct the ceremony.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_dark_stalker_boss_task_6_fetch_finish">
		<text>You serve Greh well. Join us today in the ceremonial hall. There will be singing.</text>
	</string>

<!-- HUNT MUTANTS FOR GREH TASK -->
<string id="dasc_greh_trader_task_1_name">
		<text>Destroy the Mutant Lair</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_trader_task_1_text">
		<text>A cluster of mutants has been detected in this area, posing a threat to our brothers. Clean the area and return to Svarog for your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_trader_task_1_about">
		<text>Don’t you enjoy hunting? Recently, mutants made a lair near a vital spot for us, and it would be great if someone could shoot them. Will you take care of it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_trader_task_1_finish">
		<text>Excellent! Here’s your money. It’ll be a little calmer now, thank you, brother.</text>
	</string>

<!-- ASSAULT BANDIT CAMP FOR GREH TASK -->
<string id="dasc_greh_trader_task_2_name">
		<text>Destroy the Bandit Camp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_trader_task_2_text">
		<text>The area needs to be cleared of bandits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_trader_task_2_about">
		<text>We have big problems with bandits in this area. Can you help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_trader_task_2_finish">
		<text>Hell yeah, thank you! They won’t bother us for a long time now! Here’s your reward.</text>
	</string>

<!-- FIND MUTANT MEAT FOR GREH TASK -->
<string id="dasc_greh_trader_task_3_name">
		<text>Hunt for Meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_trader_task_3_text">
		<text>Svarog asked for %s to feed the brothers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_trader_task_3_about">
		<text>If you're a good shot and aren't afraid of mutants, I have a job for you. Interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_trader_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>Food supplies are running low, and I need something to feed the brothers. Someone brings me a mutant carcass every now and then, but recently no one wants to hunt. So, if you're not busy, bring me %s. Remember, adrenaline from the animal’s excitement makes the meat tough, and the less blood during the kill, the tastier the meat. So, shoot carefully, okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_trader_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Excellent, you're quite the hunter! Here’s your reward:</text>
	</string>

<!-- dasc_greh_tech -->
<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_1_name">
		<text>Find %s for Odin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_1_text">
		<text>Bring tools to Odin so he can upgrade equipment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_1_about">
		<text>You know, brother, I'm actually quite the technician. I can repair weapons and armor, even do some upgrades! Well, I would, if I had decent tools. But where would I get them around here? Can you help me get a basic toolkit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>I need a toolkit for heavy-duty work. It should include tools and oils for weapon maintenance. If you can get it, I’ll be grateful, and I’ll even pay you... Probably.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Excellent, man! Oh, sorry, I don't have money to pay you. But I can give you a nice discount!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_2_name">
		<text>Find %s for Odin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_2_text">
		<text>Bring Odin tools for precision work. He needs a more complete set to perform more complex upgrades on equipment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_2_about">
		<text>Hey, man, if you agree to get me a more complete set, you’ll get an even bigger discount. Will you help, buddy?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>I need tools for precision work. It should have everything I need. You’ll be like a brother if you can get them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Wow, thanks, buddy! Now I’m really gonna get rich. Damn, I’m going to be successful... Unless, of course, I mess this up too. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_3_name">
		<text>Find %s for Odin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_3_text">
		<text>Bring Odin %s. He needs a unique set to perform even more complex upgrades on equipment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_3_about">
		<text>Hey, buddy, if you find something worth it - I’ll give you a discount!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>I need calibration tools. It should have everything I need. You’ll be like a brother if you get them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_tech_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Holy...! Damn, thanks, buddy! Now I’m definitely going to get rich. Damn, I’m going to be successful... Unless, of course, I mess this up too. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, dude.</text>
	</string>



<!-- dasc_greh_medic -->
<string id="dasc_greh_medic_task_1_name">
		<text>%s for Yarovit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_medic_task_1_text">
		<text>You need to find the kit and bring it to the medic Yarovit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_medic_task_1_about">
		<text>I need a good medical kit. I can patch up light wounds quickly, but for anything more serious than a simple scalpel, I’m lacking the right tools.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_medic_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>I need a good medical kit. I can patch up light wounds quickly, but for anything more serious than a simple scalpel, I’m lacking the right tools.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dasc_greh_medic_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thanks, my friend! These tools will save the lives of many brothers. Thanks again for the tools.</text>
	</string>


</string_table>
