<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<!-- pb_shurup -->
	<string id="pb_shurup_task_1_name">
	<text>Find %s for Shurup</text>
</string>
<string id="pb_shurup_task_1_text">
	<text>You need to bring Shurup some tools so he can upgrade his equipment.</text>
</string>
<string id="pb_shurup_task_1_about">
	<text>You know, buddy, I'm actually a pretty good technician. I can fix weapons and armor, and I even do some upgrades! Well, I would if I had decent tools. But where could I get them here? Maybe you can help me get a simple set?</text>
</string>
<string id="pb_shurup_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>I need a set of tools for heavy work. It should include tools and oils for working with weapons. If you can get it, I'd really appreciate it, and I might even pay you!... Probably.</text>
</string>
<string id="pb_shurup_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Great, dude! Oh, sorry, I don’t have anything to pay you with. But I can give you a nice discount!</text>
</string>
<string id="pb_shurup_task_2_name">
	<text>Find %s for Shurup</text>
</string>
<string id="pb_shurup_task_2_text">
	<text>You need to bring Shurup a set of tools for delicate work. He needs a more complete set to perform more advanced upgrades on his equipment.</text>
</string>
<string id="pb_shurup_task_2_about">
	<text>Hey, dude, if you agree to get me a more complete set, you’ll get an even bigger discount. Help me out, buddy?</text>
</string>
<string id="pb_shurup_task_2_fetch_about">
	<text>I need tools for delicate work. It should have everything I need. You’ll be like a brother to me if you get it!</text>
</string>
<string id="pb_shurup_task_2_fetch_finish">
	<text>Wow, thanks, bro! Now I’m definitely going to get rich. Damn, I’m going to be successful! ...If, of course, I don’t miss this chance too. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>
<string id="pb_shurup_task_3_name">
	<text>Find %s for Shurup</text>
</string>
<string id="pb_shurup_task_3_text">
	<text>You need to bring Shurup %s. He needs a unique set of tools to perform even more advanced equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="pb_shurup_task_3_about">
	<text>Hey, man, if you find something valuable, I’ll give you a discount!</text>
</string>
<string id="pb_shurup_task_3_fetch_about">
	<text>I need tools for calibration. They should have everything I need. You’ll be like a brother to me if you get them!</text>
</string>
<string id="pb_shurup_task_3_fetch_finish">
	<text>No way...! Damn, thanks, bro! Now I’m definitely going to get rich. Damn, I’m going to be successful! ...If, of course, I don’t miss this chance too. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>


</string_table>
