<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>


	<!-- garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup -->
	<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_1_name">
    <text>Business Proposal</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_1_text">
    <text>Filya needs the artifact %s. That's it, no unnecessary words or questions. A truly businesslike person!</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_1_about">
    <text>I'm interested in artifacts. Here's the deal: I'll give you a lead on a specific artifact, you bring it to me, and you get a reward. Both sides are happy. What do you think?</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_1_fetch_about">
    <text>My clients are interested in artifacts. Often, these are just "bright minds" who have had bad luck with connections, provided by the official scientific personnel in the Zone. So here's the deal: I'll give you a lead on a specific artifact, you bring it to me, and you get a reward. Both sides are happy. I need the artifact %s. I'll be waiting here, and so will your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_1_fetch_finish">
    <text>Good job, stalker. Here's your reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_2_name">
    <text>Dirty Work</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_2_text">
    <text>Filya gave me a dirty job - find and eliminate a stalker who managed to piss someone off.\n\nAll the necessary information is provided by Filya on the PDA. Time to get to work. Tough luck for that poor guy...</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_2_about">
    <text>Sometimes stalkers come to me when someone has wronged them or caused trouble, and I, in turn, find willing people to help them with this difficult task, so that certain individuals don't have any problems afterward. Consider me the middleman.\nRight now, I have several targets for elimination in progress. Usually, it's a stalker who has betrayed or set up his friends, but sometimes there are even contract killings of people from other factions. It's dirty work, but someone has to do it, especially when the reward is worth it, right? So, what do you say? I'll send the necessary information to your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_2_finish">
    <text>Thank you, stalker. Here’s your payment, just don't get too carried away with the killings. Mercenaries don't need any competition either. Heh-heh...</text>
</string>

<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_3_name">
    <text>Pseudo-bugs and Pseudo-mice</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_3_text">
    <text>There's a joke among stalkers: "A stalker planted a pseudo-turnip. It grew into a big pseudo-turnip! The stalker took a grenade launcher and went to harvest it. And everything would have gone perfectly, if not for the pseudo-bugs and pseudo-mice that attacked." It sounds funny, but sometimes these bugs and mice really can be a pain in the neck. It gets to the point where you can't take ten steps from the camp without having another pseudo-someone flying at you!\nThat’s why Filya suggested combining business with pleasure - earn some money by clearing the surrounding areas of mutants. It’s the right thing to do, as there’s been a surge in these creatures... Plus, trophies won’t be unnecessary.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_3_about">
    <text>By the way, did you see any mutants on your way here? The Duty guys recently cleared the area, but some newly arrived stalkers reported seeing either dogs or something else at the outer borders of the camp. If they’re not joking, these creatures pose a serious threat to both the stalkers in the camp and anyone else heading here. Not to mention that the absence of clients harms the business. So, I’m willing to pay well for mutant extermination, and I might throw in something extra. The main thing is that there’s no trace left of them. Here are the approximate coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_3_finish">
    <text>Good work. Here are your well-earned rewards.</text>
</string>

	
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- toad (Loner Trader) New Tasks -->
	
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_4_name">
    <text>Unusual Business</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_4_text">
    <text>As they say, the rich have their quirks. One such client apparently approached Filya and asked him to find a trophy – “%s”...\nFilya, in turn, promised a good payment for delivering the trophy to him, so he could send it to the client.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_4_about">
    <text>You see, I’m not just a busy person, but also quite generous to those who are willing to help me solve my problems. And right now, I have a burning order. Interested?</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_4_fetch_about">
    <text>So here’s the deal: one of my clients, who is also a great jeweler specializing in animal trophies, wants this one – %s. He’s willing to pay me a good amount for delivery. I, in turn, am willing to pay you for delivering the trophy to me first. You get what I mean? Make sure the mutant parts with its belonging and bring it to me. You won’t be shortchanged.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_4_fetch_finish">
    <text>Well done! Here’s your well-earned reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_5_name">
    <text>Cache Raider</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_5_text">
    <text>What was yours is now ours. Filya asked to steal some important documents and deliver them to him.\nThe coordinates of their location have been sent to my PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_5_about">
    <text>I’ve been whispered about a cache with some very interesting documents. I have no idea who the owner is or where they might be now, but I will reward anyone who manages to get those documents and miraculously have them appear on this bar counter. Got it? I’ll send you the last known coordinates of the stash. I doubt it’s a trap, because setting me up – that’s not something you do when you’re trying to mess with Sidorovich’s deals on the Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenup_task_5_finish">
    <text>You really impressed me. Great work, stalker.</text>
</string>


	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Clear Mutants -->

<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_1_name">
    <text>Cleaner</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_1_text">
    <text>It’s not a good idea to leave mutants unchecked. You need to find their den and clear it out. It won’t eliminate them entirely, but it will significantly reduce their population.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_1_about">
    <text>Shh... Quiet! Hear that?\nMutants have come to us again. It gives me the chills...\nThey come here often, but it’s still unclear where they come from. From all over the Zone, maybe... It’s dangerous to leave them without attention.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_1_finish">
    <text>So, you’ve already sent all the critters back to their dens? Excellent. You’ve done a good deed, my friend! Here, take this from Borya!</text>
</string>

<!-- FIND ARTEFACT FOR BEARD TASK -->
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_2_name">
    <text>Artifact Hunter</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_2_text">
    <text>When it comes to artifact orders, Borya is known for only working with his trusted people. However, there are times when even they can’t find anything on time.\nIn such cases, Borya turns to regular stalkers to fulfill the order on time, and the stalkers can earn some money.\nThe trader is willing to pay well for the artifact %s.\nYou should try to find this artifact as soon as possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_2_about">
    <text>I usually don’t buy artifacts from stalkers, but there’s an urgent order, and I wouldn’t want to let the client down. Can you find one for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_2_fetch_about">
    <text>Here’s the deal... I usually rely on my own people when it comes to hunting for artifacts, rather than buying them off stalkers. I’ve seen a lot of things over time...\nHowever, my guys haven’t found anything yet, and I’ve got a serious order burning. The client is good, reliable. I wouldn’t want us both to be stressed out over the situation. Do you know what my rule is? If the client is calm, I have nothing to worry about. It’s simple.\nSo listen, I’m looking for artifact %s. Maybe you’ve heard of it or even seen it, but that’s beside the point. If you find it, I’ll pay you well.\nWhat do you say? Can you get it for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_2_fetch_finish">
    <text>Well, stalker, I owe you! You saved Borya, and for that, I’m really grateful.</text>
</string>



	<!-- ASSASSINATION FOR BEARD TASK -->
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_3_name">
    <text>If a Friend Suddenly Turns...</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_3_text">
    <text>One of the stalkers who recently joined the military decided to take advantage of the trust of his fellow stalkers to cold-bloodedly kill them in the most despicable way, either for his own benefit or simply out of spite. In any case, Borya managed to track down the current location of the brother-killer through Skidan, and this traitor deserves no forgiveness for his actions. Borya asked to avenge all the comrades betrayed by this stalker. As they say, you reap what you sow.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_3_about">
    <text>We’ve got a little problem here. We had a good brother-stalker among us, the kind you find plenty of on “Skadovsk.” But one fine gray day, some guys from the honorable army showed up, and guess what? They made him an enticing offer, the outcome of which we weren’t aware of. Until recently.\nYou see, not long ago, we started finding dead stalkers – no calls for help or anything like that. They were either slit throats or had a 9mm hole in the back of their heads. What’s strange is that, reportedly, no one heard any gunshots. Whether you know it or not, we had a situation before with the disappearance of stalkers – we lost some good ones! So this time, I didn’t wait, and through my channels, I checked the latest events and rumors. And guess what? We found the killer! And guess who it was! It was the same brother-stalker I told you about.\nYou understand, my friend, the military offer really appealed to him, but getting a punch in the face from his own people? Unlikely. So, he decided to stab his comrades in the back. They didn’t agree with his decision, but to kill him? Too much. But our now-soldier apparently wasn’t averse to using their trust: he waited for the right moment, and bam – no more stalkers with us.\n\nSo, I contacted Sidorovich about this – he helped me find out where this brother-killer is now. There’s no point in discussing it, brother, he could have left peacefully, but he chose to start his new life with betrayal. There’s no forgiveness for such people in our society, and you know what needs to be done.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_3_finish">
    <text>Did you avenge the guys? Thank you very much, my friend. It’s a scary place, the Zone. A brother willing to kill his own for personal gain out of spite, oh, what times... Anyway, here’s your reward for bringing justice.</text>
</string>

<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_4_name">
    <text>Field of Wonders</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_4_text">
    <text>Trader Kusto offers an exchange: some decent gear, as he says, in exchange for a specific artifact. He asked for the artifact %s to be found and delivered to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_4_about">
    <text>Don’t you want to get some decent gear in exchange for an artifact?</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_4_fetch_about">
    <text>Don’t you want to get good gear while searching for rare artifacts? I can offer you such gear for one artifact – it’s called %s.</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_depo_stalker_barmenin_task_4_fetch_finish">
    <text>Great job, stalker. Here you go.</text>
</string>


</string_table>
