<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<!-- ex_gar_technik -->
<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_1_name">
    <text>Find %s for Monter</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_1_text">
    <text>You need to bring tools to Monter so he can carry out equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_1_about">
    <text>You know, buddy, I’m actually a pretty good technician. I can repair weapons and armor, even do some upgrades! Well, I would if I had decent tools. But where can you get them around here? Maybe you could help me get a simple set?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_1_fetch_about">
    <text>I need a set of tools for heavy work. It should have the necessary tools and oils for working with weapons. If you can get it, I’ll be grateful, and maybe even pay you!... Probably.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_1_fetch_finish">
    <text>Awesome, dude! Oh, sorry, I don’t have anything to pay you with. But I can give you a good discount!</text>
</string>

<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_2_name">
    <text>Find %s for Monter</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_2_text">
    <text>You need to bring Monter tools for fine work. He needs a more complete set to carry out more complex equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_2_about">
    <text>Hey, dude, if you agree to get me a more complete set, I’ll give you an even bigger discount. Help me out, buddy?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_2_fetch_about">
    <text>I need tools for fine work. It should have everything I need. You’ll be like a brother to me if you get them!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_2_fetch_finish">
    <text>Wow, thanks, buddy! Now I’ll definitely get rich. Damn, I’m going to be successful!.. If, of course, I don’t mess this up. But I still can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>

<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_3_name">
    <text>Find %s for Monter</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_3_text">
    <text>You need to bring Monter %s. He needs a unique set of tools to carry out even more complex equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_3_about">
    <text>Hey, man, if you find something good, you’ll get a discount from me!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_3_fetch_about">
    <text>I need tools for calibration. They should have everything I need. You’ll be like a brother to me if you bring them!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_gar_technik_task_3_fetch_finish">
    <text>No way...! Damn, thanks, bro! Now I’ll definitely get rich. Damn, I’m going to be successful!.. If, of course, I don’t mess up again. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>



	<!-- el_stalker_medik -->
<string id="el_stalker_medik_task_1_name">
    <text>%s for Green</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_medik_task_1_text">
    <text>You need to find the kit and bring it to the medic Green.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_medik_task_1_about">
    <text>I need a good set of medical tools. I can quickly patch up light wounds, but for anything more serious, my simple scalpel won't be enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_medik_task_1_fetch_about">
    <text>I need a good set of medical tools. I can quickly patch up light wounds, but for anything more serious, my simple scalpel won't be enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_medik_task_1_fetch_finish">
    <text>Thank you, my friend! These tools will save many lives. Thanks again for bringing the tools.</text>
</string>

</string_table>
