<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<!-- bar_npc_dolg_mechanic -->
	<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_1_name">
	<text>Find %s for Tokar</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_1_text">
	<text>You need to bring Tokar the tools so he can perform equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_1_about">
	<text>You know, buddy, I’m actually a pretty good technician. I can repair weapons and armor, even do some upgrades! Well, I would, if I had decent tools. But where the hell am I supposed to get them around here? Maybe you can help me get a simple set?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>I need a basic set of tools for heavy work. It should include tools and oils for working with weapons. If you can get them, I’ll be grateful and might even pay you!... Probably.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Great, dude! Oh, sorry, I don’t have anything to pay you with. But I can offer you a good discount!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_2_name">
	<text>Find %s for Tokar</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_2_text">
	<text>You need to bring Tokar the tools for fine work. He needs a more complete set to perform more complex equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_2_about">
	<text>Hey, buddy, if you agree to get me a more complete set, I’ll give you an even bigger discount. Will you help me out, friend?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_2_fetch_about">
	<text>I need tools for fine work. It should have everything I need. You’ll be like a brother to me if you get them!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_2_fetch_finish">
	<text>Oh wow, thanks, bro! Now I’m definitely going to get rich. Damn it, I’m going to be successful! ... Unless, of course, I screw up this chance too. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_3_name">
	<text>Find %s for Tokar</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_3_text">
	<text>You need to bring Tokar %s. He needs a unique set of tools to perform even more complex equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_3_about">
	<text>Hey, man, if you find something worth it, I’ll give you a discount!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_3_fetch_about">
	<text>I need tools for calibration. They should have everything I need. You’ll be like a brother to me if you get them!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_3_fetch_finish">
	<text>No way...! Damn, thanks, bro! Now I’m definitely going to get rich. Damn it, I’m going to be successful!... Unless, of course, I screw up this chance too. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>

<!-- bar_medic -->
<string id="bar_medic_task_1_name">
	<text>%s for Ukol</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_medic_task_1_text">
	<text>You need to find a medical kit and deliver it to medic Ukol.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_medic_task_1_about">
	<text>I need a good medical kit. I can patch up minor wounds quickly, but for anything more serious, my scalpel isn’t enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_medic_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>I need a good medical kit. I can patch up minor wounds quickly, but for anything more serious, my scalpel isn’t enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_medic_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Thanks, friend! These tools will save many lives. Thanks again for the tools.</text>
</string>

</string_table>
