<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<!-- sad_b2_stalker_tech -->
	<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_1_name">
	<text>Find %s for Palych</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_1_text">
	<text>You need to bring tools to Palych so he can perform equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_1_about">
	<text>You know, buddy, I'm actually a pretty good technician. I can fix weapons and armor, even do some upgrades! Well, I would if I had proper tools. But where would I get them here? Maybe you can help me find a simple set?</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>I need a set of tools for rough work. It should have the tools and oils for working with weapons. If you can get it, I'd appreciate it, and maybe even pay you!.. Probably.</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Great, dude! Oh, sorry, I have no way to pay you. But I can offer you a good discount!</text>
</string>

<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_2_name">
	<text>Find %s for Palych</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_2_text">
	<text>You need to bring Palych tools for fine work. He needs a more complete set to perform more complex equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_2_about">
	<text>Hey, dude, if you agree to get me a more complete set, you'll get an even bigger discount. Will you help me, buddy?</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_2_fetch_about">
	<text>I need tools for fine work. It should have everything I need. You'll be like a brother to me if you bring it!</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_2_fetch_finish">
	<text>Wow, thanks, bro! Now I'm definitely going to get rich. Damn, I'm going to be successful!.. If, of course, I don't miss this chance. But for now, I can't offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>

<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_3_name">
	<text>Find %s for Palych</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_3_text">
	<text>You need to bring Palych %s. He needs a unique set to perform even more complex equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_3_about">
	<text>Hey, man, if you find something worth it, I'll give you a discount!</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_3_fetch_about">
	<text>I need calibration tools. It should have everything I need. You'll be like a brother to me if you bring them!</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_stalker_tech_task_3_fetch_finish">
	<text>No f***ing way...! Damn, thanks, bro! Now I'm definitely going to get rich. Damn, I'm going to be successful!.. If, of course, I don't miss this chance. But for now, I can't offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>



</string_table>
