<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>


<!-- esc_leader_stalkerbase -->
	<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_1_name">
    <text>Mutants vs Predator</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_1_text">
    <text>The wildlife in the Zone is quite diverse due to emissions pushing mutants from the center. They either gradually return, or other mutants take their place.
    \nBut it doesn't make it easier for anyone, especially for the stalkers and scientists stationed nearby.\n
    \nStalkers reported to Valeryan that they spotted a cluster of mutants nearby, posing a real danger to the stalkers in the area. You need to head there and thoroughly clear the area so that only crows can be heard.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_1_about">
    <text>Stalkers came by and said that mutants have settled nearby again...
    \nHere's the thing: aside from regular migration, emissions also push the wildlife around, so we never get to rest.\n
    \nYou seem pretty experienced, and I need a hunter who can clear the area of mutants and also not get killed in the process. After all, I don't want any sins on my soul. So please assess your strength wisely.\n
    \nSo, are you up for the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_1_finish">
    <text>Thank you, stalker. Thanks to you, it's going to be much safer here now. Here's your reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_2_name">
    <text>Running on the Edge</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_2_text">
    <text>Sometimes, in the Zone, the hunt is not just for mutants, but for stalkers as well. And not always is this act immoral.
    \nAfter all, there is a big difference between mercenary and bandit jobs and eliminating extremely dangerous individuals who pose a serious threat to everyone.\n
    \nValeryan received information about one such dangerous stalker, which he passed to me on the PDA. It's time to rid the Zone of one of these threats to ensure the safety of the other stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_2_about">
    <text>I'm sure you're familiar with the dangers posed by mutants, but often, a human can be even more dangerous than any mutant. You know... as one wise person, an academic I think, once said, “Man is the greatest scoundrel in the world.”
    \nAnd the Zone is real proof of that. For example, "Monolith" and bandits—they’re the worst; you could say they’ve had their brains washed clean to the bone. But of course, this doesn't justify their actions. And then there are people by nature... well, you know. They’re just as dangerous. So, we need to act decisively.\n
    \nHere's what I propose: we need to eliminate the stalker who poses a huge threat to everyone. I'll pay well for this task. The choice is yours.
    \nBut I'll tell you right away: don't bother asking about morality—it's too late for them.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_2_finish">
    <text>Thank you, hunter. Here's your reward:</text>
</string>



	<!-- FIND WEAPON FOR HUNTSMAN TASK -->
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_3_name">
    <text>Rifle for the Hunter - Like an Axe for the Carpenter</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_3_text">
    <text>Valeryan is not only involved in planning operations to clear logs or hunting trophies, but he also helps hunters by providing them with new weapons due to loss or irreparable damage caused by close combat with their weapons.\n
    \nAnother hunter ordered a “%s” from Valeryan, and he promised to pay me well for its delivery.\n
    \nIt’s important to remember that hunters ease everyone’s life in the Zone with their good deeds, so their weapons must be in perfect condition. At the very least, out of respect for their work.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_3_about">
    <text>Have you ever had to resort to, let’s say, exotic methods of killing game?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_3_fetch_about">
    <text>Have you ever had to resort to, let’s say, exotic methods of killing game? Seasoned hunters have, and not just once. Sometimes, a weapon jams, despite being in good condition, and you can't afford to hesitate... In those cases, anything goes: backup weapons, knives, and often even the jammed gun itself.\n
    \nNot every hunter can just take a weapon and kill a kikimora or pseudodog to death. But it’s possible. The problem is that after such a no-rules fight, the weapon is usually easier to throw away than to try to repair. Especially here, where good tools are a luxury. Of course, sometimes the weapon is simply lost in battle...\n
    \nAnyway, one of the hunters urgently needs a new gun. His order is for a “%s”. Have you seen anything like it?\n
    \nI’m ready to pay well for its delivery. Just keep in mind, this is for a hunter, so the weapon must be in perfect condition. You may have issues with stalkers or factions, but betraying a hunter is the last thing you should do. After all, they make life easier for everyone here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_3_fetch_finish">
    <text>Let’s see... Condition... excellent. Yes, everything’s in place, and everything works. Good work, friend. I’ll notify the hunter about the delivery right away.\n
    \nAnd here’s the money I promised you.</text>
</string>

<!-- FIND MUTANT PARTS FOR HUNTSMAN TASK -->
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_4_name">
    <text>Features of National Hunting</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_4_text">
    <text>Valeryan needs a “%s”. Expect good money for this trophy.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_4_about">
    <text>I have an order for a specific type of trophy. Interested?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_4_fetch_about">
    <text>You’ve probably already seen that in the Zone, you can find creatures of all kinds, sizes, and ferocity? The only thing that unites them is hunger and the desire to tear apart the first stalker they come across.\n
    \nI combine business with pleasure here. I don’t hunt myself, but I can provide work for hunters and volunteers. The useful part is clearing the area near the camp from mutants. The pleasant part is the trophies they bring me, as well as the money I pay those who successfully complete the task. I either keep the trophies for myself or send them through stalkers to customers, of which there are plenty. So, as you can see, there’s always work to be done.\n
    If you’re interested, I currently have an order. Right now, I need a “%s”. Well, can you handle it? The reward is appropriate.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_stalkerbase_task_4_fetch_finish">
    <text>Another threat has been eliminated, and the camp has gained a new trophy. Excellent. Good job, hunter.</text>
</string>

	
	<!-- stalker base trader -->
	<string id="esc_trader_stalkerbase_task_1_name">
    <text>Destroy the Mutant Den</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trader_stalkerbase_task_1_text">
    <text>Shilov asked to destroy the mutant den located nearby.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trader_stalkerbase_task_1_about">
    <text>I’ve got a job for you.\nIt’s getting more dangerous every day around here. More and more dangerous mutants are nesting, and we absolutely can’t let them breed here.\n
    \nYou’ll need to clear the area I’ll mark on your PDA. Kill every creature you see. If you succeed, I won’t forget it. So, are you in?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trader_stalkerbase_1_finish">
    <text>Thanks, stalker. Because of you, we’ll be relatively safe. Here’s your reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_trader_stalkerbase_task_2_name">
    <text>Business Proposal</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trader_stalkerbase_task_2_text">
    <text>Shilov needs the %s artifact for some experiments.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trader_stalkerbase_task_2_about">
    <text>I’m interested in artifacts. Here’s the deal: I’ll give you a lead on a certain artifact, you bring it, and we both get a reward. Everybody’s happy. How does that sound?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trader_stalkerbase_task_2_fetch_about">
    <text>I need an artifact for some of my experiments. Anyway, we’re looking for an artifact called %s. Are you in?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trader_stalkerbase_task_2_fetch_finish">
    <text>Good job, friend. Here are your bonuses.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_trader_stalkerbase_task_3_name">
    <text>Treasure Hunter</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trader_stalkerbase_task_3_text">
    <text>What was yours is now ours. Shilov asked to steal important documents and deliver them to him.\nHe sent me the coordinates of their location on my PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trader_stalkerbase_task_3_about">
    <text>I’ve heard about a stash containing some very interesting documents. I have no idea who owns them or where they might be now, but I’ll reward anyone who can get those documents to magically appear on this counter. Got it? I’ll send you the latest known coordinates of the stash on your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trader_stalkerbase_task_3_finish">
    <text>You’ve really impressed me. Excellent work, stalker.</text>
</string>

<!-- esc_barman_patogen_pa -->
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_1_name">
    <text>Business Proposal</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_1_text">
    <text>Tikhonich needs the %s artifact. No questions asked, just business. A real businessman!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_1_about">
    <text>I’m interested in artifacts. Here’s the deal: I give you a lead on a specific artifact, you bring it to me, and you get a reward. Everybody’s happy. How does that sound?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_1_fetch_about">
    <text>My clients are interested in artifacts. Often, they’re just “bright minds” who’ve had bad luck with their connections, people with access to official scientific resources in the Zone. So, here’s the deal: I give you a lead on a specific artifact, you bring it, and you get a reward. Everybody’s happy. I need the %s artifact. I’ll be waiting for it here, as well as your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_1_fetch_finish">
    <text>Good job, friend. Here are your bonuses.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_2_name">
    <text>Dirty Work</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_2_text">
    <text>Tikhonich has given me a dirty job – I need to find and eliminate a stalker who has managed to upset someone.\n
    \nAll the necessary information has been provided on the PDA. It’s time to get to work. Poor guy, bad luck...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_2_about">
    <text>Sometimes, stalkers come to me when they’ve wronged someone or made an enemy, and I, in turn, find people willing to help them with their problem, so that the individuals involved won’t face any consequences. Consider me a middleman.\nI currently have a few targets for elimination. Usually, it’s a stalker who’s betrayed or ordered the death of their friends, but sometimes it’s just contract killings involving people from other factions. It’s dirty work, but someone has to do it, especially if the reward is worth it, right? So, are you in? I’ll send the necessary details to your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_2_finish">
    <text>Thanks, stalker. Here’s your payment, but don’t get too carried away with killing. Competition isn’t good for mercenaries, either. Heh heh...</text>
</string>

	
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_3_name">
    <text>Pseudo-Bugs and Pseudo-Mice</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_3_text">
    <text>There’s a joke among stalkers: “A stalker planted a pseudo-radish. It grew into a huge pseudo-radish! The stalker took a grenade launcher and went to harvest it. And everything would have surely worked out if it weren’t for the pseudo-bugs and pseudo-mice attacking.” Sounds funny, right? But sometimes these little bugs and mice can truly be a pain in the ass. It gets so bad that you can’t take ten steps outside the camp without getting attacked by another pseudo-whatever!\nThat’s exactly why Tikhonich proposed mixing business with pleasure – earn some money by clearing the surrounding area of mutants. It’s a good cause because the place is overrun by all kinds of creatures... Plus, trophies will never hurt.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_3_about">
    <text>Tell me, did you spot any mutants on your way here? The Duty guys recently cleared the surrounding area, but some new stalkers reported seeing either dogs or something else near the outer boundaries of the camp. If they’re not joking, these creatures pose a serious threat to both the stalkers in the camp and anyone heading here in the future. Not to mention, no customers means bad business. Anyway, I’m willing to pay well for mutant elimination, and maybe even throw in something extra. The main thing is that there’s no trace left of them. Here are the approximate coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_3_finish">
    <text>Good work. And here’s your hard-earned reward.</text>
</string>

	
	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- toad (Loner Trader) New Tasks -->
	
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_4_name">
    <text>Unusual Business</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_4_text">
    <text>As they say, the rich have their quirks. One of these clients, apparently, contacted Tikhonych and asked him to find a certain trophy - “%s”...\nTikhonych, in turn, promised to pay well for its delivery to him, so he could then send it to the client.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_4_about">
    <text>You see, I’m not only a busy person, but also quite generous to those willing to help me solve my problems. And right now, I have an urgent order. Interested?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_4_fetch_about">
    <text>Here’s the deal, one of my clients, who’s also a fine jeweler specializing in animal trophies, wants a specific one - %s. He’s willing to pay me well for the delivery. In turn, I’m ready to pay you for delivering the trophy to me. Understand what I mean? Make sure the mutant parts with its possession, and bring it to me. You won’t be left empty-handed.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_4_fetch_finish">
    <text>Well done! Here’s your well-earned reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_5_name">
    <text>Vault Raider</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_5_text">
    <text>What was yours - will be ours. Tikhonych asked to steal some important documents and deliver them to him.\nHe sent me the coordinates of their location on my PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_5_about">
    <text>I’ve heard about a stash with some highly interesting documents. I have no idea who the owner is or where they might be now, but I’ll reward anyone who can manage to get these documents to appear on this bar counter. Got it? I’ll send you the last known coordinates of the stash on your PDA. I doubt it’s a trap, because trying to set me up would be a whole different story compared to messing up deals with Sidorovich on the Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_pa_task_5_finish">
    <text>Now that’s impressive. Great job, stalker.</text>
</string>

</string_table>
