<!-- Furgon Toolkit Quest 1 -->
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_1_name">
    <text>Find Basic Toolkit for Furgon</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_1_text">
    <text>Furgon needs a basic toolkit to perform repairs. He asked me to find one for him somewhere in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_1_about">
    <text>Furgon, the Loner mechanic, is looking for a basic toolkit. He says he can make use of it for simpler repair jobs.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_1_fetch_about">
    <text>Find and bring Furgon a basic toolkit.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_1_fetch_finish">
    <text>I gave Furgon the basic toolkit he asked for. He seemed happy and promised to improve his repair abilities.</text>
</string>

<!-- Furgon Toolkit Quest 2 -->
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_2_name">
    <text>Find Advanced Toolkit for Furgon</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_2_text">
    <text>Furgon now needs an advanced toolkit to handle more complex repairs. He asked me to help him locate one.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_2_about">
    <text>Furgon's workbench is lacking advanced tools. If I bring him an advanced toolkit, he’ll be able to offer better upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_2_fetch_about">
    <text>Search the Zone for an advanced toolkit and bring it to Furgon.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_2_fetch_finish">
    <text>I brought the advanced toolkit to Furgon. He immediately started upgrading his setup.</text>
</string>

<!-- Furgon Toolkit Quest 3 -->
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_3_name">
    <text>Find Expert Toolkit for Furgon</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_3_text">
    <text>Furgon wants to reach the peak of his craft and needs an expert toolkit. This will be hard to find.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_3_about">
    <text>The final step for Furgon’s workshop is getting an expert toolkit. With it, he’ll be able to perform the most advanced upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_3_fetch_about">
    <text>Bring Furgon an expert-level toolkit to complete his upgrade path.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_3_fetch_finish">
    <text>Furgon was thrilled to receive the expert toolkit. His workshop is now fully equipped.</text>
</string>
