<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_0">
    <text>Who the hell are you?!</text>
</string>
<string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_1">
    <text>Stalker, just a stalker. You must be the technician - Pianist?</text>
</string>
<string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_2">
    <text>Maybe yes, maybe no. It all depends on what you need from me. How did you even find me?</text>
</string>
<string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_3">
    <text>So it's definitely you. Finding you wasn't hard, first I found your flash drive, and then you yourself. Stalkers from the camp near the farm are looking for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_4">
    <text>Looking for me? Why the hell would they need me? To bother me again? To tell newcomers how to live? Huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_5">
    <text>How should I know? They asked me, so I did it.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_6">
    <text>Alright then, let's make a deal. You go to Tokha and explain that you found me, but I’m not going back to the camp. If they want something from me, they can get off their asses and come here. Clear?</text>
</string>
<string id="val_first_dialog_pianist_task_7">
    <text>More than clear.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Stalker, wait! Who are you and what are you looking for here?</text>
</string>
<string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Hunter, I answer to Zmey. I’m looking for my friend - Bison, you know him?</text>
</string>
<string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_10">
    <text>Really! Alright, I’ll talk to our leader, he’s a smart guy and knows electronics well, so I think he’ll help with this issue, but if not, we’ll figure something out.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_11">
    <text>Alright, here are two PDAs, and I need any information about your technician. What's his name, what else does he do besides repairs, or what did he do before he disappeared?</text>
</string>
<string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_12">
    <text>The technician’s name is Pianist, but I can't tell you what he's into, I haven't been keeping track of him. I don’t know anything about his recent activities either, but I’ll talk to the guys and let you know right away. By the way, the last time they saw the technician was near the old factory, there's also a gravity anomaly there. I’ll send you the coordinates right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_13">
    <text>Alright, then I’ll head there first, and maybe clear out some mutants along the way.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Hunter, that’s good, now there’s someone to shoot the wild animals, because we have eighty percent greenery, and the wildlife in the Zone doesn’t exactly “get along,” if you know what I mean. As for your Bison, he’s been here, he was with two other stalkers, one of them I think was called Plumber, and the second… Hm… Maybe Phoenix or Felix, like that cat from the commercial, I guess.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, that’s something. As for the local fauna, I think I can help you with that if you pay well and tell me more about Bison and the guys who were with him. By the way, do you have a technician in your camp?</text>
</string>
<string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_4">
    <text>We’ll pay not a lot, but enough to get by, but our technician is missing.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Missing? And you didn’t search for him?!</text>
</string>

  <string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_6">
    <text>We searched, but where and to whom could we search here? Greenery?! Who’s afraid to even stick their nose out of the camp, or us experienced stalkers who can't leave the camp because we’re guarding this very Greenery. It’s a mess, brother, like in that saying: "Want and can't have..."</text>
</string>
<string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Listen, I could help with searching for your technician, if you want, but in return, I’ll need a favor.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_8">
    <text>That would be great! What kind of favor do you need?</text>
</string>
<string id="val_garik_storyline_start_dialog_9">
    <text>I have two PDAs, both are locked, but one of them looks like it’s cloned or the information is heavily erased. I need to unlock one of them, and with the second, figure out who it belongs to or belonged to and try to recover any information if possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_going_to_unlock_flashcard_0">
    <text>So you're the Hunter who decided to help with searching for our Technician?</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_going_to_unlock_flashcard_1">
    <text>That's right, actually, that’s why I came. I was around the place where your technician was last seen and found a flash drive, but the problem is... it’s locked.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_going_to_unlock_flashcard_2">
    <text>Really! I understand you want me to unlock it? If so, hand it over, and you can go take a walk, I’ll let you know when I’m done.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_going_to_unlock_flashcard_3">
    <text>Alright, I’ll be waiting.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_0">
    <text>Here you are, so did you manage to find Pianist?</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_1">
    <text>I did, he asked me to pass a couple of words to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_10">
    <text>Zmey, don't interrupt, let me finish. So, Felix was like a clean slate, but he quickly understood what was going on. He wandered around the area, did some tasks for us, and then it turned out that the "blues" were hunting him. He apparently solved the issue by just shooting them all. I don’t know how exactly it went, but Garik went to the place of the massacre and saw the bodies... So, where was I... Oh yes! After dealing with the "blues", he packed his stuff and headed for the old factory, the anarchists are not far from there, by the way, you passed by there when you were looking for Pianist.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_11">
    <text>Yes, I remember that factory, there were a lot of mutants there...</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_12">
    <text>That's the reality. So, look for him there, maybe you'll get lucky.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_13">
    <text>Alright, thanks for the tip.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_2">
    <text>So, what happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_3">
    <text>Here’s what I was told: I won’t be returning to the camp. If they want anything from me, they can get their asses up and come here. That’s it.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_4">
    <text>Got it. By the way, about those PDAs, I managed to unlock one of them. As for the other, I can’t help with that. It’s completely unregistered, just a password was set and the coordinates of our camp were added, and that’s all...</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_5">
    <text>Hmm... Not much, but better than nothing. By the way, about the clean PDA, I figured as much, but since I didn’t have the knowledge, I had to bring it to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_6">
    <text>Got it. Well, Zmey, if you ever want to help us, you're always welcome.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_7">
    <text>By the way, speaking of help, I think we could help each other. I’m not sure if Garik told you why I’m here, but I’ll repeat it. I’m looking for Bison and his group, or whatever’s left of it. The PDAs I gave you belonged to members of his group.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_8">
    <text>Garik mentioned your reason for visiting, but I can’t tell you much. I’ll tell you what I know. Bison was here, and he had two companions: Plumber and Felix. They were looking for some kind of artifact or something similar. They stayed with us for about three days, and then they just left. The only thing that might help you is that we later found Felix, but he was strange, like his brain had been formatted like a flash drive...</text>
</string>
<string id="val_toha_like_without_hands_task_complete_9">
    <text>That’s interesting, where is Felix now?</text>
</string>


 <string id="dl_done_first_quest_val_a3_stalker_garik_0">
    <text>So, what's going on with the case?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_done_first_quest_val_a3_stalker_garik_1">
    <text>Here it is, safe and sound.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_done_first_quest_val_a3_stalker_garik_11">
    <text>In progress.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_done_first_quest_val_a3_stalker_garik_2">
    <text>Great, here’s the gun and some ammo for it, just as we agreed. By the way, our leader wanted to have a word with you, he’s sitting to the right of me at the table.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_done_first_quest_val_a3_stalker_garik_3">
    <text>Thank you! Have a chat? Alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_done_first_quest_val_a3_stalker_garik_4">
    <text>By the way, if you ever feel like earning a little and helping our humble clan, you know where to find me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_done_first_quest_val_a3_stalker_garik_5">
    <text>I’ll keep that in mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_0">
    <text>...Thanks again, Snake! If it weren’t for you, blind dogs would’ve already eaten me...</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_1">
    <text>It’s alright, I’m just glad I got there in time, nothing else matters. But tell me, what happened to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_2">
    <text>Oh... Well, you know the purpose of our mission, so I won’t repeat it. Anyway, yesterday, Bizon, Grek, and I headed to a village, there were rumors that we could find some supplies, you know, take a break from our main task. We got to the village, and before we knew it, a sniper was firing at us, and then more guys joined in. We tried to hold them off, but it was in vain, so we decided to retreat. I told the guys I’d cover their retreat and try to catch up. They moved, and I started shooting in all directions to draw all the fire on me so they could escape. Eventually, as soon as the guys were out of sight, the fire began to subside... I thought that was it... Finally hit someone, and they decided to wait until I ran out of ammo. I wasn’t behind the house for long, one of the attackers flanked me and shot me, luckily not in the heart, though it was close. Bleeding out, I lay there for a couple of hours, then I started crawling toward the camp, but I was out of strength and sent a distress signal, and then you showed up.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_3">
    <text>Born lucky, huh? Who attacked you? Were you able to see who they were?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_4">
    <text>I was able not only to see them but also to hear their conversation.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_5">
    <text>Now that's interesting, tell me more.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_6">
    <text>They were mercenaries, and from the conversation, it was clear they were hired to eliminate Bizon, and our group was just collateral damage. I don’t know who or why they wanted Bizon gone, but the fact remains: the mercenaries were after Bizon.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_7">
    <text>Shit... Where do we even start looking for him? Where could he have gone with Grek?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_8">
    <text>We didn’t have a permanent camp, so I can’t give you a specific location. Sorry.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_buriy_base_9">
    <text>Alright, you rest and regain your strength. I’ll work with the local guys, maybe they can help with the search.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_0">
    <text>Hey, stalker! Where are you from, and where’s your gear?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_1">
    <text>Me? I escaped from the bandits, and my gear is apparently with them, “stored” for safekeeping... Anyway, never mind that, the main thing is that I managed to get my legs moving.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_2">
    <text>Well, you sure are lucky! No denying that.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_3">
    <text>Yeah, yeah, listen, maybe you can help me out? I just need a gun, I can’t go anywhere without one...</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_4">
    <text>Help you out? I think I can. Here’s the deal, I’ll give you a gun and some ammo for it, and you go grab something for me. Sound good?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_5">
    <text>Deal! What and where do I need to grab?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_6">
    <text>So, if you head northwest, you’ll find a ravine, and in the ravine, there’s a small group of anomalies. That’s where the container I need is.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_val_a3_stalker_garik_7">
    <text>Sounds simple enough, I’ll give it a try.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_wounded_buriy_0">
    <text>Help...</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_first_dialog_wounded_buriy_1">
    <text>Buri?! Damn, I’ll carry you to the camp, hang in there, bro!</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_second_quest_garik_dialog_0">
    <text>Peace to you, Garik! Toha said you picked up a distress signal?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_second_quest_garik_dialog_02_0">
    <text>Too bad about the guy...</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_second_quest_garik_dialog_02_1">
    <text>Agreed, not the best fate... However, there's a silver lining, the creature's dead, which means the chances of anyone else dying just went down. Alright, shall we head back?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_second_quest_garik_dialog_02_2">
    <text>Agreed... Yes, let's go back.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_second_quest_garik_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, there's something to it, and the signal is not far from here. Listen, shall we check it out?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_second_quest_garik_dialog_2">
    <text>Sure, I don't have anything else to do for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_garik_quest_0">
    <text>Oh, Snake! I was told recently that they saw a couple of stalkers in excellent gear near the southwest settlement, they were heading towards the swamp, not far from here. They’re probably the ones you're looking for. Also, they saw some lone mercenary there, I don't think he would interest you, but still.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_garik_quest_1">
    <text>A mercenary? Are you sure?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_garik_quest_2">
    <text>I think so. All our groups are marked on my PDA, and we've never seen those guys before.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_garik_quest_3">
    <text>Alright, I'll go check it out, maybe it really is Bison and Greek.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Good day, as we agreed: I and my men are here and ready for any task you set.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Excellent, Lieutenant! Don’t you have any questions about the operation?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Snake, I’ve already told you I know you well, so I knew you wouldn’t call me and my men unless you really needed us, that’s why we're here.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_first_dialog_4">
    <text>You flatter me, well, never mind, I’ll call in the rest of the guys and we’ll move out.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_second_dialog_0">
    <text>My men and Toha’s men are ready, shall we start?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Let’s go!</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_third_dialog_0">
    <text>The enemy is defeated, our troops are holding position.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_third_dialog_1">
    <text>Got it, did you see Bison?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_third_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes... He’s behind that building. Snake, he’s dead.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_krasnopolsky_third_dialog_3">
    <text>What?! No!</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_0">
    <text>Have you or your men encountered mercenaries in the area recently?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_02_0">
    <text>I’ve got some good news.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_02_1">
    <text>I didn’t think the guys from Duty would agree so quickly. Though, they seem to have their own score to settle with the mercs. By the way, when can we expect them?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_02_2">
    <text>The commander of the Duty squad said they’ll be here by midnight tomorrow, they’re coming to the farm.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_02_3">
    <text>Great, we’ll get ready. By the way, while you were talking to the Duty guys, Garik caught another S.O.S. signal. Go check it out.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_02_4">
    <text>Alright, I’ll go talk to Garik.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, just yesterday some guys from the Syndicate showed up here and settled at the northern checkpoint. I don’t know why they’re here, and honestly, I don’t want to know. It’s dangerous to know the mercs’ plans, I’ve learned that the hard way.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_2">
    <text>I understand. Listen, do you have any desire to get rid of some uninvited guests?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_3">
    <text>Let’s just say, I’m not against it, but I’m afraid that even if we get rid of these scumbags, others will show up.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_4">
    <text>I don’t think so. Not long ago, a group from Duty wiped out a squad of mercs near the old research institute, and we haven’t seen any more of them. I think it’ll be the same with this group.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_5">
    <text>You think so? I don’t want to take risks. But if the guys from the honorable Duty group came here and helped out, the mercs wouldn’t notice our presence.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_6">
    <text>Hmm... I think I can manage to invite them.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_7">
    <text>Now, that’s a different story! Once the Duty guys arrive, I’ll send you some of my men, I think that’s fair!</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_storyline_toha_dialog_8">
    <text>Got it, I’ll go try to contact the guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_tech_pda_vorona_locked_out_0">
    <text>Hello! Can you hack this PDA?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_tech_pda_vorona_locked_out_1">
    <text>After you brought me the radio materials, I think I’m capable of quite a lot now! So give me the PDA and come back in a couple of hours.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_tech_pda_vorona_locked_out_2">
    <text>Glad to hear it! Here’s the PDA, let me know when it’s ready if you can.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_tech_pda_vorona_unlocked_in_0">
    <text>Got your message.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_tech_pda_vorona_unlocked_in_1">
    <text>What message? Oh, right! I almost forgot, too many things going on, but about that PDA, I unlocked it. There isn’t much information on it, just some map markings, mentions of a group, an artifact, and a couple of notes.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_tech_pda_vorona_unlocked_in_2">
    <text>Alright, I’ll take a look now.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_1_dialog_0">
    <text>Found the artifact, here it is.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_1_dialog_1">
    <text>Excellent, it’s a gravity-based artifact! Here’s a little gift from me, and our trader wanted to talk to you, go speak with him. Meanwhile, I’ll think about how to help with your problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_1_dialog_2">
    <text>Thank you, this gun will come in handy. As for the trader, I’ll go talk to him now.</text>
</string>

   <string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_2_dialog_0">
    <text>I found the artifact - here it is.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_2_dialog_1">
    <text>Great, an electric-type artifact! Here's a small gift from me, and our trader was looking for you, you should talk to him, and I'll think about how to help you with your problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_2_dialog_2">
    <text>Thank you, this is a nice weapon - it will come in handy, as for the trader, I'll go talk to him now.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_3_dialog_0">
    <text>I found the artifact - here it is.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_3_dialog_1">
    <text>Great, an acid-type artifact! Here's a small gift from me, and our trader was looking for you, you should talk to him, and I'll think about how to help you with your problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_art_3_dialog_2">
    <text>Thank you, any weapon will be useful now, as for the trader, I'll go talk to him now.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, hello, and what should I call you?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_1">
    <text>I respond to Snake, I'm a hunter by profession.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Any artifacts, I'll mark some anomalous fields on your PDA, wander around there, maybe you'll find something. By the way, I wouldn't advise you to go near the gangsters now, revenge is a dangerous thing... However, there's no rush! Also, I wouldn't advise going to the village to the north of here. The guys reported spotting a group of unknowns, and there's some creature wandering around... Anyway, I suggest you listen to this advice.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_11">
    <text>Alright, I hear you. I'll go "check" the anomalies...</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright, Snake the hunter. They call me Toha, I'm the leader here.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_3">
    <text>I see, Garik said you wanted to talk about something.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_4">
    <text>That's right, so I'm curious, how did you end up with the gangsters, how did you escape from there, and what are you doing in these Godforsaken lands?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Oh, this is probably the funniest part! I'll tell you everything from the beginning, and then we'll get to the point. So, I'm looking for a stalker named Bison and his group, or rather, what's left of them. My search led me to a collector, which was a shortcut to here. When I was heading back to the surface, they hit me on the head and took my stuff, I woke up in the bandits' den, it was strange that no one was guarding me, but I used that to my advantage, escaped through the fence, and stumbled upon your camp. That's how it happened.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, that's quite a story, I wouldn't envy you. Anyway, you got out, thank God. I understand you need gear now, I can give you some, but don't get too excited, you'll have to work for the good of our clan, I think you won't refuse, because you have no other choice. Also, I'll try to help you with your search, but that's for later.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Yeah... Refusing means dying, not much of a prospect. What should I do, and how can you help with my search?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Here's some gear and a few medical supplies. I see you already have a pistol, but one pistol won't be enough for these parts, there's a stash around here, the owner probably won't need it anymore, but it will be just right for you, it's somewhere on the camp's territory, you'll find it. As for the work, for starters, you'll have to work as an artifact collector, it's dangerous work, but if you have a good detector and the right skills, you shouldn't have any problems.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_val_a3_stalker_leader_first_dialog_9">
    <text>Thanks. You say I should be an artifact collector? What kind of artifacts do you need?</text>
</string>
<string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Who are you? And which faction?!</text>
</string>
<string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Stalker, just a stalker. They call me Snake.</text>
</string>
<string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_2">
    <text>What are you looking for here?</text>
</string>
<string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Information.</text>
</string>
<string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_4">
    <text>I don't like you!</text>
</string>
<string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_5">
    <text>And I'm not a woman to care whether you like me...</text>
</string>
<string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Yeah? Damn, I forgot to replace that, alright, enough jokes. Anyway, the camp's entrance is closed for you now, but if you complete a task, you'll be able to come here like it's your home.</text>
</string>
<string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Speak, I'm listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_8">
    <text>To the east of our camp, a group of bandits has settled. As you can guess, they are a problem for us, so if they disappeared, we would be grateful. Do you understand what I'm saying?</text>
</string>
<string id="zav_freedom_stalker_start_dialog_9">
    <text>Got it, I'll be back soon.</text>
</string>


  <string id="dl_bandits_attak_done_0">
    <text>What's up with my reward?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_bandits_attak_done_1">
    <text>Here you go, hard-earned!</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_bandits_attak_sk_done_0">
    <text>The squad is dead, but the bandits are also dead...</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_bandits_attak_sk_done_1">
    <text>Sad to hear... Anyway, here's what you earned.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_bandits_attak_start_0">
    <text>Do you need any help? Toha said you wanted something.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_bandits_attak_start_1">
    <text>I need help. Remember, I hired you to take out the bandit gang that was robbing our guys near the camp? Well, it's time to clean up their hideout.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_bandits_attak_start_2">
    <text>You say "clean up"... I'm not against it, but I won't go there alone.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_bandits_attak_start_22">
    <text>I'm not really in the mood for it, maybe another time.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_bandits_attak_start_3">
    <text>I wouldn't send you there alone, it's too risky. I've already arranged for some guys to join the cleanup. They'll be waiting for you near the bandits' camp. The leader's called Groza.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_bandits_attak_start_4">
    <text>Now that's more like it! I'll go then.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_bandits_attak_wait_0">
    <text>Are you our extra shooter? Don't worry, my guys are solid! They're used to handling firearms, so let's move!</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_bandits_attak_wait_1">
    <text>Let's go!</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_bandits_attak_wait_1_0">
    <text>Looks like we got them all!</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_bandits_attak_wait_1_1">
    <text>Seems like it, alright, we'll secure the area here. You go back to the camp, your reward awaits you for helping us.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_bandits_attak_wait_1_2">
    <text>Okay, see you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_done_0">
    <text>The squad is dead...</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_done_1">
    <text>What?! How?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_done_2">
    <text>They were killed by Monoliths. I don't know the exact details, but that's what happened. When I was searching the village, I spotted a Monolith squad, and in the shed, there were corpses. I decided to investigate, but first had to deal with those fanatics. In the end, I checked the bodies, and they were your guys. I found some documents on the squad leader. Here, take them [Giving documents] - maybe they're important.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_done_3">
    <text>Ugh... This is really unpleasant... Damn, we lost those guys... May they rest in peace. Leave the documents, it seems like they were after them... Damn...</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_done_4">
    <text>Alright, I'll leave you to it...</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_start_0">
    <text>Hello! I heard on the radio that you lost a squad?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_start_1">
    <text>Yes, that's true... The guys haven't contacted me yet, though they should have returned to the camp a while ago. I gathered a team to search for them, but so far, no results.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_start_2">
    <text>If you want, I can help search for them.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_start_3">
    <text>That would be great! Look [Shows map], here is where they last made contact - it's an abandoned village, mostly mutants there, but there are a couple of houses where you can rest. They may have stopped here before returning to base. I think you should check the village, since I sent the squad to the presumed resting spot.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_lost_squad_quest_start_4">
    <text>Okay, I understand. I'll let you know as soon as I find out something.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_stalker_quest_0">
    <text>Can I help you with something?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_stalker_quest_1">
    <text>Help? Maybe. You see, we just set up our base, haven't had time to clear the area yet. And the bandits are here: robbing stalkers who bring me supplies. At this rate, I'll have nothing to trade soon. Just yesterday, another bandit squad appeared. They are bold, they set up right across from our base! Could you do something about them?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_stalker_quest_11">
    <text>No, not at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_stalker_quest_2">
    <text>No problem! They'll remember this lesson for a long time.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_stalker_quest_22">
    <text>You know, maybe another time.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_stalker_quest_complete_0">
    <text>About the bandits.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_stalker_quest_complete_1">
    <text>So, how did it go?</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_stalker_quest_complete_2">
    <text>I took them out.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_stalker_quest_complete_22">
    <text>Not yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_stalker_quest_complete_222">
    <text>Don't drag it out too long.</text>
</string>
<string id="dl_stalker_quest_complete_3">
    <text>Thanks a lot! Here's your reward!</text>
</string>


</string_table>
