<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="cyclic_quests_1_2_dialog_0">
    <text>Task completed.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_1_2_dialog_1">
    <text>Great, which one?</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_1_2_dialog_2">
    <text>The missing squad case.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_1_2_dialog_3">
    <text>Excellent, here's your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_1_dialog_0">
    <text>Any work available?</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_1_dialog_1">
    <text>Take a look at this:</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_1_dialog_22">
    <text>The missing squad case.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_1_dialog_222">
    <text>I’ve changed my mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_1_dialog_2222">
    <text>Sadly, there’s no work at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_1_dialog_223">
    <text>Alright, suit yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_1_dialog_23">
    <text>One of our recon squads disappeared in the swamp area, we've lost contact. As much as I hate to admit it, they're probably dead. Go find them. If they’re dead, bring back their gear — we need the supplies, you understand. If they’re alive, help them return to base.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_1_dialog_24">
    <text>Alright, I’ll go look for your men.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_2_1_dialog_0">
    <text>I’m here to pick up the package.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_2_1_dialog_1">
    <text>Got it. Give me the money and you’ll get the goods.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_2_1_dialog_2">
    <text>Here you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_2_1_dialog_3">
    <text>Perfect, here’s the package.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_2_2_dialog_0">
    <text>Task completed.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_2_2_dialog_1">
    <text>Great, here’s your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_2_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings! Got any work?</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_2_dialog_1">
    <text>There is. Need someone to act as a courier. Interested?</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_2_dialog_2">
    <text>Sure, what’s the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_2_dialog_22">
    <text>Sorry, I changed my mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_2_dialog_223">
    <text>Unfortunately, there’s no work right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_2_dialog_23">
    <text>Alright, your call.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_2_dialog_3">
    <text>A friend of mine supplies me with medicine from Yantar. Sadly, he can’t make it to our base, so I need you to meet him instead. I’ll give you money to pay for the order. If there’s any change left, you can keep it. Just make sure to bring the case back here. I might even throw in some meds as a bonus — always handy, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_2_dialog_4">
    <text>Got it! I’ll be back soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_3_1_dialog_0">
    <text>Task completed.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_3_1_dialog_1">
    <text>Great, here’s your reward!</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_3_dialog_0">
    <text>I need work — got anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_3_dialog_1">
    <text>Of course, there is!</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_3_dialog_2">
    <text>I’m listening carefully.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_3_dialog_22">
    <text>You know what, I changed my mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_3_dialog_223">
    <text>There’s nothing available at the moment. Come back later.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_3_dialog_23">
    <text>Alright then.</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_3_dialog_3">
    <text>Listen, I’m basically running the show here like a general, but the sergeant doesn’t let me go wild — you know, all for the good of the working people, Lenin and all that. So there’s this guy who brings me booze, tinctures, and other little goodies from Cordon and hides them here at the garbage heap. Could you bring them over? Don’t worry, I’ll make it worth your while. March that liver into action!</text>
</string>
<string id="cyclic_quests_3_dialog_4">
    <text>No problem — wait for me!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_0">
    <text>Oh, mercenary! Tell me, have you by any chance met a stalker named Lefty?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, I did. But he’s no longer among the living...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_2">
    <text>That’s a shame... A real shame. Alright, did he have a PDA?</text>
</string>


 <string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_3">
    <text>Hmm... That grief of yours doesn't seem very genuine... Something tells me you weren't really friends.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_4">
    <text>Merc, why would you even care?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_5">
    <text>Honestly, I don’t. So, what can you offer for his PDA?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_6">
    <text>AS Val and a couple of mags for it—deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_7">
    <text>Tempting offer!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_8">
    <text>Well? Do we have a deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_9">
    <text>Deal. Here you go!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_99">
    <text>I’ll think about it...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_go_0">
    <text>Yeger, is your offer still valid?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_go_1">
    <text>Of course, as agreed:\nAK-74 and a couple of mags.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_go_2">
    <text>[To himself: What a bastard...] Fine, take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_go_22">
    <text>[Assertive] Listen, we agreed on an AS Val and two mags, not an AK and rounds. Let’s settle this properly.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_go_3">
    <text>Pleasure doing business with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_go_33">
    <text>Listen here, “bluey,” that was *before* you refused to hand over the PDA. The offer’s changed. Don’t like it? Come back later and maybe I’ll throw in a sawn-off. [Laughs]</text>
</string>
<string id="el_eger_pda_levsha_dialog_go_44">
    <text>You bastard... Fine, take it...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_0">
    <text>There you are. So, did Gloomy bring you up to speed?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_1">
    <text>Sort of. But he said you'd tell me most of it.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_1_0">
    <text>Ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Are you really asking?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Then let’s move out!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright, the guys and I want to secure this territory and we need a base. The best option is an old factory, but mercs have holed up there. They’re not your friends, so no need to worry. The task is simple—take out their squads and occupy the factory. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_2_0">
    <text>The factory’s under our control. Here’s your promised payment and a personal gift from me.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_2_1">
    <text>If you’ve got more work, I’m in.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_2_2">
    <text>Glad to hear it!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_2_3">
    <text>Got any more work?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_2_4">
    <text>Look, like I said, we’re setting up a base here. As you’ve noticed, my squad is just a small part of the force. More squads are on the way, and we need supplies—rations, ammo, and medical kits.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_2_5">
    <text>Supplies are good and all, but where do I get them? Actually, never mind—I’ve got a place in mind. Just don’t feel like paying for it out of pocket. What’s the price?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_2_6">
    <text>Whoa, slow down! Hear me out—supplies and ammo need to be picked up from stalkers I’ve already made a deal with. It’s paid for, just pick it up. The whole thing’s worth maybe three to four thousand. As before—payment after delivery.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_2_7">
    <text>Alright then, wait for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_2_77">
    <text>Count me out this time.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_3">
    <text>Understood. What’s the payment?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_3_0">
    <text>Quick one, aren’t you? Seems like these documents mean a lot to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_3_1">
    <text>Spare me the drama. Just tell me what I need to do to get the documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_3_2">
    <text>Alright, no drama then. As you probably know, this area hasn’t been fully explored. Even local stalkers don’t know all the details. Turns out, there are powerful scanners in the old administrative building where the bandits used to be. Your task is to retrieve them.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_3_3">
    <text>And in return, I get the documents? Though I have a feeling it won’t be that simple.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_3_4">
    <text>You’re sharp. Here’s the deal: the documents are currently with Sapsan. I know you’re not on good terms, so I’ll send someone to retrieve them for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_3_5">
    <text>Now we’re talking! Alright, I’ll go look for those scanners.</text>
</string>

  <string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_4">
    <text>Ten thousand. Payment on completion, don’t expect an advance or anything else.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_4_0">
    <text>Whew... Here are your scanners.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_4_1">
    <text>You look pale—what happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_4_2">
    <text>The scanners were guarded by Burers, the bastards! Lucky I reacted in time.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_4_3">
    <text>Yeah... Alright, I’ll give you a small bonus for that. And here are the documents. Hopefully, they’re what you were looking for.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_4_4">
    <text>Yes, yes, that’s them! Listen, can I ask you to use your contacts to find out if there are any more documents like this?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_4_5">
    <text>Why not. But in return, you’ll have to do a bit of work. Only if I find something, though—I’m not gonna send you running around for nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_4_6">
    <text>Deal! Let me know if anything comes up—I'm heading back to camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_5">
    <text>Hmm... Alright, when do we move out?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_6">
    <text>Right now. We were just waiting on you.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_first_freedom_dialog_7">
    <text>Then let’s go!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_first_quest_dialog_0">
    <text>Alright, let’s hear it—what’s the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_first_quest_dialog_1">
    <text>Look, since your gear is “solid,” I won’t send you on anything too dangerous just yet. For starters, you need to find a stalker named Nekrasov.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_first_quest_dialog_2">
    <text>Got it. Any leads on where to look?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_first_quest_dialog_3">
    <text>Unfortunately, you’ll have to search the entire “Wastelands” area.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_first_quest_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright... If I do find him, then what?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_first_quest_dialog_5">
    <text>I’ve got a feeling he’s already dead, so bringing him back probably won’t happen. In that case, bring his PDA—we’ll see what’s what from there.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_first_quest_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright, I hear you.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_fquest_done_dialog_0">
    <text>Mission accomplished! You were right—he’s dead. But it happened recently. Here’s his PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_fquest_done_dialog_1">
    <text>Hmm... Looks like he was closely connected to stalkers. That’s good—we can use this to our advantage and maybe even improve relations a bit, thanks to this PDA. Keep it for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_fquest_done_dialog_2">
    <text>Care to fill me in on your plan? Because I’m not walking into a slaughter for no reason!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_fquest_done_dialog_3">
    <text>Easy now! Nobody’s sending you to die. You just need to take the PDA to the stalkers and hand it over. There’s nothing too sensitive on it, so the best option is to establish a connection with them. And it’ll help to have contacts with their “movement” leader. They’ve been here for half a year already, so they know the area and its inhabitants better than we do.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_fquest_done_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, what about my reward—or was I chasing down that stalker for free?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_fquest_done_dialog_5">
    <text>There’s the Gryf I know... Here’s a small payout and some ammo for your gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_fquest_done_dialog_6">
    <text>Didn’t expect you to be so stingy. Still, better than a donut hole.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_fquest_done_dialog_7">
    <text>Alright, enough chit-chat! Head to the stalkers, and I’ll try to make sure they don’t shoot you on sight.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_fquest_done_dialog_8">
    <text>Fine, I’m on my way.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_freedom_dialog_0">
    <text>There you are! So, ready for another job?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_freedom_dialog_1">
    <text>Of course. Lay it on me.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_freedom_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright, you need to help some Freedom guys clear out an old factory. Talk payment with them yourself. I’d go myself, but I’m waiting on a messenger from Jackal.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_freedom_dialog_3">
    <text>Got it. Wait—what messenger?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_freedom_dialog_4">
    <text>I can’t share all the details, but I can tell you this—he can help us with finding those documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_freedom_dialog_5">
    <text>Nice! Alright, keep me posted.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_0">
    <text>Job’s done.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_1">
    <text>Good job! But something tells me you’re holding something back.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_10">
    <text>Yeah... This situation’s not great. But I still don’t get what we’re supposed to do next.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_11">
    <text>What’s next? Simple—we find the rest of the documentation on this project. Then we cash in and get the hell out of the Zone.</text>
</string>

 <string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_12">
    <text>You’re saying reasonable things, but you're forgetting that we don’t have any intel: where to look, who might know the location. Though I think the stalkers here might be able to help — they’re not sitting around for nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_13">
    <text>See? And you said I was forgetting something. No, my friend, I just chose not to mention the part you already know quite well.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_14">
    <text>So you're suggesting I go talk to the stalkers and start interrogating them? Like, "Hey man, you wouldn’t happen to know where to find some documents, would you? Lost them like 10 years ago and still can’t find them..." Is that it?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_15">
    <text>No! Ask subtly, casually. Believe me, if you ask the right questions while talking about something seemingly unrelated, you can get what you need.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_16">
    <text>Alright, I’ll give it a try. But first, you're going to tell me all the details about this job. I don’t like working blind.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_17">
    <text>Now that’s my student, haha. So, this job — we were hired by a professor from Yantar. I can’t give his name, he wanted to stay anonymous. He told us there’s a lab in the "Dead Lands" where the C-Consciousness conducted experiments to create mutants with psi abilities — basically, Controllers. He also said they kept detailed records and created an archive, which was split into several parts. How many exactly — he didn’t say, even though he probably knows. That’s all I got.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_18">
    <text>Interesting. Alright, time to go kiss up to some stalkers and get some intel.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_2">
    <text>Heh, you’re right! We found a PDA and some documents on the bandit. The documents are connected to Project "Prometheus". I already have part of them — just some scientist’s notes. But these new ones paint a much clearer picture.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_3">
    <text>Let me take a look.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_4">
    <text>Here you go. By the way, the latest messages found on the bandit's PDA show they were here specifically to look for those documents. But they only found a part of them. And who knows how many more parts there are...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_5">
    <text>Hmm... Damn! This is exactly what we’ve been looking for!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_6">
    <text>You serious?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_7">
    <text>More than serious. As for those bandits — we knew about them, that’s why we sent you to take them out. By the way, who were the messages from?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_8">
    <text>Some guy named "Mrakobes". But no specific info on who he is.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_9">
    <text>Goddammit! So that's the rat that's been screwing everything up! I thought the Zone was punishing us, but no — it’s just Jackal’s new favorite playing his own game.</text>
</string>

<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_0">
    <text>Didn’t think the stalkers had such a tense relationship with the syndicate.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_1">
    <text>It wasn’t always like that. What you saw — that’s the result of what happened when we arrived here.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_10">
    <text>How many people are in the group? What’s the timeframe and the pay?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_11">
    <text>There are five of them, including the target. One day to complete the job. Payment is fifteen grand, plus a bonus.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_113">
    <text>I don’t understand what you’re talking about.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_12">
    <text>Alright, send me their coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_2">
    <text>What do you mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_3">
    <text>No deep meaning. When we arrived, we immediately decided to scout the area. We split up into pairs to cover more ground. That day, the fog was thick — couldn’t see a thing beyond arm’s reach. Anyway, I was with Siply — may he rest in peace — and we heard rustling in the bushes. Thought it was mutants and let off a few bursts. Turned out it was a stalker... After that, things went downhill fast. Now stalkers are out for blood.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_4">
    <text>And explaining yourselves wasn’t an option?!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_5">
    <text>They wouldn’t even listen.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_6">
    <text>I can try talking to them for you. I think stalkers aren’t fools — they’ll understand.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_7">
    <text>Maybe later. For now, I’ve got another job for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_8">
    <text>I’m listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_9">
    <text>There’s a bandit around here, goes by the name of Vint. You need to take him and his crew out.</text>
</string>

<string id="el_merc_leader_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Finally awake? Good! Now tell me — how the hell did you end up in the lab?</text>
</string>

   <string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_12">
    <text>You’re making valid points, but you’re forgetting one thing—we have no information: Where to look? Who might know the location? Although, I think the stalkers around here could help. They’re not sitting here for nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_13">
    <text>See? And you said I forgot. No, my friend, I just kept quiet about the part you already know well enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_14">
    <text>So, you’re suggesting I go talk to the stalkers and start interrogating them? Like, “Hey bro, you wouldn’t happen to know where to find some old documents, would you? Lost them about 10 years ago and still can’t find them…” That it?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_15">
    <text>No! You’ll be asking subtly, so to speak—casually in conversation. Trust me, if you ask the right questions while talking about something seemingly unrelated, you can get what you’re after.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_16">
    <text>Alright, I’ll give it a shot. But first, you’ll tell me all the details about this job. I don’t like working without knowing the full picture.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_17">
    <text>That’s my student! Heh-heh. So, a professor from Yantar hired us to find those documents. I can’t say his name—he chose to remain anonymous. He said there’s a lab in the “Dead Lands” where the C-Consciousness ran experiments creating mutants with psychic abilities—in other words, Controllers. He also mentioned they kept detailed logs and created some sort of archive, which they then split into parts. How many exactly? He didn’t say, though I’m sure he knows. That’s the situation.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_18">
    <text>Interesting. Alright, time to go kiss some stalker ass to get the info.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_2">
    <text>Heh-heh, you’re right! We found a PDA and some documents on the bandit. They’re related to Project “Prometheus.” I already had part of these documents, but it was just some scientist’s notes. These, though, give a much clearer picture.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_3">
    <text>Let me take a look.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_4">
    <text>Here you go. Also, from the last messages on the bandit’s PDA, it turns out they were here looking for those very documents—but they only found a part. And who the hell knows how many more parts there are...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_5">
    <text>Huh… Damn! This is what we’ve been looking for!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_6">
    <text>Are you serious?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_7">
    <text>Dead serious. As for those bandits—we already knew about them. That’s why we sent you—to take them out. By the way, who was the PDA message from?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_8">
    <text>Some guy named Mrakobes. No further info on who he is though.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_ko_done_dialog_9">
    <text>Goddammit! So that’s the rat who’s been screwing us over! I thought the Zone was punishing us—but no, it’s Shakal’s new favorite playing his own game.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_0">
    <text>Didn’t expect the stalkers to be on such bad terms with the Syndicate.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_1">
    <text>Wasn’t always like this. What you saw is the aftermath of how we arrived here.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_10">
    <text>How many people in the group? Deadline and payment?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_11">
    <text>Five people, including him. Deadline is one day. Payment: 15 grand and a little something extra.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_113">
    <text>I don’t know what you’re talking about.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_12">
    <text>Alright, send me their coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_2">
    <text>What do you mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_3">
    <text>No point in meaning—when we got here, we immediately started scouting the area. We split up in pairs to cover more ground. That day was super foggy—couldn’t see past your own hands. Anyway, I was with Siply, may the Zone rest his soul, and we heard rustling in the bushes. Thought it was mutants, so we opened fire. Turns out it was a stalker... After that incident, stalkers have been on edge with us.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_4">
    <text>And explaining yourselves? That wasn’t an option?!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_5">
    <text>No one even wanted to hear us out.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_6">
    <text>I can try to explain things to them. I don’t think they’re stupid—they might understand.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_7">
    <text>Maybe later. For now, I’ve got another job for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_8">
    <text>I’m listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_st_dialog_9">
    <text>There’s a bandit here—goes by the name of Vint, if I’m not mistaken. We need him and his crew taken out.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_merc_leader_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Woke up, huh? That’s good. Now tell me—how’d you end up in the lab?</text>
</string>

   <string id="el_project_prometey_03_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright, shall we move out?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_03_dialog_3">
    <text>You ready? Maybe you should check your gear again? Or finish your business?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_03_dialog_4">
    <text>No, I'm ready. Let's go...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_03_dialog_44">
    <text>Yeah, you're right! I'll be back soon...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_04_dialog_0">
    <text>What the hell?!...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_04_dialog_1">
    <text>Gloomy, where are all your men?!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_04_dialog_2">
    <text>I-I... don't know! They were supposed to wait for us here!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_04_dialog_3">
    <text>Damn it! Once again fate throws a wrench in our plans... Hmph... Alright, we have to keep moving. We didn’t waste all that effort searching for those damn documents for nothing!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_04_dialog_4">
    <text>You’re right, let’s move...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_04_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright, I’ll open the airlock.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_0">
    <text>Griff... I don’t get it... How?! They were professionals!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_1">
    <text>Gloomy, stop panicking! They were likely caught off guard. I only have one question...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright, I’ll tell you everything, just tell me — when did Jackal send you to this lab?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_11">
    <text>About three days ago... Why?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_12">
    <text>Hmph... Seems like he pulled something on you too. Alright, listen carefully and don’t interrupt! I’ll start from the beginning. First thing you need to know is — you’ve been in this lab for about a week. Next... Your group wasn’t randomly selected — you’ve all been on Jackal’s radar for a while. There just wasn’t enough proof that one of you was a mole. And in our line of work, we don’t take contracts on our own — you know how that ends. So Jackal decided to test you like this. In the end, we figured out the mole was someone named — Spider...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_13">
    <text>[Continue]</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_14">
    <text>So, the point is — that Spider apparently found another key to the locked sector and took out our guys...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_15">
    <text>I don’t get it — how the hell could I have been stuck in this damn lab for almost a week?! No food, no water?! HOW?!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_16">
    <text>Sadly, I can’t answer that... I just don’t know...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_17">
    <text>Whatever... So what exactly are we supposed to find in this lab?!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_18">
    <text>Spider. Find and eliminate him.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_19">
    <text>Alright then, let’s move on.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright, alright, what’s the question?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_3">
    <text>How did their bodies end up in the sealed sector? We’re the only ones with a key card! You sure you're not hiding anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_4">
    <text>[Looks away, then glances back at Griff] Almost...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_5">
    <text>What do you mean *almost*?!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_6">
    <text>Do you remember how you even got into this lab? Why you were heading here in the first place?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_7">
    <text>Of course. I remember Jackal ordered me and a few trusted men to head down here and retrieve some documents. But as we descended, something went wrong... I found two from the group, but we never found the third...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_8">
    <text>Good that you remember that. You should also know — my group was sent by Jackal to look for yours. But we only found you. Sorry I didn’t tell you right away — had to be sure you weren’t the mole.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_05_dialog_9">
    <text>A mole? A search party?! I don’t get it...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_06_dialog_0">
    <text>What’s wrong with you?!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_06_dialog_1">
    <text>I feel... l-like crap... *cough* *cough*...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_project_prometey_06_dialog_2">
    <text>Damn it, I’ll go myself then!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_docs_1_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello! I’ve got an unusual question for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_docs_1_dialog_1">
    <text>Make it quick, I’m busy.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_docs_1_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright! So, I’m looking for documentation on a certain project — it’s called “Prometheus.” I was hoping you might know where I can find the files or maybe even have them yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_docs_1_dialog_3">
    <text>Merc, even if I *did* have such files, I wouldn’t give them to you. As for information — no idea. That all?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_docs_1_dialog_4">
    <text>Yeah...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_first_dialog_start_0">
    <text>I’d suggest you speak fast — unless you’re looking for a bullet.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_first_dialog_start_1">
    <text>I found a stalker, and he had a PDA. From the info inside, it’s clear you knew him.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_first_dialog_start_2">
    <text>A stalker? Knew him? PDA... You got any more details? Who are you talking about?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_first_dialog_start_3">
    <text>Here’s his PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_first_dialog_start_4">
    <text>Nekrasov?! Damn... Wait, how do I know *you* didn’t kill him?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_first_dialog_start_5">
    <text>Do I look like a suicide bomber? If I killed him — or someone from my clan did — we wouldn’t have shown up here. This is a gesture of goodwill, nothing more.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_first_dialog_start_6">
    <text>Alright, I’ll believe you. But don’t get cocky — we’re not looking to cooperate with your kind.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_first_dialog_start_7">
    <text>Didn’t expect you to. Just let my guys buy some supplies and ammo from you now and then. Won’t do you any harm.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_first_dialog_start_8">
    <text>Fine — but you’re doing the shopping. If anyone else shows up at the base, they’ll get a one-way ticket to HELL. No line.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_first_dialog_start_9">
    <text>Got it, loud and clear.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_spa_dialog_done_0">
    <text>Griff, what’s the word?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_spa_dialog_done_1">
    <text>I’ve got two pieces of news for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_spa_dialog_done_2">
    <text>Well? Were you able to get the guys out?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_spa_dialog_done_3">
    <text>I was, but... the group came out of the “bubble” dead...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_spa_dialog_done_4">
    <text>Damn... Ngh... Alright, you kept your end of the deal. Here’s the access card...</text>
</string>

 <string id="el_sapsan_spa_dialog_done_5">
    <text>Thanks. Hang in there...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_trouble_01_dialog_0">
    <text>Gloomy said you wanted something from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_trouble_01_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes-yes! Griff, I urgently need help, I'm starting to lose hope...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_trouble_01_dialog_2">
    <text>Wait, can you explain clearly what happened? And what kind of help do you need from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_trouble_01_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, about 16 hours ago, our recon group got caught in a spatial bubble. I don’t think I need to explain to you what that is or how it works… Anyway, two of the guys are critical, and one of them is a very close friend of mine. I really don’t want to lose him… Damn, why did I send them out...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_trouble_01_dialog_4">
    <text>Pull yourself together! Look, I can try to pull your guys out of the anomaly, but in return I’ll need the keycard to the lab under the factory. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sapsan_trouble_01_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright, alright... I agree to everything! Just get them out!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sqf_joker_dialog_0">
    <text>Here’s your order.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sqf_joker_dialog_1">
    <text>Great! Listen, I’ve been thinking, and in addition to the payment I promised, I’ll throw in our uniform kit. I think you’ll appreciate it.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sqf_joker_dialog_2">
    <text>Pretty generous, thanks.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sqf_vasilisk_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, I’m here from Joker.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sqf_vasilisk_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah, yeah, here’s his order. Be careful with it, there are some fragile and quite dangerous items inside.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_sqf_vasilisk_dialog_2">
    <text>Got it...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_leader_first_quest_0">
    <text>What’s the talk about?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_leader_first_quest_1">
    <text>It’s awkward to ask you, you know how things are between our groups, but we have no other choice.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_leader_first_quest_2">
    <text>Spare me the sentimental crap. Just say what you need.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_leader_first_quest_3">
    <text>Basically, our trader has suspicions about one stalker, but they’re unfounded. It’s just talk, and without evidence, I can’t accuse him.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_leader_first_quest_4">
    <text>So I’m supposed to kill him?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_leader_first_quest_5">
    <text>NO! You just need to find proof of his involvement, and better yet, talk to Vasilisk – he’ll explain everything in more detail.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_leader_first_quest_6">
    <text>Alright, I’ll go talk to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_quest_rh_dialog_0">
    <text>Mercenary? Haven’t seen your kind in a while... Anyway, enough chit-chat! What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_quest_rh_dialog_1">
    <text>Found some interesting loot at the factory, just wondering who to give it to...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_quest_rh_dialog_2">
    <text>Loot, huh? Whose is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_quest_rh_dialog_3">
    <text>Beats me... Bandits hired me to find it and gave me the general area. No idea who it really belongs to.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_quest_rh_dialog_4">
    <text>Bandits?! Haha, well good thing you brought it to us! Hand it over, and here’s your reward for not giving it to those bastards – and for throwing a wrench in their plans!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_stalker_quest_rh_dialog_5">
    <text>Anytime. Let me know if you need anything else.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_technik_dialog_hello_0">
    <text>Need something fixed?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_universal_dialog_hello_0">
    <text>Merc, what do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Did Sapsan explain what you’ll be doing?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, though he left out some details. Better tell me everything from the beginning.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright, first lead is an abandoned village. Yeah, I know – lots of hiding spots. But thanks to Diesel, we managed to trace a signal from this "dandelion" guy, or rather, the spot he frequents the most. The second place is an anomalous swamp – the one with the downed MI-6 chopper. No exact location, so you’ll need to search the whole swamp and nearby area.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_first_dialog_11">
    <text>Hmm… Alright, I’ll check it out. If I find anything, I’ll contact you.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_first_dialog_12">
    <text>You won’t be able to reach me – can’t say why right now. So you’ll have to report back in person.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_first_dialog_13">
    <text>Alright...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay, listen up. A new guy recently arrived at the camp – looks like a harmless softie, but he's actually a real bastard... He’s been telling all sorts of tales, and not just made-up stories – he’s taking credit for other people’s accomplishments.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_first_dialog_3">
    <text>So what? He’s just telling stories, isn’t he? Or is there more to it?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_first_dialog_4">
    <text>There’s more, though it’s all just guesses for now… But we can verify them.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Stop dragging it out already...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Word is, this "dandelion" guy was getting close to stalkers who later either vanished or were found half-dead… But we haven’t been able to prove anything yet!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_first_dialog_7">
    <text>If I understood correctly, you want me to find evidence. Right?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Exactly! I already have a couple of leads on where the evidence might be. No idea how reliable they are, but it’s worth checking. If you find anything – bring it straight to me!</text>
</string>

  <string id="el_vasilisk_first_dialog_9">
    <text>Alright, give me your leads, I’ll check them out.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Look what I managed to find.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Let’s see… Damn! It’s locked, although… I’ll hand it over to Diesel, he’ll extract the data.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_second_dialog_2">
    <text>What should I do?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_second_dialog_3">
    <text>For now, go get some rest. As soon as I find out what’s on the flash drive, I’ll let you know.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, take care…</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_third_dialog_0">
    <text>What’s the urgency?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_third_dialog_1">
    <text>Remember that flash drive you brought me?</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_third_dialog_2">
    <text>Yeah, but it was locked...</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_third_dialog_3">
    <text>It *was*! But Diesel managed to extract all the data. Based on what we found, I was able to prove that this "dandelion" was involved in those stalkers’ deaths.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_third_dialog_4">
    <text>That’s great! Glad I could help.</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_third_dialog_5">
    <text>Anyway, Sapsan ordered a reward to be given to you — here, take it!</text>
</string>
<string id="el_vasilisk_third_dialog_6">
    <text>Much appreciated.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_eger_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, I need your help!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_eger_first_dialog_1">
    <text>What kind of help?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_eger_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Basically, I found a pretty valuable artifact the other day, but I couldn’t get to it because of mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_eger_first_dialog_3">
    <text>And what do you need from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_eger_first_dialog_4">
    <text>I just need you to watch my back, that’s all. Deal? We’ll split the profit fifty-fifty.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_eger_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Sounds pretty good… Alright, fine, let’s go!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_eger_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Let’s move.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, look who dropped by! Honestly didn’t expect to see you here. So, what brings you around?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Just thought I’d take a “vacation,” but seems like it’s not going too well...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Got it. Well then, let’s get to the point. Why are you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Long story short — Sapsan, who’s temporarily filling in for the scout leader, sent me here. He’s concerned about a recent incident where your men killed one of his scouts. Naturally, he wants to know why it happened, and also what your purpose is in this area.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Yeah, I remember that. But you see, it was an unfortunate accident. As for why we’re here — you’re a mercenary too, you know how confidential this kind of stuff is.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_first_dialog_5">
    <text>I get it, I get it. Then at least tell me what exactly happened.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Sure. We came in at night. Everything was quiet, calm… but there was such thick fog that you couldn’t see your own hand. Then we heard rustling in the bushes — figured it was a mutant! So, we let off a couple bursts. That’s how it went...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Interesting story... Alright, I’ll talk to the stalkers and explain everything. I’m sure they’ll understand — they’re not idiots.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_first_dialog_8">
    <text>That’d be nice.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_first_dialog_9">
    <text>Alright, I’m off.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_0">
    <text>...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_1">
    <text>Why so quiet?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_10">
    <text>Speak.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_11">
    <text>I need to deliver some money to someone.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_12">
    <text>That’s it? You’re being secretive, just say it.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_13">
    <text>Alright… The stalker who agreed to deliver the documents — he’s got a sister not far from here. You just need to deliver what I promised him. That’s all…</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_14">
    <text>Alright, I’ll take care of it. No need for payment.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_15">
    <text>You sure?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_16">
    <text>Yeah. Give me the money and I’ll be on my way.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_17">
    <text>Here you go, and thank you.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_18">
    <text>[With a smile] Oh, come on… I’ll owe you one.</text>
</string>

  <string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, I’m thinking about it...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_3">
    <text>What are you thinking about?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_4">
    <text>How to properly say that I completed your task.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_5">
    <text>Ugh! I don’t even know what to think anymore. Just give me the documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_6">
    <text>Here you go. By the way, I got lucky! I didn’t have to run around looking for the documents. It turned out that the stalker had already retrieved them from the stash and was keeping them, probably thinking of selling them. But, as always, we arrived just in time!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_7">
    <text>Well done, here’s your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_8">
    <text>Thank you very much. Is there any other work?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_hmyriy_three_dialog_9">
    <text>There’s something, but the pay is small.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_kareglazaya_dialog_0">
    <text>You… Who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_kareglazaya_dialog_1">
    <text>Not so important, what matters is that I was asked to give this to you [Give PDA and Money].</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_kareglazaya_dialog_10">
    <text>Can I come with you?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_kareglazaya_dialog_11">
    <text>Why not, let’s go.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_kareglazaya_dialog_111">
    <text>Unfortunately, no. Sorry.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_kareglazaya_dialog_2">
    <text>What is this and who asked you to deliver it?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_kareglazaya_dialog_3">
    <text>This is the PDA and money that your brother earned, but sadly couldn’t take himself. Who gave it to me is not important.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_kareglazaya_dialog_4">
    <text>He… What?!...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_kareglazaya_dialog_5">
    <text>I’m sorry...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_kareglazaya_dialog_6">
    <text>[Crying].</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_kareglazaya_dialog_7">
    <text>...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_kareglazaya_dialog_8">
    <text>[Through tears] Where are you going?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_kareglazaya_dialog_9">
    <text>To the Big Land.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_0">
    <text>Man... Cough... Cough... Quickly... Over here...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, what a surprise! And no bodyguards? Strange, I thought your group wouldn't leave you behind, or did something change?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_10">
    <text>I don’t know, really don’t know. They just told me to kidnap and deliver him. That’s all I know.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_11">
    <text>Fine, I’ll believe you. Now give me the medallion.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_113">
    <text>Well, you can call me sentimental, but that’s who I am. About a week ago, my stash got robbed. Of course, I dealt with the thief, but I still don’t know where he hid what he stole.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_114">
    <text>What exactly did the thief steal?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_116">
    <text>And because of some knife, you want me to turn "The Dump" upside down?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_117">
    <text>This isn’t just any knife, it’s my grandfather’s knife. He kept it from World War II... This knife is very precious to me, as a memory.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_118">
    <text>Alright, I’ll help you find it! Do you have any clues?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_119">
    <text>Here, take this. It’s the PDA of that stalker, but there’s some nonsense written on it! Maybe you can make sense of it.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_12">
    <text>Sorry, but I can't just give it away. But I can make a deal with you, and if you do everything as needed, I’ll return the medallion.</text>
</string>

  <string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_120">
    <text>Let me take a look. If I find it, I'll let you know immediately.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_13">
    <text>Either you give everything now and stay alive, or...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_14">
    <text>Well, whatever...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_15">
    <text>[Shoot]</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_2">
    <text>.....Give... Me... A... First Aid... FIRST AID...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_3">
    <text>Fine, here. But don't try anything funny, or you'll see hell before you even think about anything.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_4">
    <text>Thanks, man...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_5">
    <text>Don't get too cocky, listen carefully and answer the questions. If you answer correctly, you’ll stay alive!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_6">
    <text>Got it, ask away...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_7">
    <text>What about the Wild's group?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_77">
    <text>Why did they abandon you?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_777">
    <text>Where's the medallion you stole?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_778">
    <text>It's with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_78">
    <text>I don’t know. When I got what I was ordered to get, I reached the meeting point, but there was an ambush waiting for me. A sniper shot me from that tower, and then just disappeared...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_8">
    <text>It’s a squad I was part of or used to be part of... It's hard to say now. The squad was formed around the commander, a former military man who deserted after an incident at Agroprom when mercenaries stormed the complex. After that, he formed a group of the most experienced stalkers, with the goal of taking control of the Zone... I know, his tactics are a bit off, but believe me, he controls half of the Duty faction now, and with that, their territories.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_petruha_wounded_dialog_9">
    <text>Why do they need that medallion?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, here you are! Listen, we haven’t introduced ourselves yet. I think we should fix that, don’t you think?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_first_dialog_1">
    <text>No objections! I’m Grif, and you are?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I’m called Sapsan, I’m something like the leader here, but it’s mostly a formality. The real leader went on a raid a couple of weeks ago, and we haven’t heard from him since, so for now, I’m in charge. I think we can get down to business now, if you’re okay with that.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Let’s do it.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, listen up. Just a few days ago, a squad of mercenaries arrived on our controlled territory. You might think, so what? But it’s not that simple. They killed one of my scouts. What bothers me is that we supposedly have a truce with them. In other words, they don’t touch us, and we don’t touch them. We don’t interfere in each other's business.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Okay, that’s interesting! But I still don’t get what you need from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_first_dialog_6">
    <text>So, your task is to find out why they killed my scout, and if possible, figure out what the mercenaries need in this area. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_first_dialog_7">
    <text>I got it, but here are a couple of details. The Syndicate in the Zone might be one, but it has many leaders. In other words, I don’t know which group is involved, and if they’re enemies. Not all mercenaries get along, some groups just do jobs, while others started their own activities. Also, I’ll need some gear, because mine isn’t in the best condition...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Got it, there’s always a risk. As for the gear, go see our tech, Diesel. He’ll give you a standard set of gear. Good luck.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_first_dialog_9">
    <text>Alright. I’ll go redeem my “Past Sins”...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_np_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, here you are again. So, did you find out anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_np_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Found out! So, listen up [talk about the incident.]</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_np_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Ugh... A headache... Well, it's better than a war with the mercenaries. If I’m being honest, we probably made the mistake of sending our guy on the recon. The important thing is that it’s all resolved now, and the rest doesn’t matter. By the way, did they tell you the purpose of their visit?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_np_second_dialog_3">
    <text>No, and they won’t. This is Syndicate business, and it’s better not to get involved. Tell your people to stay at least 200-300 meters away from the church, the guys there are on edge and might shoot. Also, here’s a tip for the future: never, under any circumstances, get involved with the mercenaries’ affairs! The consequences can be pretty bad. Understand, they’re hired for serious jobs, and if they fail, they become corpses themselves. That’s why they act together and are always on edge. I hope you got that.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_np_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Got it, and I’ll pass along your advice about the church to my men. By the way, while you were out, someone named Tikhiy arrived at the camp. He wanted to talk to you. You should meet with him. Also, here’s some money for your trouble. If you need ammo or gear, there’s a safe over there [points to the safe near the door].</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_sapsan_np_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright, thanks. I’ll go talk to this Tikhiy.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_dialog_pda_petruhi_0">
    <text>Hello, Diesel.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_dialog_pda_petruhi_1">
    <text>Hello, hello! Are you here on business or just hanging out?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_dialog_pda_petruhi_2">
    <text>On business. I won’t beat around the bush! I need help unlocking a PDA, can you help me out?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_dialog_pda_petruhi_3">
    <text>Sure, no problem. Let me see it!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_dialog_pda_petruhi_4">
    <text>Here you go.</text>
</string>

  <string id="ex_b2_tech_dialog_pda_petruhi_5">
    <text>So, look. I won't take any money from you, and I don't have any tasks for you either. However, you'll have to wait for a while because I have some things to take care of myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_dialog_pda_petruhi_6">
    <text>Whoa, unexpected! Thanks, I'll wait as long as needed.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_dialog_pda_petruhi_done_0">
    <text>So, what's the verdict?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_dialog_pda_petruhi_done_1">
    <text>It's all ready, here you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_dialog_pda_petruhi_done_2">
    <text>Thanks a lot, if you need anything – I’m at your service.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_dialog_pda_petruhi_done_3">
    <text>Haha, well, nobody dragged it out of you.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_dialog_pda_petruhi_done_4">
    <text>Alright, I'm off.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, foreign guest. Sapsan told me you needed something, here you go, and be careful with it, or you'll have to return it! [Smiles]</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Return it?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Relax... Haha, you fell for it. You don't have to return anything. This is, so to speak, a gift or an advance. Anyway, I won’t bore you with boring talk, here take something else from me, I think it'll come in handy.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tech_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Thanks for the Kalash! Alright, I think it's time to go. Bye, and thanks for the Kalash!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, you can jump for joy now.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_1">
    <text>I was starting to doubt, but you pleasantly surprised me! Here’s your reward and give me my medallion.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_10">
    <text>However, it’s sad...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_11">
    <text>Listen, you’re asking about all this and listening... I understand that you also suffer?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_12">
    <text>One could say that.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_13">
    <text>Would you tell me about it?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_14">
    <text>Well, I can. There’s nothing secret here. A couple of years ago, I was just a simple emergency worker, working, eating, drinking, and not thinking about anything. But one day, my little sister was hit by a car. You know, if the driver was at fault, I wouldn’t blame myself so much. Unfortunately, it all happened very prosaically, she was just walking near her school on the playground, and this scum decided to take a shortcut... You see, I’ve long realized what happened and that nothing can be undone, but I feel more sorry for my mother, who lost her little angel... [A tear rolled down from Grif’s eye.]</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_15">
    <text>Sorry for making you remember that again.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_16">
    <text>You know, I’m grateful to you. I’ve been doing this “job” for two years. I’ve never told anyone about this.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_17">
    <text>Grif, listen! You need to leave here. You won't achieve anything here, and the pain, it will eventually subside, trust me, I know. You have a mother, do yourself and her a favor, leave...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_18">
    <text>Sorry, but my journey is not finished yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_188">
    <text>You’re right, I’ll leave...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_2">
    <text>Here you go and listen, I examined the medallion, and I don’t understand why you’re paying me ten thousand for some damn medallion?!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_3">
    <text>You know, I’m not even surprised you’re asking. You’re a mercenary, your nerves are like steel, and you can't understand what sentimental memories are...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_4">
    <text>I may be a mercenary, but I’m also a human, and yeah, maybe I overdid it with my temper in some moments, but that’s life, if it’s not you, then it’s someone else. So, will you tell me or not?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_5">
    <text>This is a family heirloom, this medallion has been passed down for more than 300 years... The last person who gave it to me was my father, and his father gave it to him. My father lived here in the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone back in '86, I was a kid back then, but he told me: "You must be strong, even if everyone turns their back on you! You must find new paths, and remember, you create your own destiny!" Since then, this medallion has been very dear to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_6">
    <text>What happened to your father?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_7">
    <text>He died... He was among those who perished in the explosion. You know, I remember that night, but I can’t recall my father’s face...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_8">
    <text>Don’t you have any photos?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_done_dialog_9">
    <text>Everything was left in Pripyat... Although, I’ve already been there, but the apartment was completely cleaned out and not a single photo, I didn’t find anything.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, hello. I was told you were looking for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_first_dialog_1">
    <text>You must be Grif, well, nice to meet you!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright, I’ll try to find your "Medallion".</text>
</string>

  <string id="ex_b2_tihiy_first_dialog_100">
    <text>To hell with it! Find your "Medallion" yourself. I don't care about searching radioactive wastelands for some scout who stole your "Medallion". Goodbye.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, it's me. But you know, time is money, so get to the point quickly, or you'll end up on the list of the departed.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Easy, easy! I need help with something.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Didn't I make myself clear? I said quickly! I don't have time for your riddles.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Got it! Listen up: the other day, my group and I were wandering the outskirts, and by chance, we ran into a pack of snorks, and in the chaos, I lost my Medallion somewhere. I would have gone and gotten it myself, but the problem is, one of the group members quickly picked it up and ran off with it.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_first_dialog_6">
    <text>What exactly do you want me to do? And what's the payment?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_first_dialog_7">
    <text>You need to find this stalker and take my Medallion from him. His name is Petruha. He's a decent guy, but something must have made him do this. Whether you kill him or not is up to you, but bring me the Medallion. I'll pay you 5000 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Tempting offer! But now clarify where I can find him?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b2_tihiy_first_dialog_9">
    <text>Ah, that's the part I don't know. The only thing that's certain is that Petruha hasn't left the "Dump" area and is still hanging around somewhere nearby.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_eger_1_branch_dialog_77">
    <text>I found his PDA, and there was... a rather interesting note! It instructed the finder to pass the documents to you. (Lie.)</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_1_branch_dialog_0">
    <text>Where are you rushing off to so quickly? What did you want to talk to me about?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_1_branch_dialog_1">
    <text>Where am I rushing to?... [Inhales and explains about the meeting with Sokol and what he revealed.]</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_1_branch_dialog_10">
    <text>Grif, if I leave here, I will only leave with you. It's your choice...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_1_branch_dialog_11">
    <text>You're not as simple as you might seem... Alright, let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_1_branch_dialog_2">
    <text>You said he's dead... How could you talk to him?!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_1_branch_dialog_3">
    <text>It's hard to explain, and I don't fully understand it myself... But as Sokol said, he thinks it's related to the time and place of his death. To put it simply, I spoke with a ghost...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_1_branch_dialog_4">
    <text>No-no... This can't be!!! You're lying!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_1_branch_dialog_5">
    <text>If I were lying, how would I know you're his sister? By the way, there was no mention of this in his PDA...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_1_branch_dialog_6">
    <text>[Silent]</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_1_branch_dialog_7">
    <text>By the way, about the conversation I mentioned... Listen, you need to leave here, I would even say run! There's nothing good here, this is a purgatory, where "demons" of all kinds have gathered. What you see as kindness or sympathy in someone is just the survival instinct, which is essential...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_1_branch_dialog_8">
    <text>Instinct? And what about your actions?! You mean to say that they will help you survive? This is nonsense that you've made up for yourself! The "demons" you're talking about are only in your head and nowhere else!...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_1_branch_dialog_9">
    <text>[Smiling] Well, maybe...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_branch_dialog_0">
    <text>Grif, where have you been?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_branch_dialog_1">
    <text>[Angrily] It doesn't matter, what do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_branch_dialog_2">
    <text>Why are you like this?!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_branch_dialog_3">
    <text>Sigh… Sorry, just a lot has happened in the last day, and I really don't feel like talking about it.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_branch_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, I won't torture you, I'll just ask. Did you manage to find Sokol?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_branch_dialog_5">
    <text>Found him... But unfortunately, he's dead. I managed to find his PDA and get information about who killed him, but the place where the killer might be, I have no idea, some abandoned camp... Maybe you know where it is? And here, take his PDA and some extra stuff...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_branch_dialog_6">
    <text>Wait! The PDA, I get, but what's in the case? What's inside?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_branch_dialog_7">
    <text>In the case, there’s money. Sokol wanted to pass it to you, but he couldn't, so I decided to help him out. Alright, let's talk about it later, but first, do you know where this abandoned camp is?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_branch_dialog_8">
    <text>Uhm... Alright... An abandoned camp, you say? Well, there's one not far from here, hunters used to stop there for a break, but something happened, and they abandoned it. The camp is to the southwest, near the swamp.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_kg_1_branch_dialog_9">
    <text>Thanks, I’ll be back soon, and we’ll need to talk, just wait for me!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_otmorozky_dizel_0">
    <text>Hello again! Sapsan said I could get a special kit from you.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_otmorozky_dizel_1">
    <text>Yes-yes, of course! Here you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_otmorozky_dizel_2">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
</string>

  <string id="ex_b_otmorozky_dizel_3">
    <text>Listen, be careful, those guys are serious. I checked them out through my channels, they are an elite squad of some Dark One. They say he's a real tough guy.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_otmorozky_dizel_4">
    <text>I'll manage somehow... And it’s probably just a setup...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_otmorozky_dizel_5">
    <text>Grif, I wouldn’t be so sure… I got the info from mercenaries, if you know Cap, you’ll understand that the information is reliable.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_otmorozky_dizel_6">
    <text>They’re just bandits, I’m used to difficulties...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_otmorozky_dizel_7">
    <text>Well, good luck to you, come back alive or not at all...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_01_need_help_0">
    <text>What’s the emergency?!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_01_need_help_1">
    <text>I’ll explain, but first tell me, did you take care of the squad?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_01_need_help_2">
    <text>I took care of them. I found one of the bandits’ PDA, and it has some very interesting correspondence, but here's the problem, half of the messages are erased. I don’t think I can recover it.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_01_need_help_3">
    <text>Dammit... Alright, give me that PDA and listen. While you were dealing with the squad, the Jackal himself contacted me and claimed that we were violating the contract. I, of course, disagreed. But he wouldn’t listen. Anyway, mercenary squads will be arriving soon, and we only have one option.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_01_need_help_4">
    <text>What’s that?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_01_need_help_5">
    <text>Run...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_01_need_help_6">
    <text>You're changing your opinion fast, but I won’t judge. I’m not going anywhere, I’m a merc myself and I’m not afraid that my own will come. Besides, this was a job, nothing personal.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_01_need_help_7">
    <text>You’re right, it’s not your place to judge us! But anyway, thanks for the help. It was nice working with you, good luck, Grif...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Grif. Good to see you! Listen, have you seen Yegor by any chance?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_1">
    <text>I’ve seen him, and I even know where he is right now...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_2">
    <text>Where is he?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_3">
    <text>That bastard is lying near the swamp.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_4">
    <text>Is he dead? Who did it?!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_5">
    <text>Don’t act dumb! You know perfectly well.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_6">
    <text>But I still don’t understand, why?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_7">
    <text>[Explain what happened and hand over the documents].</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_8">
    <text>Well… I didn’t think Yegor would be such a bastard... Alright, thanks, and here, take this from me personally, you’ve earned it.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_need_help_0">
    <text>Grif, sorry for interrupting you! But there’s a good reason for it.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_need_help_1">
    <text>Alright... Speak up.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_need_help_2">
    <text>Just now, a guy named Frown contacted me, and he said that his people intercepted bandit communications. Based on that, they plan to capture our camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_need_help_3">
    <text>That Frown... Wait, what do you want from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_need_help_4">
    <text>We need someone to eliminate their strike squad, that will at least give us some time to prepare.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_need_help_5">
    <text>Great, I was just about to retire, and now I’m being turned into cannon fodder. Well done, Sapsan!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_need_help_6">
    <text>Stop joking! Grif, understand this! If you don’t do this now, tomorrow we won’t be here, and no, we won’t leave. We’ll just die here.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_need_help_7">
    <text>Dammit... [Remembers the letter from the girl.] Fine, I’ll help, give me the coordinates of those “devils”...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_need_help_8">
    <text>Thank you, Grif. Here are the coordinates, and also, go to Diesel, he’ll give you a special gear set, you’ll need it.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sapsan_need_help_9">
    <text>Alright, I’m going.</text>
</string>

   <string id="ex_b_sokol_1_branch_dialog_1111">
    <text>I told you, it's not important!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sokol_1_branch_dialog_11111">
    <text>Why are you attached to this place?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sokol_1_branch_dialog_111111">
    <text>Exactly, I can't answer that question because I don't know myself, but I suspect the murder is connected to the place and time of my death.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sokol_1_branch_dialog_1111111">
    <text>Alright, I think that's enough. Let's get to the point.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sokol_1_branch_dialog_11111111">
    <text>Okay, listen, tell Yulia that you found my body, and give her my PDA. Here it is, just in case. It has the coordinates of a stash with money and some documents. Give the money to Yulia, and give the documents to Yegor, then watch his reaction. Also, don't forget to mention me and say I personally handed them to you! Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sokol_1_branch_dialog_111111111">
    <text>Okay, I'll do everything. Can you please tell me your real name? Don't ask why, you won't understand why I need it. Just tell me.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sokol_1_branch_dialog_1111111111">
    <text>Okay, I'll do everything. Can you please tell me your real name? Don't ask why, you won't understand why I need it. Just tell me.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_b_sokol_1_branch_dialog_11111111111">
    <text>Thank you for your honesty! I won't let you down!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_0">
    <text>Oh! You're awake, well, that's good. Looks like you really got yourself in trouble!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_1">
    <text>Got myself in trouble? Hm... I don't think so.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_10">
    <text>So here's the deal! Either you help us and make a little profit, or you get a bullet in your head and we find another fool...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_11">
    <text>[Lie] Fine! Tell me, what's the deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_111">
    <text>You must be an idiot... If you're trying to corner me, I'll take you all down in an instant.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_112">
    <text>Shit... Fine, get out of here!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_113">
    <text>Goodbye...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_12">
    <text>So, recently my buddy passed away and left something valuable at the factory, he didn't say exactly where, but it's known that the stash is real. Bring it to us, and I'll give you some cash and let you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_13">
    <text>Sounds pretty interesting! Alright, I'll find your buddy's stash...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_14">
    <text>That's good! The marker is already in your PDA, and if you need anything, we're always here, and Secretary Cherep will welcome you anytime!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_15">
    <text>Uh-huh...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_2">
    <text>Brave? Yeah?! Well, we'll fix that...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_3">
    <text>Heh... You guys are funny, alright enough talk! Tell me what you need and scatter...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_333">
    <text>Well, pray, goat!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_3333">
    <text>Already started!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_4">
    <text>What do you need? Well, for example, I really liked your gear, I've wanted something like it for a long time! Don't worry... We won't take everything, we're not animals.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_5">
    <text>Gear? Are you out of your mind? Should I also give you the keys to my apartment and meet you at the doorstep with some bread?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_6">
    <text>Oh... Looks like the guy doesn't understand humor, well, whatever. Anyway, my guys checked you out, and it turns out you're a merc, and what a merc! It's strange though, you're wandering these Godforsaken lands alone... Don't you want to share anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_7">
    <text>Share? No.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright, I won't waste time trying to convince you, I'll just put you in a tough spot.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_bandit_1_branch_dialog_9">
    <text>...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_bint_1_branch_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, stalker. What do you need?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_bint_1_branch_dialog_1">
    <text>I'm looking for a stalker named Sokol, do you happen to know where I can find him?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_bint_1_branch_dialog_2">
    <text>Sorry, no... I wasn't even acquainted with him.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_bint_1_branch_dialog_3">
    <text>Alright, sorry for disturbing you.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_dizel_1_branch_dialog_0">
    <text>Oh, hello! How can I help?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_dizel_1_branch_dialog_1">
    <text>Do you happen to know where I can find a stalker named Sokol?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_dizel_1_branch_dialog_2">
    <text>Unfortunately, I rarely leave this room, the outside world is becoming an even bigger mystery to me every day...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_dizel_1_branch_dialog_3">
    <text>Eh... Alright, sorry for bothering you.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_2_dialog_0">
    <text>So, what interesting news do you have?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_2_dialog_1">
    <text>Me? Well, I can say that I completed my task, and those stalkers are already free, and they'll be here soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_2_dialog_2">
    <text>Seriously?!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_2_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes! Now it's your turn to share some information.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_2_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright. The last time Sokol was seen near an abandoned church, but what was strange is that he was just standing there looking at the sky. It wasn't just looking… We called out to him, and he didn't respond... We stood there for a couple of minutes and then left, afraid to approach, thinking maybe the controller had taken over his mind. So, you should look for him there.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_2_dialog_5">
    <text>Got it, hope this is true information. Goodbye.</text>
</string>

 <string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, mercenary! What do you need?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, I won't beat around the bush... I need to know where stalker Sokol might be right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_dialog_2">
    <text>Hmm... I can tell you, but in return, I ask for help. Agreed?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_dialog_3">
    <text>Couldn't be otherwise, so tell me what I need to do to get the information.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, listen up. Recently, one of my people intercepted a radio message from some stalkers. From the message, it was clear that they got trapped in a spatial bubble. Your task is to figure out how to get them out of there. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_dialog_5">
    <text>Clear as day. So, I help you, and you help me. But tell me, is the information about Sokol worth it? And is it even true?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_dialog_6">
    <text>Don't worry! It's all honest, you help me, and I help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_dialog_7">
    <text>Alright, give me the coordinates where "your guy" intercepted that message.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_dialog_8">
    <text>I don't know if it will help you or not, but here you go. I hope it works out for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_eger_1_branch_dialog_9">
    <text>Ah... You're not the only one hoping for that...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, mercenary! Need something?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, I have a little job.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_3">
    <text>In general, I was hired to search for a stalker named Sokol, and they said he was recently seen here. As the leader of this camp, I think you might know something about him.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, there was such a guy, but I personally didn't talk to him because I was quite busy. If my memory serves me right, ask Eger, he must have talked to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_help_kg_sapsan_1_branch_dialog_5">
    <text>Okay, thanks!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_0">
    <text>You took your time, but never mind. Let's get to the point, if you don't mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_1">
    <text>Alright, let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_10">
    <text>Don't worry, this won't affect the job.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_11">
    <text>Okay, who exactly am I looking for?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_12">
    <text>The stalker, named Sokol, was last seen near the stalkers' camp. So, I think it makes sense to ask around there.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_13">
    <text>Alright, I got it.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_14">
    <text>What do you want as a reward for finding him?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_15">
    <text>Information.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_16">
    <text>What kind of information?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_17">
    <text>You’ll find out later. For now, I’m going to find "your stalker"...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_2">
    <text>I saw how you dealt with those bandits, and based on the way you did it, I can say you're a professional.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_3">
    <text>What are you getting at?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_4">
    <text>I need help, and I think you're the one who can handle it.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_5">
    <text>What exactly do I have to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_6">
    <text>You need to find one stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_7">
    <text>Is that all?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_8">
    <text>Yes.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_kareglazaya_1_branch_1_dialog_9">
    <text>I think you're not telling me something...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_1_dialog_0">
    <text>Dizel, they say you have any kind of radio equipment.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_1_dialog_1">
    <text>Well... Not everything, but I do have some stuff, why?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_1_dialog_2">
    <text>I need an old army frequency scanner, a simple RFID. Don't tell me you don't have it...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_1_dialog_3">
    <text>I've got one, but why should I just give it to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_1_dialog_4">
    <text>How much do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_1_dialog_5">
    <text>Five thousand, and that's the price.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_1_dialog_6">
    <text>Here, take it, give me the scanner.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_1_dialog_66">
    <text>I don't have that much money yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_1_dialog_7">
    <text>Here you go, still warm! Heh-heh.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_1_dialog_77">
    <text>When you have the money, come back!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_1_dialog_8">
    <text>Thanks...</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_2_dialog_0">
    <text>Here I am again, but this time with the piece of junk.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_2_dialog_1">
    <text>Broke it? It happens... No returns or exchanges on this product!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_2_dialog_2">
    <text>Hmm... I thought Sid, the miser, had no competition, but turns out he does! Alright, enough idle chatter. I'm here for business, I need to extract and decode the data from this scanner.</text>
</string>

  <string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_2_dialog_3">
    <text>Ah, even like that! Alright, we'll do it. You know my fee, but this time as a regular client, I'll let you pay only after the extraction and decoding!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_2_dialog_4">
    <text>How generous of you! Alright, it's a deal!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_2_dialog_5">
    <text>Great! Give me the scanner and go ahead, I'll contact you once it's ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_2_dialog_6">
    <text>Got it, I'm waiting.</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_3_dialog_0">
    <text>I got your message, what's going on?</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_3_dialog_1">
    <text>Everything's like this morning, after a couple of shots! Easy and casual, in short, I extracted and decoded the info, it's 2500 from you, and we'll be square. As a bonus, I'll give you a special detector that will help you break the "Bubble".</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_3_dialog_2">
    <text>Deal!</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_3_dialog_3">
    <text>The coordinates for exiting the anomaly, I sent them to your PDA. Once you're in the sending zone, the program will work for you, all you need to do is turn on the detector, and it will emit a directed pulse to break the "Bubble".</text>
</string>
<string id="ex_sa_dizel_1_branch_3_dialog_4">
    <text>Thanks, take care.</text>
</string>
<string id="hmyriy_vtor_quest_1_good_0">
    <text>Gloomy, the job's done.</text>
</string>
<string id="hmyriy_vtor_quest_1_good_1">
    <text>I wasn't doubting you, Grif, really glad you got my guys out of that nasty "surprise." What kind of creature was it?</text>
</string>
<string id="hmyriy_vtor_quest_1_good_2">
    <text>Well, it was a bloodsucker, kind of unusual though. It waited until I got closer and attacked, it turned out to be an interesting fight...</text>
</string>
<string id="hmyriy_vtor_quest_1_good_3">
    <text>Interesting, interesting, you've earned your reward - here you go, hard-earned!</text>
</string>
<string id="hmyriy_vtor_quest_1_start_0">
    <text>Got any work?</text>
</string>
<string id="hmyriy_vtor_quest_1_start_1">
    <text>Got something.</text>
</string>
<string id="hmyriy_vtor_quest_1_start_2">
    <text>I'm all ears.</text>
</string>
<string id="hmyriy_vtor_quest_1_start_3">
    <text>So, look, recently my fighters were returning from a mission and ran into a bloodsucker. It wouldn't be a problem, but the creature was tough. My guys fired a few mags into it, and it didn't even flinch! Long story short, almost the whole squad is dead, but one managed to survive and gave the coordinates of the attack location. I think the creature is still there. Will you take the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="hmyriy_vtor_quest_1_start_4">
    <text>I'll take it, what's the payment?</text>
</string>
<string id="hmyriy_vtor_quest_1_start_44">
    <text>No-no-no, you do it yourselves.</text>
</string>
<string id="hmyriy_vtor_quest_1_start_5">
    <text>Well, fine, if you don't want to earn, don't.</text>
</string>
<string id="hmyriy_vtor_quest_1_start_55">
    <text>Three thousand, I won't give more.</text>
</string>
<string id="hmyriy_vtor_quest_1_start_66">
    <text>Alright, wait here.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalkers_usual_dialog_0">
    <text>Got anything interesting to share?</text>
</string>
<string id="stalkers_usual_dialog_1">
    <text>Unfortunately, I have nothing interesting to tell, I haven't been anywhere for a long time...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalkers_usual_dialog_11">
    <text>You say interesting?... Well, there was this one story, so some Freedom guys came here, led by a Miklukh, wandered around the area, asking locals if they'd seen any soldiers. There were no soldiers here, honestly, although when the helicopter crashed, one survived, but he didn't stay long, he left pretty quickly... Rumors say he hid some loot here, but no one knows exactly where. He was often seen near the swamp, and there's a hole leading to some rooms, but no one goes there...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalkers_usual_dialog_1111">
    <text>Doesn't seem that interesting...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalkers_usual_dialog_11111">
    <text>Yeah, there was this one story. So, there were two friends - Sokil and Yegor. Sokil decided to make some extra cash and told his friend about it. Instead of helping, Yegor refused, but then, after Sokil had done all the work and was ready to turn it in, Yegor shot him... Rumor has it someone dealt with Yegor too. I think they did the right thing, no need for such scum wandering around the Zone...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalkers_usual_dialog_111111">
    <text>Well, I was walking... mm... anyway, I was told in one hut there's a cool place. Cool... Artifacts, like, a stash of someone's. I get there, knock on the door... it's locked... What's this? Knock again - still locked... So I open it, and... it closes itself... I realized someone's not letting me in... Well, I climb through the window. Inside, I catch my breath, straighten up, and go to check who's messing with the door... A big room... a table in the middle... long like a highway... and a chair beside it, tall like a tower. Then someone whispers in my head (unintelligible)...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalkers_usual_dialog_1111111">
    <text>Well, listen. About a month ago, me and a couple of my buddies were walking through the Dark Valley, we stumbled upon some camp, which shouldn't have been there, because we passed by forty minutes ago and there was no camp, and the trail wasn't great either. So we approach and see a fire burning, new tents, not a hole in them, and no one around! We thought, maybe they went for firewood or something. Anyway, we decided to wait, sat by the fire, and in five minutes we passed out, though we weren’t even sleepy. We wake up, and there's a stalker in a merc suit standing next to us saying: "Hm... Another group of travelers, well, welcome...". We ask: "Where to?". He stays silent... We look around, and there’s nothing, no trees, no bushes, not even grass! I don’t know what it was, but my friend Kolyan said that ghosts were trying to communicate with us. I don’t even remember how we left... Since then, I don’t trust strange camps, who knows what's waiting there...</text>
</string>
<string id="tell_us_about_yourself_bint_0">
    <text>Tell us about yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="tell_us_about_yourself_bint_1">
    <text>Well, what to tell? I used to be just a stalker, started like all the new guys at the Cordon, running errands for Sidorovich and Wolf, then slowly got on my feet and decided to go deeper into the Zone. I ended up in the "Hell" – if I can put it that way, then I got wounded and was found near a checkpoint at the Bar. How I got there, I don’t know… I don’t remember! But I didn’t stay long at the Bar, I met Diesel and Sapsan there. After I fully recovered, we went to Yantar, worked for the Scientists, doing small jobs for which we didn’t get much pay, but the last order from the Scientists was the best one, it was an easy task and we finished it quickly, got the promised reward, then packed up and went off into uncharted territory... And now we’re here...</text>
</string>
<string id="tell_us_about_yourself_dizel_0">
    <text>Tell us about yourself.</text>
</string>

  <string id="tell_us_about_yourself_dizel_1">
    <text>I haven’t been asked such questions for a long time... Well, I’ll tell you. I’m not bothered. So, I’m a former military engineer. I arrived in the Zone among the first. Back then, even the 'Cordons' weren’t fully mapped. At that time, when I was still with the military, me and a few others were sent on a reconnaissance mission. So we’re heading out, and with us was a lieutenant, a young guy, obviously a conscript, who they decided to send as cannon fodder. We reached a village, and we saw a fire burning! Well, we thought maybe one of the villagers stayed behind and didn’t comply with the evacuation order. We went to check, and as we approached the fire, we saw a stalker sitting near it. At that time, we didn’t know he was an illegal, but he jumped up, aimed his double-barrel at us, and yelled, 'You bastards, never went beyond the checkpoint! What the hell died in the forest?!' The lieutenant, out of fear, fired a couple of bursts, the stalker died, and the lieutenant got promoted and given a vacation, saying he eliminated an especially dangerous violator... You see, after that moment, I started noticing that my commanders were engaging in rather secretive activities, strange orders, and a shortage of weapons and ammo, even though we had just received supplies from the mainland. So, I decided to stick my nose in and find out what was going on. I confronted the commander, asking what was going on and where the gear was. He calmly replied: 'If you keep opening your mouth where it’s not needed, you’ll end up like that stalker, lying next to a radioactive pile.' After that, I gathered everything I had and moved on. Along the way, I met Sapsan, and thanks to him, I’ve gained significant trust among stalkers and other factions now.</text>
</string>

<string id="tell_us_about_yourself_dizel_2">
    <text>However, an interesting story.</text>
</string>

<string id="tell_us_about_yourself_medik_0">
    <text>Tell us about yourself.</text>
</string>

<string id="tell_us_about_yourself_medik_1">
    <text>About myself? What’s there to tell?... I’m just a medic, I used to work for the government. I came to the Zone with a scientific expedition, but due to disagreements and a series of failures, I decided to leave. I worked for a long time with the 'Duty' faction, but then I found out that stalkers were gathering a team to raid new territories, and they didn’t have a medic, so I decided to join them.</text>
</string>

<string id="tell_us_about_yourself_sapsan_0">
    <text>Tell us about yourself.</text>
</string>

<string id="tell_us_about_yourself_sapsan_1">
    <text>Is there nothing else for you to do? Sorry, but my life is my personal story, and I don’t feel like sharing it with everyone.</text>
</string>

<string id="tell_us_about_yourself_sapsan_2">
    <text>I understand, sorry.</text>
</string>

<string id="el_search_af_0">
    <text>I heard you might offer a contract for artifact hunting?</text>
</string>

<string id="el_search_af_1">
    <text>Well, a contract is a bit of an exaggeration, it’s more of an assignment for a search and payment, that’s all. Although, it depends on how you look at it. Artifacts are needed for creating some medicinal products and for newer, more advanced equipment, something like that.</text>
</string>

<string id="el_search_af_2">
    <text>Got it, what kind of artifacts do you need?</text>
</string>

<string id="el_search_af_3">
    <text>At the moment, I need an artifact called "Moonlight," I’ll pay good money for it, so take it, you won’t regret it!</text>
</string>

<string id="el_search_af_4">
    <text>I’ll find "Moonlight."</text>
</string>

<string id="el_search_af_5">
    <text>I’ve changed my mind.</text>
</string>

<string id="el_search_af_done_0">
    <text>Task completed.</text>
</string>

<string id="el_search_af_done_1">
    <text>Great! Give me the artifact and get your well-earned reward!</text>
</string>

<string id="el_search_af_done_2">
    <text>Here, take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="el_search_af_done_3">
    <text>Excellent! Here’s your reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="el_search_af_done_33">
    <text>Excellent! Here’s your reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="el_search_af_done_333">
    <text>Excellent! Here’s your reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="el_search_af_done_3333">
    <text>Excellent! Here’s your reward.</text>
</string>


</string_table>
