<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>

  <!-- Fatty meadow -->
 <string id="dlg_tsr_0">
  <text>Hey man. Thanks a lot, otherwise I think that bloodsucker would have eaten me—the door is pretty flimsy.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_tsr_1">
  <text>How did you even end up here?</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_tsr_2">
  <text>As clich? as it sounds, I was looking for something to loot here.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_tsr_3">
  <text>And did you find anything?</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_tsr_4">
  <text>Of course! Go up to the attic, someone hid some loot there, I’m giving it to you as thanks. Listen, if you’re not busy, come see me, please. I have a proposition for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt2_q_0">
  <text>Any thoughts?</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt2_q_1">
  <text>Let’s check this checkpoint, maybe something’s left there—I don’t think anyone’s looked there yet.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt2_q_2">
  <text>I think we should check that three-story administrative building in the middle of the complex, and the workshops too, of course.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt2_q_3">
  <text>Crazy, huh? Let’s search here, maybe the stalkers left some traces of themselves while alive. But I don’t want to stay too long, I have a bad feeling.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt2_q_4">
  <text>I don’t even know.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt1_0">
  <text>What did you want to propose to me?</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt1_1">
  <text>This is all the factory. You know, the place is not exactly “fresh,” but no one really came here because, frankly, artifacts are rare, and it’s dangerous here for the outskirts of the Zone. But recently rumors about this factory started circulating, saying some weapons are stored here that the government developed after the first explosion. You probably know the stories about the Marked One and Strelok, who looted almost all underground complexes? Well, here’s hope for newcomers to get something valuable without going deep into the center. So they came here, myself included, and then bandits followed, because where stalkers go, there’s loot to grab.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt1_2">
  <text>Do you want to help me search for valuable info in this place?</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt1_3">
  <text>Yeah. But first, help me, please. It’s better not to hang around here without a weapon. I had a good shotgun—I saved up money for it before coming here—but I went into the nearby substation and there was some strange anomaly, I was careless and it exploded! Luckily it didn’t hit me, but I freaked out and dropped the gun, ran here. You can laugh, but when you barely escape death… anyway, can you bring it to me? Also, if you want, help me with one more thing.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt1_4">
  <text>Alright, I’ll go get your shotgun.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt1_5">
  <text>Not right now.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt1_1_0">
  <text>Here, take your gun—you were unlucky.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt1_1_1">
  <text>Thanks. Here, take this "flash" as a token of gratitude, I managed to find it in that anomaly. Get ready, come one night, and we’ll go to the factory.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt2_0">
  <text>Alright, I’m ready.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt2_1">
  <text>Great, I can’t wait to uncover all the secrets of this place. But stay alert, hopefully nothing will happen.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt2_2_0">
  <text>Yeah...</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt2_2_1">
  <text>That’s always the case, you know? Almost died again and you saved me again. And there was nothing… The moral, man: rely only on objective, comprehensive info, make comparisons, and don’t live in rose-colored glasses. Ugh, damn it!</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt2_2_2">
  <text>What next?</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt2_2_3">
  <text>Will you give me the documents? I’ll keep them as a memento after the excursion. I can’t repay you, but I can be a good friend if you want to roam with me.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt2_2_4">
  <text>Here, take them, I don’t need them.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt2_2_5">
  <text>Are you kidding? I risked my life for you, three times. I’ll take them to the Bartender instead.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt3_0">
  <text>What else do you need help with?</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt3_1">
  <text>Not long ago, another idiot from the village showed up. He kept mocking my appearance. Could you kill that bastard?</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt3_2">
  <text>How am I supposed to kill him? If anyone finds out, they’ll rip my head off.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt3_3">
  <text>No one will know. I heard this jerk is looking for someone to explore the surroundings and loot. Just tell him you’re an experienced stalker, lead him to bandits or mutants, and leave him—let them tear him apart. Will you do it? No reward from me, just take his stuff if you want.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt3_4">
  <text>Alright, I’ll do it.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt3_5">
  <text>That’s too much, don’t you think? No.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt1_fromf_0">
  <text>Honestly, I’ve already been to the factory.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt1_fromf_1">
  <text>Come on, man, don’t lie. Do you have proof?</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt1_fromf_2">
  <text>Yes, this is all I found there:</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt1_fromf_3">
  <text>Nothing.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt1_fromf_4">
  <text>Wow… no miracles. Thanks for clarifying, and it looks dangerous there. I can’t repay you, except with my shotgun. Here, I don’t need it anymore:</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt1_fromf_5">
  <text>Alright, don’t bother me.</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt3_1_0">
  <text>Hey, you were looking for an experienced stalker to watch your back?</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt3_1_1">
  <text>Hell yeah, hey. And you’re the experienced one, huh? Haha, don’t take it personally. I could take them all myself, but a partner is never useless. Let’s go?</text>
</string>

<string id="dlg_rpt3_1_2">
  <text>Let’s go.</text>
</string>


</string_table>
