<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>
   <string id="wiz_foma_about_yourself_0">
    <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_foma_about_yourself_1">
    <text>Why the hell would I? You're mistaking me for someone else, stalker. I've been walking this land for a long time and I know better than to let anyone into my pocket or my soul.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_foma_second_quest_0">
    <text>You got any work for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_foma_second_quest_1">
    <text>Of course! Listen, our gatherers told me that mutants are bothering them, making it hard to collect artifacts and all that. Your job is to deal with those mutants — it's your specialty after all, hunter! As a reward for the cleanup, I’ll give you a good artifact. You’ll find it useful, trust me!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_foma_second_quest_2">
    <text>Alright, I’m in.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_foma_second_quest_22">
    <text>Maybe another time.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_jekan_free_0">
    <text>Who are you, stalker?! How can I ever thank you?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_jekan_free_1">
    <text>They call me Snake. And you must be Zhekan, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_jekan_free_2">
    <text>Yeah, but... How do you know me?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_jekan_free_3">
    <text>Get up. Once we’re outside, you’ll understand.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_complete_0">
    <text>That’s it then — finally some justice. I almost forgot what it feels like! Thank you so much, Snake!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_complete_1">
    <text>Always happy to help. I think we shouldn’t stick around here for too long, don’t you agree?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_complete_2">
    <text>You’re right. Let’s head back to camp. By the way, I’ve got something for you there — you’ve earned it!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_complete_3">
    <text>Alright, let’s go!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_going_to_village_0">
    <text>I think now’s the right time to attack.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_going_to_village_1">
    <text>You’re right. I’ll call the guys and we’ll move out. Are you ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_going_to_village_2">
    <text>Ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_going_to_village_22">
    <text>Hold on, I need to grab something.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_start_0">
    <text>So Zhekan is still alive — that’s already good news. I think we need to try and get him out of the bandits’ captivity. Are you with us?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_start_1">
    <text>I’ve already dug this deep, would be stupid to back out now.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_start_2">
    <text>Glad to hear it. Come see me at night and we’ll head out.</text>
</string>

  <string id="wiz_free_neutral_rjaviu_start_3">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_germo_case_quest_dialog_0">
    <text>Here, take your "gadget".</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_germo_case_quest_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh! You found it — good job. I hope that wasn’t the only thing in the stash?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_germo_case_quest_dialog_2">
    <text>Not just that, there was also the old man’s manuscript. It helped me figure out where the entrance to the catacombs is. By the way, what’s in the case?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_germo_case_quest_dialog_3">
    <text>Snake, I don’t meddle in your business, right? So you shouldn’t meddle in mine. Thanks for the job — you're dismissed.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_germo_case_quest_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, take care.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gift_rjaviu_to_actor_0">
    <text>I don’t mean to push, but didn’t you mention a “gift” earlier?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gift_rjaviu_to_actor_1">
    <text>Yeah, yeah! I remember. Here, take it. This is a very good and rare suit — it used to belong to one of the now-defunct groups, "Clear Sky". You might’ve heard of them. Anyway, these suits were custom made by Novikov himself. As he used to say: "We'll duct tape the hell out of everything with blue tape!" So yeah — take care of it.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gift_rjaviu_to_actor_2">
    <text>Thanks a ton, Rzhavy! I was expecting a gun, but this — a suit from a defunct faction? That’s something else! Thanks again!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_0">
    <text>Before you die, I want to know — what did you do to Zhekan?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_1">
    <text>Funny how it turned out... Some random hunter managed to dig up more info than the guys who were right there the whole time. Didn’t expect that…</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_10">
    <text>So you even teamed up with the bandits... Scum! Alright then, see you in the afterlife…</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_2">
    <text>Listen, I don’t care about you. I only care about the information on Zhekan.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_3">
    <text>I’m afraid it’s already too late…</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_4">
    <text>You sure about that? You can die quickly, or die slowly. I can make that happen!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_5">
    <text>So bloodthirsty? I don’t think so…</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_6">
    <text>Wanna find out?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_7">
    <text>Alright, damn it, I’ll talk…</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_8">
    <text>That’s more like it…</text>
</string>

 <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_9">
    <text>Zhekan is still alive, he's being held captive by the bandits from the village. They’ve got him in the basement — that’s all I know. Though… he might not be alive anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_start_0">
    <text>Hello, tell me about the stalker named Nazar.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_start_1">
    <text>Nazar? Not much to say. He was an experienced stalker — a natural-born scavenger, you could say. Why do you ask?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_start_2">
    <text>Just found his body. And his PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_start_3">
    <text>So what? I still don’t get what you want!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_start_4">
    <text>Nothing much, just curious — when did you start working with the “Blues”?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_start_5">
    <text>What do you mean? I don’t work with anyone! You drunk or what?!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_kosta_start_6">
    <text>You don’t? Well, okay then…</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_second_0">
    <text>Snake, I told the guys about Costa’s schemes. They agree with me — they want blood vengeance too.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_second_1">
    <text>Alright, but let’s handle this outside the camp. And before we kill him, I want to interrogate him.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_second_2">
    <text>Alright. Shall we go?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_second_3">
    <text>Yeah, let’s go.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_0">
    <text>Rzhavy, we’ve got a situation…</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_1">
    <text>Well? Spit it out.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_10">
    <text>Well?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_11">
    <text>Son of a bitch! He just sold him out… I bet Nazar isn’t the first one who ended up dead because of his tips. By the way, you didn’t get to meet our leader — Zhekan, did you?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_12">
    <text>No, why?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_13">
    <text>A week ago, Zhekan went on a raid with Costa. Never came back. Our "buddy" Costa said he went missing, but not before naming him his second-in-command. We were suspicious, sure, but this is the Zone — weird stuff happens, so we believed him. Now I think he killed Zhekan, just to take his place.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_14">
    <text>So what are we going to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_15">
    <text>I think a public execution would be the best course of action.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_16">
    <text>I agree. But before we do that, we need to find out what he did to Zhekan, and where he might be.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_17">
    <text>Alright, I’ll call for you in a couple of hours. I’m going to tell the guys, so no one’s left in the dark.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_18">
    <text>I’ll be waiting.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_2">
    <text>Anyway, remember how you asked me to look into what the hell the “Blues” were doing around here?</text>
</string>

  <string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_3">
    <text>Yeah, I remember, so what? You already told me — said they were looking for some kind of artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_4">
    <text>They were… But the artifact is nothing compared to what else I managed to dig up.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_5">
    <text>What is it? Out with it already!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_6">
    <text>When I was tailing the “Blues,” I took out one of their couriers — he had a PDA. At first, I didn’t think much of it. But after I reported everything to you, I went to Ivanich and asked him to unlock the PDA. He did, and there was a lead in there — turns out Costa is somehow connected to the “Blues.” So I waited until nightfall and headed to their camp. Thought they were gone already, but they were waiting for me. And they were waiting because Costa warned them. I’ll forward the proof to your PDA right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_7">
    <text>Costa? Mercenaries?... Damn, I mean, I noticed he wasn’t too chatty when it came to the mercs, but working with them?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_8">
    <text>Read what I just sent you.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_gonec_pravosudiya_rjaviu_start_9">
    <text>[Reads message archive from Krivoy’s PDA.]</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_ivanich_about_yourself_0">
    <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_ivanich_about_yourself_1">
    <text>I’m what you young folks call “an old Soviet.” I’m from the Donetsk region, got my degree, moved to the city as a young specialist to work at a factory — figured I’d spend my life there. I’m an engineer. I ended up here by accident — got stiffed on a job, no pay. Then I met a guy back on the "Big Land," he told me about the Zone, said you could make some good money here. So I came. I’ve seen all sorts of things since then, but decided to settle down and fix things for the guys — good thing I’ve got both the skills and the hands for it.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_done_0">
    <text>Got your message — well? Did you manage to crack it?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_done_1">
    <text>Of course I did! Here’s the device — and as a proper technician, I didn’t go poking around inside. All the info’s yours — knock yourself out!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_0">
    <text>Ivanich, I need your help with something!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_1">
    <text>Something, huh? Alright, spill it — unless you’re messing around.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_2">
    <text>I need a PDA unlocked — can you help?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_3">
    <text>I can help — but not for free, obviously.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_4">
    <text>How much?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_5">
    <text>Let’s say fifteen hundred, and we’ll part ways like ships in the night.</text>
</string>

 <string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_6">
    <text>Alright, here’s the PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_66">
    <text>I don’t have that kind of money.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_7">
    <text>Great! I’ll get in touch with you as soon as I’m done.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_ivanich_merc_pda_unlocking_start_77">
    <text>Come back when you’ve got it, then.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_done_0">
    <text>Here are the maps you mentioned.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_done_1">
    <text>Good job, Snake! Here's your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_start_0">
    <text>How are you feeling after being held captive?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_start_1">
    <text>Better now. Listen — while I was in captivity, I overheard the bandits talking about a downed helicopter somewhere nearby. Supposedly, there’s a map of the Zone in it with all sorts of markings.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_start_2">
    <text>So what do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_start_3">
    <text>I want you to find that helicopter and retrieve the maps. I’ll pay you well. You should start looking near the transport tunnel.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_start_4">
    <text>Alright, I’ll try to find it.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_jekan_second_quest_start_44">
    <text>Sorry, but I’ve got too much on my plate right now…</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_katacombs_foma_starik_die_dialog_0">
    <text>Got your message — what’s going on?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_katacombs_foma_starik_die_dialog_1">
    <text>It’s… well… They found the old man — not exactly in one piece…</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_katacombs_foma_starik_die_dialog_2">
    <text>Goddamn it! So what now?!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_katacombs_foma_starik_die_dialog_3">
    <text>Hold on! His PDA had info about some stash — here are the coordinates. There might be something in there that could help you. I’ll need one gadget from that stash, though. You’ll know what I mean when you find it.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_katacombs_foma_starik_die_dialog_4">
    <text>Deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_kosta_about_terr_0">
    <text>What can you tell me about this place?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_kosta_about_terr_1">
    <text>Well, listen: We’re on the grounds of what used to be a research institute. Some say it was here even before the Chernobyl disaster. After the accident, the military set up shop here. What were they doing? No idea. But there’s plenty of evidence they were here — just step outside and all the military tech will catch your eye. Northeast of us, there are some abandoned hangars — looked like a repair base or maybe just a bus depot. Hard to tell. But there’s one detail — in one of those hangars, there’s an entrance to some underground facility. What’s down there? No one knows. No one’s ever managed to get the doors open. A bit further from the hangars, there’s an old military base, but it’s sealed off and crawling with anomalies — I wouldn’t recommend going there. To the east, there’s a transport tunnel — our guys are stationed there, but bandits often raid the place. Beyond that is an old checkpoint, and that’s bandit territory now — they either shoot or rob anyone passing through…</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_kosta_about_terr_2">
    <text>Fascinating stuff!</text>
</string>

  <string id="wiz_kosta_about_terr_3">
    <text>Hold on! That’s not all! To the southwest, there’s an old village — that’s where our “younger brothers” live. Nearby, there are a couple of anomalous clusters. Further southeast, there’s a small camp of our brothers, and a road as well — though that one’s littered with anomalies.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_kosta_about_terr_4">
    <text>Wait, are you saying there’s no way out of here?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_kosta_about_terr_5">
    <text>What do you mean, no way out? There is one — you got here, didn’t you? That’s why we don’t lose hope. Guides know about secret paths we’d never find on our own! That’s how it is.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_kosta_about_yourself_0">
    <text>Tell me about yourself?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_kosta_about_yourself_1">
    <text>Haven’t been asked that in a while… Feels strange, hmm. Not much to tell really — just a regular stalker like everyone else here. Started out running errands for Sidorovich in the Cordon. Then I joined a group of loners doing artifact hunting on commission. They taught me the ropes, and then I started going solo. Got tired of it quickly though. I don’t have any problems in the Big Land, but I came to the Zone out of curiosity — and there’s just something about this place that keeps you from getting bored.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_kosta_about_yourself_2">
    <text>So how did you end up here?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_kosta_about_yourself_3">
    <text>It’s simple. A group of stalkers led by Jekan decided to explore new areas. I joined them, and here we are. Jekan was a strange guy, but a great leader. Now, where he is or whether he’ll come back — no one knows. Before he left, he made me his second-in-command and went on a raid. Why or for how long — nobody ever found out.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_krivoy_enemy_with_neutral_0">
    <text>Oh look, it’s the rat who killed one of ours. Well, pal — mind telling me what the hell you’re doing here?!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_krivoy_enemy_with_neutral_1">
    <text>[Remains silent]</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_krivoy_enemy_with_neutral_2">
    <text>Playing the silent game, huh? We’ve got all day. My boys and I aren’t in a hurry, so we’ll just wait until you feel like talking.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_krivoy_enemy_with_neutral_3">
    <text>[Remains silent]</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_0">
    <text>Snake? What are you doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_1">
    <text>Oh, just decided to catch some sun. You?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_2">
    <text>Us? Same old — got orders to secure the area, and some intel on a “blue” camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_3">
    <text>Got it. Alright, Lieutenant, I’ll be going.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_0">
    <text>Lieutenant, I’ve got a question.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_1">
    <text>I’m listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_2">
    <text>You didn’t happen to find any keys on those “blue” guys, did you?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_3">
    <text>I did find one — but I’m not giving it away just like that…</text>
</string>

   <string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_4">
    <text>I don’t have much money, and as you can see — I’ve got no gear at all.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_5">
    <text>Relax, always straight to material stuff… I don’t need any of that. There’s only one thing I’m interested in: why were you locked up in the “Blues” detention cell? Snake, I’ve known you a long time — don’t try to dodge or spin tales.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_6">
    <text>A stalker named Rusty tipped me off. He was concerned about the “Blues” showing up in this area and asked me to dig up more info. So I did. I found out the “Blues” had some kind of connection with the local neutral leader. I learned that from one of their PDAs. Turns out the “Blues” had been commissioned to get a rare artifact. They didn’t want to find it themselves and hired a local scavenger. The guy found it — but instead of paying him, they just offed him. And since no one in the camp talks about this scavenger, I figured the leader hushed it up. That’s why I decided to gather more evidence and corner the rat. But instead of finding clues, I got knocked out… I think they were expecting me.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_7">
    <text>You’re probably right! Someone must’ve tipped them off — which means someone else didn’t want you sniffing around. By the way, there was a message archive on the “Blue’s” PDA. Might be of interest to you. I sent it your way.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_second_8">
    <text>Thanks, Lieutenant. Take care.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_0">
    <text>Lieutenant, got a question for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_1">
    <text>I'm listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_2">
    <text>You didn’t happen to find any keys on the “Blue” guys, did you?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_3">
    <text>I found one — but I’m not giving it up for nothing…</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_4">
    <text>I don’t have much money, and I’m completely out of gear as you can see.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_5">
    <text>Calm down — always about the loot… I don’t want any of that. I only want to know one thing: why were you in the “Blues” holding cell? Snake, I’ve known you for a long time — skip the stories.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_6">
    <text>Looks like the “Blues” bribed the local neutral leader, who then sold them an experienced artifact scavenger — Nazar. That stalker found a rare artifact for them on request. But instead of paying him, they just killed him — no loose ends. I found Nazar’s body and decided to gather more evidence of the “Blues” working with the local neutral leader. Came back here at night to investigate, but instead of clues, someone cracked me over the head. Just like that…</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_7">
    <text>Yeah… Sad to hear that neutrals are selling out their own… Alright, here’s the key. Oh, and Snake — in the “Blue’s” PDA, there was a chat log. Might’ve been with the leader of those neutrals. I already sent you the archive.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_lt_krasnopolsky_enemy_with_neutral_third_8">
    <text>Thanks, Lieutenant. I won’t forget it!</text>
</string>

 <string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_0">
    <text>I think you’ll be interested in this...</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_1">
    <text>What do you have?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_11">
    <text>Nazar’s PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_111">
    <text>I won’t even ask where you got that — I’ll give you 1500.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_1111">
    <text>Deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_11112">
    <text>Rest in peace, Nazar...</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_12">
    <text>PDA of a mercenary envoy. Found it near the military base.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_121">
    <text>I’ll give you 1000 for it.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_1211">
    <text>Deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_12112">
    <text>Very interesting… Nicely done, hunter!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_13">
    <text>Laptop from the mercenary camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_131">
    <text>I’ll offer 2000 for it.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_1311">
    <text>Deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_13112">
    <text>So that’s how it is! Interesting… Very interesting!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_14">
    <text>Stalker Rezac’s PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_141">
    <text>I’ll offer 500 for it.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_1411">
    <text>Deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_14112">
    <text>Just as I thought — nothing interesting...</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_rjaviu_about_yourself_0">
    <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_rjaviu_about_yourself_1">
    <text>Honestly, I don’t even know what to say… Just a regular stalker, not a vet but no rookie either. Came to the Zone a couple years ago, don’t really know many people. That’s about it.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_bsd_done_0">
    <text>The mutant’s dead — tell me what you know about Bison’s group.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_bsd_done_1">
    <text>They were here, but didn’t stay long. Stocked up on food and ammo, then left. Heard from their leader they were heading toward the tunnel — that’s where you’ll find them. That’s all I know.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_bsd_done_2">
    <text>Hmm… Not much, but thanks anyway.</text>
</string>

  <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_0">
    <text>Looks like you wanted something?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_1">
    <text>Exactly! I won’t beat around the bush — I need information about the catacombs.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_2">
    <text>What catacombs?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_3">
    <text>Damn... So, I went to the tunnel you told me about. Didn’t find the group there, but I did find traces of their presence and a PDA belonging to one of them. The PDA mentions some catacombs that would lead the group somewhere, but unfortunately, I couldn’t get more info. That’s why I’ve come back to you for help.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_4">
    <text>Interesting... I’ve heard of the catacombs, sure, but I always thought they were just stories. Turns out they’re not. As for the catacombs themselves, I can’t help you, but there’s an old man who sometimes drops by the bar. He’s around here pretty often, and he should know what these catacombs are and where they lead.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_5">
    <text>Great. Where can I find him?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_6">
    <text>That I don’t know. But I can let you know when he shows up again — not for free, of course.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_7">
    <text>Of course. What do you want in return?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_8">
    <text>Here’s the deal — I don’t have any jobs right now to settle the score. So I suggest this: when something comes up, you handle it. Deal? By the way, if you don’t want to wait for my message, ask around — maybe the guys have some easy work for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_katacombs_9">
    <text>Deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_0">
    <text>A hunter? Interesting! Very interesting... Why are you standing there? Speak up — what brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_1">
    <text>How do you know I’m a hunter? Eh, never mind. Costa said I should talk to you about Bison’s group. What can you tell me?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_2">
    <text>About Bison’s group? Not much, but you understand you’ll have to pay for the info, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_3">
    <text>I understand. How much?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_4">
    <text>No, no, no — you misunderstood. I’m not really interested in money. I have a more productive offer.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_5">
    <text>I’m listening...</text>
</string>

   <string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_6">
    <text>Alright, there’s a swamp not far from here, and some creature lives there that’s been interfering with our guys collecting artifacts. Sounds like a job right up your alley.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_7">
    <text>Let’s get this straight. I kill the creature, and you tell me everything you know about Bison’s group. That right?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_8">
    <text>That’s right. Look, here’s where the creature is. Once you’re done, come back.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_foma_start_9">
    <text>Alright, wait for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_kosta_start_0">
    <text>New face? Interesting! So, who are you? What brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_kosta_start_1">
    <text>I’m a hunter — they call me Snake, and I’ve got business. I’m looking for a group of stalkers led by Bison. According to my info, they should have passed through here. What can you tell me?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_kosta_start_2">
    <text>Well then, Hunter Snake... honestly, I’ve got nothing to tell you. You’d better head to the bar and talk to Foma, our local trader. If your people were here, they definitely talked to him. By the way, they call me Kosta, just so you know.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_kosta_start_3">
    <text>Thanks, I’ll go have a word with him.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_0">
    <text>Hey, stalker! I know you!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_1">
    <text>Dude, you must be mistaken. It’s my first time here — no way you know me...</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_2">
    <text>Oh no, I remember! You’re the hunter — Snake, if I’m not mistaken. You were with Gonta’s group, clearing out that snork nest near Zaton, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_3">
    <text>Yeah... that happened. Why?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_4">
    <text>No reason — I was the stalker you guys saved. They call me Rusty, by the way. Nice to meet you.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_5">
    <text>Ah, I see! That clears things up. Nice to meet you too. So, have you been around here long?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_6">
    <text>Not really — just started my third week. Why?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_7">
    <text>Listen, have you seen Bison’s group or the man himself by any chance?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_8">
    <text>Nope, man. Better go check with our leader or the trader — if they were here, those guys would know for sure.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_dialog_rjaviu_start_9">
    <text>Alright, I’ll talk to them. Anyway, I gotta go…</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_done_0">
    <text>So, what’s the deal with the “blue boys”?</text>
</string>

  <string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_done_1">
    <text>Nothing extraordinary. They were hired to search for a rare artifact, but I couldn't find out which one. The important thing I learned is that they plan to leave soon. So, no need to worry about them anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_done_2">
    <text>Is that all you found out?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_done_3">
    <text>They didn’t look for the artifact themselves, they hired some stalker. That guy found the artifact, and they killed him. Also, their leader, a guy called Crooked, that’s all.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_done_4">
    <text>Not much, but let’s hope they leave. Anyway, I’ll try to dig up some information about the leader of the “blues.”</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_done_5">
    <text>Try, but something tells me they’re just a one-off group. They were hired, don’t know each other, and once the job’s done, they’ll scatter. By the way, what about my reward?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_done_6">
    <text>Who knows… Here’s your reward, I think it’s more than enough!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_0">
    <text>Well, here you are. Want to make some money?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_1">
    <text>Of course, tell me what needs to be done.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_2">
    <text>Look, our guys just came back from a raid and said they saw a small group of mercenaries. They were hanging around the old military base. The guys waited a bit and saw how the “blues” easily broke the gate and disappeared inside. Your job is to find out what the hell the “blues” are doing here.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_3">
    <text>"Blues"? They’re everywhere, with contracts all over the Zone, so it’s not surprising they showed up here. By the way, did you tell Kosta about the “blues”? And why do you care what the “blues” are doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_4">
    <text>I did tell him, but he just shrugged and said it’s none of our business and we shouldn’t interfere with the “blues.” I wouldn’t bother, but something about their presence near our camp is bugging me. So, what do you think?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_5">
    <text>Kosta’s right, it’s best not to get involved with the “blues,” but on the other hand… Alright, fine. I hope the reward’s worth it.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_6">
    <text>You won’t be disappointed with the reward, don’t worry!</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_storyline_mercs_rjaviu_start_7">
    <text>I hope so… Because I’ll be putting myself in danger.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_done_0">
    <text>Ivanych, I’ve got news about the scanner and the lockpick.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_done_1">
    <text>What’s the news?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_done_2">
    <text>The lockpick’s dead, probably killed by mutants. The scanner was with him, and I’ve installed it at the spot you mentioned.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_done_3">
    <text>Pity about the stalker, but this is the Zone — no one’s safe from anything...</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_done_4">
    <text>I agree. Do you have any other work for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_done_5">
    <text>Yeah, there is. Come back later, I’m a bit busy right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_done_6">
    <text>Alright, see you.</text>
</string>

  <string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_go_0">
    <text>Good luck, do you have any work for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_go_1">
    <text>Thank you! Work? Always. It all depends on what you're good at...</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_go_2">
    <text>What am I good at? A lot of things. For example, I have experience working with the scientists' techs. I helped them set up equipment and measure anomalous fields. I'm also quite good at hunting all kinds of wildlife.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_go_3">
    <text>Really? Hunting doesn’t interest me much, but your experience with scientists is just what I need.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_go_4">
    <text>Well… Don't keep me in suspense. What’s the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_go_5">
    <text>Well, I signed a contract with the scientists a couple of months ago. They provide me with equipment, and I set up scanners or find people for research in various complexes, basically like a foreman — make a little money for myself and for the people. So, regarding the scanners, I sent a stalker a while ago to install one, but I haven’t heard from him in ages. The last time he contacted me, it was near the anomaly where the scanner should be installed. I have a feeling he’s dead, but the job needs to be done. So, find him and grab the scanner from him. I'll mark the installation point for you, and don’t worry about the reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="wiz_tech_secondary_quest_1_go_6">
    <text>Got it, I’ll head out right away.</text>
</string>

</string_table>
