<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="city_npc_army_kep_start_dialog_0">
    <text>You came from below, huh? Who are you? We'll take you to the boss now, He'll decide what to do with you...</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_army_kep_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_0">
    <text>Wow! What a surprise! We haven't seen each other in ages buddy. Water under the bridge right? So tell me, how did you end up here?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_1">
    <text>Really, another money-making scheme comrade major?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_2">
    <text>Easy there with the accusations. What are we, thugs? We have a serious situation now, and you have no choice to help. You're a criminal who's illegally here after all, no? Do you know what they'll give you? 15 years for illegal intrusion into a restricted military facility... Ah, maybe I'll shoot you to avoid the hassle of processing and transportation.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_3">
    <text>Hold on, don't get agitated, chief! I'm not planning on dying so easily after all this work.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_4">
    <text>Don't worry, you'll live... not for long though. Just kidding. I know why you're here. While you were roaming Cordon, your partner spilled quite a bit of interesting information to us. Especially about the artifact and the reward for it. The location of the damn thing... I thought I'd lost my mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_5">
    <text>Really! He didn't tell me about that.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_6">
    <text>Of course not! Several of my men died due to his false leads, may they rest in peace. And what, you think I'm okay with rotting in Cordon for another 10 years until retirement? And then? Living off a meager Ukrainian pension for the rest of my life? No thanks! This is a great opportunity. I found out where they're hiding this artifact through my channels, and we decided to take the risk with my guys. You only live once! Seeing as you're here too, that means my sources weren't lying.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_7">
    <text>I expected to find the artifact in the underground, where your men caught me on the way out.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_8">
    <text>That's a false lead. We checked, there's nothing there except SPECTRUM, they catch stalkers who reach there and eliminate them. They constantly patrol that lab. My fighters were just waiting for them to come back up, and then you showed up. According to my intel, the artifact is already at their base in the CPSU building, across the district. We're preparing for an operation to eliminate the group. If you help me, I'll let you go when it's all over. You'll be a free and alive man. I give you my officer's word.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_9">
    <text>I don't have a choice, do I? I accept your offer. What do I need to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_10">
    <text>We know on which frequency SPECTRUM is communicating, but our radio station is ancient Soviet crap. Damn Ukrainian army! Anyway, we quickly arranged for the delivery of radio parts from the mainland to Cordon, which will allow us to modify our station and start monitoring the necessary frequency. A few hours ago, there was an attempt to transport it here by helicopter but it came under fire. Thankfully no one died but the chopper has returned to base. They reported that they dropped the cargo from the side, and now we need to retrieve it. I don't want to send my fighters, some of them are on assignment and if I send the rest now, the base will be defenseless. You've arrived at the right time. Will you go for reconnaissance, search the area, and try to find the box with the parts? I've sent you the approximate drop zone on your PDA. That's it, you can go now. And remember, no funny business or we'll deal with you fast.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_11">
    <text>Alright, I'll go and search for the parts.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_0">
    <text>Phew, damn, they almost got me there! It was some kind of setup; as soon as I grabbed the box their fighters appeared...</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_1">
    <text>What did you expect, you're not shooting boars here like in Cordon! Anyway, good job, looks like you weren't even grazed. Alright, the parts are here, let's start monitoring their channel.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_2">
    <text>What's next?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_3">
    <text>Our scout, Sidorenko, returned from his assignment barely alive. I thought he was done for... but he's still kicking, resilient guy. He'll be fine before his wedding, or his funeral.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_4">
    <text>What was his assignment?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_5">
    <text>Patience, you'll find out soon. So, here's the deal: SPECTRUM somehow got hold of an APC. Yeah, really. The boys from the post sold it to them, like clockwork; they gave it to them for a crate of vodka, damn bastards! So, it poses a serious threat to us. Sidorenko's task was to plant explosives on the APC. We planned to detonate it remotely at the beginning of the assault to confuse their defense plans.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_6">
    <text>What should I do?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_7">
    <text>He got caught in an ambush and had to run. He couldn't set the explosives and, to get away faster, he dropped them somewhere on a playground. "Under a giraffe" he said. Do you know how many playgrounds here? You need to find the charge and set it on the APC. You're an experienced fighter; you can handle it. Go.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_8">
    <text>Understood. I'll get to it.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_0">
    <text>Job's done.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_1">
    <text>I had no doubts about you. We intercepted an important conversation while you were away. SPECTRUM is planning to transport their top brass from the Zone tomorrow morning, which, as it turns out, is currently in the city. I think they're doing it to transport the artifact instead. Two helicopters are scheduled for this job, which indirectly confirms my suspicion. We must intercept the artifact. According to the information, the helicopter departure will be covered by sniper fire and an APC, which we've already taken care of. Your task is to provide cover for my assault group.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_2">
    <text>You plan to capture the artifact and then transport it to the mainland yourself?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_3">
    <text>You got that right. If everything goes well, we will never see each other again.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_4">
    <text>I really hope so.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_0">
    <text>Shroud, Shroud, stop!!! ... Don't kill me. I know what you want!</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_1">
    <text>How do you know my name?!</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_2">
    <text>We know everything about all experienced stalkers of the Zone. We are SPECTRUM, we planned to take control of the Exclusion Zone and continue the experiments that the Consciousness scientists couldn't finish.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_3">
    <text>Stop feeding me bullshit! Where is the artifact, scumbag?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_4">
    <text>There is no artifact! We announced such a large prize so that all experienced stalkers would rush to find it, which we then recruit to guard the laboratories.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_5">
    <text>I've seen your recruitment methods. You simply killed anyone who was able to reach you and posed a threat. I'm not going to ask again, where is the artifact?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_6">
    <text>It doesn't exist! Take... Take this case, there's a lot, a lot of money here. Just don't kill me. Tell them you found no one here... I beg you!</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_7">
    <text>You convinced me! Give me the case... </text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Show me what you got there.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_final_dialog_1">
    <text>Here's the case. So how are we getting out of here?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_final_dialog_2">
    <text>You're dumber than I thought. Goodbye.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_final_dialog_3">
    <text>What?!</text>
</string>
</string_table>
