<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_13">
    <text>Well... Uh... I'm leaving... [runs away]</text>
</string>
<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_12">
    <text>[Master] He wants to kill us, Vasily. [Vasily] Kill us? How can he kill us, he's pathetic. [Master] He can't kill us. We're tired of talking to him. [Vasily] Yes, tired of it. Get out of here, stalker, while your protection lasts, and don't come back. [TOGETHER] GET OUT OF HERE!</text>
</string>
<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_11">
    <text>You must be destroyed - you are MONSTERS!!!</text>
</string>
<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_10">
    <text>[Master] Yes, we feed. If you haven't noticed, we don't have full life-support equipment here, we need to eat somehow. [Vasily] Stupid stalkers, stupid scientists, stupid soldiers. They come to the city. Our city. We control them and bring them here, they die here and we feed on them. [Master] We feed deliciously.</text>
</string>
<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_9">
    <text>Is that why there are so many corpses here? You feed on them?</text>
</string>
<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_8">
    <text>(you feel careful attempts to probe a weak spot in your mind) [Master] What a good protection. Where did it come from? Tell him, Vasily. [Vasily] We were brought here in a tube. They were going to dispose of us. But we are not lab animals to be disposed of. We disposed of them ourselves. [Master] We disposed of them excellently. The water here is now very nourishing. [Vasily] Very nourishing, Master, excellent water. They decompose, we feed on them.</text>
</string>
<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_7">
    <text>Calm down, I'm not going to obey you. Where did you come from?</text>
</string>
<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_6">
    <text>[First] He wants to know what we are, Vasily. [Second] What a curious stalker. Is he a scientist? I was a scientist too. Let's explain to him, Master. [First] Okay, okay, let's explain. [TOGETHER] WE'LL EXPLAIN. [First] This scum in a spacesuit you see in front of you is Vasily. He also wanted to know what we are, before. He found out. We EXPLAINED it to him. [Vasily] And what you see right behind me, in the ventilation shaft and here - that's Master. Master requires OBEDIENCE. [TOGETHER] OBEY! (the pressure on your mind sharply increases and then weakens again).</text>
</string>
<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_5">
    <text>What the hell is going on here? What are you even?</text>
</string>
<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_4">
    <text>(the pressure on your mind sharply increases but then weakens significantly) [First] We can't penetrate his mind, Vasily. [Second] He's aggressive, Master. He's well protected. [First] He's a scientist and came to study us? [Second] Maybe we can kill him? [First] No, we can't kill him, his mind is inaccessible, the protection interferes. [Second] Then we'll have to talk to him, Master. [First] Yes, talk, we can talk, it will give us time to come up with something. [TOGETHER] WE'LL TALK TO YOU, STALKER.</text>
</string>
<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_3">
    <text>Hey, get out of my head, freaks!</text>
</string>
<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_2">
    <text>(you feel something trying to penetrate your mind, unsuccessfully) [First] We can't feel him, Vasily. [Second] He's protected from us, Master. [TOGETHER] Why can't we feel you, stalker, what are you protected with?</text>
</string>
<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_1">
    <text>Umm... I... Came to find the source of the radiation.</text>
</string>
<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_0">
    <text>(you hear two voices in your head) [First] Strange guest we have today, isn't it, Vasily? [Second] Yes, strange guest. How did he get here? [First] Indeed, how did he get here? [TOGETHER] HOW DID YOU GET HERE, STALKER?</text>
</string>


</string_table>
