<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>

<!--
	Faction Patches
-->

<string_table><string id="csky_patch">
    <text>Clear Sky Stalker Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="csky_patch_description">
    <text>A patch torn from the suit of a Clear Sky stalker.</text>
</string>

<string id="freedom_patch">
    <text>Freedom Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_patch_description">
    <text>A patch torn from the suit of a Freedom member.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_patch">
    <text>Loner Stalker Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_patch_description">
    <text>A patch torn from the suit of a loner stalker.</text>
</string>

<string id="ecolog_patch">
    <text>Ecolog Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_patch_description">
    <text>A patch torn from the suit of a scientist.</text>
</string>

<string id="bandit_patch">
    <text>Bandit Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="bandit_patch_description">
    <text>A patch torn from the suit of a bandit.</text>
</string>

<string id="duty_patch">
    <text>Duty Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="duty_patch_description">
    <text>A patch torn from the suit of a Duty member.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolith_patch">
    <text>Monolith Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="monolith_patch_description">
    <text>A patch torn from the suit of a Monolith member.</text>
</string>

<string id="army_patch">
    <text>Military Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="army_patch_description">
    <text>A patch torn from a soldier’s uniform.</text>
</string>

<string id="merc_patch">
    <text>Mercenary Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="merc_patch_description">
    <text>A patch torn from the suit of a mercenary.</text>
</string>

	<string id="st_clearsky_fp">
    <text>Clear Sky Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_clearsky_fp_descr">
    <text>This patch depicts a sunrise against a clear sky with a pair of birds. It symbolizes the core values of the Clear Sky faction — healing the Zone and avoiding armed conflict. Clear Sky seeks to significantly reduce the frequency and intensity of emissions and other anomalous phenomena. However, only a small number of stalkers believe such a goal is even possible.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_freedom_fp">
    <text>Freedom Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_freedom_fp_descr">
    <text>This patch features a green wolf, a coat of arms, and the national flag of Ukraine, all set against a black background. The design reflects the social nature of the Freedom faction, their love for their homeland, and the fierce, determined, and untamed character of its fighters. Nevertheless, stalkers still question why anarchists would include any national flag — especially as part of their equipment.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_stalker_fp">
    <text>Loner Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_stalker_fp_descr">
    <text>Used among loner stalkers who don’t belong to any particular faction, this patch is quite common among mercenaries who sell them to mysterious buyers. Although loners are numerous in the Zone, most are either scattered in small groups or lone wanderers, often falling prey to more organized or criminal groups.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_ecolog_fp">
    <text>Ecolog Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ecolog_fp_descr">
    <text>This patch displays a pair of golden wings on a white-turquoise background resembling water, with two turquoise stars above — symbolizing the scientists’ goals in the Zone. Their patches are in high demand on the Zone’s black market, as wearing one can grant access to various opportunities and nearly unrestricted travel. For their own safety, scientists never part with their patches voluntarily — though that rarely stops those without a moral compass.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_bandit_fp">
    <text>Bandit Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bandit_fp_descr">
    <text>The bandit patch features a cracked skull over a white shield. This symbol reflects the vision of some Zone underworld leaders — that they’re not just thugs, but rulers who impose their own order wherever they choose, offer "protection" for a price, and deliver merciless retribution to those who dare challenge them.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n 
    </text>
</string>

	<string id="st_dolg_fp">
	<text>Duty Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_dolg_fp_descr">
	<text>The “Duty” patch features a golden target on a red-and-black shield background. The emblem symbolizes the group's military affiliation and their main mission: protecting the outside world from the Zone and destroying its abominations.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_monolith_fp">
	<text>Monolith Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_monolith_fp_descr">
	<text>This patch features a pair of wings in profile against the backdrop of a golden sun, possibly representing the Monolith itself. The most intriguing aspect is that it belongs to individuals believed to be brainwashed, and the emblem is found nowhere else in the world. Its mere existence raises questions — do members retain some creativity, or is someone orchestrating the group's operations? Monolith patches are highly valued by other stalkers as trophies, symbolizing both survival skills and the defeat of a dangerous enemy.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_army_fp">
	<text>Military Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_army_fp_descr">
	<text>The Armed Forces of Ukraine patch features three shields with a pair of crossed swords behind them, all enclosed in a laurel wreath. The central shield is colored in the national flag and bears the Ukrainian coat of arms. This symbolizes their self-perception as protectors and peacekeepers within the Zone — though whether they truly live up to this image is subject to debate.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_merc_fp">
	<text>Mercenary Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_merc_fp_descr">
	<text>The only element on this patch is a predatory blue bird on a black background. It likely reflects the nature of mercenaries: cold, calculating, and professional soldiers of fortune — ready to strike or eliminate a target at any moment, no questions asked.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_isg_fp">
	<text>“ISG” Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_isg_fp_descr">
	<text>This patch depicts a white microscope surrounded by a stylized laurel wreath on a crimson background. Hidden from plain view, the back of the patch bears an inscription identifying it as belonging to the “International Scientific Group under UN protection.”\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
	</text>
</string>

	<string id="st_greh_fp">
	<text>Sin Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_greh_fp_descr">
	<text>This patch is unsettling to hold in your hands. On a black background, a serpent appears in the upper left corner, and an Orthodox cross in the upper right. In the center is a darkened star bearing the word “SIN.” Yet, holding it for an extended period strangely evokes a sense of peace.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_renegade_fp">
	<text>Renegade Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_renegade_fp_descr">
	<text>This patch displays a yellow scorpion on a green shield. Its existence hints that the group may once have had a greater purpose — though nowadays, few believe its members share any unity beyond their desperation and will to survive. Today, the patch is commonly found among outcasts and hardened criminals… perhaps due to nostalgia, or simply style.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
	</text>
</string>


<string id="st_spectrum_fp">
	<text>"Spectrum" Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_spectrum_fp_descr">
	<text>A patch of a mysterious group. Who sponsors this PMC? A mystery we won't uncover any time soon. One thing is clear — this is a very dangerous faction.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_milstalk_fp">
	<text>"Military Stalkers" Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_milstalk_fp_descr">
	<text>A patch of stalkers who signed a contract with the military. They survive in the Zone's conditions where the military lacks experience. They carry out various government assignments.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_atribute_fp">
	<text>"Attribute" Patch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_atribute_fp_descr">
	<text>A patch of unknown cultists calling themselves "Attribute". No one knows where they came from, but rumors of their cruelty have spread across the Zone. Who are they, and what are they searching for?\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
	</text>
</string>


</string_table>