<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<!--
  New Artefacts
-->
<string_table>

<string id="st_af_raibloko_name">
	<text>"Paradise Apple"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_raibloko_descr">
	<text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Type 1 anomaly\n%c[default]A rainbow-colored sphere the size of an apple that slowly rotates about a meter and a half above the ground. Emits a faint, barely audible beep. Has zero-gravity properties, offers mild psi protection, and heats up significantly in areas with high radiation. Parent anomaly: Orchestra (Echo). High selling price. Of interest to scientists and collectors.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_seaej_name">
	<text>"Sea Urchin"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_seaej_descr">
	<text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Type 4 anomaly\n%c[default]A rare and valuable artifact created by the "Burning Fluff" anomaly. Its appearance genuinely resembles a sea urchin, covered with numerous spines. Increases blood pressure when worn and causes bleeding due to pricking. However, it also helps expel accumulated radiation from the body. Its use is difficult, as bandages are constantly needed to stop the bleeding.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_mayatnik_name">
	<text>"Pendulum"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_mayatnik_descr">
	<text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Type 3 anomaly\n%c[default]Quite rare. Found only in the northern parts of the Zone. Its main properties are still under research.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_lifekam_name">
	<text>"Stone of Life"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_lifekam_descr">
	<text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Type 4 anomaly\n%c[default]Artifact bonuses:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Increases bullet resistance %c[255,238,15,26](%c[255,1,128,54]+25%c[255,238,15,26])\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Impact protection %c[255,238,15,26](%c[255,1,128,54]+10%c[255,238,15,26])\n%c[default]A gelatinous semi-transparent sphere, covered in a moist film, warm to the touch. When in contact with the body, it adheres and gradually begins to be absorbed. Accelerates regeneration, increases strength and reaction speed, reduces pain sensitivity. Makes the user almost invulnerable, as even bullet wounds are barely felt and seem not to cause serious harm. However, the process doesn't stop there. Gradually, the person begins to change. Emotions shut down, memory fades, the body transforms—becomes denser, more flexible. Eventually, the only known specimen disappeared from the scientists' camp, leaving behind three corpses. Nothing more is known about it.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_vedsleza_name">
	<text>"Witch's Tear"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_vedsleza_descr">
	<text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Type 2 anomaly\n%c[default]A fairly common artifact in the center of the Zone. Has an elongated drop-like shape with a reddish hue and green shimmer. Formed near the "Burner" anomaly. Increases resistance to high temperatures. Radioactive.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_gubka_name">
	<text>"Sponge"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_gubka_descr">
	<text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Type 1 anomaly\n%c[default]A fairly common emerald-colored viscous substance generated by the "Jelly" anomaly. When carried, it creates a special chemical field that protects against harmful effects.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_sluda_name">
	<text>"Mica"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_sluda_descr">
	<text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Type 4 anomaly\n%c[default]The most powerful (and thus useful) artifact of the "Jelly" anomaly. Greatly increases blood clotting. Almost transparent yet solid sphere. Extremely rare and expensive.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_oblivion_name">
	<text>"Oblivion Lost"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_oblivion_descr">
	<text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Type 2 anomaly\n%c[default]A small blue-white sphere the size of a fist, resembling ice with tiny dark blue specks. Capable of accelerating any object (bullet) passing through it to incredible speeds. Also offers protection from psi effects.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_indeikam_name">
	<text>"Indian Stone"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_indeikam_descr">
	<text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Type 2 anomaly\n%c[default]A light gray, egg-sized rounded stone with dark wavy lines and dots across its surface. In the Zone, the "Indian Stone" can enhance or suppress, partially or fully, the properties of other artifacts. Loses power outside the Zone. Used in artifact assemblies. Medium selling price.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_sverlo_name">
	<text>"Drill"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_sverlo_descr">
	<text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Selection not possible\n%c[default]The Drill is one of the rarest artifacts found in the Zone. The first specimen was discovered by a stalker nicknamed Lemur. Named after its intricate elongated cylindrical shape with a silvery hue. Its properties are still not fully studied, making practical field use impossible. Extremely high price.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_oreh_name">
	<text>"Nut"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_oreh_descr">
	<text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Selection not possible\n%c[default]Another extremely rare artifact of the Zone. A dark brown sphere the size of a walnut, hence its name. Grants energy and a sense of satiety. Its main property is the ability to cure rare diseases such as brain cancer and others. No wonder it's so highly valued.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_chertyaico_name">
	<text>"Devil's Egg"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_chertyaico_descr">
	<text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Selection not possible\n%c[default]Roughly the size and shape of a chicken egg, deep black and shimmering in the light. When broken, releases a powerful impulse of unknown origin. Cures cancer, blood diseases, and some other illnesses. Also removes the negative influence of the Guardian Devil while keeping the positive effects. If broken incorrectly—or even if left whole—contact can be instantly lethal. Gradually burns through metal and wood. Parent anomaly: Devil's Web. Has negative weight, so it must be searched for under roofs or ceilings, where it gets trapped instead of rising skyward. This likely explains its extreme rarity: most of them simply fall upward and vanish.</text>
</string>

	<string id="st_af_oko_name">
    <text>"Eye"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_oko_descr">
    <text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Selection is not possible\n%c[default]A semi-transparent, dull blue-green orb with faint edges, about the size of a fist. The center of the artifact is densely matte in color. The Eye possesses a truly unique ability to record events happening nearby and replay them within itself—essentially acting like a kind of video camera. Additionally, it grants extra protection against chemical and electrical damage.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_blacksoul_name">
    <text>"Black Soul"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_blacksoul_descr">
    <text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Selection is not possible\n%c[default]A variant of the regular Soul artifact, this one is black and red in color. Its effect is the exact opposite of the regular Soul. It drains the life force of its bearer, quickly leading the body to exhaustion. It also has a negative impact on the psyche, causing aggression and paranoia. If shattered, it produces a bright greenish flash more powerful than a flashbang grenade. Extremely rare, it forms at sites of massive death within the Carousel anomaly. Highly dangerous and not recommended for direct contact. Of interest only to scientists and hardcore collectors.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_skripka_name">
    <text>"Violin"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_skripka_descr">
    <text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Selection is not possible\n%c[default]A round, shimmering, zero-gravity formation. The “Violin” is of purely aesthetic value—it hovers half a meter above any surface and shines with all the colors of the rainbow. Additionally, it emits a melodic chime in various tones from the slightest breeze. Despite lacking practical use, it fetches a decent price. Mostly sought after by collectors and other eccentrics from the Big Land.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_poipruz_name">
    <text>"Singing Spring"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_poipruz_descr">
    <text>%c[default]For the selector:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Anomaly type: 2\n%c[default]A fairly rare, though not particularly expensive artifact. Spawned by the Echo anomaly, it resembles an elongated spring. Slightly reduces radiation. Other potential properties, if any, are not yet known.</text>
</string>


</string_table>