<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>


<string_table>


<string id="st_wpn_spareparts">
	<text>Weapon Spare Parts</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_descr">
	<text>
Spare parts that at first glance appear to belong to an AKM rifle. The wooden elements aren't exactly in good condition, but most likely only rookies would be interested in buying them. Some stalker probably replaced parts of their weapon when they found something newer—and stashed the old ones to avoid being accused of theft.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item
	</text>
</string>


	<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_small">
	<text>Small Weapon Parts</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_small_descr">
	<text>
A handful of small weapon parts. Usually includes springs, screws, triggers, short barrels, firing pins, bolts, and similar components. They may not fetch a high price, but they are in fairly good condition and can be used to replace broken parts in other firearms. In that role, they can substitute the most damaged parts and help begin a more substantial repair.\n\n
%c[0,140,140,140]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[0,153,255,255] • %c[0,140,140,140] technological device\n
%c[255,238,153,26] • %c[0,140,140,140] used to repair firearms\n
%c[255,238,153,26] • %c[0,140,140,140] cannot be used if condition is below: %c[0,170,170,170]1%\n
%c[255,238,153,26] • %c[0,140,140,140] base repair value: %c[0,170,170,170]1%\n\n
%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED ADD-ONS:\n
%c[255,238,153,26] • %c[0,140,140,140] additional small weapon parts %c[0,170,170,170]+1–3%
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_spareparts">
	<text>Large Weapon Parts</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_spareparts_descr">
	<text>
A bundle of large weapon parts. Usually includes long barrels, handguards, covers, grips, receivers, bolt carriers, and so on. They may not be worth a fortune, but they are in decent condition and can be used to replace broken components in other firearms. These parts are suitable for repairing the most damaged elements and for initiating more substantial repairs.\n\n
%c[0,140,140,140]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[0,153,255,255] • %c[0,140,140,140] technological device\n
%c[255,238,153,26] • %c[0,140,140,140] used to repair large firearms\n
%c[255,238,153,26] • %c[0,140,140,140] cannot be used if condition is below: %c[0,170,170,170]1%\n
%c[255,238,153,26] • %c[0,140,140,140] base repair value: %c[0,170,170,170]3%\n\n
%c[0,140,140,140]SUPPORTED ADD-ONS:\n
%c[255,238,153,26] • %c[0,140,140,140] additional weapon parts %c[0,170,170,170]+1–3%
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_waste_light">
	<text>Light Weapon Scrap</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_waste_light_descr">
	<text>
Small fragments of firearms. They're in such poor condition that it's difficult to identify their origin. Mostly useless now, but a resourceful stalker might salvage something usable for weapon repair. If nothing else, they can be sold for a few rubles.\n\n
%c[0,140,140,140]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[0,153,255,255] • %c[0,140,140,140] technological device\n
%c[255,238,153,26] • %c[0,140,140,140] used for: %c[0,170,170,170] weapon maintenance (+1%) %c[0,140,140,140](only with repair kits)
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_waste_heavy">
	<text>Heavy Weapon Scrap</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_waste_heavy_descr">
	<text>
A bundle of large mechanical weapon parts in very poor condition. Not much can be salvaged, but some pieces might still be fitted into a firearm. Due to the amount of metal and materials, this scrap is usually more valuable than a handful of light weapon debris.\n\n
%c[0,140,140,140]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[0,153,255,255] • %c[0,140,140,140] technological device\n
%c[255,238,153,26] • %c[0,140,140,140] used for: %c[0,170,170,170] heavy weapon maintenance (+2%) %c[0,140,140,140](only with repair kits)
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_outfit_waste_light">
	<text>Cloth Scraps</text>
</string>
<string id="st_outfit_waste_light_descr">
	<text>
A bundle of small fabric pieces, most likely cut or torn from clothing. There's not much you can do with them except sell them for a few rubles or patch up a tear in your pants.\n\n
%c[0,140,140,140]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[0,153,255,255] • %c[0,140,140,140] technological device\n
%c[255,238,153,26] • %c[0,140,140,140] used for: %c[0,170,170,170] equipment repair (+3%)
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_outfit_waste_heavy">
	<text>Armor Scraps</text>
</string>
<string id="st_outfit_waste_heavy_descr">
	<text>
A bundle of small fragments of protective materials—like Kevlar—used in modern body armor and helmets. The individual pieces are too small to be of much use for serious repairs, so they are often sold rather than used for patching up your vest.\n\n
%c[0,140,140,140]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[0,153,255,255] • %c[0,140,140,140] technological device\n
%c[255,238,153,26] • %c[0,140,140,140] used for: %c[0,170,170,170] equipment repair (+6%)
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_tech_waste">
	<text>Electronic Scrap</text>
</string>
<string id="st_tech_waste_descr">
	<text>
Small electrical and electronic components extracted from various devices found in the Zone. Most are too damaged to be reused, but they can still be sold to get at least some value from them.\n\n
%c[0,140,140,140]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[0,153,255,255] • %c[0,140,140,140] technological device
	</text>
</string>

	
	

</string_table>