<?xml version="1.0" encoding="st_windows-1251"?>
<string_table>

	<string id="st_ammo_new_93x64_tog">
    <text>9.3x64 Brenneke TOG Rounds</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo_new_93x64_tog_descr">
    <text>
    Torpedo Optimal Bullet Ś ammunition loaded with a 16-gram expanding bullet of original design developed by Brenneke for big game hunting. The bullet's design ensures expansion when passing through soft tissue depending on resistance, while preventing significant fragmentation. This guarantees deep penetration and a clean exit wound in case of a through shot.
    </text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo_new_93x64_tog_s">
    <text>9.3x64 Brenneke TOG</text>
</string>

<string id="st_ammo_new_93x64_sp">
    <text>9.3x64 Brenneke NPZ SP Rounds</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo_new_93x64_sp_descr">
    <text>
    Civilian ammunition loaded with a 17.5-gram semi-jacketed expanding bullet. The lead bullet in a tombac jacket expands rapidly upon impact, causing severe wounds. It also has significant stopping power and is used for hunting very large game. This cartridge was manufactured at the Novosibirsk Cartridge Plant.
    </text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo_new_93x64_sp_s">
    <text>9.3x64 Brenneke NPZ SP</text>
</string>

<string id="st_ammo_new_93x64_tug">
    <text>9.3x64 Brenneke TUG Rounds</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo_new_93x64_tug_descr">
    <text>
    Torpedo Universal Bullet Ś a hunting cartridge with a two-part 19-gram lead bullet made by Brenneke. The front part disintegrates upon impact, causing serious wounds, while the rear, made of stronger material, continues forward, ensuring impressive penetration. The tapered tail reduces friction in soft tissues, further improving penetration. The copper-nickel coating reduces barrel wear, and a special cutting edge causes heavy bleeding, making it easier to track wounded game.
    </text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo_new_93x64_tug_s">
    <text>9.3x64 Brenneke TUG</text>
</string>

<string id="st_ammo_new_93x64_7n33">
    <text>9.3x64 Brenneke 7N33 SNB Rounds</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo_new_93x64_7n33_descr">
    <text>
    A military sniper cartridge developed around the turn of the 21st century. It is loaded with a 17-gram bullet featuring a dual-core Ś hardened steel front and a lead rear. Capable of reliably penetrating body armor up to BR5 class and causing severe wounds.
    </text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo_new_93x64_7n33_s">
    <text>9.3x64 Brenneke 7N33 SNB</text>
</string>

<string id="st_ammo_new_127x108_7n34">
    <text>12.7x108 mm 7N34 SN Rounds</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo_new_127x108_7n34_descr">
    <text>
    A military sniper cartridge adopted in 2012. Exclusively used in ASVK and ASVKM sniper rifles due to its different ballistics compared to machine gun rounds. The bullet is dual-core Ś hardened steel tip and lead base. Provides reliable target engagement through BR5-class armor and behind light cover at ranges up to 1.5 km.
    </text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo_new_127x108_7n34_s">
    <text>12.7x108 mm 7N34 SN</text>
</string>

<string id="st_ammo_new_127x108_bs">
    <text>12.7x108 mm BS 7-BZ-1 Rounds</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo_new_127x108_bs_descr">
    <text>
    Military armor-piercing incendiary ammunition with a tungsten carbide core. The bullet consists of a steel jacket plated with tombac, a metal-ceramic core encased in lead, and an incendiary compound compressed in the tip between the core and jacket.\n
    Upon impact, the core pierces the armor, and the incendiary mix ignites from the shock, entering the penetration path.\n
    Effective against BR6-class armor, cover, and light armored vehicles.
    </text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo_new_127x108_bs_s">
    <text>12.7x108 mm BS 7-BZ-1</text>
</string>

<string id="st_ammo-300blk_fmj">
    <text>.300BLK Full Metal Jacket</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo-300blk_fmj_descr">
    <text>
    The .300 AAC Blackout, also known as 7.62x35mm, is an intermediate cartridge developed in the United States by Advanced Armament Corporation (AAC) for use in the M4 carbine. Its goal was to match the ballistics of the 7.62x39mm or, more closely, the 7.92x33mm Kurz cartridge in the M4 platform.
    </text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo-300blk_fmj_s">
    <text>.300BLK FMJ</text>
</string>

<string id="st_ammo-300blk_sp">
    <text>.300BLK Soft Point</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo-300blk_sp_descr">
    <text>
    The .300 AAC Blackout, also known as 7.62x35mm, is an intermediate cartridge developed in the United States by Advanced Armament Corporation (AAC) for use in the M4 carbine. Its purpose was to replicate the ballistics of the 7.62x39mm or, more closely, the 7.92x33mm Kurz cartridge in the M4. These rounds were modified to deal greater damage and expand upon impact.
    </text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo-300blk_sp_s">
    <text>.300BLK SP</text>
</string>

<string id="st_ammo-300blk_ap">
    <text>.300BLK Armor-Piercing</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo-300blk_ap_descr">
    <text>
    The .300 AAC Blackout, also known as 7.62x35mm, is an intermediate cartridge developed in the United States by Advanced Armament Corporation (AAC) for use in the M4 carbine. Its purpose was to achieve ballistics similar to the 7.62x39mm or, even more similarly, the 7.92x33mm Kurz cartridge in an M4. These rounds have been modified to pierce armor.
    </text>
</string>
<string id="st_ammo-300blk_ap_s">
    <text>.300BLK AP</text>
</string>


</string_table>