<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
    <string id="st_helm_respirator_gp">
		<text>Gas mask GP-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_gp_descr">
		<text>Civil gas mask GP-5 is designed to protect respiratory organs, face and eyes from the effects of poisonous and radioactive substances, as well as from pathogens and toxins. Has a tolerable indicator of protection against radiation, among stalkers is not widely distributed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_freedom">
		<text>Gas mask XM28</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_freedom_descr">
		<text>The gas mask consists of an obverse part and a filtering-absorbing system (FPS), which are connected together directly or by means of a connecting tube. The gas mask kit includes a bag and non-fogging films, and, depending on the type of gas mask, the interphone membranes, a tricot hydrophobic cover, overhead insulating cuffs, a waterproof bag, a flask cover with a flap and a tag can be included. Used mainly by the Freedom clan of the Stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_dolg">
		<text>Gas mask RSh-4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_dolg_descr">
		<text>Composition: filtering-absorbing box EO-16, connecting tube, helmet-mask ШМ-41Му or ШМС, bag. The set includes - a box with non-fogging films, overhead warming cuffs NMU-1 (for ШМ-41Му), a box with spare membranes for the intercom device (for ШМС). The EO-16 filter-absorbing box has the form of a cylinder 17.5 cm high and 10.7 cm in diameter. There is an internal screwed neck in the bottom of the casing. The helmet-mask ShM-41Mu consists of a body, a spectacle unit, fairings and a valve box. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_battle_dolg">
		<text>Combined-arms protective helmet 6B7 &quot;Borit-M&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_battle_dolg_descr">
		<text>It is intended for use in a set of combat equipment (&quot;Barmitsa&quot;) as a means of armored protection for servicemen of the Airborne Forces and the Airborne Forces in the conduct of all types of combat operations. Provides protection from the bullets of PM, APS and fragmentary pistols with a mass of 1 g at a speed of 580 m / s. The body material is a composite material (a combination of aramid fabrics and a film polymer binder). The protection area is 11.5 square meters. Weight - 1,2 kg. The helmet consists of a body and a sub-unit. The body is made of a composite consisting of ballistic fabric and a special film binder. The undercut device is a belt system that allows fast and reliable fixation of the product on the head of the serviceman, provides protection against impacts with an energy of up to 50 Joules.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_tactic_freedmon">
		<text>Protective helmet &quot;PASGT-H&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_tactic_freedmon_descr">	
	    <text>Designed to protect the head, temples, ears and partially neck from ballistic shrapnel hits, ready-made killer elements (shrapnel bullets, needle arrows), projectiles and air bombs, various kinds of fragments, stones, and local objects scattered during the explosion. In addition, the helmet protects against non-ballistic strikes. The helmet was adopted by the US Army in the early eighties. It is made of reinforced Kevlar Kevlar 29 or Kevlar KM2. Of the latter material, the helmet is 10% lighter with the same level of protection. Any metals for the helmet dome are neither fully nor partially used. The helmet is completely non-metallic and non-magnetic.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_battle_monolit">
		<text>Helmet of Monolith &quot;Sphere of MKM&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_battle_monolit_descr">
		<text>Helmet &quot;Sphere MKM&quot;, is a modification of the standard army sample M12 of this helmet made by special order grouping Monolith. The gas mask provides increased protection against radiation and chemical hazards. Has a built-in night vision device. Used in elite combat units of the group.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_battle_merc">
		<text>Battle Helmet mercenaries &quot;Raptor M1&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_battle_merc_descr">	
	    <text>Designed to order one of the western private military campaign. After additional refinement I found myself applying on the territory of the Zone. It has increased protection against radiation, chemical and psychological effects. It is in the standard equipment of the assault combat groups of the mercenary clan.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hunter_shlem">
		<text>Steel helmet ЧН-2МТ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hunter_shlem_descr">
		<text>This sample is a regular steel helmet that was in the standard equipment of the assault brigades of the Pure Sky grouping. At one time, the mechanics of the clean-ups created a very high-quality element of outfitting their fighters, in many respects not inferior to other similar alternatives. Even now, after the death of the clan, their equipment is in high demand in the Zone. Not an exception, and this helmet is used by many free walkers, as well as stalkers from the groupings Guardian and Insight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_pmk1">
		<text>Military gas mask PMK-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_pmk1_descr">
		<text>A gas mask with a high degree of protection and increased comfort in wearing. Military version of gas mask type GP-7. Has a number of improvements in comparison with the civilian option. A special design of large glasses, greatly improving the visibility and allowing you to aim shooting and work with optics. It is equipped with a device for receiving water and an adapter for an army jar. It is equipped with a filter with increased absorptive power. Technical characteristics: filter life - 230 hours, duration of continuous stay - 24 hours, intelligibility of speech - 95%, audibility - 100%, mass of gas mask complete without a bag - 960gr.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_gp7">
		<text>Military gas mask PMK-3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_gp7_descr">
		<text>The gas mask PMK-3, the latest generation with a high degree of protection and increased comfort in wearing. It is intended for protection of respiratory organs, face and eyes from poisonous substances, toxic chemicals, biological aerosols and radioactive dust, СЯЯВ, СЯВ. Technical characteristics: filter life - 240 hours, duration of continuous stay - 24 hours, intelligibility of speech - 95%, audibility - 100%, mass of gas mask complete without a bag - 960gr.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_hardhat_respirator">
		<text>Helmet &quot;Pure breath&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_hardhat_respirator_descr">
		<text>Developed by craftsmen from the group &quot;Clear Sky&quot;. It was used by stalkers of the grouping together with the armored suit CHN-3a. The helmet consists of a steel helmet with spectacles and a cleverly pre-mounted respirator with two good filters. As a result, they received a good helmet with a high level of protection, both from gunshot wounds and from harmful substances, while its steel base extinguishes psi radiation. Now used by the stalkers of the groupings of Insight, Guardian and Retribution.</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_helm_tell">
		<text>Antitellipathic helmet U2</text>
	</string>
      	<string id="st_helm_tell_descr">
		<text>The antitallpatic helmet U2, developed by the scientist Sakharov, is an improved prototype of headphone antipsy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_vakuum">
		<text>Helmet &quot;Vacuum&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_vakuum_description">
		<text>The &quot;Vacuum&quot; helmet is named because of the specific air filtration, that is, not even filtration, but the creation of gas, which is perceived by the lungs as air. An insulating helmet made of a universal fiber is created, which protects the wearer from an aggressive environment. It is used in conjunction with many stalker scientific overalls such as SEVA, &quot;PS6-9mD&quot; and others.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_pmg2">
		<text>Gas mask filtering PMG-2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_pmg2_descr">
		<text>The gas mask is almost the same as GP-5 with a black mask of ShMP, the difference in the other helmet is SHM66-u. The mask is distinguished by the presence of cutouts for the ears (it is important for the military to hear orders), and the presence of a colloquial membrane, which is absent in GP-5. In contrast to the industrial GP-5, the PMG-2 gas mask is used by the military. In the Zone it is quite rare in the main for beginner stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_ip4">
		<text>Gas mask insulating IP-4 MK</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_ip4_descr">
		<text>Modern insulating gas mask for general use. Compact and light enough in comparison with other insulating masks. Designed for work with insulating suits like KIH-5, placed under a suit on the back, in the form of a knapsack, and also with other suits, instead of a filtering gas mask, when the filtering gas mask can not be used. A comfortable mask with a soft obturator and podmasochnikom, with fixing straps provides comfort in work and excellent audibility. Insulating respirator IP-4 MK with RP-7B Complete with regenerative cartridges RP-7B, and one mask MIA-1. There is an intercom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_m17a2">
		<text>M17A2 gas mask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_m17a2_descr">
		<text>Isolating American General Purpose Gas Mask. It was developed as a complete set of standard equipment for the military personnel of the US Army and NATO countries. Comfortable mask made of silicone with vinyl cover, with fixing straps provides comfort in work and excellent audibility. Has average protection indicators.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_1respirator_mcu2">
		<text>Gas mask MCU-2 / P</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_1respirator_mcu2_descr">
		<text>A modern American general gas mask. It was created for the military personnel of the Air Force and the Navy of the US Army. Has a sufficiently high protection against harmful effects. On the territory of the Zone occurs mainly with the composition of a protective kit of some stalkers from the clans &quot;Svoboda&quot; and the Mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_mcu2">
		<text>Protective mask for Drager M2000</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_mcu2_descr">
		<text>M2000 - a combined-arms gas mask, developed by the German company Dragerwerk and designed to protect against chemical and biological agents, as well as particles of radioactive dust. The front part of the gas mask comes in three sizes, which, according to the company, covers 94% of the possible head sizes. The mask is made of hypoallergenic materials, a uniform distribution of pressure on the head is achieved through six belts. The viewing angle is at least 90 °, the design allows the installation of additional light filters to protect against sunlight and laser beams. The mask can be subjected to all standard decontamination methods, including hot steam treatment at temperatures up to + 170 ° C. Maintenance does not require special tools, the service life is 20 years. On the territory of the Zone occurs mainly with the composition of a protective kit of some stalkers from the clans &quot;Svoboda&quot; and the Mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_localizator">
		<text>Gas Dismantle Set GDZK</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_localizator_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Head protection = 45%\n%c[default] An original gas mask (self-rescuer filtering), specially designed for evacuation in case of fire and protecting a person from fire and carbon monoxide poisoning, as well as toxic combustion products. A hood made of thick rubberized fabric with a wide viewing window effectively protects the head from open fire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_localizator1">
		<text>Gas mask isolating KIP-9 &quot;Localization&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_localizator1_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Head protection = 65%\n%c[default]This insulating mask was developed in one of the research institutes specially for joint use with army isolating kits. It was originally intended to complement the isolating kit FIR-7M, but within the Zone it became more widely known, as in many scientific stalker suits such as SEVA, PS6-9mD was installed instead of the standard &quot;Screen&quot;. It differs by one of the best ratio of price and quality.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_geonik">
		<text>Isolating Helmet BH-3G &quot;Geonik&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_geonik_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Head protection = 60%\n%c[default]This insulating helmet was developed in one of the western research institutes specifically for joint use with US military isolating kits. Provides a high degree of protection against abnormal influences. It is used mainly by mercenaries and stalkers of the Monolith grouping.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_spectrum">
		<text>Insulating helmet ISH-12K &quot;Spectrum&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_spectrum_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Head protection = 60%\n%c[default]Insulating helmet of a new generation The Spectrum was initially created for joint use with scientific insulating suits such as Ecolog and Tiger. However, it was subsequently finalized and applied in combination with any stalker&apos;s overalls. It is characterized by increased thermal stability.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_fenix">
		<text>Helmet insulating CGP-2 &quot;Phoenix&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_fenix_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Head protection = 85%\n%c[default]The data on this super-perfect helmet have been kept secret for a long time and only relatively recently a few of its capabilities became known to the stalkers. It was developed on the basis of some Western samples in one of the secret scientific laboratories within the Zone. In its parameters it surpasses all existing analogues. Originally created for no less legendary scientific overalls with elements of exoskeleton TIK-1M &quot;Tiger&quot;, but in the aftermath of the development it became possible to use it together with suits TK-900, SSP-99 &quot;Ecolog&quot;, SS-99M and others. The only drawback is the high price.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_xm50">
		<text>Combined-arms American gas mask XM50</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_xm50_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Head protection = 45%\n%c[default]The main requirements for the combined service general gas mask XM 50 (JSGPM) are: protection against OB - 24 hours, lower resistance to breathing, less weight and volume. Combined-arms US gas mask XM 50 is one of the most promising PPE, currently undergoing field testing in the US Armed Forces. The optimal combination of LP material, the design of both valves and the filtering unit provided the new gas mask with ease of use, high physiological and hygienic parameters, reduced resistance to breathing and good ergonomics. To reduce the value of SD in the design of this sample, three technical solutions were used: an increase in the surface area of ??the filters, a decrease in the resistance of the filter layers, and resistance of the inlet and outlet valves. In small batches it is delivered to the limits of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_battle">
		<text>Sphere M12 helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_battle_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Head protection = 65%\n%c[default]An aluminum/titanium helmet with a cloth exterior that comes with pockets for additional steel armor pieces and an armor face mask. Sphere M12 is normally used as part of a combination that includes PSZ series Spetsnaz body armor. Quite popular in the Zone thanks to its respirator and built-in first generation night vision device, as well as providing the maximum head protection possible. Comes with electronics slots.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_hardhat">
		<text>Steel helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_hardhat_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Head protection = 30%\n%c[default]A desperately outdated steel army helmet without any additions. Provides no protection against anomalies or radiation, but can deflect bullets. This helmet was never particularly popular in the Zone, except for use in brief armed conflicts between factions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_protective">
		<text>Screen helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_protective_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Head protection = 15%\n%c[default]A light helmet with an airtight visor intended for protection from anomalies. Judging by the design, the helmet is made by the same Defense Research Institutes as the SEVA bodysuit. Its intended use may very well be in combination with military suits for operations in highly anomalous areas. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator">
		<text>Military gas mask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_descr">
		<text>Original Russian military gas mask. The SMC helmet mask is very comfortable, it has an intercom and a very effective windshield blower. It is intended for filtering radioactive dust and poisonous substances from the air. Widely used by both beginners and veterans of all factions due to their functional indispensability. It is not equipped with protection against bullets, debris and mechanical influences.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_tactic">
		<text>Tactical helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_tactic_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Head protection = 60%\n%c[default]A Western model of a tactical helmet that lacks camouflage. It is not known how it made its way into the Zone. The helmet is designed to provide a squad leader with strategic superiority over the enemy via its many scanners and satellite communications devices, which have not been installed in this particular helmet. Comes with multi-layered Kevlar protection and armored elements to protect electronic components. Includes a respirator and a first generation night vision device.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Armored Suit CHN-2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>PSZ-9d Duty Armor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_outfit_name">
		<text>PS5-M Universal Protection</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_name">
		<text>Bulat armored suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novice_outfit_name">
		<text>Leather trench coat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>SEVA bodysuit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specops_outfit_name">
		<text>Berill-5M armored suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_name">
		<text>Sunrise bodysuit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Freedom Guard bodysuit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_name">
		<text>Wind of Freedom bodysuit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novice_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 50 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 60 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 0\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 10%\n%c[default]Normal cloak of black leather. Special protection does not provide the carrier, except that it will not freeze at night and soften the bite of a blind dog. It is quite inconvenient, but, nevertheless, it is often used by bandits - probably, solely because of appearance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_description">
		<text>This DIY stalker bodysuit is a combination of a bodysuit of twin-layered rubberized cloth with plexiglass lining and built-in body armor. Despite the fact that the body armor is incapable of protecting the wearer from even pistol bullets, the suit enjoys great popularity due to its low cost and modification potential. Comes with built-in artifact containers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_description">
		<text>This lightweight stalker bodysuit is made by Freedom craftsmen. The suit&apos;s fabric is treated with Horizon, a special solution developed by the faction by trial and error to increase resistance to anomalies. Like the Sunrise suit, the Wind of Freedom comes with built-in body armor and artifact containers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>The stalker&apos;s overall with a reinforced body armor, produced by artisans of the Svoboda group, is a successful combination of combat and anomalous defenses. Built-in bulletproof vest from armored plates and stacked in several layers of Kevlar can stop the pistol bullet. To protect against abnormal influences, the fabric of the suit is impregnated with the composition &quot;Sovereign&quot;. Equipped with a container for artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_outfit_description">
		<text>This modern version of the Duty bodysuit is better suited for stalker recruits who are used to lightweight suits. Unlike the PSZ series, this suit provides good protection against anomalies while also being capable of stopping a pistol bullet. The suit cannot be modified with an artifact container, but may be upgraded with a combat support system instead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>The early model of the Dolgas overalls is the SS3-9 special-purpose armored vest, adapted for use in Zone conditions. It is able to protect against automatic bullets, but it is very cumbersome and almost does not provide protection from abnormal influences. Installation of containers for artifacts is not provided, but installation of various auxiliary systems is possible.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 71 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 81 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 20%\n%c[default]This suit, produced by one of Kiev&apos;s Defense Research Institutes, is a great alternative to homemade stalker suits. While its built-in body armor can only stop a pistol round, the anomaly and radiation protection system is second to none. Fully upgradeable and boasting two built-in artifact containers, this bodysuit is the equipment of choice for many experienced stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>Once used as standard by Clear Sky assault squads, after the faction’s elimination this armor serves as a reminder that even an excellent protective bodysuit cannot guarantee you safety this side of the perimeter. The armor is capable of stopping a pistol bullet, while the wearer is also well protected from anomalies. Comes with a built-in artifact container.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specops_outfit_description">
		<text>This item comprises military PS5 series body armor with beryllium sputter modified for use in the Zone. Designed for assault operations in highly radioactive areas, it is ineffective in areas of high anomalous activity. The suit makes its way to stalkers through the military, who exchange it for loot. Does not come with an artifact container.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_description">
		<text>This modern military armored suit is designed for assault operations in anomalous areas. Comprises a PSZ-12p heavy military armored suit, built-in compensation suit, and an anomalous protection bodysuit. The armor provides excellent protection against bullet and fragmentation damage, without greatly reducing the wearer&apos;s mobility. Does not come with an artifact container.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 90 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 100 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 0\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 70%\n%c[default]An experimental sample of a military exoskeleton. Was never mass-produced due to extraordinary cost and some design flaws. Despite this, it is in demand due to its ability to take on the weight of all carried equipment, and therefore small batches are made in underground facilities outside Ukraine. Comes with a built-in artifact container.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>SEVA bodysuit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>This bodysuit, intended for conducting research in the Zone, combines a closed-cycle respiratory module and an external isolation coating, resulting in excellent protection from anomalies. Due to poor protection from physical impact, the suit is not a good defense against bullet and fragmentation damage. Comes with a built-in artifact transportation container.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>This exoskeleton provides outstanding protection against bullet and fragmentation damage at the cost of mobility.  Vulnerable to armor-piercing rounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_military_outfit_description">
		<text>A military armored suit made for assault operations. Provides outstanding protection against full metal jacket rounds and fragmentation damage without reducing the wearer&apos;s mobility. Vulnerable to armor-piercing rounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_military_outfit_name">
		<text>Military armored suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_novice_stalker_outfit_name">
		<text>Leather jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_novice_bandit_outfit_name">
		<text>Bandit jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sniper_prikid_outfit_name">
		<text>Sniper camouflage gown</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sniper_prikid_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 38 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 58 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 1\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 20%\n%c[default]Camouflage camouflage kit for special units. It consists of a strong lightweight body armor and camouflage cape. It is convenient in real combat operations when it is necessary to merge with the terrain. In addition to masking, it provides protection for the fighter from bullet wounds. Adapted for use in the zone, contains a built-in container for artifacts. Most snipers use stalker groups.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="killer_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>The scientific suit of the mercenary PSSO-9KM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 68 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carry weight = 88 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 3\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 45%\n%c[default]Scientific overalls of a mercenary stalker. The samples are taken from the equipment of special forces of the Western armies intended for conducting combat operations on the territory with an unfavorable environment. Due to the special treatment of the fabric, the resistance of the armor is enhanced when the plates are physically displaced. The protective characteristics slightly outperform the army bulletproof vests of the series PSZ-7. Some coarse parts of the overalls are replaced by similar ones, but made of insulating materials, which increases the resistance to electrical influences.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="freedom_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>Scientific suit of Freedom PSZ-6Ms</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="freedom_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 68 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 82 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 35%\n%c[default]This armored suit was created by the craftsmen of the group &quot;Svoboda&quot; specially for scientific research in the Zone. The closed breathing system and special impregnation of materials provide excellent protection against radiation, chemically aggressive environment and harmful abnormal influences. However, the built-in body armor breaks even with a pistol bullet, so the suit is not suitable for active combat operations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>SSP4-9Md &quot;Universal Protection&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 62 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 71 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 35%\n%c[default]An excellent protective suit for the Zone, designed specifically for the grouping &quot;Debt&quot;. Dolgovtsy appreciate it for its excellent anti-anomalous qualities. In the composition: overalls SSP4-9d, a breathing system with a closed cycle, built-in system for suppressing the effect of abnormal fields. Provides quality protection against any abnormal effects of the zone. Protection from fragmentation and bullet wounds is low. Due to the special impregnation of materials, the heat resistance of the overalls was increased.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="recovery_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>Scientific Overalls of Insight SRP-10MR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="recovery_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 68 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carry weight = 88 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 4\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 55%\n%c[default]Scientific coveralls of the stalkers of the clan of Insight. The samples are taken from the equipment of special forces of the Western armies intended for conducting combat operations on the territory with an unfavorable environment. Approximately the same technology produced mercenary mercenaries, so in many respects these costumes are similar. However, in this version, a large emphasis was put on protection not only from abnormal influences, but also a good combat armored suit - quite light and not interfering with the movement. Therefore stalkers of Insight and choose this truly universal protection.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="clearsky_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>Scientific suit of the Clear Sky CHN-6MS</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="clearsky_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 68 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 82 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 4\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 45%\n%c[default]The armored suit CHN-6MS was designed by craftsmen from the &quot;Clear Sky&quot; group &quot;especially for scientific research in the Zone. However, the beginning war of factions did not allow the Clear Sky to establish a full-scale production of this wonderful combination zone, in connection with which only a limited party was released. The closed breathing system and special impregnation of materials provide excellent protection against radiation, chemically aggressive environment and harmful abnormal influences. Now this costume is used by the stalkers of the Dawn and Guardian clans.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="neutral_seva2_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>Insulating brooch &quot;Insights&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="neutral_seva2_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 62 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 70 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 3\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 35%\n%c[default]An excellent protective suit created by the craftsmen of the grouping. Enlightenment, which carries the more common name SEVA 2, is a modification of the second generation of SEVA, which has proved itself in the past. Appreciated by experienced stalkers involved in the collection of artifacts, rather than fighting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_heavy_bron_outfit_name">
		<text>Heavy armored suit of bandits TPK-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_heavy_bron_outfit_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 50 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 70 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 55%\n%c[default]Heavy armored suit of bandits. Used by some gangsters who know the Zone well, they themselves obtain artifacts, but sometimes even catch newcomers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Heavy armored suit of military TPK-12MZ &quot;Malachite&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="army_heavy_outfit_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 50 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 70 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 1\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 60%\n%c[default]The heavy armored combat suit of the military TPK-12MZ &quot;Malakhit&quot; was developed at one of the closed research institutes in the middle of the 2000s. It was he who became not a very good basis for creating an experimental model of the military exoskeleton of the first demonstration. But despite this a small batch of these armored suits was still released and used by the military to conduct special operations in the Zone. The last time the military in such suits saw during the storming of the Chernobyl nuclear power plant. After the failure of the storm, the stalkers began to pull off these suits and bring them to the merchants. Now some merchants are selling these suits because their characteristics are not bad enough, despite the significant flaws in the basic design.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="recovery_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Heavy armor suit of Insight TBP-3X &quot;Savior&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="recovery_heavy_outfit_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carry weight = 55 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 70 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 4\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 60%\n%c[default]Heavy armored suit of the group Enlightenment was not accidentally received his appointment. &quot;Savior&quot; really is a very high-quality combat armored suit of a new generation with high protective indicators. Delivered to the Zone in small batches for the needs of the Enlightenment clan, is the standard equipment of the elite combat groups of the group.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Heavy armor suit of ZHP-11GC &quot;Elliptor&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_heavy_outfit_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 60 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 75 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 1\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 65%\n%c[default]Heavy armored suit of nagmeniki. Costume of veterans of mercenaries. Used by groups of mercenary veterans in particularly difficult tasks. The manufacturer is unknown, but it is non-exclusive that their production was based on some kind of a sub-variant of the armored suit TPK-12MZ &quot;Malachite&quot;.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Heavy armored suit of Freedom TBS-4 &quot;Buran&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_heavy_outfit_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 90 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 100 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 3\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 80%\n%c[default]The heavy armored suit of Liberty TBS-4 &quot;Buran&quot; is a military analogue &quot;Malachite&quot; brought to mind. Used by veterans and some masters of the group &quot;Freedom&quot;, along with their equally popular exoskeleton. This suit protects well from anomalies and bullets, but its price is high.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_heavy_bron_outfit_name">
		<text>Heavy armored suit Dolga TDB-1M &quot;Universal&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_heavy_bron_outfit_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 90 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 100 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 80%\n%c[default]Heavy armored suit Duty as well as his Freedom analogue was created from the army &quot;Malachite&quot;. Costume of veterans and masters of the grouping. It was done more to destroy mutants, so it protects them better than it does anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="neutral_heavy_bron_outfit_name">
		<text>Heavy armored suit TPK-12MSS &quot;Neutrite&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="neutral_heavy_bron_outfit_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carry weight = 55 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 65 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 4\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 55%\n%c[default] The prefabricated short name &quot;Neutritus&quot;, developed by free stalkers, was created back in the time of the famous war of clans when a good combat armored vehicle solved a lot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Heavy armor suit of Monolith ZHP-12C &quot;Sentinel&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_heavy_outfit_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 60 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 65 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 4\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 65%\n%c[default]This version of a heavy armored suit was created on the special order of Monolith as a lightweight version of their almost perfect exoskeleton. In many respects it surpasses all its analogues.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="clearsky_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Heavy armored suit of the Clear Sky CHN-7TB &quot;Guard&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="clearsky_heavy_outfit_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carry weight = 55 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 70 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 4\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 60%\n%c[default] CHN-7TB &quot;Guardian&quot; is almost the last development of the well-known throughout the Clan Zone &quot;&quot; Clear Sky &quot;&quot;. By the end of the clan war, when the grouping was practically destroyed, only 10 units of this armored suit were released. Most of them were captured by maraders and free stalkers, but two or three samples were saved. Later, their production was able to resume and put into service the clans of receivers of the Clear Sky - Dawn and Guardian.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecolog_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton TIK-1M &quot;Crab&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecolog_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 100 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 110 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 4\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 98%\n%c[default]Heavy insulating complex - U1-M &quot;Crab&quot;, is designed for complex protection from the aggressive environment, also has a simplified exoskeleton. The most optimal protection for the study of anomalies. Developed by unique technologies in single copies. It is almost impossible to get it because of the high price.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecoarmy_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Experimental exoskeleton &quot;Lizard&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecoarmy_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 90 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 130 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 5\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 98%\n%c[default]This experimental sample of the military exoskeleton is a deep modification of the scientific exoskeleton Crab, designed for complex protection against any damaging impact factors. The most optimal protection is both in the study of anomalies, and in the case of necessity of conducting military operations. Developed by the newest unique nanotechnology. A single drawback is a high price.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_recovery_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton Insights</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_recovery_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 90 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 110 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 3\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 85%\n%c[default]This sample is a modification of the army exoskeleton of the second generation developed specially for the order of the gaining strength of the clan &quot;Insight&quot;. High combat performance of this exoskeleton makes it an unsurpassed option of high-tech and high-quality protection.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_rs_1b_outfit_name">
		<text>Light suit RS-1B</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rs_1b_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 40 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 57 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 15%\n%c[default] Light armored suit RS-1b was developed by Dawn on the basis of the existing costume of the grouping &quot;Clear Sky&quot; CHN-1. By combat and other parameters, these costumes are almost identical. Gives protection from abnormal influences weak. Is able to stop the pistol bullet. It is not intended for serious expeditions into the interior of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rs_2_outfit_name">
		<text>Armored Suit PZ-2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rs_2_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 50 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 66 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 35%\n%c[default]Regular armored suit of the group Enlightenment. Equipped with a reinforced armor, capable of withstanding the hit of bullets at flight. In all respects it is better than PZ-1b, but still its protection is not so good as to consider this armored suit a reference one. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rs_3b_outfit_name">
		<text>Armored Suit PZ-3B</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rs_3b_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 50 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 80 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 55%\n%c[default]Heavy armored suit of the Dawn. Such uniforms are completed by special units of the clan. Excellent protection against anomalies and other effects. In many respects it is an analogue of the famous Chernihnebovskiy ChN-3a.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_ecolog_kih7_outfit_name">
		<text>Isolation kit FIR-7M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecolog_kih7_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 70 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 80 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 35%\n%c[default]Appointment Costume insulating FIR-7M is designed to protect against the effects of liquid and gaseous corrosive chemicals. Technical description The suit consists of a tight overall with a hood, the front part of which is glued panoramic glass. The trousers of the jumpsuit end in infrequent noses of rubberized material. The suit of FIR-7M is used in combination with compressed air devices such as AIR-98MI-20, ASV, AVK, etc., as well as with KIP-9 insulating gas mask. The gas mask is placed in the sub-space. Technical characteristics. Time of protective action: for gaseous chemical action not less than 60 minutes, for liquid chemical treatment - not less than 15 minutes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecolog_burn_outfit_name">
		<text>Costume heat-reflecting TK-900</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecolog_burn_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 78 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carry weight = 88 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 3\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 50%\n%c[default]The time of protective action at an ambient temperature of 200 ° C is 960 s, the duration of contact with an open flame is 45 s, the temperature interval in which the use of the kit is allowed is from -40 ° C to + 900 ° C. Package: outer shell with a porthole and a compartment for the breathing apparatus, a set of shoes, a thermal insulating overall with a helmet and a helmet &quot;Phoenix&quot;, mittens outer, mittens heat-insulating.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecolog_hrom_outfit_name">
		<text>Overalls isolating experimental EKI-1 &quot;Chromium&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecolog_hrom_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 78 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carry weight = 88 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 4\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 50%\n%c[default]One of the latest experimental developments of scientists produced in the exclusion zone. Chromium overalls represent first-class protection against all known abnormal effects, and teksthe provides a high level of resistance to mechanical damage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_light_outfit_name">
		<text>Light armored suit CHN-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_light_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 57 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 67 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 15%\n%c[default]Lightweight armored suit was standard equipment of stalkers of the clan &quot;Clear Sky&quot;. For sewing, the fabric treated with Horizon composition was used, which significantly increases the protective properties in conditions of abnormal activity. Equipped with an integrated body armor and containers for artifacts. Now it is used by the clans of the heirs of the Pure Sky - the Dawn and the Guardian.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="recovery_light_outfit_name">
		<text>Light Suit Enlightenment PZ-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="recovery_light_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 57 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 67 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 15%\n%c[default]The most lightweight costume produced for the Stalker clan of Insight. For its basis was taken the most popular costume among this class - Pure-Nebov CHN-1. However, after the improvements, PZ-1 began to surpass its analogue in its parameters</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_battle_outfit_name">
		<text>Heavy armored car &quot;Freedom&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_battle_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 74 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 84 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 4\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 64%\n%c[default]Combat armored suit of the group &quot;Freedom&quot; developed on the basis of its debt analog. Used by special assault units of the grouping. The main difference from the debt option is the installation of four containers for artifacts in addition to various auxiliary systems.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="neutral_nanos_outfit_name">
		<text>Nano Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="neutral_nanos_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 100 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 110 kg\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 98%\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Masking = 10%\n%c[default]Incredible exoskeleton characteristics. Such a suit is the dream of any stalker. With such parameters, Nano is suitable for all conditions of the zone. But the rarity of this costume makes it the most expensive in the Zone, in addition, almost none of the mechanics of the Zone can work with the costume materials, because it was created by scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nano_outfit_name">
		<text>Nano suit &quot;Black Tiger&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nano_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 75 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 85 kg\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 50%\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Masking = 10%\n%c[default]This is a very rare costume, possibly created in the X8 lab. This is the first prototype of the Nano Suit, based on the PSZ-9D suit, it is an amazing protective suit for the Zone, because it combines excellent protection from anomaly, bulletproof qualities and can restore your health by getting damaged. Of course, he concedes to his &quot;brother&quot; Nano Exoskelet, but still it is the dream of many stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_nanos_outfit_name">
		<text>Nano Exoskeleton &quot;Debt&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rassvet_nanos_outfit_name">
		<text>Nano Exoskeleton &quot;Dawn&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="free_nanos_outfit_name">
		<text>Nano Exoskelet &quot;Freedom&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dfr_nanos_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]All characteristics coincide with the characteristics of Nano Exoskeleton, after it appeared, &quot;Duty&quot;, &quot;Freedom&quot; and &quot;Guardian&quot; copied it and made similar ones, excluding the helmet, because the nano-exoskeleton filters could not be copied.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_nevidim_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Invisible&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_nevidim_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 100 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 110 kg\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 98%\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default][Default] Under the influence of electromagnetic properties of artifacts, the material of this exoskeleton acquired the ability to refract light rays in such a way that the material itself is practically invisible. At the same time, he did not lose his qualities, but also acquired negative properties. When wearing a suit, the body is exposed to the radiation background of the costume itself and an unquenchable hunger caused by changes at the molecular level.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_t_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Titan&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_t_description">
		<text>%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Masking = 10%\n%c[default]Equipped with titanium and chrome plates, as well as Kevlar inserts, this exoskeleton is the best protection against enemy firearms.</text>
  	</string>
	<string id="stalker_heavy_1_name">
		<text>Armored Suit &quot;Sunrise&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_heavy_1_description">
 		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 75 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 85 kg\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 60%\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default][Default] Cardan&apos;s version of the heavy armored jumpsuit of ITChPR-3a stalker &quot;Sunrise.&quot; The basis was the components of various costumes and prototype exoskeleton, available in the Zone. The main ones were the armor base of exoskelette, army armored vests with berylium spraying, built-in aluminum-titanium helmet with armored cover and an anomalous coveralls. Despite the manual assembly provides excellent protection from bullets and shrapnel and at the same time is convenient, almost does not limit the mobility of the carrier. Equipped with 2 containers for artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="soldier_izol_1_outfit_name">
		<text>Insulating armored suit &quot;Gagarin&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="soldier_izol_1_outfit_description">
 		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 57.5 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 67.5 kg\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 60%\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default][Default] Army insulating armored suit &quot;GAGARIN&quot;, created to conduct assault operations in the extreme conditions of the Zone. It is supplied with an external insulating coating and a closed-cycle breathing system, the main element of which is the modification of the gas mask GP-17. Thanks to such a solution, it perfectly protects against abnormal influences. The basis of armor protection is the modification of the Fort Redoubt T7 vests, which provides excellent protection against shell shells and debris, while not reducing the owner&apos;s mobility. Despite the excellent protective properties from the point of view of stalkers, it has the following disadvantages: small weight loss and lack of built-in containers for artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_voen_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton of the Military Poppy-2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_voen_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 200 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 210 kg\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Masking = 10%\n%c[default]Popularly known as a tractor - this is the second prototype military exoskeleton, tested in the conditions of the Zone. In the batch production did not go due to some flaws in the design. Despite this, it is in demand and is therefore secretly released in small batches outside of Ukraine. The costume was created as an alternative to the well-proven Scatu 9M zone in the field. A very powerful exoskeleton has an excellent dynamic armor and additional titanium insertions on the torso and back, a colossal load-carrying capacity, thanks to the new-generation servo drives, PNV-3rd generation, but even Zonovskie exoskeletons surpass this in many ways.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="killer_exoskeleton_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton Mercenary Mak-2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_exoskeleton_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 200 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 210 kg\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Masking = 15%\n%c[default]Supposedly got to the Zone from secret laboratories, when he was cut out by mercenaries. The production uses armor protection of the 6th degree, which gives him superiority over the ordinary exoskeleton. The focus is on mobility, which is why containers for artifacts have been removed, but it&apos;s worth it, not only are the servo drives built on artifacts help raise 80 kg of extra weight, they also remove all tension, run in such an exoskeleton you will not be tired , But the abnormal stability is very low, because mercenaries do not climb anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_heavybron_outfit_name">
		<text>Monolith &quot;Tramp&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_heavybron_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 70 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 80 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 1\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 30%\n%c[default]The stalker&apos;s overall with a reinforced body armor, produced by the artisans of the &quot;Monolith&quot; group, is a successful combination of combat and anomalous defenses. Built-in bulletproof vest from armored plates and stacked in several layers of Kevlar can stop the pistol bullet. To protect against abnormal influences, the fabric of the suit is impregnated with the composition &quot;Sovereign&quot;. Equipped with a container for artifacts. It is a standard outfit of Monolith stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_cs_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Armorpiece CHN-3a</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_dolg_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>PSZ-9d armor &quot;Duty&quot; (Worn)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_dolg_outfit_name">
		<text>PS5-M Universal Protection</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_military_outfit_name">
		<text>Bulat armored suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_novice_outfit_name">
		<text>Leather trench coat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>SEVA bodysuit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_specops_outfit_name">
		<text>Berill-5M armored suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_stalker_outfit_name">
		<text>Sunrise bodysuit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_svoboda_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Freedom Guard bodysuit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_svoboda_light_outfit_name">
		<text>Wind of Freedom bodysuit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_heavy_stalker_outfit_name">
		<text>Protective suit &quot;Master&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_bandit_raid_outfit_name">
		<text>Armored suit &quot;Raider&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_svoboda_army_outfit_name">
		<text>Armored suit &quot;Commander&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_bandit_prikid_outfit_name">
		<text>S12 bandit jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_csky_specnaz_outfit_name">
		<text>Armorpiece CHN-3a</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_ecolog_regular_outfit_name">
		<text>SSP-99 Ecologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_ecolog_military_outfit_name">
		<text>SS-99M protective suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_killer_outfit_name">
		<text>Merc suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_csky_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Dawn&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_freedom_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Freedom&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_monolit_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Monolith&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_dolg_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Duty&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_army_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Military&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_bandit_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Bandit&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reduce_killer_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Mercenary&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_spectacles">
		<text>Degterev&apos;s glasses</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_spectacles_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Head protection = 0%\n%c[default]Points with integrated 3rd Generation PNV.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_piranhas">
		<text>Helmet &quot;Pure Breath&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_piranhas_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Head protection = 23%\n%c[default]A light helmet with an airtight visor intended for protection from anomalies. Judging by the design, the helmet is made by the same Defense Research Institutes as the SEVA bodysuit. Its intended use may very well be in combination with military suits for operations in highly anomalous areas. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_mercenary">
		<text>American gas mask M40</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_mercenary_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Head protection = 38%\n%c[default]M40 medium-defensive gas mask with hermetic visor, designed to protect the face from some abnormal influences. Safely protects against poisonous and many chemical hazardous substances, radioactive dust and bacterial agents. Respect among stalkers, mainly used by members of the group &quot;Mercenaries&quot;.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_novice_stalker_outfit_name">
		<text>Leather jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_novice_stalker_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 50 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 60 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 0\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 5%\n%c[default]An ordinary thick jacket, one of the many. It slightly increases bullet and splinter protection. It does not protect from anomalies and other affects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_novice_bandit_outfit_name">
		<text>Bandit jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_novice_bandit_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 50 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 60 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 0\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 7%\n%c[default]Traditional bandit clothing is a leather jacket with woven armor elements. Gives protection, extremely inadequate in the harsh conditions of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_killer_outfit_name">
		<text>Merc suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_killer_outfit_description">
		<text>Stalker overalls from the group &quot;Mercenaries&quot;. As a basis samples of equipment of special forces of the western armies are taken. Due to the special treatment of the fabric, the resistance of the armor is enhanced when the plates are physically displaced. The protective characteristics slightly outperform the army bulletproof vests of the series PSZ-7.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecolog_regular_outfit_name">
		<text>SSP-99 Ecologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecolog_regular_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 70 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 80 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 3\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 35%\n%c[default]A SSP-99 chemical protection suit specially designed for the Zone conditions. It is used by scientific expeditions and the eco-stalkers who cooperate with them. It has an integrated air-filtering and air-conditioning system. It is heat and electricity resistant, provides good protection from radiation and biological anomalies. It is resistant to chemically aggressive environments. It is not designed for combat, so it provides neither bullet, nor splinter protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecolog_military_outfit_name">
		<text>SS-99M protective suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ecolog_military_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 78 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carry weight = 88 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 3\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 50%\n%c[default]High quality modified SSP-99 suit. It provides increased body protection from bullet and splinter damage. It is designed for the guards working with scientific expeditions. It provides good protection from radiation and biological anomalies. It is resistant to chemically aggressive environments and other effects dangerous to the body.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_monolith_outfit_name">
		<text>Armored suit &quot;Prophet&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_monolith_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 77 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 87 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 4\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 40%\n%c[default]The overall of the stalker of the group &quot;Monolith&quot;, the manufacturer is unknown. Excellent protection against small arms of medium level. The level of protection against abnormal activity is provided perfectly. Contains a modernized container for artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_heavy_stalker_outfit_name">
		<text>Protective suit &quot;Master&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_heavy_stalker_outfit_description">
		<text>This DIY stalker bodysuit is a combination of a bodysuit of twin-layered rubberized cloth with plexiglass lining and built-in body armor. Despite the fact that the body armor is incapable of protecting the wearer from even pistol bullets, the suit enjoys great popularity due to its low cost and modification potential. Comes with built-in artifact containers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandit_raid_outfit_name">
		<text>Armored suit &quot;Raider&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandit_raid_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 72 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 82 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 0\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 40%\n%c[default]This armored suit was designed by bandits. Bandit engineers made it look like Bulat&apos;s armored suit, but they did not keep similar characteristics, because this prototype provides less protection. It is mainly used for conducting raider operations. It is not equipped with containers for artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_svoboda_army_outfit_name">
		<text>Armored suit &quot;Commander&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_svoboda_army_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 76 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 86 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 55%\n%c[default]The overalls of the military personnel of the group &quot;Svoboda&quot;, produced by artisans of this group, are a successful combination of combat and anomalous defenses. Built-in bulletproof vest from armored plates and stacked in several layers of Kevlar can stop the pistol bullet. To protect against abnormal influences, the fabric of the suit is impregnated with the composition &quot;Sovereign&quot;. Equipped with a container for artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dolg_army_outfit_name">
		<text>Commander&apos;s Dagger&apos;s Battlegear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dolg_army_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 76 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 86 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 55%\n%c[default]The overalls of the leading military personnel of the group &quot;DOLG&quot;, produced by artisans of this group, are a successful combination of combat and anomalous defenses. Built-in bulletproof vest from armored plates and stacked in several layers of Kevlar can stop the pistol bullet. To protect against abnormal influences, the fabric of the suit is impregnated with the composition &quot;Sovereign&quot;. Equipped with a container for artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandit_prikid_outfit_name">
		<text>S12 bandit jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandit_prikid_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 50 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 60 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 0\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 5%\n%c[default]The traditional clothing of a scoundrel is a leather jacket with stitched armor elements. Gives protection, extremely inadequate in the harsh conditions of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_csky_specnaz_outfit_name">
		<text>Armorpiece CHN-3a</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_csky_specnaz_outfit_description">
		<text>Once it was a regular equipment of special forces of the &quot;Clear Sky&quot;. This protective suit is able not only to stop the pistol bullet, but also provides good protection against abnormal influences. Equipped with additional containers for artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_csky_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton of &quot;Clear Sky&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_csky_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 150 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 160 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 80%\n%c[default]Modernization of the customary exoskeleton was created with the participation of artisans from the &quot;Pure Sky&quot; grouping. &quot; The use of lighter materials made it possible to reduce the weight of the costume itself, and also to increase the maximum tolerated weight. Thanks to the new system of movement, it was possible to achieve the possibility of running. Unfortunately in the wide production and did not hit because of the death of the group.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rs_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Insights&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rs_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 150 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 160 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 2\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 80%\n%c[default]Modernization of the usual exoskeleton. Created with the participation of artisans from the group &quot;Insight&quot; on the basis of the existing prototype of the exoskeleton of the group &quot;Clear Sky&quot;. The use of lighter materials made it possible to reduce the weight of the costume itself, and also to increase the maximum tolerated weight. Thanks to the new system of movement, it was possible to achieve the possibility of running.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_freedom_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Freedom&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_freedom_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 100 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 110 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 3\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 80%\n%c[default]Modernization of the usual exoskeleton. Created with the participation of artisans from the group &quot;Freedom&quot;. The use of lighter materials made it possible to reduce the weight of the suit itself. Thanks to the new system of movement, it was possible to achieve the possibility of running. Also, a special breathing system has been added, which allows to provide the owner with excellent endurance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dolg_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Duty&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dolg_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 90 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 100 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 1\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 90%\n%c[default]Modernization of the usual exoskeleton. Created with the participation of artisans from the group &quot;Debt&quot;. The use of lighter materials made it possible to reduce the weight of the suit itself. Thanks to the new system of movement, it was possible to achieve the possibility of running. Added additional Kevlar plates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_monolit_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Monolith&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_monolit_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 110 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 120 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 3\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 85%\n%c[default]Modernization of the usual exoskeleton. Created with the participation of artisans from the group &quot;Monolith&quot;. The use of lighter materials made it possible to reduce the weight of the suit itself. Thanks to the new system of movement, it was possible to achieve the possibility of running. Additional containers for artifacts are also installed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandit_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Bandit&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandit_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 80 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 90 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 0\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 60%\n%c[default]Modernization of the usual exoskeleton. Created with the participation of artisans from the bandits &quot;Bandits&quot;. The use of lighter materials made it possible to reduce the weight of the suit itself. Thanks to the new system of movement, it was possible to achieve the possibility of running.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_army_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Military&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_army_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carrying weight = 90 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 100 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 1\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 98%\n%c[default]Modernization of the usual exoskeleton. Created with the participation of artisans from the group &quot;Military&quot;. The use of lighter materials made it possible to reduce the weight of the suit itself. Thanks to the new system of movement, it was possible to achieve the possibility of running. Introduced additional Kevlar plates of a new generation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_killer_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton &quot;Mercenary&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_killer_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>%c[default]Transfer characteristics:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Min. Carry weight = 88 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Max. Carrying weight = 98 kg\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Containers for artifacts = 1\n%c[default]Protection features:\n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default]Bullet resistance = 75%\n%c[default]Modernization of the usual exoskeleton. Created with the participation of artisans from the group &quot;Mercenaries&quot;. The use of lighter materials made it possible to reduce the weight of the suit itself. Thanks to the new system of movement, it was possible to achieve the possibility of running.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
