<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
    
<string id="st_x27_docs1_descr">
    <text>May 17, 2007. Archive. Top Secret. Notification for the Deputy of Laboratory X-series, Branch 27 from Hofmanov A.G. According to the directive of the Head of the Third Section of the AOZT "Chernobyl Anomalous Zone", I inform you: from August 1, 2007, the laboratory will transition to a 24-hour work schedule with 3 shifts. The laboratory will be divided into 3 sections by floors. Floor I: technical control department; Floor II: synthesis of the drug under the code name ALD-95 and its derivatives; Floor III: transportation of finished products. All employees who have undergone training and received corresponding security clearances of categories A, B, C must report to their curator to receive work instructions.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs1_name">
    <text>Archive Document</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs2_descr">
    <text>April 23, 2009. Order IV-4231/a. Due to the need to improve the quality of produced drugs, a decision has been made to partially unseal the laboratory complex X-27. I order the redistribution of space on the third floor of the complex for laboratory needs, specifically: 1. Construct isolated rooms for storing biomaterials. 2. Relocate and connect the necessary equipment to the underground complex. 3. Create an archive for storing current information. Approved: Inaev V. N.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs2_name">
    <text>Order</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs3_descr">
    <text>Experiment log. It contains descriptions of various experiments on "unthinking with apathy" (most likely referring to zombies or zombified subjects). According to the latest entries, the scientists were testing a drug that reduces the effects of chemical burns on the body.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs3_name">
    <text>Experiment Journal</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs4_descr">
    <text>Laboratory maps. Inside, only 2 pages remain, schematically showing the plans of laboratories X-27 and X-18.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs4_name">
    <text>Old Folder</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs5_descr">
    <text>A hard drive from one of the computers of Laboratory X-27. It may contain useful information.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_docs5_name">
    <text>Hard Drive</text>
</string>
<string id="st_x27_inaev_pda_descr">
    <text>Audio Recording No. 534: The negligence of the leadership towards our section is simply disheartening. I have been working in this laboratory for the fourth year now, but since the change of management, everything has been getting worse and worse. Unknown individuals broke into the laboratory, destroyed and looted the sealed floors, and it seems they will soon reach our wing as well. Now, instead of providing suitable transport, they decided that we should walk and carry valuable samples and papers ourselves. We won’t even manage to cover a few kilometers with such heavy loads, not to mention how dangerous it is in the Chernobyl Zone lately. Furthermore, they’ve assigned some clowns from a group called "Monolith" to us, and I don’t feel safe with them at all, quite the opposite. There’s suspicion that they’re using our drugs on themselves, even though that is strictly prohibited.\n\nIt’s just outrageous, I don’t have enough words to express all my thoughts in this recording. I’m going now to demand an explanation. I will not tolerate such treatment, neither towards myself nor my subordinates.</text>
</string>

	
</string_table>
