<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>


	<!-- patogen -->
	<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_1_name">
	<text>Business Proposal</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_1_text">
	<text>Patagenych needs the artifact %s. Just like that, no extra words or questions. A real businessman!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_1_about">
	<text>I'm interested in artifacts. Here's the deal: I give you a lead on a specific artifact, you bring it, and you get a reward. Both sides are happy. So, what do you think?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>My clients are interested in artifacts. Often these are just "bright minds" who’ve been unlucky with contacts and are in possession of scientific knowledge in the Zone. So here's the deal: I give you a lead on a specific artifact, you bring it, and you get a reward. Both sides are happy. So, I need the artifact %s. I'll be waiting for it here, along with your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Good job, my friend. Here’s your bonus.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_2_name">
	<text>Dirty Work</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_2_text">
	<text>Patagenych gave me a dirty job - find and eliminate a stalker who managed to piss someone off.\n\nPatagenych has provided all the necessary information on the PDA. Time to get to work. Poor guy’s out of luck...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_2_about">
	<text>Sometimes stalkers come to me when they've pissed someone off, or caused trouble, and I look for people willing to help them with this dirty job so they don’t end up with problems later. Consider me the middleman.\nI currently have a few elimination targets in the works. Usually, it’s a stalker who’s betrayed or ordered the death of their friends, but sometimes it’s hired hits on people from other factions. It’s dirty work, but someone has to do it, especially when the reward’s worth it. So, what do you say? I’ll send the details to your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_2_finish">
	<text>Thanks, stalker. Here’s your payment, but don’t get too carried away with the killing. Competition isn’t good for mercenaries either. Heh-heh...</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_3_name">
	<text>Pseudobugs and Pseudomice</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_3_text">
	<text>There’s a joke among stalkers: “A stalker planted a pseudoradish. It grew into a giant pseudoradish! The stalker took a grenade launcher and went to harvest it. He probably would’ve succeeded, if only the pseudobugs and pseudomice hadn’t attacked.” It sounds funny, but sometimes these bugs and mice can really be a pain in the neck. It even gets to the point where you can’t take ten steps from the camp without being attacked by some pseudomonster.\nThat’s why Patagenych suggested we mix business with pleasure - make some money by cleaning up the mutant infestation around the area. It’s the right thing to do, since they’re multiplying here... And the trophies definitely won’t be unnecessary.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_3_about">
	<text>Tell me, have you seen any mutants on your way here? The Duty guys recently patrolled the area, but new stalkers reported seeing either dogs or something else near the outer borders of the camp. If they’re not joking, these creatures pose a big threat to the stalkers in the camp and anyone heading here. Not to mention that a lack of clients hurts business. So, here’s the deal: I’m willing to pay well for mutant extermination, and maybe even throw in something extra. The main thing is to leave no trace of them. Here are the approximate coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_3_finish">
	<text>Good work. Here’s your hard-earned payment.</text>
</string>

<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
<!-- New Tasks -->

<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_4_name">
	<text>Unusual Business</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_4_text">
	<text>As the saying goes, the rich have their quirks. One such client, it seems, approached Patagenych and asked him to find a trophy - “%s”...\nPatagenych, in turn, promised a good payment for delivering the trophy to him so that he could forward it to the client.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_4_about">
	<text>You see, I’m not only a busy person, but also extremely generous to those who wish to help me solve my problems. And right now, I have an urgent order. Interested?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_4_fetch_about">
	<text>So here’s the deal: one of my clients, who’s also a great jeweler specializing in animal trophies, wants one such trophy - %s. He’s willing to pay me a good sum for the delivery. I, in turn, am willing to pay you for delivering it to me first. Understand what I mean, right? Make sure the mutant parts with its possession and bring it to me. I won’t skimp on the payment.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_4_fetch_finish">
	<text>Well done! Here’s your hard-earned payment.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_5_name">
	<text>Cache Robber</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_5_text">
	<text>What was yours will soon be ours. Patagenych asked me to steal important documents and deliver them to him.\nHe sent the coordinates of their location to my PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_5_about">
	<text>I’ve been told about a stash containing some very interesting documents. I have no idea who owned it or where they are now, but I’ll reward anyone who can manage to get those documents and make them magically appear on this bar counter. Got it? I’ll send you the last known coordinates of the stash on your PDA. I don’t think this is a trap because setting me up is not something you’d want to do—unlike Sidrovich, I don’t lose deals easily on the Cordone.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_task_5_finish">
	<text>Now that’s what I like to see. Great work, stalker.</text>
</string>


	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Clear Mutants -->

<string id="esc_wolf_task_1_name">
    <text>Cleaner</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_task_1_text">
    <text>Leaving mutants unchecked is not a good idea. You need to find their lair and clean it out. This won't wipe them out completely, but it will significantly reduce their population.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_task_1_about">
    <text>Shh... Quiet! Hey, did you hear that?
    \nMore mutants have come. It sends chills down my spine...\n
    \nThey come here often, but it's not clear where they are coming from. Maybe from the whole Zone... It's dangerous to leave them unchecked.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_task_1_finish">
    <text>Done clearing out the little creatures? That's great. You've done a good deed, my friend! Here, take this from Dog!</text>
</string>

<!-- FIND ARTEFACT FOR BEARD TASK -->
<string id="esc_wolf_task_2_name">
    <text>Artifact Hunter</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_task_2_text">
    <text>When it comes to artifact orders, Dog is known for working only with his trusted people. However, sometimes even they fail to find anything in time.\n
    \nIn such cases, Dog turns to ordinary stalkers, so he can fulfill the order on time, and the stalkers can make some money.\nThe trader is willing to pay well for the artifact %s.\n
    \nYou need to find this artifact as soon as possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_task_2_about">
    <text>I usually don't buy artifacts from stalkers, but there's an urgent order, and I wouldn't want to let the client down. Can you get one for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_task_2_fetch_about">
    <text>There’s a job... I usually rely on my people when it comes to hunting artifacts, not buying them from others. I've seen all kinds of things here...\nHowever, my guys haven't found anything yet, and I have an urgent order. The client is good, trusted. So, I wouldn’t want us both to worry about this situation. Do you know the rule I follow? If the client is calm, I don't have to worry. It’s simple.\n
    \nSo, listen, I'm looking for the artifact %s. Maybe you've heard of it, or even seen it, but it doesn't matter. If you find it, I'll pay you well.\nWhat do you say? Can you get it for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_task_2_fetch_finish">
    <text>Well, stalker, you’ve earned it! You've helped Dog, and I thank you for that.</text>
</string>

<!-- ASSASSINATION FOR BEARD TASK -->
<string id="esc_wolf_task_3_name">
    <text>If a Friend Turns Suddenly...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_task_3_text">
    <text>One of the stalkers who recently joined the military decided to use the trust of his fellow stalkers to coldly kill them in the most treacherous way, either for his own benefit or simply out of spite. Either way, Dog managed to track down the whereabouts of the brother-killer through Skidan, who deserves no forgiveness for his actions. Dog has asked for revenge for all the comrades this stalker betrayed. As they say, you reap what you sow.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_task_3_about">
    <text>We have a small problem here. There was a good stalker among us, one of the many in "Skadovsk." But one gray day, military guys showed up and, guess what? They made him an enticing offer, the results of which were unknown to us. Until recently.\nYou see, just recently, we started finding dead stalkers – no signals of distress or anything like that. They were either found with their throats slit or with a 9mm hole in their skulls. What's strange is that no one heard any gunfire. You know, we’ve had a case of missing stalkers before – lost some good guys! So this time I didn't wait around, and through my channels, I uncovered the recent events and rumors. And guess what? We found the killer! And the best part? It was the same brother-stalker I told you about.\nYou see, the offer from the military appealed to him greatly, but taking a punch from his own comrades? He wasn't keen on that. So he decided to stick a knife in the back of his friends. They didn't agree with his decision, but to kill them? That’s too much. But now, our ex-stalker-turned-soldier clearly wasn't against betraying them: he waited for the right moment and - bam - no more stalkers with us.\n\nSo, I contacted Sidorovich about this - he helped me find out where this traitor is now. There’s no question here, brother, he could have left peacefully, but he chose to start his new life with the betrayal of his loyal friends. Such people have no place among us, so you know what needs to be done.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_task_3_finish">
    <text>Did you get your revenge for the guys? Thanks a lot, buddy. This place is awful, the Zone. A brother ready to betray another for personal gain or out of spite... What times we're living in... Anyway, here's your reward for delivering justice.</text>
</string>


<!-- kusto -->
	<string id="esc_trader_kusto_task_1_name">
    <text>Field of Wonders</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trader_kusto_task_1_text">
    <text>Trader Kusto is offering an exchange: some decent equipment, according to him, in exchange for a specific artifact. He asked to find and deliver the artifact %s to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trader_kusto_task_1_about">
    <text>Don't you want to get some decent gear in exchange for an artifact?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trader_kusto_task_1_fetch_about">
    <text>Don't you want to get some good gear while hunting for rare artifacts? I can offer you such equipment for one artifact - it's called %s.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trader_kusto_task_1_fetch_finish">
    <text>Great job, stalker. Here you go.</text>
</string>



</string_table>
