<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>


	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- Decimate the Enemy Task -->
	
<string id="bar_npc_voronin_task_1_name">
	<text>Between the Hammer and the Anvil</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_voronin_task_1_text">
	<text>Captain Ivantsov wants to thin out the enemy ranks and also show everyone else what happens when the "Duty" or defenseless stalkers are attacked from behind.\n\n"%s" will serve as the evidence that must be provided to Ivantsov.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_voronin_task_1_about">
	<text>Listen, kid, we aim to destroy the Zone, but we don’t turn our backs on ordinary stalkers when scum attacks them... And our enemies will take advantage of our desire to protect defenseless stalkers. Filthy criminals, anarchists, and fanatics driven by greed, ignorance, or lies...\nEven though the Zone remains our main threat, and we don’t want to ignite a large-scale conflict, show our enemies what kind of retribution awaits them for their cowardly attacks.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_voronin_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>Listen, kid, we aim to destroy the Zone, but we don’t turn our backs on ordinary stalkers when scum attacks them... And our enemies will take advantage of our desire to protect defenseless stalkers. Filthy criminals, anarchists, and fanatics driven by greed, ignorance, or lies...\nEven though the Zone remains our main threat, and we don’t want to ignite a large-scale conflict, show our enemies what kind of retribution awaits them for their cowardly attacks. Eliminate them. "%s" will serve as the evidence.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_voronin_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Great job. Protecting the world and people from the Zone and scum is our common goal.\n\nThis will serve as a lesson to the other cowards. Well, if not, as they say, repetition is the mother of learning.</text>
</string>

<!-- Petrenko (Duty Trader) Defend Rostok Task -->

<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_1_name">
	<text>With Shield or on the Shield</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_1_text">
	<text>Intelligence reports have come in about approaching enemy forces near Rostok. The Duty soldiers have already taken defensive positions, but Pushkin doesn’t want to risk his men in case of a possible slaughter if the enemy manages to call reinforcements. That’s why he asked to intercept and destroy the enemy forces before they reach Rostok.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_1_about">
	<text>According to recent intelligence, enemy forces are approaching our positions. This gives us some advantage. The guys have already taken their positions, but I want to make sure that the enemy doesn’t call for reinforcements. So I need you for a preventive strike. No time to waste, so try to make sure these guys “disappear” on their way here. Can you do that?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_1_finish">
	<text>Well done, soldier. I hope the other idiots have the instinct for self-preservation not to mess with us in the near future...</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_2_name">
	<text>Fight Fire with Fire</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_2_text">
	<text>According to Pushkin, "Freedom" has successfully occupied one of Duty’s camps. The Colonel seems to want to demonstrate the speed and strength of our reaction, assigning me to take back the territory occupied by the enemy.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_2_about">
	<text>There’s an important task: "Freedom" just took one of our camps, so to fix this, I need a good fighter who can “persuade” them to change their mind. What do you say?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_2_finish">
	<text>Task completed? Ah! Great job! They’re really going to get a beating, you know...</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_3_name">
	<text>Orders to Eliminate</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_3_text">
	<text>There are plenty of enemies for "Duty." You probably don’t even need to look for them—just the Zone and mutants with Monolith forces are enough!\nNevertheless, there are ideological enemies for the Duty members as well...\nPushkin actually has a list for this job. He assigned me to find and eliminate a target from that very list.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_3_about">
	<text>I have a list of very important people who need to be dealt with. Mostly, they are notorious criminals, informers, rapists, or just thugs who learned too much. But there are also squad leaders and even high-ranking "Freedom" members. Extract any information you can from them, then finish them off.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_3_finish">
	<text>Great! Here’s the promised reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_4_name">
	<text>Every Hunt Has Its Worries</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_4_text">
	<text>"Duty" has never hidden its views on the Zone and all associated phenomena and creations, which is why it gladly accepts like-minded individuals into its ranks and freely issues contracts for mutant culling to stalkers who want to contribute to containing the Zone or just earn a little by doing good. Pushkin assigned me to conduct a mutant culling and also collect a certain trophy from them—"%s".</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_4_about">
	<text>"Duty" needs help in culling mutants. Are you in?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_4_fetch_about">
	<text>As you probably know, we fully encourage and reward stalkers who contribute to destroying the Zone and its horrors—whether they are fanatics of all kinds or mutants. This time, it’s mutants. Recently, hunters passed through here and shared the latest maps of mutant migrations. So, "Duty" could use help in culling the particularly dangerous or overly persistent beasts, depending on your skills, and also collect some trophies to show the greenhorns what they’re up against. Or just for the sense of pride and a job well done, haha. If you deliver me the trophy "%s," you’ll get a good reward. Are you in?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_trader_task_4_fetch_finish">
	<text>Well done, hunter. Here’s your reward.</text>
</string>


	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!--(Clear Sky) Lost to the Zone Tasks -->
	
	<string id="bar_npc_nimble_task_1_name">
	<text>Natural Selection</text>
</string>	
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_task_1_text">
	<text>You need to find a mutant part - “%s” - for Vitalik. He believes that important data can be obtained from his experiments, but first, the mutant part needs to be found and delivered.</text>
</string>		
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_task_1_about">
	<text>Recent studies show that mutants adapt well to the anomalous conditions of the Zone. Could you please help me collect tissue samples for my further research? Perhaps, the results will help us survive in such an aggressive environment.</text>
</string>		
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>Recent studies show that mutants adapt well to the anomalous conditions of the Zone.\n\nCould you please help me collect tissue samples for my further research?\nMaybe, the results will help us survive in such an aggressive environment.\nThe following samples are needed: “%s”.</text>
</string>	
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Excellent! The samples are in great condition! Thank you very much. Now, I’ll get back to my research.</text>
</string>
	
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_task_2_name">
	<text>Scientific Progress</text>
</string>	
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_task_2_text">
	<text>Vitalik seems to share the scientific interest of researchers, mainly related to artifacts.\n\nHe asked me to find the artifact %s for his research.</text>
</string>		
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_task_2_about">
	<text>Artifacts can provide invaluable information for our research. Unfortunately, the Valley of Shadows is a very dangerous place. Could you please help us?</text>
</string>		
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_task_2_fetch_about">
	<text>Artifacts can provide invaluable information for our research. Unfortunately, the Valley of Shadows is a very dangerous place. Could you please help us? We need to find %s.</text>
</string>	
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_task_2_fetch_finish">
	<text>Even after all these years, they never cease to amaze me! What a wonderful specimen! Thank you for your invaluable help to science.</text>
</string>

<!-- bar_npc_barman -->
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_1_name">
	<text>Business Proposal</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_1_text">
	<text>Maladrinus needs the artifact %s. That's it, no unnecessary words or questions. Truly a businessman!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_1_about">
	<text>I'm interested in artifacts. Here's the deal: I give you a tip on a specific artifact, you bring it to me, and you get your reward. Both sides are happy. What do you think?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>My clients are interested in artifacts. Often, these are simply "bright minds" who got unlucky with their connections, or those whom official science figures in the Zone rely on. So, here's the deal: I give you a tip on a specific artifact, you bring it to me, and you get your reward. Both sides are happy. I need the artifact %s. I'll be waiting here, and so will your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Good job, buddy. Here’s your bonus.</text>
</string>
	
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_2_name">
	<text>Dirty Work</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_2_text">
	<text>Maladrinus gave me a dirty job - I need to find and eliminate a stalker who managed to offend someone.\n\nMaladrinus provided all the necessary information on the PDA. Time to get to work. Looks like bad luck for the poor guy...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_2_about">
	<text>Sometimes, stalkers come to me when they've been wronged, and I look for people willing to help them out so that the specific individuals won’t have any further issues. Think of me as a mediator.\nI currently have a few targets for elimination. Usually, it's a stalker who betrayed or ordered the death of his friends, but sometimes it’s just a contract killing for another faction. It’s dirty work, but someone has to do it, especially if the reward is worth it, right? So, are you in? I'll send the necessary information to your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_2_finish">
	<text>Thank you, stalker. Here’s your payment, just don’t get too carried away with killing. Mercenaries don’t need the competition. Heh-heh...</text>
</string>

	
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_3_name">
	<text>Pseudobugs and Pseudomice</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_3_text">
	<text>There’s a joke among stalkers: “A stalker planted a pseudoradish. It grew into a giant pseudoradish! The stalker took a grenade launcher and went to harvest it. He probably would’ve succeeded, if only the pseudobugs and pseudomice hadn’t attacked.” It sounds funny, but sometimes these bugs and mice can really be a pain in the neck. It even gets to the point where you can’t take ten steps from the camp without being attacked by some pseudomonster.\nThat’s why Maladrinus suggested we mix business with pleasure - make some money by cleaning up the mutant infestation around the area. It’s the right thing to do, since they’re multiplying here... And the trophies definitely won’t be unnecessary.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_3_about">
	<text>Tell me, have you seen any mutants on your way here? The Duty guys recently patrolled the area, but new stalkers reported seeing either dogs or something else near the outer borders of the camp. If they’re not joking, these creatures pose a big threat to the stalkers in the camp and anyone heading here. Not to mention that a lack of clients hurts business. So, here’s the deal: I’m willing to pay well for mutant extermination, and maybe even throw in something extra. The main thing is to leave no trace of them. Here are the approximate coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_3_finish">
	<text>Good job. Here’s your hard-earned payment.</text>
</string>
	
<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
<!-- toad (Loner Trader) New Tasks -->

<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_4_name">
	<text>Unusual Business</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_4_text">
	<text>As the saying goes, the rich have their quirks. One such client, it seems, approached Maladrinus and asked him to find a trophy - “%s”...\nMaladrinus, in turn, promised a good payment for delivering the trophy to him so that he could forward it to the client.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_4_about">
	<text>You see, I’m not only a busy person, but also extremely generous to those who wish to help me solve my problems. And right now, I have an urgent order. Interested?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_4_fetch_about">
	<text>Here’s the deal: one of my clients, who’s also a great jeweler specializing in animal trophies, wants one such trophy - %s. He’s willing to pay me a good sum for the delivery. I, in turn, am willing to pay you for delivering it to me first. Understand what I mean, right? Make sure the mutant parts with its possession and bring it to me. I won’t skimp on the payment.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_4_fetch_finish">
	<text>Well done! Here’s your hard-earned payment.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_5_name">
	<text>Cache Robber</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_5_text">
	<text>What was yours will soon be ours. Maladrinus asked me to steal important documents and deliver them to him.\nHe sent the coordinates of their location to my PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_5_about">
	<text>I’ve been told about a stash containing some very interesting documents. I have no idea who owned it or where they are now, but I’ll reward anyone who can manage to get those documents and make them magically appear on this bar counter. Got it? I’ll send you the last known coordinates of the stash on your PDA. I don’t think this is a trap because setting me up is not something you’d want to do—unlike Sidrovich, I don’t lose deals easily on the Cordone.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_barman_task_5_finish">
	<text>Now that’s what I like to see. Great work, stalker.</text>
</string>



</string_table>
