<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<!-- bar_npc_dolg_mechanic -->
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_1_name">
	<text>Find %s for Tokar</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_1_text">
	<text>You need to bring Tokar some tools so he can upgrade equipment.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_1_about">
	<text>You know, buddy, I’m actually a pretty good tech. I can fix both weapons and armor, even do some upgrades! Well, I would… if I had proper tools. But where do you get them around here? Maybe you could help me find a simple set, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>I need a set of basic tools for rough work. It should have tools and oils for working with weapons. If you can get it, I’ll be grateful, I might even pay you!.. Probably.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Awesome, man! Ah, sorry, I don’t have anything to pay you with. But I can give you a good discount!</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_2_name">
	<text>Find %s for Tokar</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_2_text">
	<text>You need to bring Tokar fine work tools. He needs a more complete set to carry out advanced upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_2_about">
	<text>Hey man, if you agree to get me a more complete set, you’ll get an even bigger discount. What do you say, pal?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_2_fetch_about">
	<text>I need fine work tools. They’ve got everything I need. You’ll be like a brother to me if you get them!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_2_fetch_finish">
	<text>Whoa, thanks, bro! Now I’ll definitely strike it rich. Damn, I’ll make it big!.. If I don’t blow this chance too. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_3_name">
	<text>Find %s for Tokar</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_3_text">
	<text>You need to bring Tokar %s. He needs a unique set to perform even more advanced upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_3_about">
	<text>Hey, man, if you find something worthwhile – I’ll give you a discount!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_3_fetch_about">
	<text>I need calibration tools. They should have everything I need. You’ll be like a brother to me if you get them!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_mechanic_task_3_fetch_finish">
	<text>No fuc—! Damn, thanks, bro! Now I’ll definitely strike it rich. Hell, I’ll finally make it!.. If I don’t screw up this chance too. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, pal.</text>
</string>

<!-- bar_medic -->
<string id="bar_medic_task_1_name">
	<text>%s for Ukol</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_medic_task_1_text">
	<text>You need to find a kit and bring it to medic Ukol.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_medic_task_1_about">
	<text>I need a good set of medical instruments. I can patch up light wounds fast, but for anything more serious, a simple scalpel just isn’t enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_medic_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>I need a good set of medical instruments. I can patch up light wounds fast, but for anything more serious, a simple scalpel just isn’t enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_medic_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Thanks, friend! These instruments will save many lives. Thanks again for the tools.</text>
</string>


</string_table>
