<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<!-- blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic -->
	<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_1_name">
	<text>Find %s for Petrovich</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_1_text">
	<text>You need to bring Petrovich some tools so he can upgrade his equipment.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_1_about">
	<text>You know, buddy, I'm actually a pretty good mechanic. I can fix weapons and armor, and I can even do some upgrades! Well, I would if I had the right tools. But where can you get those here? Maybe you can help me get some basic tools, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>I need a set of tools for heavy work. It should include tools and oils for working on weapons. If you can get it, I'd be really grateful, and maybe I'll even pay you!... Probably.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Great, dude! Oh, sorry, I don't have anything to pay you with. But I can give you a nice discount!</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_2_name">
	<text>Find %s for Petrovich</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_2_text">
	<text>You need to bring Petrovich a set of tools for delicate work. He needs a more complete set to perform more advanced upgrades on his equipment.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_2_about">
	<text>Hey, dude, if you agree to get me a more complete set, you'll get an even bigger discount. Help me out, buddy?</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_2_fetch_about">
	<text>I need tools for delicate work. It should have everything I need. You'll be like a brother to me if you get it!</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_2_fetch_finish">
	<text>Wow, thanks, bro! Now I’m definitely going to get rich. Damn, I’m going to be successful! ...If, of course, I don’t miss this chance too. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_3_name">
	<text>Find %s for Petrovich</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_3_text">
	<text>You need to bring Petrovich %s. He needs a unique set of tools to do even more advanced equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_3_about">
	<text>Hey, man, if you find something valuable, I’ll give you a discount!</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_3_fetch_about">
	<text>I need tools for calibration. They should have everything I need. You’ll be like a brother to me if you get them!</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_mechanic_task_3_fetch_finish">
	<text>No way...! Damn, thanks, bro! Now I’m definitely going to get rich. Damn, I’m going to be successful! ...If, of course, I don’t miss this chance too. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>

<!-- blck_val_a31_bandit_medic -->
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_medic_task_1_name">
	<text>%s for Antibiotic</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_medic_task_1_text">
	<text>You need to find a medical kit and take it to the medic Antibiotic.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_medic_task_1_about">
	<text>I need a good set of medical tools. I can patch up minor wounds quickly, but when it comes to more serious injuries, my scalpel just isn’t enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_medic_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>I need a good set of medical tools. I can patch up minor wounds quickly, but when it comes to more serious injuries, my scalpel just isn’t enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="blck_val_a31_bandit_medic_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Thanks, friend! These tools will save many lives. Thanks again for bringing them.</text>
</string>


</string_table>
