<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations">
		<text>Locations</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_army_warehouses">
		<text>Army Warehouses</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_army_warehouses_text">
		<text>
			%c[pda_green]Information\n%c[ui_gray_1]A deserted army base next to a dilapidated hamlet and a small marsh. The hamlet, once infested by a legion of bloodsuckers, has earned a dark reputation that keeps most stalkers away. Meanwhile, the army base has been used as Freedom's main HQ for years. It is from this base that they defend the Barrier to the north from the Monolith, and from where many brave and foolish stalkers try to break deeper into the Zone.
			\n \n%c[pda_blue]Connected Locations%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• Rostok
			\n• Dead City
			\n• Red Forest
			\n• Radar
			\n• Truck Cemetery
			\n• Grimwood
			\n• Yuzhniy
			\n• Promzone
			\n \n%c[pda_yellow]Trivia%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• This location was the military HQ prior to the Second Large Emission in 2011, which zombified most of the soldiers present.
			\n• The voices of those now-dead soldiers are said to be heard over select radio frequencies from almost any point in the Zone.
			\n• Contrary to popular belief, not all Freedomers stationed here get high for recreational reasons. Some do so to stave off the ambient dread caused by the Brain Scorcher, which can give off subliminal effects up to several kilometers away.
		</text>
	</string>
			
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_dark_valley">
		<text>Dark Valley</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_dark_valley_text">
		<text>
			%c[pda_green]Information\n%c[ui_gray_1]A grim place that owes its reputation to two things: the Bandit stronghold to the north and the underground lab to the east. Local Bandit lords do their best to keep the lab sealed, and for good reason - almost no one comes out alive, and no one can really say why.
			\n \n%c[pda_blue]Connected Locations%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• Garbage
			\n• Darkscape
			\n• Truck Cemetery
			\n• Yuzhniy
			\n \n%c[pda_yellow]Trivia%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• This location was Freedom's HQ during the 2011 Faction Wars.
			\n• The Military seldom sends light Spetsnaz units to this area, generally aimed towards securing or reinforcing the lab.
			\n• Prior to their mishaps beyond the Barrier, Duty was almost on the brink of eliminating the Bandit threat from this location once and for all.
		</text>
	</string>
			
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_dead_city">
		<text>Dead City</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_dead_city_text">
		<text>
			The %c[pda_white]Dead City%c[ui_gray_1], once full of energy, is now nothing more than a crumbling ruin.\n
			\n%c[pda_green]Information%c[ui_gray_1]
			\nFormerly inhabited by those who could not find a home within Limansk or Pripyat, much of the location's history has since been long forgotten.\n
			\nThe name given to it by stalkers can be considered an accurate one, likening the city to a corpse because of its condition - decaying and wasting away at the hands of the elements.\n
			\nDespite being under constant siege from invading Monolith and mutants, the Mercenary faction has established their headquarters here, maintaining a small yet powerful presence.
			\n \n%c[pda_blue]Connected Locations%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• Limansk
			\n• Army Warehouses
			\n• Yantar
			\n• Grimwood
			\n \n%c[pda_yellow]Trivia%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• Until sometime after 2012, most stalkers didn't believe this location existed. Having lost that secrecy, Mercs instead use their reputation to deter unwanted visitors.
		</text>
	</string>
			
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_garbage">
		<text>Garbage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_garbage_text">
		<text>
			%c[pda_green]Information\n%c[ui_gray_1]A vast machinery graveyard. Right after the first accident whole heaps of radioactive waste were dumped there. Mostly ruins of old buildings infested with mutants. Much like the outskirts of the Zone, the place swarms with rookie stalkers, with an occasional bandit loitering around, always on the lookout for freebies. Landmarks include a derelict train hangar in the middle of the area, along with a flea market to the north.
			\n \n%c[pda_blue]Connected Locations%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• Cordon
			\n• Dark Valley
			\n• Agroprom
			\n• Rostok
			\n• Wild Territory
			\n• Yuzhniy
			\n \n%c[pda_yellow]Trivia%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• The train hangar is rumoured to be a meeting ground for the Zone's dedicated mutant hunters.
			\n• This location was once the HQ of the Bandits under Yoga's rule, who'd capture and enslave stalkers to work in artefact labour camps.
			\n• The myriad scrap heaps have existed here since the original accident in 1986.
			\n• As the crossroads between Duty, Stalker, Military and Bandit territories, this location can often fall into a state of anarchy.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	
		
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_red_forest">
		<text>Red Forest</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_red_forest_text">
		<text>
			%c[pda_green]Information\n%c[ui_gray_1]Actually just the westernmost traversable area of the Red Forest, and also arguably the safest. Still, it is widely considered one of the most dangerous areas in the entire Zone due to the high mutant activity.
			\n \n%c[pda_blue]Connected Locations%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• Army Warehouses
			\n• Jupiter
			\n• Limansk
			\n• Radar
			\n• Grimwood
			\n \n%c[pda_yellow]Trivia%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• The name "Red Forest" came from the pine leaves in the area, which turned bright ginger in colour after absorbing fatal levels of radiation from the 1986 Chernobyl disaster.
		</text>
	</string>
				
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_truck_cemetery">
		<text>Truck Cemetery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_truck_cemetery_text">
		<text>
			%c[ui_gray_1]The %c[pda_white]Truck Cemetery%c[ui_gray_1], officially the %c[pda_green]Rassokha Equipment Cemetery%c[ui_gray_1], is a giant scrapyard full of irradiated vehicles.\n
			\n%c[pda_green]Information%c[ui_gray_1]
			\nA dark echo of the smaller and safer "Garbage" area to the south-west, the Truck Cemetery is a dumping site for vehicles that'd been used in extensive radiological cleanup operations following the 1986 disaster.\n
			\nWhilst most of the equipment rotting here was in perfect working order all those decades ago, it had no practical way of being decontaminated. Other equipment had simply broken down entirely. Either way, the heroic machines that mitigated the Chernobyl disaster were all left here to die.\n
			\nSince the Zone's ultimate inception in 2006, however, this area has bustled into life. Sometimes, it's the site of spates between factions. Usually, it's a breeding ground for mutants.\n
			\nDespite being so isolated and difficult to get to, many stalkers have noticed the vehicles here are gradually being stripped bare - with many believing that somebody, perhaps the military, is attempting to salvage the metals and illegally sell them for scrap.
			\n \n%c[pda_blue]Connected Locations%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• Army Warehouses
			\n• Rostok
			\n• Dark Valley
			\n• Yuzhniy
			\n• Promzone
			\n \n%c[pda_yellow]Trivia%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• Despite the risks, Bandits have set up a base in the northern part of this area, possibly to liase between Freedom and Dark Valley.
			\n• Many of the vehicles here have begun to lose their radioactivity, implying they'll soon be safe to remove and legally scrap should the government ever gain control of this area.
			\n• This map is a popular stash spot for paranoid stalkers, as few others are willing to brave mutants and anomalies just to find a needle in a haystack.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_promzona">
		<text>Promzone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_promzona_text">
		<text>
			%c[pda_green]Information\n%c[ui_gray_1]An abandoned train station originally used after the 1986 disaster to transport radioactive garbage from the Northern Regions to the Truck Cemetery, and eventually to "Garbage". \n
			\nOriginally thought lost to an immense sized anomaly field, the emission that revealed Yuzhniy uncovered this region as well.
			\n \n%c[pda_blue]Connected Locations%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• Army Warehouses
			\n• Truck Cemetery
						
		</text>
	</string>
		
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_grimwood">
		<text>Grimwood</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_grimwood_text">
		<text>
			%c[pda_green]Information\n%c[ui_gray_1]A region of the forest between the Army Warehouses and the Dead City. Similarly dangerous as the main regions of the legendary forest, full of mutants and deadly anomalies. Little human life is present, making it a good hiding place for those wanting to disappear.
			\n \n%c[pda_blue]Connected Locations%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• Army Warehouses
			\n• Dead City
			\n• Red Forest
			
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_poselok_ug">
		<text>Yuzhniy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_locations_poselok_ug_text">
		<text>
			%c[pda_green]Information\n%c[ui_gray_1]A ghost town with seemingly no history or evidence that it ever existed. And yet, here it is. After a massive emission, the empty field between Garbage and Truck Cemetery suddenly revealed the town now named "Yuzhniy". \n
			\nIt seemingly got everything a functioning town should have, infrastructure, residential and service buildings, but there's an overwhelming feeling that the place just doesn't belong; the surprisingly well kept grass doesn't help with this feeling either. \n
			\nThere's even a theory, or really, a sort of legend shared between the stalkers of the Zone that Yuzhniy is a town that the Zone "ate" in an alternate reality and have "spit" it out in our own after the emission. Another tall tale is that the town always existed, but the Zone erased its existence even from the minds of people, shrouding it until now.\n
			\nWhatever the case, Yuzhniy is now considered a potential new frontier for the rookie and the experienced stalker both.
			\n \n%c[pda_blue]Connected Locations%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• Army Warehouses
			\n• Garbage
			\n• Dark Valley
			\n• Truck Cemetery
			\n \n%c[pda_yellow]Trivia%c[ui_gray_1]
			\n• Freedom have moved into the town and have a small outpost. Bandits have also moved in from the nearby Truck Cemetery. An all out faction war might be inevitable in the future.
			
		</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>