<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>

<!--
	ia ne eby kak eto delat
-->

<string_table>

<string id="st_knifebf4">
    <text>SP-8 Machete</text>
</string>
<string id="st_knifebf4_descr">
    <text>SP8, a survival machete made from a single piece of high-carbon steel.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_kukri">
    <text>United Cutlery M48 Kukri</text>
</string>
<string id="st_kukri_descr">
    <text>The M48 series tactical kukri made by "United Cutlery". It features a stainless steel blade and a rubberized handle. A perfect addition to any survivalist’s arsenal!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_tactical_knife">
    <text>Monolith Knife</text>
</string>
<string id="st_tactical_knife_descr">
    <text>A strangely shaped knife with mysterious markings, taken from a Monolith member. Apparently used as a ritual blade, but that doesn’t seem to be its only purpose.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_knife_combat">
    <text>Taiga-1 Machete</text>
</string>
<string id="st_knife_combat_descr">
    <text>A truly versatile survival tool. It's a weapon, a shovel, an axe — anything you can imagine. It was developed and produced in the USSR for various agencies.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_knife_6x4">
    <text>6X5 Bayonet Knife</text>
</string>
<string id="st_knife_6x4_descr">
    <text>The 6X5 bayonet knife was adopted in 1989 for use with AK-74 rifles. Not suitable for skinning thick-skinned mutants.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_tomahawk">
    <text>SOG Voodoo Hawk Tomahawk</text>
</string>
<string id="st_tomahawk_descr">
    <text>The SOG Voodoo Hawk combines three top features: an extended cutting head, a compact fiberglass-reinforced nylon handle, and a metal pommel at the end.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_knife_hunting">
    <text>Bars A-2607 Damascus</text>
</string>
<string id="st_knife_hunting_descr">
    <text>The Bars A-2607 knife is made of Damascus steel with a wenge wood handle and a brass guard.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_knife_needle">
    <text>Bars A-2607 95x18</text>
</string>
<string id="st_knife_needle_descr">
    <text>The Bars A-2607 knife is forged from 95X18 steel with a handle made of fine wood and a brass guard. Not suitable for skinning thick-skinned mutants.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_knife_swat">
    <text>Miller Bros. Blades M-2</text>
</string>
<string id="st_knife_swat_descr">
    <text>The "M-2" tactical sword made by Miller Bros.</text>
</string>

<string id="wpn_sapper_shovel">
    <text>Sapper's Shovel</text>
</string>
<string id="st_sapper_shovel_descr">
    <text>A durable, military-style entrenching tool used by sappers. Can be used for digging, chopping, and in desperate times — as a brutal melee weapon.</text>
</string>


</string_table>