<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
<string id="antl_novice_outfit_name">
	<text>Jacket</text>
</string>
<string id="antl_novice_outfit_description">
	<text>%c[ui_gray_1]A fairly thick jacket worn over a warm wool sweater, paired with jeans tucked into sturdy hiking boots. Quite popular among rookie stalkers, though infamous among veterans who consider its protection only slightly better than grandma’s sweater.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="antl_trenchcoat_outfit_name">
	<text>Trenchcoat</text>
</string>
<string id="antl_trenchcoat_outfit_description">
	<text>%c[ui_gray_1]A long, heavy trenchcoat. Its protective qualities may vary depending on the tailor. While overall it’s only slightly better than a leather jacket, it remains popular among rookies who still care about appearance.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="antl_army_outfit_name">
	<text>Army Vest</text>
</string>
<string id="antl_army_outfit_description">
	<text>The standard gear issued to soldiers in the Zone, and a testament to bureaucratic efficiency, as the tender for developing gear went to the lowest bidder. The vest offers moderate protection against weak mutant attacks, and is only slightly better than the jackets worn by rookie stalkers — which says a lot.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="antl_stalker_outfit_name">
	<text>“Sunrise” Suit</text>
</string>
<string id="antl_stalker_outfit_description">
	<text>%c[ui_gray_1]A suit crafted by local Zone artisans. It consists of double-layered rubberized fabric with a plexiglass lining and an integrated ballistic vest. One of the oldest suits used by stalkers, the “Sunrise” is considered the bare minimum for stalkers planning deeper Zone excursions. Despite this, it remains popular among both rookies and veterans for its low cost and upgrade potential.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="antl_rhb_outfit_name">
	<text>NBC Suit</text>
</string>
<string id="antl_rhb_outfit_description">
	<text>%c[ui_gray_1]A budget NBC (nuclear, biological, chemical) protection suit with a kevlar vest. Mass-produced outside the Zone for military and disaster response use. Comes with a GP-5 gas mask adapted for modern filters. Although not designed specifically for the Zone, it’s a popular choice among stalkers for its thoughtful weight distribution and protection comparable to common stalker suits.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="antl_seva_outfit_name">
	<text>“SEVA” Suit</text>
</string>
<string id="antl_seva_outfit_description">
	<text>%c[ui_gray_1]Produced by a Kyiv-based military research institute, this suit offers a high-quality alternative to the Zone’s many homemade options. It includes a closed-loop breathing system and an integrated anomaly suppression system. Excellent material selection makes it a solid choice. Its only downsides are the high price and poor ballistic protection — even with a decent vest, it's not recommended for firefights.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_antl_ecologist_outfit_orange_name">
	<text>SSP-99 “Ecologist”</text>
</string>
<string id="st_antl_ecologist_outfit_orange_description">
	<text>%c[ui_gray_1]Designed for Zone conditions, the SSP-99 is used by scientific expeditions and ecologist-aligned stalkers. Made from thermal-insulating and dielectric materials. Includes a built-in air filtration and cooling system, offering excellent radiation and chemical protection. Not built for combat and provides no protection against bullets or shrapnel.\n \n</text>
</string>


	<!-- Skat-9 Military Armoured Suits -->
<string id="antl_skat_outfit_name">
	<text>“SKAT-9” Armored Suit</text>
</string>
<string id="antl_skat_outfit_description">
	<text>%c[ui_gray_1]An excellent armored suit fully suited for Zone conditions. This heavy military-grade suit was developed for assault operations in anomalous activity zones. Components include: the PSZ-12p heavy body armor, anomaly-protective overalls, and a compensation under-suit. Provides outstanding protection against bullets and shrapnel, while still remaining comfortable and not overly restrictive. Originally intended strictly for military stalkers and special forces, the suits eventually found their way onto the Zone’s open market.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="antl_exo_outfit_name">
	<text>Heavy Combat Suit</text>
</string>
<string id="antl_exo_outfit_description">
	<text>A heavy armor suit that essentially acts as the under-armor of a full exoskeleton. Its protection level is comparable to that of a true exoskeleton, but the lack of servomotors and a power source means no strength enhancement. On the bright side, it’s cheaper to maintain and doesn’t hinder running. Composed of three parts: a tactical helmet, heavy armored vest, and a reinforced bodysuit.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="antl_seva_heavy_outfit_name">
	<text>Heavy Scientific Suit</text>
</string>
<string id="antl_seva_heavy_outfit_description">
	<text>%c[ui_gray_1]The official heavy-duty military suit variant designed for scientific security personnel. Offers protection almost impervious to small-caliber weaponry, and its integrated anomaly shielding system greatly assists with artifact retrieval and anomaly research. These protective features make it a valuable asset for scientific expeditions within the Zone.\n \n</text>
</string>

</string_table>
