<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia__anthology">
	<text>ANTHOLOGY</text>
</string>
	
<string id="encyclopedia__anthology_mod">
	<text>ANTHOLOGY</text>
</string>

<string id="encyclopedia__anthology_mod_text">
	<text>
		%c[pda_white]Anthology Developer%c[ui_gray_1] - Макс Ратный Ратниченко.\n
		%c[pda_white]Addon Compilation%c[ui_gray_1] - Серега Hyper.\n
		%c[pda_white]Weaponsmith%c[ui_gray_1] - Денис Denis9x39.\n			
		%c[pda_white]Administrator%c[ui_gray_1] - Дедушка Ли.\n			
			
		\n%c[pda_green]Development Assistance:%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\n• Map, logs, and script creation: Melinite
		\n• SDK assistance: Андрей Непряхин
		\n• SDK assistance: Алексей Лоскутов
		\n• SDK assistance: Сталкер ШЕВА
		\n• SDK assistance: Kryiron Ai
		\n• Development help: Alcatraz396
		\n• Development help: PastKNIGHT
		\n• Development help: Jr.Anthologist / Саня
		\n• Development help: Jlyn4ik (Trovo,Twitch)(Danila)
		
		\n%c[pda_green]Mod Links:%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\n• Discord: https://discord.gg/xMkuD74cwt
		\n• VK: https://vk.com/club219667646
	</text>
</string>

<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_story_spatial_anomaly">
	<text>Spatial Anomaly</text>
</string>

<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_story_spatial_anomaly_text">
	<text>
		%c[pda_white]Main character%c[ui_gray_1] - Beast.\n
		\n%c[pda_green]Information%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\nUpdate 4.1 is the final update for the "Spatial Anomaly" modification. The patch not only brings a number of fixes, but also introduces many new features, as well as new quests. This version of the modification takes into account all player feedback and suggestions, making the mod even better. The story tells us about the well-known mercenary "Beast" and his attempts to survive inside a mystical place called the "Spatial Anomaly," where completely different laws reign. Everything is now scarce: ammo, medicine, drinkable water, food, and even bolts. Yet nothing will stop the mercenary who seeks a way to escape this deadly trap.\n
		\n%c[pda_green]Characteristics%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\n• Faction: Mercenaries\n• Freeplay mode: yes\n• Living Legend continuation: yes\n• Mod developers: PROFFESIONAL and others
	</text>
</string>

<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_story_call_of_pripyat">
	<text>Call of Pripyat</text>
</string>

<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_story_call_of_pripyat_text">
	<text>
		%c[pda_white]Main character%c[ui_gray_1] - Degtyarev.\n
		\n%c[pda_green]Information%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\nA military expedition to the center of the Zone vanishes under mysterious circumstances. The task of finding out what happened to the crews and uncovering the causes falls to Major Degtyarev, an SBU operative. You will answer the Call of Pripyat in the third chapter of the cult S.T.A.L.K.E.R. series.\n
		\n%c[pda_green]Characteristics%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\n• Faction: Loners\n• Freeplay mode: yes\n• Living Legend continuation: no\n• Developers: GSC Game World
	</text>
</string>

<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_story_path_in_the_dark">
	<text>Path in the Dark</text>
</string>

<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_story_path_in_the_dark_text">
	<text>
		%c[pda_white]Main character%c[ui_gray_1] - Shroud.\n
		\n%c[pda_green]Information%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\nThe Zone hides many secrets — both its own and those brought from outside. Adventurers calling themselves stalkers try to uncover these mysteries. Some succeed, but most disappear in the Zone forever.\n
		\n%c[pda_green]Characteristics%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\n• Faction: Loners\n• Freeplay mode: yes\n• Living Legend continuation: yes\n• Mod developers: Spectrum Project
	</text>
</string>


<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_story_in_a_web_of_lies">
	<text>Death Defying 2 : In a Web of Lies</text>
</string>
<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_story_in_a_web_of_lies_text">
	<text>
		%c[pda_white]Main character%c[ui_gray_1] - Varg.\n
		\n%c[pda_green]Information%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\nThe protagonist of the storyline is a free stalker named Varg. For a long time, he was part of Orest’s stalker squad, making a living by hunting rare and valuable artifacts around Agroyantar. But by fate’s will, ending up in the Swamps, Varg takes on a contract from the Clear Sky faction to search for a group of scientists who mysteriously disappeared in the western parts of the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone. In addition, he was tasked with finding traces of a Clear Sky search party that had followed the scientists in hot pursuit.\n
		\n%c[pda_green]Characteristics%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\n• Faction: Loners\n• Freeplay mode: no\n• Living Legend continuation: no\n• Mod developers: Geonezis, Goroff, makdm, gridgt, Falcon
	</text>
</string>

<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_story_valley_of_rustles">
	<text>Valley of Whispers</text>
</string>
<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_story_valley_of_rustles_text">
	<text>
		%c[pda_white]Main character%c[ui_gray_1] - Max.\n
		\n%c[pda_green]Information%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\nA new storyline, not connected with the plot of the original game. The story follows a simple stalker named Max, who decided to earn some money before leaving the Zone. All events of the mod take place in a brand-new location. There will be plenty of space to explore, things to search for, enemies to fight, and questions to ponder.\n
		\n%c[pda_green]Characteristics%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\n• Faction: Loners\n• Freeplay mode: yes\n• Living Legend continuation: yes\n• Mod developers: Den-Stash
	</text>
</string>

<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_story_forgotten_squad">
	<text>Forgotten Squad</text>
</string>
<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_story_forgotten_squad_text">
	<text>
		%c[pda_white]Main character%c[ui_gray_1] - Snake.\n
		\n%c[pda_green]Information%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\nIn this story, you will play as an experienced hunter nicknamed "Snake." Our hero must track down his comrade nicknamed "Bison" and his group, who have gone missing. Following their trail, the protagonist arrives in the vicinity of the former Scientific Research Institute and begins his search. The main storyline takes about 4 hours to complete, with additional time needed for side quests and exploration.\n
		\n%c[pda_green]Characteristics%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\n• Faction: Loners\n• Freeplay mode: yes\n• Living Legend continuation: yes\n• Mod developers: Another Team
	</text>
</string>

<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_story_shadow_of_chernobyl">
	<text>Shadow of Chernobyl</text>
</string>
<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_story_shadow_of_chernobyl_text">
	<text>
		%c[pda_white]Main character%c[ui_gray_1] - Marked One.\n
		\n%c[pda_green]Information%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\nThe events take place in the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone, which has turned from a place where destinies were broken into a threat to all mankind. The Zone reveals its secrets reluctantly, grudgingly, and only a rare hero can reach its very heart and discover what danger awaits there. A danger compared to which marauders, hostile factions, all monsters, and anomalies of the Zone will seem like mere preparation for an encounter with something far more fatal and terrifying.\n
		\n%c[pda_green]Characteristics%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\n• Faction: Loners\n• Freeplay mode: no\n• Living Legend continuation: no\n• Developers: GSC Game World
	</text>
</string>


	
	<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_breeder">
	<text>Artifact Transmuters</text>
</string>
<string id="encyclopedia_anthology_breeder_text">
	<text>
		\n%c[pda_green]List of Transmuters:%c[ui_gray_1]\n
		\n• Professor Plyusnin. Location: Clear Sky Base. Anomaly type: Type 1 anomaly \n
		\n• Doctor Makovetsky. Location: Zaton Skadovsk. Anomaly type: Type 1 anomaly \n
		\n• Professor Panin. Location: Cordon Vehicle Depot. Anomaly type: Type 1 anomaly \n
		\n• Assistant Anokhin. Location: Yantar Scientists’ Bunker. Anomaly type: Type 1 anomaly \n
		\n• Doctor Brunko. Location: Jupiter Yanov. Anomaly type: Type 2 anomaly \n	
		\n• Gloomy. Location: Army Warehouses, Freedom Base. Anomaly type: Type 2 anomaly \n
		\n• Associate Professor Loskutov. Location: Bar. Anomaly type: Type 2 anomaly \n
		\n• Professor Zelenkov. Location: Research Institute Outskirts. Anomaly type: Type 2 anomaly \n
		\n• Professor Bozhevsky. Location: Jupiter Scientists’ Bunker. Anomaly type: Type 3 anomaly \n
		\n• Doctor Kravchenko. Location: Scientific Station, Scientists’ Bunker. Anomaly type: Types 1, 2, 3, 4 anomalies \n	
		\n• Professor Skorik. Location: Anomalous Forest, Scientists’ Bunker. Anomaly type: Types 1, 2, 3, 4 anomalies \n
		\n• Associate Professor Bezgodko. Location: Outskirts, Scientists’ Camp. Anomaly type: Types 1, 2, 3, 4 anomalies \n
		\n• Associate Professor Shkrekov. Location: Anomalous Fields, Scientists’ Camp. Anomaly type: Types 1, 2, 3, 4 anomalies \n
	</text>
</string>

</string_table>