<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
    
<string id="item_doc_labx2_name">
	<text>Documents from X-2</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_labx2_name_desc">
	<text>Top Secret documents. Date: August 15, 1987.\nThe documents describe a new phenomenon discovered by a group of scientists led by Professor Kaimanov at Branch No. 2 of the "X" network complex. This phenomenon was named "Psi" — the ability of living beings to generate special directional waves affecting other living beings. These waves were later termed "Psi-Emission," and for the first time in history, a living specimen capable of generating such emission within a small range was cultivated. It was then decided to transfer all documentation and research objects related to Psi to Branch No. 16, where a special facility for cultivating a more powerful source of emission had just been completed.</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_labx3_name_desc">
	<text>Many pages are damaged, only a small portion remains.\n\n...A decision was made a week ago to test a new serum on test subjects. No changes were observed in the first days. After a few days, strange metamorphoses began: hair loss, increased aggression. Several test subjects were literally torn apart by their peers.\n\n...Subjects' conditions stabilized. Hair coverage is about 10% of the original. Claws have grown significantly, the oral cavity mutated into several tentacle-like structures with suction pads, and an optical camouflage ability appeared. Activity surges are random and likely food-seeking behavior. Senior lab technician Burnov A. N. suggested that this may indicate heightened predatory instincts. It was decided to attach monitoring devices to the subjects.\n\n...Yesterday we attempted to train the subjects. It appeared they completely lack intelligence. I can barely imagine how to train a killing machine to obey anyone. All forms of control were tested. The results match those from other labs. The experiment is considered complete. I think we’ll be ready to test on larger creatures in a week.</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_labx3_name">
	<text>Report on Project "Supersoldier"</text>
</string>

<string id="item_labx3_pda_name">
	<text>PDA from X-3</text>
</string>

<string id="item_labx3_pda_name_desc">
	<text>Door password: 4526</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_10_labx6_name">
	<text>Technical Documentation of TP-1 Device</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_10_labx6_name_desc">
	<text>Top Secret documents. Date: May 22, 1997.\nThe documents describe the operation of a device used for teleporting inanimate objects. Scientists from this lab managed to build a device capable of relocating objects to predetermined coordinates through quantum tunneling without causing any damage. A massive energy requirement during teleportation was noted, making the process difficult to perform frequently. The rest of the text can only be deciphered by a scientist with two advanced degrees in quantum physics.\n\nThe middle section references experiments with teleporting living subjects, but the observation log was sent to another wing of the lab located slightly north of the main complex.</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_11_hospital_name">
	<text>Unified Railway Map</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_11_hospital_name_desc">
	<text>The folder contains numerous notes and maps of railway lines running beneath the entire Chernobyl Exclusion Zone. It includes a list of all secret X facilities and strategically important stations. It appears these were used for transporting equipment, experiment subjects, military hardware, and biological waste. Notably, after the 1986 disaster, the O-Consciousness actively used this network, making their activities virtually undetectable. Currently, many routes are blocked, and the few remaining are used by Monolith forces to move squads across the Zone.</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_12_bunker_lab_1_name">
	<text>Documents from Bunker-A1</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_12_bunker_lab_1_name_desc">
	<text>--</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_13_okrest_name">
	<text>Report on ZX-16 Module Stress Tests</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_13_okrest_name_desc">
	<text>Classified. To the Head of the Psi-Barrier Project, Prof. Chubko V. M. From Lab X-16 Head, PhD Prihodko P. S.\n\nTests were conducted under conditions of forced reduction of the thermal shutdown barrier by 50%. The ZX-16 unit was operated under the standard "Perimeter Protection" psi-field mode. The tests revealed uncontrolled psi-emission spikes and induced fields after 5–6 minutes of operation. Psi-field intensity exceeded the design limits by 50–60%, reaching absolute values of 170–190 psiA. These results contradict Kasyanov’s theory on induced psi-fields, which predicted a reduction in emission during overheating. Some staff believe increased emitter temperature enhances the neural activity of the Y-1M pseudo-brain, turning it into a retransmitter, not just a source. This requires further study, but we lack the funding. Others claim they’re going insane after these tests. This is a real issue — we’ll have to let some staff go.\n\nBiomaterials exposed to psi-fields were rendered useless due to irreversible brain and CNS damage. CT scans and EEG data are attached in a separate report. Despite the unexpected and unpredictable results, the experiment was valuable, showing that combining the emitter with the Y-1M brain may yield more stable results than our competitors at Lab X-19.\n\nP.S. To continue research, we need new biomaterial: 10 animal and 10 human subjects from colony 1296-bis. Please also send additional guards — it’s becoming hard to restrain subjects after psi-exposure. Some escaped during the last experiment. The guards managed to eliminate some, the rest fled into a highly irradiated zone and pursuit was halted.</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_14_sci_name">
	<text>Excerpt from "Controller" Experiment Documentation</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_14_sci_name_desc">
	<text>From deep within the lab beneath the science station\n\nExperiment Log:\n[Prototype #8] High mortality after implantation; survivors show no telekinetic abilities. Self-harming episodes.\n[Prototype #11] Declared failure during development.\n[Prototype #17] Displays extreme aggression, reproduction banned. Final specimens sent via rail tunnel for containment.\n\n[Prototype #37] Observation journal of Professor Dvupalov.\nDay 1 post-implantation. Vitals are within expected parameters. I’m confident this time I made the right choice.\nDay 10. Subject is awake, conditioned reflexes returned. No evident disorientation. Tests show the brain can process human speech — promising, despite inability to establish direct contact.\nThree months. All indirect cognitive stimulation efforts failed. It’s like the subject isn’t even here.\nFive (six?) months. Physical stimulation also failed. The subject never used its abilities. I’m beginning to suspect brain damage.</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_15_collaider_name">
	<text>A Scientist’s Confession</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_15_collaider_name_desc">
	<text>"We must destroy all records of the research and experiments conducted here. We are no longer the naive youths who began this work. Countless experiments and operations, meticulous labor, often thankless. The complications of secret access protocols, where only the director knows the full scope. Times have changed, and those who once supported us would not understand now. To the public, we are monsters. Yes, we conducted inhumane experiments, both on animals and humans. But we must remember who and what we fought for, and despite unbearable working conditions, we continued serving our homeland.\n\nUnfortunately, these are hard times for us, and our response must be as harsh as the conditions we face. We must become reclusive scientists, severing all ties with the outside world. Time is short — the USSR is no more, and we will be prosecuted for our criminal experiments. Sooner or later, the truth will be revealed through the documents stored in KGB and secret government archives overseeing new weapons research. This lab’s facility must never be found, and what it’s capable of must never leave these walls. We will either be the creators of a miracle — or of a true hell."</text>
</string>


	<string id="item_doc_16_kas_name">
	<text>Dr. Chernykh's Diary</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_16_kas_name_desc">
	<text>Found among the papers in the underground "Orbita" bunker.\n\nReceived "Alpha", a product of the Caribbean experiment. This fascinating artifact has a unique ability to convert biological alpha-psi emission into electromagnetic beta-psi emission and vice versa. This discovery significantly expands our technological capabilities, allowing safe use of existing equipment and paving the way for revolutionary innovations. Are we on the threshold of accessing the Noosphere?\nNo, not at all. Creating a stable channel for data reception turned out to be a real problem, mainly because the ionospheric-noospheric barrier is far more energetically stable than I expected. I am considering three options:\n * First, I could increase the intensity until it results in brain burnout.\n * Second, I could explore the possibility of merging multiple consciousnesses.\n * The third, a more unconventional option, is to use the signature imprint not only as a channel key but also as a way to create a Mediator within the Noosphere itself. Data would go directly to the Mediator, avoiding the barrier and significantly reducing energy consumption — quite tempting, isn’t it? The problem is, how do we retrieve data from the Mediator? If we can figure out how to tune a "Source-Mediator" system in a superposition form to bypass the barrier, we’ll be in business.\n\nAs tempting as it sounds, this remains unlikely for now. I’ll focus on the first two options for the time being.</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_17_country_name">
	<text>Notes of the Pen Enclosure Security Chief</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_17_country_name_desc">
	<text>Many pages are damaged. Only a few could be deciphered.\n\nSecurity Chief: Yesterday, guard Glebov G.R. threw a piece of meat to the test animals as a joke. They tore it apart and devoured it within seconds. After that, several specimens tried to break out of their cages, preventing the lab assistants from collecting the scheduled sample doses. Despite Glebov’s irresponsible behavior, I suggest equipping maintenance staff with pneumatic weapons for self-defense in emergencies.\n\nSecurity Chief: Yesterday, the experiment almost spiraled out of control. About twenty test animals broke loose, wrecked two enclosures completely. Thankfully, the research staff managed to seal themselves upstairs. We were ordered to clear the rooms and corridors. Three guards suffered bite wounds. I hope they’ll be okay. Hopefully, they'll finish those experiments on creating...</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_18_los_name">
	<text>Observation Log</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_18_los_name_desc">
	<text>The log describes experiments on human teleportation using the "TP-1" device.\n\n[Test Subject #9. Result: appeared halfway through the floor, fatal outcome. Cause: coordinate error.]\n\n[Test Subject #12. Result: torn apart during the teleportation process. Cause: system malfunction, additional calibration required.]\n\n[Test Subject #14. Result: successfully teleported to target coordinates, but collapsed dead within a minute due to exhaustion and severe bodily strain. Cause: unsuitable method of transfer.]\n\n[Test Subject #17. Result: after successful teleportation, the subject did not appear at the designated coordinates. Guards failed to locate the subject anywhere within or outside the facility. Cause: unknown.]\n\nFurther attempts yielded no successful outcomes. The experiments were called off.</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_19_aver_name">
	<text>Letter to Strelok from Pilgrim</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_19_aver_name_desc">
	<text>"Strelok, I’m leaving this note in case you come back to our old hideout. I found a path to the old village. After consulting with Fang, we decided to move there as a group. We took all the supplies with us — sorry, but Fang said not to leave anything for the Avengers. By the way, don’t bother looking for Shura the gynecologist or the others either — we took them too. It’s safer for them in the village."\n\nP.S. As compensation for the supplies, Cyclops left you a stash hint — naturally, in verse. Memorize it...\n\nIn endless hills where vastness roars,\nStand lone green pillars near open moors,\nBut no clear road will take you near,\nLet rain reveal the path unclear.</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_20_labx11_name">
	<text>Noosphere Project Documents, 1989</text>
</string>

<string id="item_doc_20_labx11_name_desc">
	<text>According to a report from Lab X-18, alpha-psi emission of biological origin was discovered during the study of sentient brains. I have no idea where Pyotr Kalugin gets his test subjects — and I don’t intend to find out. I want no part in this research after hearing what my colleagues described, even though their twisted in vivo methods yield impressive results.\n\nThey successfully tested IRCD-1 (individual remote communication device) — the "FIBER-1P" module — at the "Troposphere" communication station (TCS). As a side effect, they obtained data suggesting that psi-emission may be linked to a powerful external information field.\n\nCurrent issues:\n * Very limited range (no more than 50 meters)\n * Susceptibility to interference\n * Interference from a much stronger, unknown psi-source.\n\nBiological psi-emission has several internal, fundamental limitations unlikely to be overcome soon. The only obvious solution is to artificially grow a massive brain. Lab X16 has several volunteers for the project, including Professor Prihodko, but that path won’t lead us to the Noosphere. Until alternative approaches are found, we’ll focus our efforts on electromagnetic generation of psi-emission.\n\nObjectives:\n * Increase channel throughput\n * Create a "tunnel" to block interference\n * Expand the effective range\n\nThe team working on electromagnetic psi-emission modeling discovered beta-psi emission. A physical prototype will be presented shortly.\nPart of the team under Professor Chubko is working in Lab X10. They have already tested the "Rainbow," an omnidirectional antenna for psi-emitter with electromagnetic excitation.</text>
</string>


</string_table>