<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1250"?>
<string_table>

<string id="st_exo_recipe_1">
<text>Behavior of "Battery" Artifacts in Artificial Electromagnetic Fields</text>
</string>
<string id="st_exo_recipe_1_descr">
<text>A scientific paper written by V.R. Solenov and R.R. Romanovich, detailing the behavior and observed effects of Battery artifacts under various intensities of electromagnetic fields. At certain levels of EMP, the Battery emits short, intense bursts of direct current from the artifact, without affecting the field's strength. The text is very long and comprehensive, containing equations, graphs, black-and-white photographs, and test records. At the end of the paper, there are schematics on how to enclose such a Battery artifact to emit higher voltage when exposed to a positive current. The note bears the official seal of the Ukrainian Ministry of Science.\n\n
    %c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
    %c[d_green] • %c[ui_gray_2] informative\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] crafting recipe\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable\n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_exo_recipe_2">
<text>Observation and Analysis of the "Fully Empty" Artifact's Projective Gravitational Envelopes</text>
</string>
<string id="st_exo_recipe_2_descr">
<text>A scientific paper written by A.N. Perchenov and V.R. Solenov, detailing the observation of peculiar gravitational effects of the Fully Empty artifact. According to the document, the space between the Empty disks results from a partial spacetime distortion between the disks, creating a miniature gravitational anomaly. The contents of what is "full" in the Fully Empty remain unknown, with speculation that it is a visible form of air particles charged with highly excited zero-point energy. When exposed to alternating current of a specific amperage in a vacuum, the contents temporarily disperse, and the gravitational anomaly contained between the two disks expands to form an almost impenetrable "envelope," trapping and deflecting solid objects entering the space from their original trajectory. The discovery of this behavior allegedly injured four interns and two lab assistants when the correct configuration was found. The experimental record contains a diagram of the vacuum sealing device required to replicate this behavior.\n\n
    %c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
    %c[d_green] • %c[ui_gray_2] informative\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] crafting recipe\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable\n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_exo_recipe_3">
<text>Application of "Lightning" Artifact Fields to Engine Output</text>
</string>
<string id="st_exo_recipe_3_descr">
<text>A scientific paper written by R.R. Romanovich and A.N. Perchenov, detailing the peculiar effects that Lightning artifacts have on electrically powered machines. When the Lightning artifact is exposed to a positive electric current in a vacuum, it creates anomalous fields of varying size that significantly enhance the physical output of electric machines in the area—motors run faster, CPUs overclock, and even mechanical watches tick faster. Various experimental records emphasize the tendency for machines to overheat and wear out if the field is maintained for an extended period. Much of the paper speculates on what might cause such behavior, with the latest prevailing theory involving quantum-level influences that increase the flow of electricity and magnetic strength. However, these theories remain unconfirmed. In the middle of the paper is a diagram detailing the construction of the artifact containment chamber used in the experiments.\n\n
    %c[ui_gray_3]PROPERTIES:\n
    %c[d_green] • %c[ui_gray_2] informative\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] crafting recipe\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable\n</text>
</string>



</string_table>
