<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="stalker_duty_girl_name">
		<text>Anna</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_join_0">
		<text>I need an extra hand in the next mission. Can you help me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_join_1">
		<text>Sure. Lead the way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_join_2">
		<text>Aren't you having a good time with her? Sorry, I'm busy now.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_leave_0">
		<text>I think we should part ways for now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_leave_1">
		<text>Are you sure?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_leave_2">
		<text>Yes. There is something I must deal with alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_leave_3">
		<text>Nevermind. One second thought, two would be better.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_leave_4">
		<text>Alright. Good hunting. I will return to Rostok. Remember to drop by from time to time.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_actor_ask_companion_0">
		<text>We have different enemies and friends. Is there any way for us to hunt together?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_actor_ask_companion_1_lone">
		<text>My presence can convince the Ukrainian troops to leave you alone. But don't try anything stupid. I won't help if you piss them off. In return, make sure anarchists don't give me trouble. Then I think we can get along.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_actor_ask_companion_1_csky">
		<text>My presence can convince the Ukrainian troops to leave you alone. But don't try anything stupid. I won't help if you piss them off. In return, make sure anarchists and mercenaries don't give me trouble. Then I think we can get along.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_actor_ask_companion_1_army">
		<text>I can convince free stalkers and Clear Sky members that you're not a threat. You better act accordingly too. I won't help if you piss them off. Then I think we're fine to get along.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_actor_ask_companion_1_ecol">
		<text>You don't have many enemies, ehh? I think we can get along if you can convince anarchists and mercenaries to not attack me.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_random_chat_1">
		<text>Better stock up more ammo when we can.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_random_chat_2">
		<text>You know, you could leave the Zone. Settle down, start over, marry a girl...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_random_chat_special_1">
		<text>You don't look good. Better treat your wound soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_random_chat_special_2">
		<text>You have sight of radiation. Are you okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_random_chat_special_3">
		<text>A new day, and we are still alive. That's great.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_random_chat_special_4">
		<text>It's morning. Time to kick some mutant's asses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_random_chat_special_5">
		<text>Morning. I guess those freedoms are still dreaming of bloodsuckers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_random_chat_special_6">
		<text>Night is comming. The Zone is even more dangerous now but coming along is opportunity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_random_chat_special_7">
		<text>Night falls. Should we rest for while?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_companion_random_chat_special_8">
		<text>How many mutants you have killed today?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_chat_0">
		<text>I want to ask you something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_chat_1">
		<text>Yes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_chat_2">
		<text>Nevermind.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="duty_girl_chat_hunting_chimera_0">
		<text>You were eager to kill the chimera. It was because of your father?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_chat_hunting_chimera_1">
		<text>Yeah, kind of. You know, most of Duty members, me included, are those who lost their friends, their family to the Zone. Such memories won't be forgotten easily.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_chat_monolith_elite_0">
		<text>Those men seem to follow your commands.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_chat_monolith_elite_1">
		<text>I know medicine and usually help wounded people, so they seem to like me. Or maybe I'm not as strict as other Duty officers.</text>
	</string>
		
	<string id="duty_girl_chat_capture_the_brirge_0">
		<text>Why did the Monolith want to block the route?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_chat_capture_the_brirge_1">
		<text>They are monolithians. They always prevent people from reaching the center of the Zone. I think those we fought were fresh victims of the Brain Scorcher. Experienced stalkers will try to cross the Brain Scorcher's psy field to reach the center of the Zone. Many things could happen, mutant attacks that break their protection equipment, unable to cross the field on time, etc. The route is dangerous, but at the same time it also leads to new areas that haven't been scanned by anyone.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_chat_capture_the_brirge_2">
		<text>I saw there were some free stalkes joining us in the fight at the bridge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_chat_capture_the_brirge_3">
		<text>Maybe they were influenced by our action of reopening the route, having their friends stuck in the north, so they came to help. Or maybe they just came for the reward. Regardless, any help is welcome.</text>
	</string>
	
<!----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
	Quests
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------>
	<string id="duty_girl_first_meet_0">
		<text>It has been years since I last saw a girl.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_first_meet_1">
		<text>I guess you will see me around more often.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_first_meet_2">
		<text>I haven't seen you before. Are you a new recruit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_first_meet_3">
		<text>I joined Duty one year ago. It was a field recruitment. My father was a free stalker and I'm with him. One day, we were attacked by a chimera. I managed to survive by hiding in a truck cabin, but he didn't make it. He was killed when trying to protect me. Then a Duty expedition squad found and rescued me. So I joined them, since I had nowhere else to go and I want to revenge for my father. I have been trained and fighting alongside with them since then. Now our commission is over, we return to the base waiting for the next orders.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_first_meet_4">
		<text>What a sad story. I'm sorry to hear that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_first_meet_5">
		<text>I'm fine. Hey, you were the guy running around asking for work lately, weren't you? I'm currently in charge of some Duty's special operations. If you need work, I might have some for you.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_hunting_chimera_init_0">
		<text>Do you have any work that I can help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_hunting_chimera_init_1">
		<text>I'm going to go hunting now. There is a chimera that has been bothering Barman for a while. Join me and I will share you half of the bounty. See me at the Flea Market.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="duty_girl_hunting_chimera_move_0">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_hunting_chimera_move_1">
		<text>I just saw it chasing some bandits from distance. I'm glad to see you. It was a big one, I would have to abandon the mission if you didn't come to help. It must has returned to it's lair by now. Follow me and stay close.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_hunting_chimera_hunt_1">
		<text>Look. It is a black chimera.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_hunting_chimera_hunt_2">
		<text>It isn't aware of us. Good.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_hunting_chimera_hunt_3">
		<text>You better make the first shot count.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_hunting_chimera_hunt_4">
		<text>Phew! That was close.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_hunting_chimera_done_0">
		<text>The monster is dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_hunting_chimera_done_1">
		<text>You're tougher than I thought. I'm looking for some good fighters for my mission, and you're a good addition. I will explain it in details, but I think you should prepare some better gears. Here, take the reward.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="duty_girl_monolith_elite_init_0">
		<text>Do you have any work that I can help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_monolith_elite_init_1">
		<text>Yeah. There is one. Quite a dangerous one, I'm afraid. Just recently, a group of monolithians appeared in Army Warehouses blocking the path to the Red Forest. They aren't any monolithians, scouts reported that they are very well armed. People cry to reopen the route so here we are. We will gather at the abandoned house in the Army Warehouse. See you there.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_monolith_elite_join_0">
		<text>I come to join you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_monolith_elite_join_1">
		<text>Good to see you. Here is your supplies. Prepare yourself and tell me when when you're ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_monolith_elite_join_2">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_monolith_elite_move_1">
		<text>Buckle up men. It won't be easy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_monolith_elite_move_2">
		<text>Remember to keep your head down and follow my hand signals.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_monolith_elite_move_3">
		<text>Move.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_monolith_elite_move_4">
		<text>This is it. Good work, men!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_monolith_elite_move_5">
		<text>Damn, he was spotted.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_monolith_elite_move_6">
		<text>Everyone, attack.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_monolith_elite_done_0">
		<text>I come to collect my reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_monolith_elite_done_1">
		<text>Yeah, here you are. I knew I can count on you. Your contributions today will be known among Duty men.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_loot_stash_init_0">
		<text>Do you have any work that I can help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_loot_stash_init_1">
		<text>I haven't got anything yet. But perhaps you would be interested in this. You did well in the recent mission and I think the reward is quite underpaid. These are the coordinates obtained from the PDA of one of the monolith fighters. A stash, no doubt. No one has secured it yet, we have to prepare for the next move. So consider it a bonus for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_loot_stash_init_2">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_capture_the_brirge_init_0">
		<text>Do you have any work that I can help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_capture_the_brirge_init_1">
		<text>The Monolith has come again. They captured the outpost near the bridge in the Red Forest. We will drive them away, at the same time capture it and establish a forward outpost to maintain the route. Our rallying point is the bus stop in the Red Forest. See you there.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_capture_the_brirge_join_0">
		<text>I come to join you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_capture_the_brirge_join_1">
		<text>We scouted ahead. Our foe has less skilled fighters, but they come by the number. Spotted around 10 men but I'm sure they have backup hiding around. It will be tougher than the previous fight. Take your supply and be ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_capture_the_brirge_join_2">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_capture_the_brirge_move_1">
		<text>Be careful, they are even tougher than before.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_capture_the_brirge_move_2">
		<text>Don't advance too far. Stay together.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_capture_the_brirge_move_3">
		<text>Move.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_capture_the_brirge_move_4">
		<text>Looks like that was the last one. Good work, people!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_capture_the_brirge_move_5">
		<text>Damn, he was spotted.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_capture_the_brirge_move_6">
		<text>Everyone, attack.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="duty_girl_capture_the_brirge_done_0">
		<text>I come to collect my reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_girl_capture_the_brirge_done_1">
		<text>Thanks for your help. Our men are on the way here and the outpost will be operational soon. My mission is over. I think I will be idle for a while. If you need an extra hand in your missions, you just need to ask.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	
</string_table>