<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>

<!--
	Weapons
-->

<string_table>
	
<!-- [WPN] Weapon Base — База оружия для A.N.T.H.O.L.O.G.Y (Denis9x39) -->

<string id="st_wpn_m16a4">
	<text>M16A4</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_m16a4_descr">
	<text>The M16A4 is a 5.56?45mm gas-operated assault rifle. It is the latest modification of the legendary AR-15 rifle used by the U.S. Armed Forces. The fourth-generation M16A4 is essentially an M16A2 but with a flat-top upper receiver featuring a MIL-STD-1913 rail and a handguard optionally equipped with the M5 Adapter Rail System for mounting various accessories. The M16A4 is the standard service rifle of the U.S. Marine Corps and is used in some Army units. While most U.S. Special Operations Forces prefer its smaller sibling, the M4A1, or other 5.56mm carbines over the M16A4, the rifle is still in use by units such as the USMC F.A.S.T. and support units like the MARSOC Marine Special Operations Support Group (MSOSG).  

	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS:  
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] NATO suppressor  
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Optics: ACOG, Colt3x, pn23, Mark-4 CQ/T  
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] M203 under-barrel grenade launcher  
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_m16">
	<text>M16</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_m16_descr">
	<text>The M16 (official designation: Rifle, Caliber 5.56 mm, M16) is an American 5.56?45mm automatic rifle developed from the AR-15 and adopted in the 1960s. In 1964, the M16 officially entered service, replacing the M14. By 1966, it was the standard rifle for all U.S. forces in Vietnam. Initially, the M16 proved to be an extremely unreliable firearm. However, by the early 1970s, it had matured into a capable combat weapon with a number of significant advantages (and naturally, some drawbacks). Compared to its main global rival, the AKM, the M16 offered superior accuracy and precision in semi-auto fire and was more comfortable and ergonomic. On the downside, it required much more careful maintenance and higher-quality ammunition. In extreme conditions like dirt and dust, the AKM proved more reliable. The M16 and its variants remain standard infantry weapons for the U.S. military today. With over 8 million units produced, it is one of the most widely used rifles in the world.  

	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS:  
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] NATO suppressor  
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Optics: ACOG, ACOG-Trijicon, Colt, Mark-4 CQ/T  
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] M203 under-barrel grenade launcher  
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_kedr">
	<text>PP-91-01 "Kedr-B" Submachine Gun</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_kedr_descr">
	<text>The PP-91-01 "Kedr-B" is a submachine gun chambered in 9?18mm Makarov, equipped with an integrated suppressor. The PP-91 or "Kedr" (designed by Yevgeny Dragunov) was developed in the early 1990s for the USSR Ministry of Internal Affairs, based on the earlier PP-71. It features a 120 mm fixed barrel, chrome-lined for durability and corrosion resistance. The weapon supports both standard and special 9?18mm rounds. With the stock deployed and fired from a rest, the PP-91 can place four single shots within a 50 mm circle at 25 meters. It uses a hammer-fired mechanism and allows both semi-automatic and fully automatic fire, with no burst limiter. The fire selector is combined with a safety and is designed as a flat lever that can be easily operated even with gloves. The lowest position is safe: trigger and bolt are locked. Middle is semi-auto. Top is full-auto. Rate of fire ranges from 800 to 1000 rounds per minute. Effective up to 50 meters with maximum range around 100 meters. Due to its relatively weak cartridge, muzzle energy is low—around 295 joules.  

	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS:  
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] "Pion-M" laser sight  
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_eft_rsh12">
	<text>RSh-12 Heavy Revolver (12.7?55mm)</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_eft_rsh12_descr">
	<text>The RSh-12 is a rare large-caliber revolver developed for special forces. It uses a powerful 12.7?55mm cartridge capable of penetrating heavy armor and delivering devastating damage at close range. While it suffers from heavy recoil, low rate of fire, and significant weight, its massive stopping power compensates for these drawbacks. Ideal for mutant hunting and close-quarters combat.  

	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS:  
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Optics (rare): Micro T1, DeltaPoint, or RMR — via a top-frame rail adapter (if implemented in mod)  
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] PB-12.7 suppressor or custom "heavy suppressor"  
	</text>
</string>


<!-- [WPN] Weapon Base — База оружия для A.N.T.H.O.L.O.G.Y (Denis9x39) end -->



<!-- 
Grenades 
-->


<string id="st_grenade_f1">
    <text>F-1 Grenade</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_f1_short">
    <text>F-1</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_f1_descr">
    <text>Defensive anti-personnel hand grenade. Designed to inflict casualties during defensive combat. Due to the wide shrapnel spread, it must be thrown from behind cover.\n\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Blast power: %c[ui_gray_1]High\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Explosion radius: %c[ui_gray_1]4.2 m\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Shrapnel radius: %c[ui_gray_1]48 m\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Fragment count: %c[ui_gray_1]380 (fine shrapnel)\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Fuse delay: %c[ui_gray_1]~4 seconds</text>
</string>

	
<string id="st_grenade_rgd5">
    <text>RGD-5 Grenade</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_rgd5_short">
    <text>RGD-5</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_rgd5_descr">
    <text>Soviet offensive hand grenade. Classified as a timed, anti-personnel fragmentation grenade. Designed to injure or kill enemy personnel via high-velocity casing fragments upon detonation.\n\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Blast power: %c[ui_gray_1]Medium\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Explosion radius: %c[ui_gray_1]3.2 m\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Shrapnel radius: %c[ui_gray_1]43 m\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Fragment count: %c[ui_gray_1]240 (fine shrapnel)\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Fuse delay: %c[ui_gray_1]~4 seconds</text>
</string>

	
<string id="st_grenade_smoke">
    <text>Smoke Grenade</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_smoke_short">
    <text>Smoke</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_smoke_descr">
    <text>Handheld smoke grenade. Intended for creating a smoke screen. Deployment time: 10 seconds.</text>
</string>

	
<string id="st_grenade_thermite">
    <text>Thermite Grenade</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_thermite_short">
    <text>Thermite</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_thermite_descr">
    <text>Incendiary (thermite) hand grenade that releases extreme heat upon detonation (2200°C), thanks to a thermal reaction where powdered aluminum reacts with iron oxide, creating molten iron and aluminum oxide. Loaded with 600 or 800 grams of thermite compound.\n\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Blast power: %c[ui_gray_1]Medium (thermal damage)\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Explosion radius: %c[ui_gray_1]4.6 m\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Shrapnel radius: %c[ui_gray_1]None\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Fragment count: %c[ui_gray_1]None\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Fuse delay: %c[ui_gray_1]~4 seconds</text>
</string>


<string id="st_grenade_rgn_short">
    <text>RGN</text>
</string>	

<string id="st_grenade_rgo_short">
    <text>RGO</text>
</string>


	
</string_table>
