<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>


<string id="yan_stalker_sakharov_player_query_brain_scorcher">
    <text>Professor, I need a psi-helmet.</text>
</string>

<string id="saharok_brain_start_0">
    <text>Wait a moment, dear... Could you spare me another minute of your attention?</text>
</string>
<string id="saharok_brain_start_1">
    <text>Yes, yes? What interests you?</text>
</string>
<string id="saharok_brain_start_2">
    <text>Some of my suspicions are being confirmed... About X-16.</text>
</string>
<string id="saharok_brain_start_3">
    <text>How do I get into the X16 laboratory? Where exactly is the entrance?</text>
</string>
<string id="saharok_brain_start_4">
    <text>We’ve been interested in the X16 laboratory for quite a while... Well, more precisely, the device inside that generates radiation directly affecting people’s minds. I’m afraid I must disappoint you: you can’t break in without special psi-protection. The result will be tragically inevitable – even if you manage to avoid the horde of zombies around the entrance, you risk becoming one of them. This is very serious.</text>
</string>
<string id="saharok_brain_start_5">
    <text>What should I do?</text>
</string>
<string id="saharok_brain_start_6">
    <text>Now, the way to the laboratory is open to you... though, if the radiation source is not neutralized or weakened, you might not make it back... So, here’s the deal, esteemed one. Our calculations helped us pinpoint the approximate location of the emitter, and we’ve established that it’s in an underground facility. I’ve taken the liberty of marking the location on your map.</text>
</string>
<string id="saharok_brain_start_7">
    <text>Alright, I agree.</text>
</string>

<string id="saharok_brain_reward_0">
    <text>It’s done. The psi-radiation source in X-16 has been shut down!</text>
</string>
<string id="saharok_brain_reward_1">
    <text>You’ve done a wonderful job, Stalker! Shutting down the radiation allows us to outfit new expeditions and explore previously inaccessible areas. And also... from now on, we’ll follow a highly favorable pricing policy for you.</text>
</string>


</string_table>
