<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>

<string_table>
	<!-- Freedom trader -->
	<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_1_name">
	<text>Destroy the Mutants' Lair</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_1_text">
	<text>Sava asked to destroy the lair of mutants that have settled nearby.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_1_about">
	<text>There's a job, basically.\nEvery day it's getting more dangerous here. More and more dangerous mutants are nesting nearby, and we cannot let them breed here.\n\nYou will need to clear the area I mark on your PDA. Kill every creature you see. If you do, I won't forget it. So, are you in?</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_1_finish">
	<text>Thank you, stalker, thanks to you, we will be relatively safe. Here's your reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_name">
	<text>Business Proposal</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_text">
	<text>Sava needs the artifact %s for some experiments.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_about">
	<text>I'm interested in artifacts. Here's the deal: I give you a lead on a specific artifact, you bring it to me, and I reward you. Everyone's happy. So, what do you think?</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_fetch_about">
	<text>I need an artifact for some of my experiments. Anyway, we're looking for an artifact called %s. Are you in?</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_fetch_finish">
	<text>Good job, buddy. Here’s your premium reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_name">
	<text>Treasure Hunter</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_text">
	<text>It used to be yours, now it’s ours. Sava asked to steal important documents and deliver them to him.\nHe sent me the coordinates of their location on the PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_about">
	<text>I heard about a stash with some really interesting documents. I have no idea who owned them or where they might be now, but I’ll reward anyone who can somehow make sure these documents show up on this bar counter. Got it? I’ll send you the last known coordinates of the stash on your PDA. I doubt it’s a trap because setting someone up isn’t like messing with Sidrovich and ruining deals at the Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_finish">
	<text>Well done. Great job, stalker.</text>
</string>

<!-- Bandit trader -->
<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_1_name">
	<text>Commotion in the Village</text>
</string>
<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_1_text">
	<text>Recently, a pack of mutants attacked the gang that held one of the points in the Village, killing and eating them all.\nMoreover, the pack has now made it their lair.\n\nBurhan doesn't like this situation, as such a mutant lair scares off stalkers and poses a threat to the boys who aren't prepared to be in a place they used to walk around with no problems.\n\nThe mutants need to be destroyed.</text>
</string>
<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_1_about">
	<text>Here’s the deal: the local beasts from the Junkyard got into the Village recently. They ate the guys holding the position and made their lair by the road, bastards. Now the stalkers won’t go near it – they’re afraid, little chickens.\n\nAt this rate, no one will come here at all, and then how are we supposed to shake down the cash? Not from mutants, damn it.\n\nI’ve marked the location on your PDA. Go shoot the mutants, and you’ll get your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_1_finish">
	<text>Good job, damn! Here’s the cash. Listen, I see you’re a real guy, so I’ll put in a good word for you with the boss.</text>
</string>

<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_name">
	<text>Wet Work</text>
</string>
<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_text">
	<text>One of the fearless stalkers not only took out some of our boys but also pissed off Burhan by trying to rise through the ranks by messing with the guys. Burhan doesn't like this situation, so he asked to find this guy and "straighten things out with him".</text>
</string>
<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_about">
	<text>Here’s the deal: there’s a rat causing a lot of trouble. He’s taking out our boys and talking behind their backs, trying to raise his own status. That’s not how we do things around here, damn it.\n\nIf you take care of this scum, you won’t leave empty-handed. No matter what anyone says, Burhan stands by his word!\nYou’ll get a decent payout for the job... But make sure to handle it quietly, no mess.</text>
</string>
<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_finish">
	<text>Nice, you took care of that jerk! No doubt about it. Here’s your money.</text>
</string>

<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_name">
	<text>Get Some Meat</text>
</string>
<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_text">
	<text>The mutant meat supplies in the bandit village are running out, and right now, there aren’t many volunteers willing to go against mutants.\n\nBurhan asked for help with this so he can feed the boys. "%s" is what he needs right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_about">
	<text>If you’re a good shot and not afraid of mutants, I have a job for you. Interested?</text>
</string>
<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_fetch_about">
	<text>The food supplies are running low, and I need something to feed the boys. Some people bring me a mutant or two from time to time, but right now, no one wants to hunt. So, if you’re free and interested in work...\n\nBasically, "%s" would be very helpful right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_fetch_finish">
	<text>Good, here’s your reward:</text>
</string>


</string_table>
