<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>


	<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_1_name">
	<text>Find %s for Vilnov</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_1_text">
	<text>You need to bring tools to Vilnov so he can perform equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_1_about">
	<text>You know, buddy, I’m actually not a bad technician. I can fix weapons and armor, even do some upgrades! Well, I could, if I had proper tools. But where do you get them around here? Maybe you could help me get a basic toolkit, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_1_fetch_about">
	<text>I need a set of basic tools. It should have the instruments and oils for working with weapons. If you can bring it, I’ll be grateful, I might even pay you!.. Probably.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_1_fetch_finish">
	<text>Awesome, man! Oh, sorry, I’ve got nothing to pay you with. But I can give you a good discount!</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_2_name">
	<text>Find %s for Vilnov</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_2_text">
	<text>You need to bring Vilnov a set of fine tools. He needs a more complete kit to perform more advanced equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_2_about">
	<text>Hey man, if you agree to get me a more complete set, you’ll get an even bigger discount. Will you help, pal?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_2_fetch_about">
	<text>I need a set of fine tools. Everything I need should be in there. You’ll be like a brother to me if you bring it!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_2_fetch_finish">
	<text>Holy crap, thanks, bro! Now I’ll definitely get rich. Damn, I’ll finally be successful!.. If I don’t blow this chance too. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_3_name">
	<text>Find %s for Vilnov</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_3_text">
	<text>You need to bring Vilnov %s. He needs a unique set to perform even more advanced equipment upgrades.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_3_about">
	<text>Hey kid, if you find something really valuable – I’ll give you a discount!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_3_fetch_about">
	<text>I need a set of calibration tools. It should have everything I need. You’ll be like a brother to me if you bring it!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mechanic_furgon_pa_task_3_fetch_finish">
	<text>No fuc—! Damn, thanks, bro! Now I’ll definitely get rich. Hell, I’ll finally be successful!.. If I don’t blow this chance too. But for now, I can’t offer you anything better than a discount. Sorry, buddy.</text>
</string>


</string_table>
