<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>


	<!-- cit_trader -->
	<string id="cit_trader_task_1_name">
    <text>Business Proposal</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_1_text">
    <text>Filin needs the artifact %s. Just like that, no unnecessary words or questions. A real businessman!</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_1_about">
    <text>I am interested in artifacts. Here’s the deal: I give you a tip about a certain artifact, you bring it to me and get a reward. Both sides are happy. So, what do you think?</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_1_fetch_about">
    <text>My clients are interested in artifacts. Often, they’re just “bright minds” who had bad luck with connections, ones that official science personnel in the Zone have access to. So, here’s the deal: I give you a tip on a certain artifact, you bring it to me, and you get a reward. Both sides are happy. So, I need the artifact %s. I’ll wait for it here, along with your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_1_fetch_finish">
    <text>Well done, my friend. And here’s your bonus.</text>
</string>

<string id="cit_trader_task_2_name">
    <text>Dirty Work</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_2_text">
    <text>Filin gave me a dirty job – find and eliminate a stalker who managed to piss someone off.\n\nAll the necessary information has been provided by Filin on the PDA. Time to get to work. Tough luck for that poor guy...</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_2_about">
    <text>Sometimes stalkers come to me when someone has wronged them or done something really bad, and I, in turn, look for willing helpers to resolve the issue so certain individuals won’t have problems later on. Consider me a middleman.\nI currently have a few targets for elimination. Usually, it’s a stalker who betrayed or hired someone to betray their friends, but there are also the occasional contract killings of individuals from other factions. It’s dirty work, but someone has to do it, especially if the reward is worth it. So, what do you say? I’ll send the necessary information to your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_2_finish">
    <text>Thanks, stalker. Here’s your payment, but don’t get too carried away with killing. Mercenaries don’t like competition either. Heh-heh...</text>
</string>

<string id="cit_trader_task_3_name">
    <text>Mutant Bugs and Mice</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_3_text">
    <text>There’s a joke among stalkers: “A stalker planted a pseudo-turnip. It grew into a giant pseudo-turnip! The stalker took a grenade launcher and went to harvest it. Everything would have gone well if it weren’t for the pseudo-bugs and pseudo-mice.” Sounds funny, right? But sometimes those bugs and mice can really be a pain in the ass. It even gets to the point where you can’t take ten steps out of camp without being attacked by some pseudo-whatever!\nThat’s why Filin suggested combining business with pleasure – earn some money by clearing the surrounding areas of mutants. It’s the right thing to do, since there are so many of them around... And the trophies certainly won’t hurt.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_3_about">
    <text>By the way, did you see any mutants on your way here? The Duty guys recently swept the area, but the new stalkers said they saw either dogs or something else around the outer edges of the camp. If they’re not joking, these creatures could pose a serious threat to both the stalkers in the camp and those coming here. Not to mention the fact that a lack of clients is bad for business. So, here’s the deal: I’ll pay well for mutant elimination, and maybe even throw in a little extra. The main thing is to leave no trace of them. Here are the approximate coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_3_finish">
    <text>Good job. And here’s your well-earned pay.</text>
</string>

<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
<!-- cit_trader (Loner Trader) New Tasks -->

<string id="cit_trader_task_4_name">
    <text>Unusual Business</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_4_text">
    <text>As they say, the rich have their quirks. One such client, it seems, approached Filin and asked him to find a trophy – “%s”…\nFilin, in turn, promised to pay well for the delivery of the trophy to him so that he could send it to his client.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_4_about">
    <text>You see, I’m not only a busy person, but I’m also quite generous to those who want to help me solve my problems. And right now, I have an urgent order. Interested?</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_4_fetch_about">
    <text>Here’s the deal: one of my clients, an excellent jeweler specializing in animal trophies, wants one – %s. He’s willing to pay me a good amount for delivery. I, in turn, am willing to pay you for the initial delivery of the trophy to me. You get it, right? Make sure the mutant parts with its belongings and deliver them to me. I won’t shortchange you.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_4_fetch_finish">
    <text>Nice work! Here’s your well-earned reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="cit_trader_task_5_name">
    <text>Cache Raider</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_5_text">
    <text>What was yours is now ours. Filin asked me to steal important documents and deliver them to him.\nHe sent me the coordinates of their location on the PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_5_about">
    <text>I’ve heard whispers about a stash with some very interesting documents. I have no idea who owned it or where they might be now, but I’ll reward anyone who can make those documents miraculously appear on this bar counter. You get me? I’ll send you the last known coordinates of the stash on your PDA. I doubt it’s a trap, because setting up traps isn’t what Sidorovich does when he tries to cancel a deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_trader_task_5_finish">
    <text>You’ve made me happy. Excellent work, stalker.</text>
</string>


</string_table>
