<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>


	<!-- ----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- (Doctor) -->
<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_1_name">
    <text>Scientific Donor</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_1_text">
    <text>The Doctor is very busy conducting a series of experiments using tissue samples from the Zone's fauna. At least, he was busy until all available materials ran out.\nNow, he needs any help he can get to provide the necessary samples.\n\nI agreed to help him solve this problem. The “%s” needs to be found and delivered in good condition as soon as possible, while the sample retains its freshness. Otherwise, the Doctor won’t accept it.\n\nNow, I just need to find a donor who will provide this sample...</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_1_about">
    <text>I’m experiencing a severe shortage of required animal materials, and therefore, I urgently need an experienced hunter to gather certain samples. Can I count on you?</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_1_fetch_about">
    <text>I’ve been conducting a number of particularly important experiments in my laboratory related to the properties of certain fauna species.\nUnfortunately, I miscalculated my sample reserves, which are needed for unexpected circumstances and experimental deviations - I’ve used up the last available material I had.\n\nThese experiments are of great importance to the scientific community and myself, so I need to replenish the necessary materials. I need “%s”.\n\nLet me make it clear, I’m not interested in the details of how you gather the samples. You are free to go hunting, buy them from traders, or other stalkers. The only thing I require is timely delivery and the freshness of the materials. They will be of no use if they lose their freshness.\nOnce you gather everything I need, you’ll need to return here as quickly as possible. Are you ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_1_fetch_finish">
    <text>Just look at this! The samples have retained their freshness as much as possible! I’m extremely grateful, young man. Simply excellent work. I will immediately continue my experiments.</text>
</string>

<!-- Collect New Artefact Task -->
<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_2_name">
    <text>Scientific Progress</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_2_text">
    <text>The Doctor is conducting a series of, in his words, important research related to artifacts.\n\nUnfortunately, the professor has completely exhausted the material needed for highly accurate data. Because of this, he had to pause his research.\n\nHe asked me to find and deliver the artifact %s. He promised a good payment for its delivery.</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_2_about">
    <text>Would you help me with my research, young man? A monetary reward will not be long in coming.</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_2_fetch_about">
    <text>Simply splendid! You can’t imagine how much you can help humanity!\n\nAt the moment, I’m conducting a number of important laboratory studies, but I’ve used up all available material samples! Without it, the accuracy of the data and the selection is useless!\n\nI beg you, I urgently need the artifact %s so that I can immediately return to my research and continue it.</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_2_fetch_finish">
    <text>Young man, your eagerness to extend a helping hand to science in its time of need is simply invaluable. How I wish there were more people like you here! The scientific laboratory and I personally thank you for your help.</text>
</string>

<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_4_name">
    <text>In the World of Mutant Animals</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_4_about">
    <text>You see, our zoologist colleagues have attached tracking devices to several representatives of the local fauna so that we could obtain a full set of data about them: their movement, behavior, habits, everyday life, and so on. Unfortunately, I regret to inform you that after one of the recent anomalies, a couple of these trackers stopped working properly - they still transmit coordinates, but... alas, only those. No other data is available. So, you will need to find the target, extract the device manually, and bring it back here - there’s no other way, unfortunately. On the other hand, you’ll be able to help the Zone’s inhabitants get rid of a potential problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_4_stage_0">
    <text>According to the Doctor, the zoologists have been studying the lifestyles of various mutants using attached tracking devices. However, a recent anomaly seems to have damaged them - instead of all the data, scientists only receive the creature’s current coordinates. While the data is still being recorded on the tracker’s medium, the only way to access it is to find the mutant, eliminate it, and take the device.</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_4_stage_1">
    <text>Retrieve the device with the data dropped by the mutant</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_smart_terrain_doc_doctor_task_4_stage_2">
    <text>Return the device to the Doctor</text>
</string>


</string_table>
