<?xml version="1.0" encoding="Windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_hello_11">
		<text>What are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_kill_digger_traitor_1">
		<text>Hmm ... you need to think. So look. You need to remove one bar. If I agree to work, I will make the client at the old bus stop, which is behind the eastern wall. Will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_hello_11">
		<text>Well, what's there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_hello_11">
		<text>You ... ik! What do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_bandit_secret_0">
		<text>Yoga gave me the coordinates of his cache. He says that according to rumors there are now either monsters, or anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_bandit_secret_1">
		<text>According to rumors? Hahe! I know for that cache: this is, in kind, Yogin's favorite joke. Do you decide, you are the first, to whom he had adjusted the coordinates? There are already enough suckers, who were pushed for this stash. The latter, however, somehow thought out to fill up the psi-pill, which lived there, but then still grabbed thirty thousand volts with her ass. So, if you are storing more closely by him or a diving suit, it will easily take the Yogi reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_destroy_flea_market_0">
		<text>Yoga decided to clean the diggers from a flea market once and for all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_destroy_flea_market_1">
		<text>What? Did he tear off the tower? This is such a dairy cow! ... Well, everything, blah, count, the plowman was covered. Akela missed! The smugglers lay down, there will be no flea markets - and what will the diggers stream revive? Frive! It will pass for three months, there will be no one to knit the grandmothers with the boys with the boys, and what will the yoga say to them then? .. Well, nothing, nothing. Then I definitely have a couple of words to brothers. Oh, yoga, you yourself dug up the grave ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_hello_11">
		<text>Well?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_join_0">
		<text>How do I get to your brigade?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_join_1">
		<text>Once under the wing to yoga I wanted, yoga and ask. He sits in his carriage, suffering a garbage. There are such fools like you! Maybe you will change your mind, lamb, as you will send a little on it ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_kill_digger_traitor_0">
		<text>Yoga ordered me a man named Avoska. Do you know this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_kill_digger_traitor_1">
		<text>Nope, I didn't hear. Only my advice to you: do not forget to yourself, dear. The person, when he looks in the muzzle, becomes very generous ... Here you can do a blessing to fuck. The main thing is that the client squeezes his eyes as soon as possible, otherwise he will begin to regret the generosity and will not be beneficial for you, but a bunch of rotten layouts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_kill_smuggler_0">
		<text>Yoga ordered me some kind of smuggler and several of his diggers customers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_kill_smuggler_1">
		<text>Well, yoga is an evil Buratino for himself! Whatever the diggers got there, this would not really help them. We can squeeze them at any moment, only it is convenient to milk them. But with a smugglers - this is he in vain. What does he think that my goods appear from the air? .. Well, fucking, his problems.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_questions_0">
		<text>I have a couple of questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_questions_1">
		<text>Valya.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_questions_11">
		<text>What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_questions_111">
		<text>What I do, what I am doing ... I pour booze and kick the bolts, that's all things. I do a garbage, in short. I can steer from a youngster, not a girder to anyone! And here, damn it, you have to command the vodara bubbles ... The soul is sparkling! Yoga, bitch, faded: the point does not rise from the place! Boys like they work, but without a light, but what's the point? And I would find what to take everyone, but under the very form. If I had a plowman, I would have stolen such a thing - the zone was shaking, as if on a large emission! ..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_questions_1111">
		<text>Yes. I also wanted to ask ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_questions_1112">
		<text>Clear. Well, we've been chatted and enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_questions_12">
		<text>What's new in the zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_questions_121">
		<text>Well ... emissions are whining more often. The old paths are covered, the cards are now in a different way. A lot of new things have opened - and the scattering there, I think, are not athole. There are already a lot of their teeth to grind the piece to grab the piece! Well, what? If there is a concept and the guys are sensible, it's a sin not to stare a couple of farts for yourself ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_questions_13">
		<text>How do you get along with your neighbors?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_questions_131">
		<text>And in every way. According to concepts, only we live. And whatever they tell you about us - all the garbage. We are wolves, and the rest are sheep and bull. They live by lawlessness, and we graze them according to our modest forces. Look: a landfill, huh? Only who will find good in this heap of shit - everything rushed: stupid graters, a mess, they will certainly sew someone's thread ... And the boys will come and say: вЂњQuiet, sha!вЂќ. And it will be quiet. Because order and law. I'll tell you the truth of others, so far it doesn't work out, only the turn will also reach them. But this is all then, wait another to my other need ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_questions_14">
		<text>Although no, another time we chat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_barman_questions_141">
		<text>Laded.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_hello_11">
		<text>Darov, man! Do not want to shoot in crows?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_hello_111">
		<text>Want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_hello_1111">
		<text>Great. Of the options, I have a game for interest, for money or a record. What of this to your liking?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_hello_112">
		<text>No, not pulling.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_hello_1121">
		<text>Well, how you want. If what, I'm always here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_hello_21">
		<text>Here are your butteros, as promised. Everything is honest. Well, what else do you want to shoot?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_hello_31">
		<text>It happens to everyone. Maybe you still want to try?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_hello_41">
		<text>Where did you dump, man? Shooting behind the fence is your private business. Maybe you still want to shoot in all the rules here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_hello_51">
		<text>We will then be thrown - what does it tick, chop it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_hello_511">
		<text>Understood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_0">
		<text>For money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_1">
		<text>From these words I love! Well, according to the rules, you already do not need to wipe it, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_11">
		<text>So. Let's shoot already.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_111">
		<text>Not a bazaar, man! Well, what do you think, how many raven in a minute you have time to demolish?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_111111">
		<text>It goes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_1111111">
		<text>Get out. Well, man, prepare the trunk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_11111111">
		<text>Ug.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_111112">
		<text>I don't have so much money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_1111121">
		<text>Well, can you choose what you can afford?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_11111211">
		<text>Yes, I will choose another number of raven.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_11111212">
		<text>No, not interesting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_111112121">
		<text>Well, you can play an interest. Or on the record, the current really hit the pocket. What can you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_12">
		<text>No, tell me all the same.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_121">
		<text>For money is the most entertainment. You tell me, you'll end the raven in a minute, put butteros and forward. If everything is as it should, the kid said - the kid did, then you get your own back and the same amount from above. If not, my money. And keep in mind, the more birds, the more bets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_money_13">
		<text>Something I got sick of playing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_questions_0">
		<text>Are there any general rules?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_questions_1">
		<text>Yes, count, no. I cut my time, you are preparing and starting to extinguish at a signal. You will have time to remove as much as you need in a minute - the young man and the hero. And how you will extinguish them, this is your business. Take the current, you will go out for this fence - the game is over. Well, how - for interest, for money, for a record?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_quit_0">
		<text>Somehow nothing smiles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_quit_1">
		<text>How you want. If what, I'm always here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_record_0">
		<text>At the record.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_record_11">
		<text>Let's start.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_record_1111">
		<text>Agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_record_11111">
		<text>Well, right now, let's see which of you is the champion!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_record_1112">
		<text>I agree, but there is no money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_record_11121">
		<text>Well, there are simpler options: for money or at all for an interest. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_record_1113">
		<text>I ... changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_record_12">
		<text>Reminded the rules.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_record_121">
		<text>This is for real fathers. If you smell that it is strong to beat the current record - you are betting, well, adequately record. If you are in the nature of the record, I give these grandmas to you in double size. Well, the title of the champion for you is not the hell of the dog. Well, if not, then there will be butteros here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_record_13">
		<text>I ... changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_training_0">
		<text>Of interest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_training_1">
		<text>Training, right? Do you cut the rules?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_training_11">
		<text>Yes. Let's shoot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_training_111">
		<text>Lada. Well, how many raven do you master?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_training_11111">
		<text>Good. Well, come on, combine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_training_111111">
		<text>Ug.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_training_21">
		<text>No. Tell.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_training_211">
		<text>Well, for interest - if you don't want to get dough. So, practice, or if the mood is bad. You decide how many raven you will make in a minute, and try to do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_training_31">
		<text>I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_training_311">
		<text>Not a question. Well, the choice is the same: for money or on the record. What can you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_fixer_questions_111">
		<text>What is this "such"? I did not finish the academies, yes, but I have what I need! At the factory, at my best experts, I knocked out: you know how much it was given? And how I once again washed the award with the roots at lunchtime, the senior master, bitch, - he had a tooth for a long time! - I got us. Well, to the management, that, вЂњhow much you canвЂќ, вЂњaccurate productionвЂќ, вЂњyou will someday we will cut our orderвЂќ ... The factory was almost a license plate. So they fired, bastards. Then I was attached to ZhEU with a locksmith. Well, too: just that, only they call me. Special because! Respecting ali: the money is stuck there, the glass is poured. It was good! Only once with a Vitka-Santechnik, they were advised. Word for word, he is my mother, and I moved him in a screwdriver in the face. He remained alive, and I was in a strict regime LTP. I leaned back, I came home - the hut is empty: Lilka, wife, left, endured everything. So I untied the grief, fermented ... I even caught the squirrel. The hut, clearly, was licked, and bomzhazhavo, until he got here. And then they think for a person, because you can't drink talent. Well, in a love to the boys! Sometimes I can take a whiter and a little white, so keep you in mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_fixer_questions_121">
		<text>And then! Do not look that my hands are shaking: I didn't correct my health after yesterday. Here's how to pump a hundred drops now, everything will play! And be sure: I will make any better bitch-teething. What your soul wants, I can portray everything. Fix the barrel - with our pleasure. To knock the new Kevlar Bronir - yes for God's sake, it will be better to be new. Apr ... Ap -Grade - so that a good person would not help, fight for health. And you will pour a working person for the labors - so thank you to you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_fixer_questions_131">
		<text>Yes, I will see me, to be honest what is going on there. I feel good at the base. Dry law is not introduced, and okay. There is always work, but what else do I need? I don't need a woman to hell - one is a hassle with them ... The life, one might say, is established, so what other head to score all kinds of garbage? No, well, of course, everything happens ... you saw Kiryuhu - such, all in acne? His pimple is called. Well, since I didn't see it, it means that he crawled up grief again. In short, I somehow noticed: I began to run somewhere. The case, I think, is clear: I got a hope, not all the good gives to the common fund. Others also noticed, it came to yoga. He called the yoga acne to him: lead, he says, carrion, to his dike. The one: Pahan, so you, I'm not a rat, what I want to swear! .. Well, I led it anyway where to go ... In short, he picked up a blind dog and fed. Nobody almost talked with a pimple, they did not count for a person. And he is some kind of, but a living soul is needed. Yoga saw - brutalized. You say who warmed up, nits? The puppy, clearly, immediately a bullet, and the acne moved properly and the shares were deprived. Such a thing is life ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_fixer_questions_141">
		<text>And this is Senka, my bosom is friendly. How much we burned with a little white - you will not cross! We have lawy, you know, we are from the first day - the fisherman of the fisherman, as they say. Well, they drank like people for acquaintance. Then, however, they filled each other's face - they talked for life, argued Maleyo, well, and ... no, do not think! Senka is a mental man, although we, sometimes, are mutusing each other a little on a drunken business. But you can always talk to him when it's bad at heart. My only friend is real! ..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_fixer_questions_151">
		<text>Do you know such a thing - not to interfere with beer vodka? So with weapons, I answer you! Take one thread, but only one thing, understand? But then bring this business to ... to ... in short, so that only the ceiling is higher. It does not matter that - accuracy there or rate of fire - but do it to the very last point. And I tell you: with one hundred percent pumping, you will get more than if the little things, the fifth to tenth, rest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_hello_21">
		<text>I hope Avoska has already moved the horses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_hello_31">
		<text>The smuggler will not get alive in any way from the landfill. Only if the diggers receive weapons, you will specifically disappoint me. I expressed myself clearly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_hello_41">
		<text>The diggers are still on the flea market, and you are some kind of here. You surprise me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_hello_61">
		<text>Do you want to grind about something, or did you look out of politeness?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_hello_91">
		<text>I am all attention.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_first_0">
		<text>Will you take me to your brigade?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_first_1">
		<text>Take a hurry, cormorant! You will go through the check, then we'll trample. Only a real test, on the blood. I just have such a job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_0">
		<text>Well, now I'm mine or what? Will you take me to the brigade?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_1">
		<text>What are you dumb? I gave you a job? Gave. So do it, and there we'll already look.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_2">
		<text>You did work as it should, there are no questions. Yes, only it was very smooth for you that everything happened ... I suspiciously it for me. So you will twist in the zone, but for now I will bring inquiries. If everything is really clean with you, I'll light up to you on the PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_3">
		<text>I look that you are a вЂњfreedomвЂќ wolf ... And here is another flock, and the leader here is me. Ready to break with the old Codl?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_4">
		<text>You, how will I look, from the "Dolgovsky" visors ... And here on everyone is one elder - I, he was strewn? Well, what is really ready to replace their bosses to my authority?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_5">
		<text>I have my own ports, and in the brigade I have "brothers. You proved that not Fraer. So if you express such a desire, consider, you already walk under me. So I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_51">
		<text>Yes, he always dreamed of boy romance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_511">
		<text>You are still overlooking it. In the courses of our concepts?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_5111">
		<text>No. If it is not fallen, explain.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_51111">
		<text>In short, in the zoom of lawlessness: everyone wets whom he wants. And we live according to concepts and teach others, for which we remove our legal share. In the landfill, everything is in order, now the turn of the cordon. In order to close there, you need to knock out a stalker from there and show who is really power here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_511111">
		<text>All.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_5112">
		<text>I know the concepts, you can not strain.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_51121">
		<text>Oka, there is no bazaar. Your handicon is now tuned to our frequencies: you will always be in courses what and where the boys create and what layouts we have with other flocks. Well, what are you standing? I said everything! Walk, bro, not the corn of the eye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_511211">
		<text>I understood everything. I begin to pour into the team.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_join_main_52">
		<text>I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_kill_digger_traitor_0">
		<text>I would like to work for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_kill_digger_traitor_11">
		<text>I take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_kill_digger_traitor_111">
		<text>Great. The man is crying as a blade. Come on to the stop - I think that he will be in place for your arrival.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_kill_digger_traitor_1111">
		<text>Understood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_kill_digger_traitor_12">
		<text>No, the "wet" work is not for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_kill_digger_traitor_121">
		<text>Well, your business ... How do you change your mind - tell me. Who knows, maybe the little man will be alive at that time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_kill_digger_traitor_told_0">
		<text>I still decided to take up the work that you proposed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_kill_digger_traitor_told_1">
		<text>You are lucky: the client has not yet been capitalized. So, as I said, he will be at the old bus stop - this is near the road. Take him away. Yes, they cry it with a stroke, so do not confuse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_kill_digger_traitor_told_11">
		<text>Understood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_meet_greet_b_2">
		<text>Spit on my bald skull, whom I see!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_questions_0">
		<text>I would like to know something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_questions_1">
		<text>More specifically.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_questions_11">
		<text>Tell about yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_questions_111">
		<text>You are not a prosecutor and not a trace that I offer my life to you. You are a bastard bird, and I saw a lot of all kinds of birds while I knocked out into people. And he got out only because he was not Tryndel, and if he opened his mouth, then he thought well in advance. And in the bread to someone, if it happened, before and stronger than others he managed to attach.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_questions_1111">
		<text>Clear. I would like to know something else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_questions_1112">
		<text>I understand. There are no more questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_questions_12">
		<text>Are you not afraid that the stalkers will laugh and go to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_questions_121">
		<text>The normal man should only be afraid of one thing: what will become ... in short, unconventional, this is if for especially intelligent. And so I'm not afraid of anything and anyone. To keep the diggers in the landfill for the udder, I have enough strength. If a whole flock breaks on us, we still hang! And the new boys come to me to wait. We'll collect the good shobel, so we will immediately dump from this shit, we will settle on a decent base. And whoever lived there used to stop living, like that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_questions_13">
		<text>Are you generally interested in what is happening in the zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_questions_131">
		<text>One thing is swaying: the scudies of the warriors can come or the other who is ready for us to get the barrel. And all the other to the back and lower. Although these emissions-shymes, but how warriors with stalkers in the zone will vomit, sometimes I note. From all this you can fuck your interest. So I will move you an interesting bike. We had one fraer, the cook was called. Not because he cooked a khavka, but simply вЂњmeat grindersвЂќ thoroughly sensed with his fingers in a hundred steps. Well, he became a greyhound. I say that every day I save you from the fierce death, and the share of yoga gives me the same. I forgot who he was walking under, Lysha Line ... I called him, but immediately knocked into unconsciousness, but while he was lying, fingers to him, a bitch, crossed. Then the boys blindfolded him, twisted their hands and took him to the place. I decided this way: a hundred steps will pass - I'll leave alive, let the sixth. But he just did not go: just at his favorite "meat grinder" he ran into. There was a cook - the minced meat became. What? Do not pamper!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_questions_14">
		<text>Perhaps nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_questions_141">
		<text>Well done. You know less - you will live longer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_reward_0">
		<text>Do not you think that the reward over the past business will not pay for my risk?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_reward_111">
		<text>Not a fig seems to me, and so it is! SHISH? But you, I'll see so, a man grated, so I will tell you at one cache. Until the last ejection - the fact that the most infinite was - I recovered in that cache the barrel. And I will tell you the trunk, very special. This place after the emission covered it tightly, although one fraer pushed me before his death that there was not an anomaly, but just the creatures bred Docher. But the creatures of the local are also stirring specific, it is now hard to get there. The coordinates are reliable I will drive you, so if there is excess health, take a walk. You can come - take the good: count, I gave you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_reward_1111">
		<text>Well, let's see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_join_0">
		<text>You can't tell you, how to enter your group?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_join_1">
		<text>Ah, this Pahan decides. Go to the groin! His car in the hangar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_0">
		<text>Will you answer a couple of questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_1">
		<text>So!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_11">
		<text>How did you become such a mechanic?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_111">
		<text>What does вЂњlikeвЂќ mean? At least I did not finish the academies, but my hands were gold, at the factory there was the best specialist, a board of honor, bonuses and letters. I washed regularly with roots, of course. But our head, bitch, somehow burned us. And the plant was almost a number of rooms, they worked on the defense industry. Everything, fired, bastards. Well, I was attached to ZhEK with a locksmith. A little what happened - they only called me, special because. Well, the money is stuck there, and the glass is poured. It was good. And then with Vitka, a plumber, we got a little behind the bottle ... Word for word, well, I moved it with a screwdriver. He survived, and they gave me a strict regime. I leaned back, I came home - the hut is empty, Lilka, wife, left ... Well, I was so fermented from grief - I even caught the squirrel! The hut was stupid in stupidity, Bomzhevvo. So I got here. And here they think for a person, because I can do a lot. I, too, in a love of boys, sometimes I can take a natural product for work, so keep in mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_1111">
		<text>Yeah. Will you resolve another question?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_1112">
		<text>Clear. Well, enough questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_12">
		<text>Can you do something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_121">
		<text>And then! Do not look that my hands are shaking. I just have not yet corrected my health after yesterday. But now a little white is a hundred drops, and everything will play. And if Spock, I will work better than any bitch -teetical. That's what I want to have fun, without a bald! Fix the barrel - so to fix the barrel. Branding the new Kevlar to paste - yes for the sake of God, it will be better new. The upgrade will be needed - on you, fight for health, and do not forget transparently, pour in the hard worker for the labors.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_13">
		<text>Are you in the know at all, what is happening around?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_131">
		<text>Yes, I am a side of what is happening around. Dry law is not introduced, and okay. There is work, drink too, and I have nothing more to lose. My life, no matter how shit it is, will not change anything. So the fuck in vain to score a head with gossip? But everything happens here. Have you seen Kiryuha? Such, all in acne. His pimple is called everyone. Well, since I have not seen, it means that he crawled up grief. In short, somehow I noticed: Kiryuha, I went to run to our base. Well, I think Kiryuha started a dash, from walking, not all the good gives. Others also noticed. It got to yoga. He called Kiryuha to him. Well, he says, Padal, lead to a dile. Kiryuha is like this: Pahan, yes, you, I am not a rat ... led, showed. In short, he picked up and fed the Chernobyl puppy of the Chernobyl dog. Nobody almost talked with Kiryukha, they did not count for a person. And here no matter what, but a living soul. Yoga as I saw - brutalized. Who, he says, warmed up, nits? Well, the puppy is a bullet in the forehead, and Kiryuhu was chosen and deprived of their shares. Eh, life ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_14">
		<text>And what kind of comrade in the corner is forever sleeping?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_141">
		<text>And this is my most so friendly bosom, Senka. Oh, how much Vodara we burned together - you won't cross! We have fed up with him directly from the first day, as I am here. Well, they drank like people for acquaintance. Then the truth was filled with each other - they talked for life, so they argued Maleho. No, don't think, Semyon Ivanovich is a normal man, even though we even now sometimes get drunk each other. But you can always talk to him when it's bad at heart. My only friend is like that of Gerasim.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_15">
		<text>What characteristics can you advise to improve weapons?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_151">
		<text>Well, there is such a principle - do not interfere with beer vodka. No, without a bald. So with weapons. Take one characteristic, but only one, hear? And bring it to the ceiling. It doesn't matter that: either accuracy is there, or rate of fire, but improve to the very last possibility. And with such one hundred percent pumping you will achieve more than a few, but improved half.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_16">
		<text>And, okay, enough questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_tech_questions_161">
		<text>Well, I am always ready to talk to hearts, you will keep in mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_join_0">
		<text>How would I join your clan?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_join_1">
		<text>In yoga, ask! Only he leads such issues. It can not be difficult: the вЂњbossвЂќ and вЂњregistration of routesвЂќ will not notice the blind, hehe!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_questions_0">
		<text>Do you want to chat until there are customers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_questions_1">
		<text>Yes, easily. What is the bazaar about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_questions_11">
		<text>Tell about yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_questions_111">
		<text>Uh, brother, I drove commerce at the Union! There was this ... who "damned speculators." He burned on a serious deal, well, and received in full. He won that he was awarded, and at the same time he also brought acquaintances among the people of Vorovsky. As he leaned back, he began to work with the crocks, to take them mining. For three years, they tied it again, and went out, so the вЂњscoopвЂќ had been covered for a couple of years. Something did not grow together with the new orders, I had to work for a long time, impoverished at all, and then the bam - the zone painted. I come here, and here is Lafa: almost everything is like in the old days! With my experience, now it is traded here - that's it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_questions_1111">
		<text>I understood the thought. Tell me anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_questions_1112">
		<text>Understood. Well, stop flueping their tongues.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_questions_12">
		<text>What do you think about yoga?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_questions_121">
		<text>I will say that: there is no yoga left in the ace of yoga for long. I feel the chubby: Borov will sit it, will give it to the fullest. Everything goes to that. Pahana lifted his nose without measure, only one show off. The snake warmed up, but he does not notice that the good half of the boys is already clear. I'm not telling you this so that you are now dazzling to the left and right: I showed you trust so that you could believe me. Yes, so if you come across something interesting, drag me to me. Keep in mind that I am with yoga, that with a wart in my place I always register.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_questions_13">
		<text>Tell me about the landfill.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_questions_131">
		<text>Yes, the boys here, in this parach, dragged themselves without much joy. After all, after all, even here they didn't even divert: garbage is here, radiation ... And then it was finished with a couple of stalkers to dug the things of the expensive. And all - the little people rushed here from the entire zone as sores on the old kurva. The mess was happening complete, but then our boys put the order. The main thing is that the hand is strong and the trash holds this firmly. And the zone should be like a zone: either red garbage or black thieves. Here the boys here are black suit. The hedgehog is clear that you need to pay for the order. The boys also want to eat, so they are supposed to be a share from everything. Eh, and to me, although it's not sour here, all the hunt to get to the places of glory ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_questions_14">
		<text>What are the latest news in the zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_questions_141">
		<text>I do not like such words - "Latest news." And you insert them less, so that in kind the news does not get onto the news, which will be the last for you. Although our creatures are not so dumb here, but the other day there was one story ... In short, the stalker tuned the same - white as a wall, his hands are shaking ... With some horseradish began to confess. The topic is this: he was washed off with a friend from the poltergeists, and then the ox falls on them. Well, the guy was stirring, the reflex turned on, he turned on, he was a friend obliquely and put it. He himself, clearly, immediately gave the deru, and the carcasses rushed to the body: well, to run for the meat to run when there is a ready? Well, then on the second bubble of vodka his consciousness turned on, he and let's howl to the whole landfill: вЂњIgoro-oo-oh, you gave me the only first a first-aid kit, and I, like a bitch, like the last creature, finished you! ..вЂќ. In short, I hung up, and hanged on a belt at night. Such circumstances with people are happened ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_questions_15">
		<text>Yes, about anything, probably.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_questions_151">
		<text>As you want, yours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_attack_0">
		<text>About the attack of a concentration camp ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_attack_1">
		<text>Listen. I have a long -standing dream: to give a worthy rebuff to the bandits, to press them as they pressed us. The main problem is that the diggers are intimidated and do not believe that this is possible. Before their eyes, there is a prospect of being in a concentration camp, so the desire to do something immediately disappears. So, the only way to realize my dream is to make the diggers believe in victory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_attack_11">
		<text>And how do you plan to do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_attack_111">
		<text>I want to free the diggers from the concentration camp, and to equalize the concentration camp with the ground. Then the diggers will understand that the bandits are not omnipotent. It will be like a symbol, like a storm of barracks of Moncada! To do this, I needed a weapon - so that the group of my guys had at least some chances in battle with the bandits. But this chance is small, because I am very asking you to stand at the head of my guys. You are an experienced fighter, you will definitely succeed with you! So will you help us in the right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_attack_1111">
		<text>Attack a concentration camp? I will help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_attack_11111">
		<text>No wonder I believed in you! Look: these are the coordinates of the point where my guys should already be with a weapon from the caches. I will contact them now and tell you that you are going to them. Neither fluff nor pen!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_attack_111111">
		<text>To hell.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_attack_1112">
		<text>Somehow your speeches do not inspire me. I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_attack_11121">
		<text>What is there to think! Either the diggers will unite, or over time, the bandits will take away all power! And when they trample outside the landfill, the whole zone will quarrel, and you too! Well, man, come on! In the attack of a concentration camp, you are our only trump card!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_attack_2">
		<text>The concentration camp needs to be attacking! This is the only way the diggers will understand that they are power! Will you help us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_break_0">
		<text>Goodbye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_0">
		<text>Medical complex, you say ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_1">
		<text>Yes, as it is written in the instructions, "Field set of quick -action medicines." He dug him in one caches of the appearance of the zone. This is probably still from some of the first scientific groups. As for me, horseradish is quite valuable, but no one takes it in two thousand - too unhealthy amount for a simple digger. Listen, man, buy, huh? I need money desperately!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_11">
		<text>Medical kit for two thousand? Okay, come on. Come in handy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_111">
		<text>Man, you know me how to help out! Here is your medical complex. You know ... Eh, damn it, with conspiracy! Maybe I'm doing stupidly, only it seems to me - you can trust you. You see, I lacked these two pieces to buy a batch of weapons from a smuggler. Now I can at least somehow arm my guys!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_1111">
		<text>Um-g. And what does trust have to do with it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_11111">
		<text>The fact is that Avoska just now went to meet with a smugglers. If he had these two thousand, he could not just stare these trunks for us, but immediately pick them up. In general, I ask you to take this money into a stroke. Here are the coordinates of the meeting place, I will now light up to him to be waited. But anyway, hurry up, Lada?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_111111">
		<text>Laded.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_1111111">
		<text>Well, if I were not mistaken in you. Thanks in advance!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_11111111">
		<text>There is nothing for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_111112">
		<text>More times repeat, that need do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_1111121">
		<text>Two thousand string bags must be attributed, who is waiting for a smuggler.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_11111211">
		<text>Understood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_111113">
		<text>I will think.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_1111131">
		<text>N-yes ... I hope I was still not mistaken in you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_11111311">
		<text>Hope dies the last.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_112">
		<text>It would be happy, but we recently decided that we turn all the large things at the flea market only at night, when there are no extra eyes and ears nearby. So come when it gets dark. The medical complex will wait for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_12">
		<text>I will buy. I'll collect two thousand, and buy it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_121">
		<text>Man, if you buy, I will be grateful to you by the coffin of life! Just keep in mind: such large transactions only occur at us at night when there are no extra eyes around. I myself introduced this rule, therefore, it should adhere to it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_13">
		<text>I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_131">
		<text>Christmas trees, man, well, nowhere to take more money!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_2">
		<text>Yeah, in just two thousand! I would give it cheaper, only I need at least two pieces ... do you buy?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_3">
		<text>Exactly. Have you already got two pieces?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_31">
		<text>Got it. Give your medical complex.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_32">
		<text>Not yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_bring_money_321">
		<text>Eh ... Well, the medical complex is waiting for you. And how I wait! All the same, I have nowhere to take more money from now on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_11">
		<text>Drive, man, and without you is sickening! The weather is shitty: no matter what day, it rains. Zero production: all rich places either under bandits or under monsters. At least something you will do, so you can take out from the landfill - they will take it away. Also, some kind of horseradish freshness and the guys were sank ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_111">
		<text>Can I help something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_1111">
		<text>Help, you say? And the devil knows if you can trust you. Although ... I still have no much choice. I desperately need one thing from Digger named Fresh. If you suddenly really want to help ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_112">
		<text>Well, these are your personal problems.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_1121">
		<text>Yes, yes, everyone does not care about everyone ... Oh, fresh, where are you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_12">
		<text>Ehe-he, my share is heavy ... Where did this freshness go, unkn the it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_13">
		<text>So, man, you just asked about help, or is it really ready to help freshly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_14">
		<text>So, did not look at the freshness?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_15">
		<text>Well, so, did not bring the old PDA of freshly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_21">
		<text>Didn't you think of buying a medical complex? Understand, man, if I had not urgently needed money, I would give this business so differently!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_22">
		<text>Well, it turned out to be assembled on a medical complex?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_31">
		<text>Take these two pieces as a hose, yeah? I believe in your honesty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_311">
		<text>It pleases.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_32">
		<text>Man, why are you spinning here! The string bag is washed off, bastard!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_321">
		<text>He will not go anywhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_33">
		<text>Man, are you left the KPK Avoski there? Yes, this is the only thread that connects us with that party!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_331">
		<text>Understood. Be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_34">
		<text>Did you bring the CPC a smuggler? Thank you ... Damn, for sure, the smuggler himself Avoska to the bandits and handed over! Ehh, here believe the people after this! After all, a string bag himself was sitting in a concentration camp, but still the skillful interest was stronger ... Okay, this is all in the past, like a string bag. By the way, my guys have already taken the weapon from the caches - weapons to attack the concentration camp. I think now I can tell you about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_342">
		<text>Just keep in mind: I have already freed the diggers from the concentration camp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_51">
		<text>Well, we, consider, are ready to attack the concentration camp. Tell you details?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_52">
		<text>A man, it is pointless to attack a concentration camp without you. We are diggers, not soldiers! Fighters from our guys are bad, they are not familiar with tactics. So, they can cover with non -intended fire. With you, this is already some kind of power. Listen, I ask you ... Can you lead the attack on the concentration camp?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_53">
		<text>Come on, man, my guys are already waiting for you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_531">
		<text>I went. Be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_54">
		<text>Man, what are you doing here?! Our guys are dying there!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_55">
		<text>Eh, man, I feel, I have already died our fighters ... Try to take revenge on them. Beat these freaks in a concentration camp, free our!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_61">
		<text>Listen, man, life is not such a bad thing!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_hello_71">
		<text>Eh, my life is my tin ... why are we so?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_0">
		<text>About Fresh ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_1">
		<text>Yes, look, what a situvina: freshly - he is from our Digger brotherhood - had to bring me his old PDA, but disappeared somewhere. And he himself does not appear, and no one comes out of his group, but I need this crap right now! I myself would have staggered or send a string bag, only we, as luck would have it, should stick out here in the near future. Maybe you will come out to bring this PDA to me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_11">
		<text>Can. Where can I find this freshness?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_111">
		<text>Where to find him is the devil knows him, he is a free person. But his camp south is from here, behind the tanks and mountain of trash. If the fresh is there, you will tell him that you are from the wild. Well, even if he doesn't, you climb into his tool box, the same PDA should lie under the second bottom. Under my responsibility. Remembered?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_1111">
		<text>I remembered.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_11111">
		<text>Here is the gut.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_1112">
		<text>You know, I was in that camp. Not a single living soul and a bunch of corpses torn to shreds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_11121">
		<text>Ah, M-mother, and them too! .. You see, some crap wanders around the landfill at night and attacks those who are poorly armed-that is, on us, the digger. And, most importantly, no one has survived yet, no one will tell you who it is and what. Digger's life, the stepmother is non -shaped ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_111211">
		<text>Since this is happening, now it's certainly not the time to regret yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_1112111">
		<text>That's right, you're right ... so remembered where to get the PDA?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_11121111">
		<text>I remembered.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_1112112">
		<text>Yes, you're right ... So, there is an old PDA of freshly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_1113">
		<text>So, come on again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_11131">
		<text>In short: in the camp of freshly, south of here, behind the tanks and mountain of trash, you need to take the old PDA and bring me. Take the PDA either at the freshness himself, or in a box with his instruments.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_11132">
		<text>In a word, in the freshfire camp - this is south of here, behind the tanks and mountain of trash - you need to take the old PDA from the tool box and bring me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_12">
		<text>You know, somehow there is no desire to work as a boy on the run.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_121">
		<text>Yes, I ask you humanly for help, and you ... uh!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_2">
		<text>Yeah, where did they go there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_21">
		<text>And the devil knows them. I haven't looked at them yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_211">
		<text>Listen, man, I really desperately need the PDA! Look at them, be a friend.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_3">
		<text>CPC you have, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_31">
		<text>Yes. Here, hold.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_311">
		<text>Man, you just saved me! Here, hold on to the labors. TEK-S, now we'll look ... Damn, only one and a half things! It can be seen that he was not paid for the last order ... So ... You see, I and I, a bright memory, used this PDA to transfer money to each other. So, now I desperately need finances, and the freshness could not collect how much he promised. Now we need to get two more pieces somewhere, and I already scrape everything that I could!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_3111">
		<text>There are grief in life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_31111">
		<text>Although wait! I have one thing - a cool medical complex, I have not found a buyer for it yet. Maybe he will interest you? I generally wanted to sell it for three pieces, but since such things, I'll give you in two. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_32">
		<text>There is no so much with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_leader_old_pda_321">
		<text>Listen, since freshly with his guys broke into shreds - the world of their souls - well, I just need blood from the nose of the PDA. Bring, be a man!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_messenger_hello_dialog_11">
		<text>Yes, I meant everything in mind, while these bastards are fumbling here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_messenger_hello_dialog_21">
		<text>Eh, brother, Digger's life is hard ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_hello_11">
		<text>Ah ... eh? What are you? You don't see something, I rest!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_hello_21">
		<text>Um-mm ... Leave me ... Let me sleep ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_hello_31">
		<text>Are you from yoga? .. Damn, well, finally! What have you pulled with the calculation for so long?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_hello_41">
		<text>Yes, yes! I'm already running! Now I will only check something so as not to run into yoga people, and immediately go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_hello_411">
		<text>Come on, come on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_kill_0">
		<text>We will not pull anymore. Yoga asked to pay you completely.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_kill_1">
		<text>That's great ... Hey, hey man, wait! Yoga, decided to get rid of me?! You ... you, don't shoot! I'll pay you more! ..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_kill_11">
		<text>How much?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_kill_111">
		<text>N-well, e-it ... I don't know how much yoga promised you, that then I have the coordinates of the cache of one smuggler! There should be a batch of goods for five pieces!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_kill_1111">
		<text>Five pieces, you say? Then give the coordinates and so that no one else saw you here. Do you understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_kill_11111">
		<text>P-nuclear! Of course I understood! A cache in the trunk of a rusty sharpener, here ... Here are the coordinates! Thanks to T-Teba, man! I will leave with my paths, no one will see me, I give a tooth! So I ... I ran, yeah?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_kill_111111">
		<text>Cheshi is still intact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_kill_1112">
		<text>A cache with goods, right? Gather trick. Bai-Bai.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_kill_12">
		<text>Not interested. Bai-Bai.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_smuggler_0">
		<text>They told me you can arrange a meeting with a smugglers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_smuggler_1">
		<text>And, is it sent to you for weapons? Well, yes, I can. Look: I usually intersect with a smugglers near one of our excavations, to the west from here. Keep the coordinates. The smuggler should now be somewhere in those parts, so go, and for now I'm lighting up for him to suit him. Money with you? That's glorious.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_digger_traitor_smuggler_11">
		<text>Yeah, I understood the thought. Be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_bandits_0">
		<text>Not afraid of the raid of bandits?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_bandits_1">
		<text>I'm afraid of course. What to do? After all, you need to live somehow. True, we are already taught caution: in the afternoon we have only any trifle on the shelves, so as not to attract excess attention. And then we try not to move much and breathe less. You know, God takes care of the aged.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_goods_0">
		<text>What are you trading?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_goods_1">
		<text>Yes, all sorts of trash. You know that the last time I dug, then I sell it. Well, according to the little things there, which was made. Still, in the Barter zone - great power!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_hello_1">
		<text>Healthy! Are you interested in something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_market_0">
		<text>What is this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_market_1">
		<text>This is a guy, a flea market, and here we are, respectively, flea markets. We trade in the extinct than God sent ... True, I'll tell you, my goods really have a frank junk. But at least somehow I flounder ... And how did you - have come to trade, or so?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_traders_0">
		<text>Are you the only merchant here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_traders_1">
		<text>No, what are you! Here, other guys are injected, we just have a rule: large transactions - only after sunset. In the afternoon, yes, I am trading alone: вЂ‹вЂ‹I have an inexpensive product and a little it. But at night, real life begins here, because the product is already completely different.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_evening_trader_rest_0">
		<text>default text</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_evening_trader_rest_1">
		<text>text in default</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_evening_trader_rest_11">
		<text>A?! What, Schucher? .. Damn, rushed me! What you do not see - I sleep.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_evening_trader_rest_111">
		<text>Well, Izvini. Goodbye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_evening_trader_trade_0">
		<text>default text</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_evening_trader_trade_1">
		<text>text in default</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_evening_trader_trade_11">
		<text>Healthy, boy! If you need to, you say, do not be shy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_evening_trader_trade_111">
		<text>text in default</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_rest_11">
		<text>Something you are early. Not the time for serious matters, I understand? You ... Look later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_rest_111">
		<text>Understood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_11">
		<text>Good night! Interested in something specific?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_111">
		<text>Behind him, relatives. Show.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_112">
		<text>No, just to chat with you. Be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_21">
		<text>What are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_211">
		<text>I would have to bargain. Is there a desire?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_2111">
		<text>To bargain? Who are you at all?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_21111">
		<text>I see you don't need money. Okay, I'll go to the floor of the floor above: they have enough questions not to ask such questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_211111">
		<text>Wait, man! You say you know the guys from above? Well, they will not deal with anyone ... I have a product. Show?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_2111111">
		<text>That's how it would be right away. Show.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_21112">
		<text>Not your business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_212">
		<text>Honest Barter. Do not know the merchants nearby?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_2121">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_21211">
		<text>Not a single one?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_212111">
		<text>Yes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_2121111">
		<text>Sure?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_21211111">
		<text>Sure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_212111111">
		<text>Man, I'm not a bandit. Not a military man. Not zombies. Are you a merchant or who?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_2121111111">
		<text>Dealer. Will you ask the goods or ask questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_21211111111">
		<text>Watch the goods. Show.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_21212">
		<text>Then come.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_night_trader_trade_213">
		<text>Nothing from you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_commentators_11">
		<text>Damn, from this feathers fly when you extinguish from a vertical! Well, finally! ..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_commentators_111">
		<text>Ahem ... I'll go like something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_commentators_12">
		<text>What, man, do you hate the feathered? Do not strain, there are many of us here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_commentators_13">
		<text>Well, what are you standing? Come on, urine of creatures, so that bloody scraps in all directions!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_break_0">
		<text>Goodbye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_robbery_11">
		<text>Well, get a bun, it's time to share a habar. Do not think, it's not just like that: this is a fee for us that we are protecting the law and order in the landfill. Suffer?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_robbery_111">
		<text>Well, if for order, then hold on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_robbery_1111">
		<text>From this sensible fraer! Well, so I'm taking it all, yeah? You, if there is a pistol, leave yourself, you can. We are not animals - the last to select, we have everything according to the law! As you run into the creatures, you will remember us with a kind word. Well, the tablecloth is the road! Kit sausage!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_robbery_11111">
		<text>And you are goodbye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_reward_0">
		<text>I came for a reward for stripping a flea market.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_reward_1">
		<text>Ah, there is such a thing! Hold on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_reward_11">
		<text>Hmm. Isn't it not enough for a serious matter?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_trader_reward_111">
		<text>I am not deciding, he has ahead? As much as Pahan said, I give out so much ... And if it's a hint that I have clamped, then I'll put you on the peak for such a way. In truth, in kind, the yoga threw little yoga. You're here, you go to him. All boys know, you worked clearly, so if the yoga does not want to exhibit before the brother, he will still put it on top, he will not go anywhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_hello_11">
		<text>Healthy! Are you interested in something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_hello_11111">
		<text>What is this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_hello_111111">
		<text>This, a guy, is a flea market, and we are on it, respectively, flea markets. We trade in a freeze than God sent ... True, I'll tell you, our goods are mostly frank junk in the afternoon. But although we are not on the wave, but we are still fluid quite vigorously. And what - did you come to trade, or so, from the bay -bary?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_hello_11112">
		<text>What are you trading?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_hello_111121">
		<text>Yes, all sorts of trash. What for the last time I got, I sell it. Well, according to the little things there, which was made. Still, in the Barter zone - great power!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_hello_11113">
		<text>Are you the only merchant here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_hello_111131">
		<text>No, of course! Here the other guys are shaking. We just have a rule: large transactions - only after sunset. So in the afternoon I am trading - I have an inexpensive product and a little it. But at night here the very life begins: the goods are already completely different, and the people are more conversational.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_hello_11114">
		<text>Not afraid of the raid of bandits?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_hello_111141">
		<text>I'm afraid of course! And what to do, you somehow need to live? True, we are already taught caution: in the afternoon we have one little things on the shelves, so as not to attract excess attention. And then we try not to move much and breathe less. You know, God takes care of.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_flea_market_24h_trader_hello_11115">
		<text>Nothing so far. Be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_bookmaker_hello_61">
		<text>Finally shot normally! You should play the Babos - it is. Well, do you still want to shoot?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_robbery_12">
		<text>Well, pull the PDA, it's time to share the Babos. Do not think, it's not just like that: this is a fee for us that we are protecting the law and order in the landfill. Suffer?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_robbery_121">
		<text>Well, if for order, then hold on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_robbery_1211">
		<text>From this sensible fraer! Well, so I'm taking it all, yeah? And leave your own yourself, you can. We are not animals - I will take away the trunks and the equipment, we have everything according to the law! As you run into the creatures, you will remember us with a kind word. Well, the tablecloth is the road! Kit sausage!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_robbery_12111">
		<text>And you are goodbye.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_100">
		<text>Hello. How are you? Do you like to shoot at ravens? I can argue that you will not beat my record.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_200">
		<text>Ah, is it you again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_210">
		<text>Do you want to try to beat the record again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_211">
		<text>First explain the rules to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_2110">
		<text>The rules are simple: you need to knock down the possible number of raven in one minute with the help of your weapon. Just do not go far, otherwise I will not count.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_212">
		<text>And what is the record now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_2120">
		<text>Current record 0</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_213">
		<text>Let's shoot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_214">
		<text>No, thanks. I will probably go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_220">
		<text>I said that you would not go far. Not counted.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_230">
		<text>Time has passed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_231">
		<text>Congratulations, you broke the record.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_232">
		<text>Unfortunately, you could not do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_300">
		<text>Do not waste time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_crows_per_minute">
		<text>Think</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_money_stake">
		<text>Well, then the bet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_record_crows">
		<text>This is the choice of a real kid! You need to have time to take as many raven as possible in a minute. Record now</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_dialog_record_stake">
		<text>Well, with this record, the rate is equal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_game_get_ready">
		<text>Get ready!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_game_runned_out">
		<text>You got out of the zone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_game_time_is_out">
		<text>Time has passed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crowkiller_game_crows_killed">
		<text>The raven was killed:</text>
	</string>

</string_table>

