<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_0_txt">
<text>Well, gloomy. How did it happen that you survived, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_1_txt">
<text>I could not die before you, freak.</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_2_txt">
<text>Ha ha ha! Yes. You, as before ... you are trying to joke - with a serious face. Nothing has changed.</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_3_txt">
<text>You laugh when I send you and your friends to hell.</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_4_txt">
<text>Oh, what are you? When did you manage to become so cool? What will you do to us, an idiot. And who else? So, Athena, right? Oh-ho-ho! So she is from the SBU. Do you know who set you up and asked the military to bang? Not the headquarters, no. I made her. I told her to do it. Do you understand?</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_5_txt">
<text>Who are you arranging a circus here?</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_6_txt">
<text>Before you, buddy! To whom else? Ha ha ha ... let me guess, do you want to dump from the zone? Fly away on the helicopter? Into a happy life? Did you want to go home? So you have no one there. What do you do there? Stay! We will find you use, do not worry.</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_7_txt">
<text>Yes, you went to hell. Why am I not dead yet? Put me a bullet in the forehead, I'm tired of listening to your nonsense.</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_8_txt">
<text>Kill you - it would be too boring, understand. You are such a useful resource ... And I know how to make you do dirty work, as in the good old, huh? Hehe-heh.</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_9_txt">
<text>At least try - I will not work for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_10_txt">
<text>Yes? Ha ha ha. Have you heard the guys? What kind of boy here is serious ... And if we do otherwise? For example, she will kill her, but will we make you to find her corpse? How is the idea? A?</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_11_txt">
<text>Stupid. Stupid. Anything else? I'm already tired.</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_12_txt">
<text>And if this woman really helps you get out of the zone? Will you run to save her? Come on, say that you stopped appreciating people and doing everything only for your own good. Come on, Come me, I know what you are.</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_13_txt">
<text>You really have problems with your head. Can you take your tongue at least a little? If you want to offer me something, do it right away. And then I arranged for me here, a concert.</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_14_txt">
<text>Here. I like this mood, it means that we almost agreed. Hehe-heh. It remains only to discuss what I will offer you now. Ahem ... how do you need an idea to work for us and do dirty work in exchange for her life?</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_15_txt">
<text>And how do you like the idea to go fucking, along with your proposals?</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_16_txt">
<text>Yeah ... so? Will you continue to build yourself cool? Okay, mutilate, I will explain differently. Myron, shot the "steep" knee. We take a woman and turn off, if he survives, he will find us. Went.</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_17_txt">
<text>Yes, you all went to hell, Lord, let me die.</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_177_txt">
<text>Joke! Let's cooperate, of course! Yes, I am with both hands for guys!</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_188_txt">
<text>Another conversation, gloomy. A completely different conversation. Guys, we turn off. You can't kill him, so, slightly stroke the head, hehe.</text>
</string>
<string id="cs_b81_solomon_dialog_199_txt">
<text>Uh, well, guys, my head hurts, hey, well, no need on the head!</text>
</string>

<string id="az_pidor_lider_punch_gostop_dialog_0_text">
<text>Well, kid, remember me? Remember how you threatened me? Hehe, who is now on horseback, insignificance. We took your clothes, but there is no money yet. Take your knees, ask for forgiveness and turn your pockets, and maybe then, we will leave you alive. I understood everything?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_pidor_lider_punch_gostop_dialog_1_text">
<text>Can't you go a fuck? I will solve you with a knife. You should have killed me as soon as you caught me, morons.</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_out_az_help_koval_dialog_0_text">
<text>So you say, our own authorities want to kill us ... Hmm ... deeds ... although, I already had similar guesses. Thank you, mercenary. I did not expect such an act from you. After all, from us already there is no sense in essence, and you have helped us. Thank you friend, I will definitely give you a duty, do not hesitate, we will see each other, I don't forget my friends.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_out_az_help_koval_dialog_1_text">
<text>Take care of yourself, friend.</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_army_choice_killed_dialog_kovalskie_0_txt">
<text>Gloomy, what happened? Ah ... you are behind the news ... buddy, while quiet ... we ourselves do not know what is wrong with the headquarters ...</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_choice_killed_dialog_kovalskie_1_txt">
<text>Colonel! Collect the detachment and running from here, you are already hunting for you. I will explain everything on the way to a safe place, let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_choice_killed_dialog_kovalskie_11_txt">
<text>Yes, so, I walked by simply.</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_0_text">
<text>Hello gloomy ... did you check? There is no tail for you?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_1_text">
<text>Listen, what is it for? Took and called me here? What's happening? Who could follow me?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_2_text">
<text>I need to tell you something ... I work for the SBU. And I have a serious conversation for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_3_text">
<text>I listen carefully.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_4_text">
<text>I have work for you, just in your specialty ... Do you understand what I mean? You must kill some people.</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_5_text">
<text>Continue.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_55_text">
<text>The prototype of the medicine that you did has already used. Why would I help you?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_555_text">
<text>The prototype of the medicine for the virus, which you still create, will be ready soon?</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_6_text">
<text>Thank you for being ready to listen to me further!</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_66_text">
<text>Please listen to me ... they ... they ... will kill me, if you will not help me, I beg, just - listen to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_666_text">
<text>He is ready and I will give it to you if you help me, just listen to me, please!</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_7_text">
<text>Well, I'm listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_8_text">
<text>I saw the military, in the vicinity of the dome. Are you familiar with them? I saw how you talked to them about something. Listen...</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_9_text">
<text>Wait. Did you follow me?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_10_text">
<text>No ... True, no. It happened by accident. But that is not the point. You understand ... I need you to kill them ...</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_11_text">
<text>First, no. I need them, since they are my only path to the great Earth. Secondly, you know, this is very strange. Are you from the SBU? Ask to kill your own?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_12_text">
<text>I ... cannot tell you all the details. Wait, do you want to get beyond the perimeter? But what if I help you with this.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_13_text">
<text>How? I don't know who you really are. Why are you asking to kill the military, although you yourself are?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_14_text">
<text>The headquarters ordered me ... This detachment has no value more ... Yes, no matter how rude it sounds, but they are ordered to eliminate them, and you need to do it so that they do not know that the order was from the authorities ... Please believe me. Well, what do you need? Show a certificate? Here, look! What else? Money? How many? Turn outside the zone? What?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_15_text">
<text>I would have to leave the zone for starters. So why, the headquarters ordered them to be killed?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_16_text">
<text>Please do not ask me the reason. This is secret ... I myself do not want this ... But, they will kill me ... as well ... like them ... if I do not fulfill the order.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_17_text">
<text>Well, take a sniper rifle. Nap on the roof and kill them, what interferes?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_18_text">
<text>Of me, a bad fighter, especially a shooter ... I arrived here more as a researcher, I had other goals.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_19_text">
<text>Now I wonder how you will send me home?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_20_text">
<text>Just as they told you. Through a helicopter. Listen, they said that now they could not send a helicopter? They said, after all, am I right? Do you know why? Because the authorities are no longer needed. I do not know all the details, but apparently they failed some kind of operation. To be honest, I am not sure of my words, but so the facts received by me say. Please help me ... I understand that my request is not even pleasant, but ... I, however, can send you home. I still have powers for this, I give you a word!</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_pu_dialog_wtg_21_text">
<text>Give me time to think. If anything, I'll be back.</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_army_kovalskie_heli_work_new_quest_0_txt">
<text>Colonel, there is no news yet?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_kovalskie_heli_work_new_quest_1_txt">
<text>There are ... but not joyful ... With a helicopter, they still have to wait, they have some malfunctions, the hell will understand this bosses.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_kovalskie_heli_work_new_quest_2_txt">
<text>It's clear. Then I'm free, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_kovalskie_heli_work_new_quest_3_txt">
<text>Yes ... do not worry, I already said that as soon as there are news, I will inform you. I don't know how much more time will take. We are already tired of sitting here too, specifically.</text>
</string>

<string id="lx15_killer_zasad_dialog_type_0_text">
<text>Guy, lower the trunk and slowly come to me. Give the documents that you found and we will not touch you.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_killer_zasad_dialog_type_1_text">
<text>Yeah! I already knelt down and hold out my hands. Fuck you.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_killer_zasad_dialog_type_111_text">
<text>OK. Only calmly.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_killer_zasad_dialog_type_1111_text">
<text>Oh, morons. Hello!</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_killer_zasad_dialog_type_2_text">
<text>In vain, stalker ... we wanted in a good way.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_killer_zasad_dialog_type_222_text">
<text>Well done. How obedient you are, hehe. Give the documentation here.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_killer_zasad_dialog_type_333_text">
<text>I changed my mind. Let's go to hell!</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_killer_zasad_dialog_type_3_text">
<text>And I want to do so.</text>
</string>

<string id="lx15_animeboy_dead_start_friend_dialog_0_txt">
<text>This is my fault ... if I just went with them ... Damn ...</text>
</string>

<string id="lx15_animeboy_dead_friend_dialog_0_txt">
<text>Your mother ... Oleg ... Grisha ... could not save ... killed ... blah ...</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_animeboy_dead_friend_dialog_1_txt">
<text>My condolences.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_animeboy_dead_friend_dialog_2_txt">
<text>Leave me for the time of one ... please.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_animeboy_dead_friend_dialog_3_txt">
<text>As you say.</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_afina_choice_wake_dialog_0_text">
<text>God bless! You are alive ... How is your health? Does your head hurt? Listen ... your ... partner ... he died ... right here, fell and died ... I do not know what happened to him!</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_choice_wake_dialog_1_text">
<text>The head does not hurt, everything is fine, relax - it happens to him. Hehe. Do not take it in mind, warn everyone not to worry. How much was I in a disconnection?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_choice_wake_dialog_2_text">
<text>Funny!? Happens?! How does it happen ??? The man died right here, for no reason! What's happening?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_choice_wake_dialog_3_text">
<text>Yes, I say, do not take it in mind! He is not quite a person, you know? Ay, okay, you won't understand anyway, but I have no time to explain to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_choice_wake_dialog_4_text">
<text>A fool ... Lord ... I don't understand anything ... How are you? Is everything okay with you?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_choice_wake_dialog_5_text">
<text>Everything is gorgeous. The head does not hurt. Okay, I'll go. I still have business. Do not do such frightened eyes, it's just a corpse.</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_choice_karp_prototip_vnz_dialog_0_txt">
<text>I hope you made the right choice. So ... I don't have so much time left, so I think that if we still see each other, I will collect much more information about this virus and we will help you, do not hesitate.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_choice_karp_prototip_vnz_dialog_1_txt">
<text>Who would help you ... You are, like an anomaly ...</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_choice_karp_prototip_vnz_dialog_2_txt">
<text>I'm trying ... how much I already tried to find out from this schizoned monolithic, what is happening to me ...</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_choice_karp_prototip_vnz_dialog_3_txt">
<text>Are you talking about chrome? I saw him in the M-15 laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_choice_karp_prototip_vnz_dialog_4_txt">
<text>Yes? ... Listen, I'll tell you one thing. Do not listen to this idiot. I don't know who he is or what he is, but there is no sense from him ... Okay, next time we talk - I already feel that I will lean out soon, I hope that we will meet. Not a fluff!</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_choice_karp_prototip_vnz_dialog_5_txt">
<text>See you.</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_afina_prototip_kpp_dialog_0_txt">
<text>Athena. While I was going here with my partner, he told me a lot about this virus. Is there a chance that your medicine will kill me?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_prototip_kpp_dialog_1_txt">
<text>Listen ... There is always risk, that's right. Moreover, we only recently finished with the first test “prototype”. We know whether there are no experimental ones to check it in the case. But, he should not kill you ... True and not the fact that it will help ... side effects are possible, but it should not be killed. I guarantee you.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_prototip_kpp_dialog_2_txt">
<text>Yes. Sounds, of course, encouraging ...</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_prototip_kpp_dialog_3_txt">
<text>But we will not be able to do better ... until the "prototype" is checked. Thy business, gloomy. If you do not want, not worth it. Suddenly, we will still find a way to check it on someone else.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_prototip_kpp_dialog_4_txt">
<text>I hope I will not turn into a huge spider. Come on here, now we will find out.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_prototip_kpp_dialog_44_txt">
<text>Perhaps not. Leave it so far with you. Maybe I will really find more information about this virus and inform you.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_prototip_kpp_dialog_55_txt">
<text>Fine. This is your choice ... I hope you still have time.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_prototip_kpp_dialog_66_txt">
<text>Oh, but I hope.</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_karp_kpp_dialog_0_txt">
<text>Hello again, gloomy.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_karp_kpp_dialog_1_txt">
<text>Convinced. Now I definitely believe you. I personally saw your corpse ... Oh hell.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_karp_kpp_dialog_2_txt">
<text>Solomon is alive. And not only he ...</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_karp_kpp_dialog_3_txt">
<text>What? Where is he!?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_karp_kpp_dialog_4_txt">
<text>I don't know yet. But, I do not advise looking for him, because he is looking for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_karp_kpp_dialog_5_txt">
<text>So even better. I hope that we will meet as soon as possible, because I am not going to stay in the zone for a long time.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_karp_kpp_dialog_6_txt">
<text>He is dangerous. Gloomy, my advice to you - do not try to find it, but it is better to get it out of the zone as soon as possible. Wait, what about the virus? Has found anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_karp_kpp_dialog_7_txt">
<text>I found documents about him. Now they have scientists on a Reme. I should warn me when my "medicine" will be ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_karp_kpp_dialog_8_txt">
<text>Yeah ... good. Let's go there while I have time - I have to check something with you. Went.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_karp_kpp_dialog_9_txt">
<text>Wait. What about Solomon? How did you find out that he is alive and looking for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_karp_kpp_dialog_10_txt">
<text>With my fucking reincarnation, I have time to visit such places in the zone ... that it becomes difficult to conceal anything from me. Okay, this is not the point - you want to get even with him? Thy business. And now, go to the VNZ.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_karp_kpp_dialog_11_txt">
<text>OK. You will tell me on the way everything you know.</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dva_dialog_0_text">
<text>Glad you are alive, a mercenary. Thank you for helping to establish a connection. Do not know what with my guys who went to this task?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dva_dialog_1_text">
<text>They are dead. The monoliths apparently tried.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dva_dialog_111_text">
<text>One of your fighters was alive, but when I dealt with the monoliths, he committed suicide.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dva_dialog_2_text">
<text>Eh ... annoying. Damn the guys die, very young ... shitty ...</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dva_dialog_222_text">
<text>Fanatics are bad ... prayed to him with their prayers ... Damn ...</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dva_dialog_3_text">
<text>What about your headquarters? Did they answer?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dva_dialog_4_text">
<text>Yes. We contacted them. Now my guys make them a way through the air so that they fly without adventures ... new ...</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dva_dialog_5_text">
<text>And soon there will be a new helicopter?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dva_dialog_6_text">
<text>No less than a day in a day. No way ... But, we believe and wait for the best. As soon as the helicopter is on the way to us - I will definitely inform you, and as we agreed, we will take you with us. I do not let my words into the wind.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dva_dialog_7_text">
<text>Fine. Then I will wait for the message from you.</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dialog_0_txt">
<text>Oh, I wish you health! You're just in time.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dialog_1_txt">
<text>You sent a message, what happened? What about the new helicopter?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dialog_2_txt">
<text>This is our commander called you, but he went somewhere for intelligence. He ordered him to wait for him here. So ... at the expense of a helicopter. We cannot contact the headquarters, something or someone is jamming our signal.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dialog_3_txt">
<text>And what will we do?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dialog_4_txt">
<text>Several of our soldiers are already trying to eliminate this problem, but this is not enough ... Your help would be very useful.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dialog_5_txt">
<text>Waiting for details.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dialog_6_txt">
<text>In principle, we tracked all the suspicious signals that spoil us in touch. We have their coordinates, we only need to eliminate them. Two of ours have already set off for this task, but there is no news from them, they do not answer ... Could you do this dirty work for them? By the way! You can replenish the ammunition and medicines from our soldiers, I allow.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_army_heli_glava_dialog_7_txt">
<text>If this helps to quickly get out of the zone. I'm in business. Come on the coordinates.</text>
</string>

<string id="lax_a_m15_done_afina_virus_dialog_0_txt">
<text>I have documents. Tentatively, when will the prototype of the medicine be ready for the virus?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_done_afina_virus_dialog_1_txt">
<text>Great. Come them here soon! So ... good. Now we will start with the professor. Be in touch. I will inform you as soon as everything is ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_done_afina_virus_dialog_2_txt">
<text>Fine. I hope it will be very soon.</text>
</string>

<string id="lax_a_m15_animeboy_strange_dialog_0_txt">
<text>Your mother ... The doors closed again ... Okay, we will look for the way out in another place. Now, let's share. I will go to look for my friends, and you look for what you came for. I hope everything will go well.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_animeboy_strange_dialog_1_txt">
<text>OK then. Thy business.</text>
</string>

<string id="lx15_contract_s11_dialog_animeboy_final_saying_0_txt">
<text>Where did you disappear for several hours? Glad of course to see you alive ...</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_contract_s11_dialog_animeboy_final_saying_1_txt">
<text>If I was so worried, I could follow me and check.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_contract_s11_dialog_animeboy_final_saying_2_txt">
<text>I was going to. Sorry, I could not.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_contract_s11_dialog_animeboy_final_saying_3_txt">
<text>OK. It doesn't matter anymore, thanks for that.</text>
</string>

<string id="lx15_contract_s11_dialog_xromoi_0_txt">
<text>I have not seen each other for a long time, my friend.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_contract_s11_dialog_xromoi_1_txt">
<text>Not ... again my head is a mess ... What do you need? You are just my sick fantasy.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_contract_s11_dialog_xromoi_2_txt">
<text>Fantasy? So Karp told you?</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_contract_s11_dialog_xromoi_3_txt">
<text>He has nothing to do with it. You are just a ghost. So what the hell am I talking to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_contract_s11_dialog_xromoi_4_txt">
<text>Really. What a good question ... When you find out the answer, let me know.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx15_contract_s11_dialog_xromoi_5_txt">
<text>What? Will you just leave again?</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_afina_atr_start_dialog_13">
<text>Hello handsome.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_atr_start_dialog_12">
<text>Hello, gloomy.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_afina_atr_start_dialog_11">
<text>We haven't seen each other for a long time, handsome.</text>
</string>

<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_0_txt">
<text>Here are your things. The container will not be touched. Hold it.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_1_txt">
<text>Did you really do it? Is it true? Thank you! Gloomy ... You are my hero! Thank you very much, really. I no longer knew what to do ...</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_2_txt">
<text>Is the contents of the container so important for you? Okay ... This is not my business. I helped you, and now you will help me?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_3_txt">
<text>Yes, sure! Thanks again! What did you want to know? I listen carefully.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_4_txt">
<text>Scientists said that you most likely know about the virus, from which now all the authorities are baking.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_5_txt">
<text>Ahh ... you're talking about experiments ... on the creation of a super-soldier ... Yes, I know a lot about this. What exactly do you want to know?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_6_txt">
<text>I need information about him. There are suspicions that I am infected. And I need any clues so that scientists try to create a medicine for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_7_txt">
<text>It cannot be ... how are you ... how could you get infected? ... For a long time? Were there any loss of consciousness? There is no feeling that 8 new paws will come out of the back now?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_8_txt">
<text>So ... You really know about the virus. Listen, Athena. I would not want to turn into a huge spider. I need a cure for the virus, are there any offers?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_9_txt">
<text>It just so happened that I also study this virus. You know, here nearby - there is an old metro ... complex. According to my information, in the depths of the metro, there is a laboratory. Not so long ago, a detachment of scientists who made the first tests with this very virus was evacuated from there. I think that if you find the documentation that stayed there, I can help you with the professor. It will be in my interests, so if you start the search, then it is from there. Wait, maybe this will come in handy ... this, decoder. I don't know what is now with the laboratory, but if some doors are closed, it can help. Hold it.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_10_txt">
<text>Thank you. I will go for information there.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_11_txt">
<text>Wait ... SPA ... thank you, really. You are the first who is not afraid of this freak. I can't understand why everyone is so afraid of him ... Can I somehow thank you?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_12_txt">
<text>I did it in my interests. Nothing personal, everything is fine. Thanks for the decoder.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_122_txt">
<text>A kiss ... isn't it difficult?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_133_txt">
<text>Oh ... well, you give, ha ha. Yes, of course, handsome. %C[255,238,153,26]*kisses you on the cheek*</text>
</string>
<string id="az_radar_afina_dialog_to_complate_quest_shmotki_144_txt">
<text>How nice. Okay, thanks for the decoder. I am looking for information. I hope that we will see you again!</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_0_txt">
<text>What are you, kid?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_161_txt">
<text>Nothing. Passed by.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_1_txt">
<text>You have a kid in your pants, a muddy. You are quiet, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_2_txt">
<text>Didn't understand. You, Malaya, do you know who are you chasing at all? Yes, you know who I am ...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_3_txt">
<text>Yes, I don't care who you are. Do you remember Athena? Return her things. I'm waiting.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_4_txt">
<text>Ha ha. Guys, have you heard? This little one came to intercede for that woman. Ha ha ... boy, you know who I am and what I can? Do you think she will give you? Small, turn around and go home, my guys are no longer in the mood.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_5_txt">
<text>Now I and your guys will turn your knees in the other direction. Will you walk like dinosaurs, check?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_6_txt">
<text>You look, I don't get it with whom you are talking, right? Well, the kid ... I decided to start a fight in the bar? Listen to me carefully, kid. There are ten pieces from you and your clothes. No? So fail, otherwise you will have problems.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_7_txt">
<text>No, you didn't understand that. I'll attach the trunks instead of my nose to you! Believe me, for me, a couple of Bolvanov is an ordinary warm -up.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_777_txt">
<text>Do you want ten thousand for her things?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_666_txt">
<text>Yes, kid. Something doesn't suit you?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_6661_txt">
<text>I understand you, hold the money. Give her things here.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_6662_txt">
<text>Either you give me her things, or I break your hands and legs. I'm not joking.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_6663_txt">
<text>Either you give me her things, or I break your hands and legs. I'm not joking.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_7777_txt">
<text>I have only 5 thousand.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_8888_txt">
<text>Ay. Okay, come on for five. Take it and fail!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_9999_txt">
<text>Hmm ... See you.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_8_txt">
<text>Oh, you are scum ... well, well ... we'll meet you and I are still outside the bar ... We'll see how cool you will be, man. Take it and get out!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_888_txt">
<text>Ha ha. That's how it would be right away. On, take her clothes and fail her, kid!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_9_txt">
<text>I will wait for our meeting, in another setting. See you also.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_stalker_dialog_s_pidorom_1_999_txt">
<text>Yes. Until new meetings.</text>
</string>

<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_txt_0">
<text>What do you need? ... I am busy, can you not interfere? %C[255,238,153,26]*squelching*</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_txt_111">
<text>OK. I will not interfere.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_help_me_txt_2">
<text>Listen ... Scientists said that you can help me with something.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_help_me_txt_3">
<text>Yes? Who will help me? %C[255,238,153,26]*again squelching*</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_help_me_txt_4">
<text>I understand. Well, tell me. What's happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_help_me_txt_5">
<text>Yeah ... well, I will tell, again ... And the sense? No one wants to help anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_help_me_txt_6">
<text>Well, tell me, and there we'll see. Suddenly, I will help with something.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_help_me_txt_7">
<text>Yes? Ahem ... Yeah, I know you. You are not the first, you are not the last to come up and ask, and then, people like you, just squeeze your shoulders and leave.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_help_me_txt_8">
<text>Will you devote me to details or not?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_help_me_txt_9">
<text>Yes, one freak ... in a bar ... I got a halved, took my things and said that he would give it out only through the bed. Freak ... That's just this is not the most offensive. It's a shame that among my things are very important documents for one recent incident. There is so much useful information about the virus, which now everyone has begun to study so actively. That's just, no one can help me. They say that this freak, a very influential stalker. Like, his connections are very serious, and that it is better not to contact him.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_help_me_txt_10">
<text>If I return your things and documentation, will you help me? I just need to find out about this virus. Wipe the tears, beauty. Say who he is, where he is now and what his name is.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_help_me_txt_11">
<text>Quiet ... What, scared? Do you know him too? Sits with his friends in a bar of stalkers, what is here, down the elevator ...</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_help_me_txt_12">
<text>For the "quiet" he is very loud. I will fix it.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_help_me_txt_13">
<text>What? Is it true? Will you help me? Wait ... here, take the money ... He can ask for a ransom ... It's better not to crush him and do not provoke a conflict. By the way, what is your name?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_afina_welcom_help_me_txt_14">
<text>Call - gloomy. See you.</text>
</string>




<string id="az_virus_contract_bandits_0_txt">
<text>Brother. Do not know anything about the virus from which all the military is now on the platoon?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_bandits_1_txt">
<text>L ... well, I don't even know, you need to scientists. On a ray's software, you know? L ... maybe they know something.</text>
</string>

<string id="az_virus_contract_stalkers_0_txt">
<text>Friend. Do not know anything about the virus from which all the military is now on the platoon?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_stalkers_1_txt">
<text>Hmm ... well, bro, it seems to me that you need to scientists. On the Promo Ru that. Maybe they know something.</text>
</string>

<string id="az_virus_contract_lesnik_1_txt_0">
<text>Listen, grandfather. Do you know anything about the virus from which all the military is now on the platoon?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_lesnik_1_txt_1">
<text>Oh gloomy. As I understand it, you talked to the carp? Mmm ... okay, this is of course not mine. Yes, who can know, scientists on a Reman. I think that they are only.</text>
</string>

<string id="az_virus_contract_shystrie_1_txt_0">
<text>Listen, friend. Do you know anything about the virus from which all the military is now on the platoon?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_shystrie_1_txt_1">
<text>No, I didn't hear. Maybe scientists know something. Ask them better.</text>
</string>

<string id="az_virus_contract_proff_1_txt_0">
<text>Professor, do you know anything about the virus from which the military is now not his own?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_proff_1_txt_1">
<text>Eh ... we tried to get any information about this virus. But, while we have no hooks. Sorry, a young man. Perhaps Athena knows something useful ... Ask her.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_virus_contract_proff_1_txt_11">
<text>No, alas ... We were not able to get enough information about these experiments, as in actually the virus itself. But perhaps a girl ... Athena seems to know something.</text>
</string>

<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_0">
<text>We have not seen for a long time ... gloomy.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_1">
<text>Listen. I don't know who to trust. What are you or who are you? Brother, what did the zone do to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_2">
<text>I don't know the buddy ... After I disappeared in the mines of the red forest, something terrible happened. With my body, with my mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_3">
<text>Bright Bratan. Very bad. He spoke with the forester ... Did you want to discuss something with me?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_4">
<text>Yes. By old friendship ... I wanted to warn you, about what I myself learned about it recently, while I traveled around the zone through my shuttle reincarnation.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_5">
<text>Warn? Waiting for details.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_6">
<text>What happened to the detachment? Where is Solomon? ... You found the way in the D-6, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_7">
<text>Yeah, found. Solomon is a traitor. Myron was also with him at the same time. I can't vouch for the rest. Maybe you too, knew everything?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_8">
<text>Knew? About that this is all a setup? No, friend, did not know. But while he traveled, he found out about it. Ahem ... so gloomy, at the expense of the contract. As I understand it, the authorities again conduct some experiments, what they specifically have done there - I do not know. But, I heard about some spiders who became the carriers of this very virus. In the D-6, did not meet any spider-shaped creatures?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_9">
<text>Mmm ... met. When I climbed into the reactor to save the cartridge, one such crap from the ceiling and jumped. Terrible creature. The spider was the size of an armored personnel carrier.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_10">
<text>Has he hooked you? This spider. Did he enter into close contact with you?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_11">
<text>Um ... Well, with a paw of me slightly clung. And what?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_12">
<text>Badly gloomy. For you, it's bad. Most likely, you were infected with this nonsense. How is it to be well -being? Were there any loss of consciousness? How often? Maybe there were glitches?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_13">
<text>So ... And now I'm starting to get nervous. Losses of consciousness really began to occur quite often and without obvious reasons. Glits? Yes, I'm talking to you now, I think, I think I was crazy?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_14">
<text>We all have gone crazy, brother. But this is not the worst. I learned a little about this virus. I will not explain to you what kind of infection this is, but I will say directly. You don't have much left ... But the strangest thing is that after you completely lose your psi-bond with the brain, this creature that is inside you will come out. Simply put ... You will turn into the same spider as the one in the D-6. I'm serious.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_15">
<text>Your mother. I can do anything ... Can I do anything with these?</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_16">
<text>Maybe yes ... or maybe not. I have one information. That scientists have some documentation about this virus. They seem to even study it, though according to the data obtained, it's like looking for a needle in a haystack, you know? If you do something, then first find out from them. I don't know, maybe they will help with something. So ... I think I am everything ... I have a couple of minutes left, I feel ... I will kill me now. Okay, we will see each other, I will return, do not hesitate. And until then, try to stay alive, gloomy.</text>
</string>
<string id="az_contract_karp_dialog_1_text_17">
<text>Devilry...</text>
</string>










<string id="contract_a2_lesnik_dialog_search_0_txt">
<text>Oh, gloomy. Glad to see you in health, lad!</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_a2_lesnik_dialog_search_1_txt">
<text>I am also glad to see you alive, grandfather. Can you explain what is happening and where did you disappear?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_a2_lesnik_dialog_search_2_txt">
<text>Well ... it was so ... our conductor, turned out to be linden. The controller of you and me, the brains in that complex were powdered when we were looking for a way out. It turns out that he was still with us in the house ... But I can't understand why he did not kill us. For some reason he pretended to be a guide, and even knew so much about him, this is strange ...</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_a2_lesnik_dialog_search_3_txt">
<text>The fact that something is wrong with the conductor, I already understood. Karp told me something before his death ... They say, do not trust him, this is not him. I did not give this much sense, but I thought about his words. Yes, and we did not go to the dead city, you did not immediately understand this?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_a2_lesnik_dialog_search_4_txt">
<text>No ... I'm old already, I have not the same head. Eh, not the same ... The fact that we did not go out in the dead city - I understood only when I got into that complex again. And he met someone again ... Carpa ... He told me that it was not a guide.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_a2_lesnik_dialog_search_5_txt">
<text>Carp? ... is he ... alive?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_a2_lesnik_dialog_search_6_txt">
<text>Oh, I don't know, son. Don't know. It seems yes, but it seems not. He became something like an anomaly ... I do not know how to explain it.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_a2_lesnik_dialog_search_7_txt">
<text>Devilry. He said something about his reincarnation ... Your mother, what is happening here. Okay, okay. Where is he now, do not know?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_a2_lesnik_dialog_search_8_txt">
<text>Eh ... is it worth it to trust? He ... an anomaly ... I don't even know. Okay son. This is already your business. He asked me to tell you that he would wait for you at the P-I plant. But ... my advice to you, do not play with these otherworldly forces. Who knows what he really is. Maybe it used to be your comrade, but now ... this is clearly not a living person. This is something else.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_a2_lesnik_dialog_search_9_txt">
<text>Yes, grandfather. I myself don't know what he is ... But perhaps this is “something”, he will be able to answer my questions ... I have to meet him.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_a2_lesnik_dialog_search_10_txt">
<text>Thy business, gloomy. Good luck. Oh yes ... son, hold on. Remember him? This is the same gun that you fixed in that mysterious house ... I think it will come in handy. And I will be here ... if anything, call your grandfather.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_a2_lesnik_dialog_search_11_txt">
<text>And good luck, old man. Thank you for keeping the gun.</text>
</string>












<string id="contract_sold_see_dialog_done_0_text">
<text>Quiet! Do not move.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_sold_see_dialog_done_1_text">
<text>What happened? Where are the others? Military?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_sold_see_dialog_done_2_text">
<text>Do not ask unnecessary questions and go better to the main thing. And do not do stupid things, the shooter is good from me, do not check.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_sold_see_dialog_done_33_text">
<text>I also shoot well. Better down the gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_sold_see_dialog_done_44_text">
<text>I willingly believe. But I do not advise you to hire, we have a whole detachment here, do you realize? In the end, we could bang you for a long time.</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_sold_see_dialog_done_3_text">
<text>OK. I understood ... only easier, okay?</text>
</string>
<string id="contract_sold_see_dialog_done_55_text">
<text>OK. Understood.</text>
</string>





<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_0_txt">
<text>Mercenary?! What the hell? How did you end up here?</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_1_txt">
<text>Military? So, calmly. Just don't shoot!</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_2_txt">
<text>So. Now you are here alone and you better answer me. Otherwise, you will go to the next world. Tuck? I repeat. How did you end up here?</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_3_txt">
<text>How was I tired of telling everyone about my adventures ... And now this time the military ... wait, and where ... And where are the others? Was there only me in the tunnel?</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_4_txt">
<text>Mercenary, are you raving? You were abandoned by your comrades as a little girl and you went crazy? Now there is no one besides me and my fighters. Do you want to join the controller? No? Then enough to experience my patience ... I ask the last time! Who is it? How did it turn out?</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_5_txt">
<text>Frowning. I am a mercenary under a contract. Not from the local "blue".</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_6_txt">
<text>ABOUT! So there it is. Oh, how lucky you were that you ran into my detachment. It was ordered to destroy your detachment, back in the red forest, when you sent a whole landing to you. Eh ... it's a pity that we were reported to us that you put a whole detachment there. Right?</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_7_txt">
<text>We had no choice. They were not going to take us alive. Do not blame me!</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_8_txt">
<text>Eh ... what sadness ... are you ready to cooperate with the SBU? Now we are going for a cordon, on the turntable. You, so to speak, can be delivered to the big land. But if you want to stay, the corpse of the controller is there behind you.</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_9_txt">
<text>I think that on the Great Earth, the SBU will have a lot of questions ... But I have no choice, I will fly with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_10_txt">
<text>Well, great, mercenary. There is a place on board for you. At the same time, you will tell you more about your adventures. For me for the report - you for Alibi.</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_11_txt">
<text>Can I find out why they hunted our detachment in a red forest? And why, your customers - decided to get rid of us?</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_12_txt">
<text>If you want to know, it means ... if only you have a butt ... Oh ... okay. Their entire plan to capture was covered ... This contract of yours - in fact, was not at all in the murder of a certain super -soldier. Apparently, not everyone in your detachment knew the details of the contract, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_13_txt">
<text>Solomon ... This reptile knew everything. I'm sure. He used me. I hope this bastard is already dead.</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_133_txt">
<text>Don't know. I trusted everyone in my detachment.</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_14_txt">
<text>Hmm ... yes. It happens. Who can use it like how it can ... I don't climb into other people's affairs. Well, do not worry, boomerang to everyone and everything will return. I know. Hehe</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_144_txt">
<text>Trusted? Hmm ... well, trust among the thugs, this is something new. But, it's not for me to judge. After all, I am not a lover of thrill. Hehe</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_15_txt">
<text>The conductor said that we will go out to the dead city? Are we in it now? So, okay. And what about departure? Will we fly on this turntable immediately beyond the perimeter?</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_16_txt">
<text>A? A dead city? You probably definitely rave ... We are in the vicinity of the radar - "dome". This is the center of the zone. I don't know what kind of noodles a guide hung on your ears. Turnie? ... yes. On her is a native. Now we'll go to the place of evacuation, it is here, in a hundred meters, nearby. It's just that it is impossible to land here, anomalies in the air, hell, fly right above their heads ...</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_17_txt">
<text>Again there are more questions than answers ... Okay. Fine. I understand. Then, moved to the place of landing?</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_18_txt">
<text>Hey! Yes. Moved. Svic! Turn your devices, everything is already ready for a long time. And you, a mercenary, will help us. To the place of evacuation, everything, Ba-go!</text>
</string>
<string id="blacker_lesnik_dialog_1_19_txt">
<text>On the road.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_wood_optimalalloptis_hello_start_0_text">
<text>Hello, gloomy.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_wood_optimalalloptis_hello_start_1_text">
<text>Oh, gloomy! What fate?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_wood_optimalalloptis_hello_start_2_text">
<text>Good day, gloomy.</text>
</string>	
<string id="rad_wood_optimalalloptis_hello_start_3_text">
<text>Hmm ... what brought you here, a mercenary.</text>
</string>

	<string id="about_a2_s11_dialog_bandit_0">
		<text>This, listen. Where is the stalker camp here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_a2_s11_dialog_bandit_1">
		<text>Oh, damn it, Masha-sufferer! ... Okay, do not be loaded, brother - this is like I'm joking. In short, stalkers are not stalkers, but to stomp the least to the "GPP of the Old". Well, and la ... there is still a camp on the "probation - a beam." I'll drop the coordinates right now ... And checked: like my kid, for free.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_a2_s11_dialog_stalker_0">
		<text>I wanted to know. Where is the stalker camp here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_a2_s11_dialog_stalker_1">
		<text>Now I will show ... Everything, look at your PDA. In general, this is an old checkpoint. There is a very large camp in these vicinity. And also, the camp is on the "VNZ - Ray". You see on the map?</text>
	</string>

<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_cvetok_dialog_0_txt">
<text>I have a flower. What about the decoder?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_cvetok_dialog_1_txt">
<text>Great, give him here soon. Ahem ... Remember I told you about the second task.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_cvetok_dialog_2_txt">
<text>Yes. I remember. Let's immediately about the task.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_cvetok_dialog_3_txt">
<text>Fine. So, look ... On the territory of the complex, a very interesting mutant started. We do not even know how dangerous and tenacious it is. But for research, we need its fabric. You could get them?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_cvetok_dialog_4_txt">
<text>After I bring you a piece of the skin of this creature, will you give me a decoder?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_cvetok_dialog_5_txt">
<text>Certainly! As agreed. By the way, we do not know how strong this mutant is, so we will give you a grenade launcher for 6 charges. I hope that everything will be fine with you, but the flesh of the monster will not suffer ... Hold it. Try to use shells wisely.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_cvetok_dialog_6_txt">
<text>I'll be back soon.</text>
</string>

<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_mutant_dialog_0_txt">
<text>Here you have a giddle. She was in the body of this mutant.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_mutant_dialog_1_txt">
<text>A stunning sight ... This is a completely different type of mutants. Apparently evolution begins to make itself felt ... oh yes. Here is a decipher. Thanks for the work, this is a small award. Your work matters in our research.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_mutant_dialog_2_txt">
<text>I am glad.</text>
</string>

<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_vnz_deshifr_dialog_0_txt">
<text>Professor, I have a dealing with you. I need a decoder. You see, what am I talking about?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_vnz_deshifr_dialog_1_txt">
<text>Hmm ... yes, I understand perfectly. Well, young, man. We have such a couple of things for the whole "base". I just can't give it like that, sorry ...</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_vnz_deshifr_dialog_2_txt">
<text>Do not languish, professor. What do you need?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_vnz_deshifr_dialog_3_txt">
<text>Well ... It is necessary that you help us in several matters! To begin with ... we need a special abnormal flower that may grow in an “abnormal village” not far from here ...</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_vnz_deshifr_dialog_4_txt">
<text>Well, let's say I will find it. Cook the device.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_vnz_deshifr_dialog_5_txt">
<text>Maybe we will agree somehow with money?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_vnz_deshifr_dialog_6_txt">
<text>No, young man. I don't need money. I work for the prosperity of science and technology!</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_to_az_radar_professor_vnz_deshifr_dialog_7_txt">
<text>Good, good, I will find this flower. Cook the device.</text>
</string>

<string id="lax_a_m15_animeboy_start_dialog_0_txt">
<text>You can not look for anything here ... The damn cage is closed! Grisha, Oleg ... Damn, how they managed to ...</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_animeboy_start_dialog_1_txt">
<text>Um, as I understand it, are your friends?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_animeboy_start_dialog_2_txt">
<text>Yes ... your mother ... What kind of crap is going on! MGX ...</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_animeboy_start_dialog_3_txt">
<text>Do not raise this grille? There is a control panel right there, what's wrong with it?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_animeboy_start_dialog_4_txt">
<text>You will move this grill from the place ... the control panel? He needs a key card, or a special decoder ... we have neither one nor the other.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_animeboy_start_dialog_5_txt">
<text>I have. Let me try to open this door.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_animeboy_start_dialog_6_txt">
<text>Yes? Eat? Hmm ... Well, come on, try it!</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_animeboy_start_dialog_7_txt">
<text>Follow the bars. Now I'll try to open.</text>
</string>

<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_0_text">
<text>Who is it? ... What did you forget here?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_1_text">
<text>Calmly. I will explain now.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_2_text">
<text>Ha, yes, a mercenary, try. And look at me, any extra movement and I shoot, okay?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_3_text">
<text>I understood, I got it. I'm here on the assignment, mine.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_4_text">
<text>Ahem ... I heard some kind of explosion and shooting outside. What happened there?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_555_text">
<text>I was attacked by a detachment of mercenaries, I killed everyone. Now it's quiet, everything is in order.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_666_text">
<text>Hmm, and you are well done. You know, for such a "feat", hehe, I will even brush your hand. Look what ... I decided yourself like it, well, man, well, you are a real killer. Eh, okay, what am I. Ahem ... can I find out what are you looking for here?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_5_text">
<text>At the entrance to the complex, I was ambushed. These were mercenaries.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_55_text">
<text>I don't know ... The shooting began there, I just rushed here soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_6_text">
<text>Curious ... very curious. Hmm, now I would like to know what you are looking for here?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_7_text">
<text>I need to get to the laboratory and find useful documents about the new virus.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_8_text">
<text>Here it is. Why do you need them, I won't ask, it's not particularly interesting, my friend. Eh ... Well, I want to tell you right away that the next couple of days - there was nobody here, only our squad of stalkers. However, during this time, something strange happened.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_9_text">
<text>And what happened, if not a secret?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_10_text">
<text>I sent a couple of my inspecting the collector at the end of the tunnel. There, between the passage from the tunnel to the collector - there is a semi -automatic door. We thought for a long time how to open it, after which the door opened for a while and my two fighters seemed to drag there by the wind, after which the door closed again. I don't know what it was, but this thing did not open anymore. It would be nice to find the key card or some decoder for it ... but where? Oh yes, this is in your interests, since the entrance to the collector is the only way in the depths of the complex, to the laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_11_text">
<text>I have a decoder. Can I look at the door?</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_12_text">
<text>Yes, if you can open it, we will be grateful ... We need to find our guys. Go look. Do not be afraid, no one will shoot. I warned everyone.</text>
</string>
<string id="lax_a_m15_podstrel_start_dialog_13_text">
<text>Yes. Fine.</text>
</string>

<string id="poisk_shnir_dialog_start_0_txt">
<text>I recorded the last active coordinates of our group. We can go for their search right now!</text>
</string>
<string id="poisk_shnir_dialog_start_11_txt">
<text>Okay, lead, I'm behind you.</text>
</string>
<string id="poisk_shnir_dialog_start_22_txt">
<text>I will check for myself, give only the coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="poisk_shnir_dialog_start_221_txt">
<text>You are sure? Maybe it's better to look around together? So safer!</text>
</string>
<string id="poisk_shnir_dialog_start_222_txt">
<text>No, I myself. Stay here.</text>
</string>
<string id="poisk_shnir_dialog_start_2222_txt">
<text>Okay, let's go together.</text>
</string>
<string id="poisk_shnir_dialog_start_33_txt">
<text>Wait, I forgot something.</text>
</string>

<string id="s11_provodnik_dialog_to_go_na_1">
<text>Where can you spend me?</text>
</string>
<string id="s11_provodnik_dialog_to_go_na_22">
<text>On the basis of scientists - "VNZ-Luch"</text>
</string>
<string id="s11_provodnik_dialog_to_go_na_33">
<text>On the base of stalkers - "Old GPP".</text>
</string>
<string id="s11_provodnik_dialog_to_go_na_4">
<text>And how much will it cost?</text>
</string>
<string id="s11_provodnik_dialog_to_go_na_5">
<text>In connection with the position of the zone ... well ... for 2000 rubles. Nothing more than yet, excuse me. I guarantee a quick and safe way.</text>
</string>
<string id="s11_provodnik_dialog_to_go_na_6">
<text>Fine. Take me a safe way.</text>
</string>
<string id="s11_provodnik_dialog_to_go_na_66">
<text>I still do not need your services.</text>
</string>

<string id="sviaz_a2_kpl_texnik_dva_dialog_0">
<text>I restored the connection. What's with the radio transmitter?</text>
</string>
<string id="sviaz_a2_kpl_texnik_dva_dialog_1">
<text>Yes, you're well done! Here, hold your radio transmitter. Everything works, tune now as you want.</text>
</string>

<string id="sviaz_a2_kpl_texnik_dialog_0">
<text>Listen, there is a matter. I need to configure the radio transmitter to the closed channel.</text>
</string>
<string id="sviaz_a2_kpl_texnik_dialog_1">
<text>I will look ... hehe ... Come on, you bring me a bottle of brandy, and then we will talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="sviaz_a2_kpl_texnik_dialog_2">
<text>Are you laughing? Where I will find such alcohol to you in the zone. Joker.</text>
</string>
<string id="sviaz_a2_kpl_texnik_dialog_3">
<text>Didn't you joke now either? Hehe, okay drove. Yes, joking. I generally drink only on holidays ... Yeah. And at the expense of your receiver ... I want to say right away that the connection is broken, there are constantly some interference. I even know where they come from, but sending for verification - there is no one, as you see. Well, it is not necessary in principle ...</text>
</string>
<string id="sviaz_a2_kpl_texnik_dialog_4">
<text>Wait, wait. What other interference?</text>
</string>
<string id="sviaz_a2_kpl_texnik_dialog_5">
<text>Interference? Well, as I understand it, these are such structures that knock down all signals, most likely - these are "sectarian buildings." Monoliths, damn them! For some reason they instructed the muffles and apparently they are plotting something, hell knows. In principle, in connection with our situation - radio communications have not been needed for a long time, since there is a single Internet network in the zone, so we have not been using channels for a long time. But if you need it so much, I can send you the coordinates of the places where the interference comes from, how to get rid of all the interference, blow to me - I will set up your radio transmitter to the desired channel.</text>
</string>
<string id="sviaz_a2_kpl_texnik_dialog_6">
<text>There is no particular choice, good. Tear off the coordinates of these "interference".</text>
</string>


<string id="agr_a2_znakomstvo_dialog_mark_0_txt">
<text>Where did you get such a large assortment of things on sale?</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_a2_znakomstvo_dialog_mark_1_txt">
<text>You are new apparently here, right? Well, how to explain to you ... I have ties with the military and very avid experienced merchants beyond the territory of the zone. They supply all this written off to me - and I sell it here. And yes, it turns out very profitably, I have my percentage ...</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_a2_znakomstvo_dialog_mark_2_txt">
<text>Clearly.</text>
</string>


<string id="agr_b3_texnik_medved_dialog_o_safe_0_txt">
<text>Listen, I have a box that is closed to some sort of sophisticated lock. Can you open?</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_b3_texnik_medved_dialog_o_safe_1_txt">
<text>Hmm ... work is not from lungs, plus the cost of important spare parts. This will cost you in 29 thousand rubles, goes?</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_b3_texnik_medved_dialog_o_safe_2_txt">
<text>It goes. Hold the money.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_b3_texnik_medved_dialog_o_safe_22_txt">
<text>I'll go later.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_b3_texnik_medved_dialog_o_safe_3_txt">
<text>So ... excellent. Hey! Stop ... do not leave, now I will reveal it before your eyes. So ... so ... Oh! So it turned out. Keep the contents ... wow! You were lucky, such a habar pulled off! You are lucky! Okay, take it good.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_b3_texnik_medved_dialog_o_safe_4_txt">
<text>Great. I take it!</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_b3_texnik_yar_dialog_o_safe_0_txt">
<text>Listen, I have a box that is closed to some sort of sophisticated lock. Can you open?</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_b3_texnik_yar_dialog_o_safe_1_txt">
<text>Oh, not ... everything is too sophisticated here, the brain is boiling ... Sorry, I'm not strong in this.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_b3_texnik_yar_dialog_o_safe_2_txt">
<text>Nah, well, you bent ... This is not to me, certainly.</text>
</string>

    <string id="kpl_a2_texnik_materials_done_0_txt">
        <text>Here, technician. I found the whole list of your radio materials. Hold it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="kpl_a2_texnik_materials_done_1_txt">
        <text>Thank you so much! Take a reward. Oh yes! With your finds - now I can do any modernization.</text>
    </string>

    <string id="kpl_a2_texnik_b200_second_took_0_txt">
        <text>Why don't you do modernization?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="kpl_a2_texnik_b200_second_took_1_txt">
        <text>You see, Llya so that I can do them, I do not have enough piles of different components. They say that on the test complex "P-I", there are some radio materials. They would have come in handy for me. Do you want modernization? Bring me everything that I wrote out on this sheet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="kpl_a2_texnik_b200_second_took_2_txt">
        <text>OK. Understood.</text>
    </string>	
	
<string id="kpl_a2_shnir_dialog_start_0">
<text>Mercenary, it's good that I found you!</text>
</string>
<string id="kpl_a2_shnir_dialog_start_1">
<text>Oh, military. Did something happen? Where is your commander?</text>
</string>
<string id="kpl_a2_shnir_dialog_start_2">
<text>Just about this I need you. He asked to convey that he went towards the plant with the group and that soon they would return.</text>
</string>
<string id="kpl_a2_shnir_dialog_start_3">
<text>Have you tried to contact with your own?</text>
</string>
<string id="kpl_a2_shnir_dialog_start_4">
<text>And hell is there! The connection disappeared, as if evaporated ... Any attempts to switch to our channel - as if they are encoded. It seems to me that something or someone blocks our connection with them. Well, since the "center" does not answer, at the moment - there is no one to wait for help from.</text>
</string>
<string id="kpl_a2_shnir_dialog_start_5">
<text>And what did you decide?</text>
</string>
<string id="kpl_a2_shnir_dialog_start_6">
<text>The commander said that he would establish everything. You just need to wait.</text>
</string>
<string id="kpl_a2_shnir_dialog_start_7">
<text>Clear. Remind me, where did he go?</text>
</string>
<string id="kpl_a2_shnir_dialog_start_8">
<text>On the "P-I" complex, it is, not far from the plant. If you really want to, run for reconnaissance, check for yourself. But I repeat, he said that they were not for long, I think he would return soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="kpl_a2_shnir_dialog_start_9">
<text>Soon? And ... for a long time they are already there?</text>
</string>
<string id="kpl_a2_shnir_dialog_start_10">
<text>Yes, nothing. They just left.</text>
</string>
<string id="kpl_a2_shnir_dialog_start_111">
<text>It's clear. I will keep in mind.</text>
</string>

<string id="kpl_a2_shnir_dialog_start_222">
<text>I will wait for them here. With my ammunition, far from the camp.</text>
</string>

<string id="cit_a2_sich_typical_quests_start_0">
<text>Is there any other work?</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_a2_sich_typical_quests_start_1">
<text>Yes. There is something for you. This is what I can offer you.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_a2_sich_typical_quests_start_2">
<text>I take everything. Prepare a reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_a2_sich_typical_quests_start_3">
<text>I still refuse to do all this work.</text>
</string>

<string id="cit_a2_sich_typical_quests_dones_0">
<text>About your tasks.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_a2_sich_typical_quests_dones_1">
<text>Yes, I'm listening carefully. What do you have?</text>
</string>

<string id="cit_a2_sich_typical_quests_dones_11">
<text>I examined the scanner near the anomaly "Turned out". Here are the results.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_a2_sich_typical_quests_dones_22">
<text>I examined the scanner near the anomaly "Electro-Gril". Here are the results.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_a2_sich_typical_quests_dones_33">
<text>I examined the scanner near the anomaly "Fire drone". Here are the results.</text>
</string>

<string id="cit_a2_sich_typical_quests_dones_4">
<text>Here is your reward. Great.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_a2_sich_typical_quests_dones_5">
<text>It's nice to deal with you, Shcherban.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_a2_sich_typical_quests_dones_555">
<text>Nothing. I'm still in the process.</text>
</string>


<string id="sector_11_one_tactic_hello_dialog_0_text">
<text>Hello, gloomy.</text>
</string>
<string id="sector_11_dva_tactic_hello_dialog_0_text">
<text>Hello gloomy.</text>
</string>
<string id="sector_11_tri_tactic_hello_dialog_0_text">
<text>Great gloomy, how is life?</text>
</string>

<string id="kupol_kiparisoptis_hello_start_0_text">
<text>Good night, traveler. What did you come with?</text>
</string>


<string id="sector_dialog_texnik_skupka_0_text">
<text>Do you buy damaged weapons?</text>
</string>
<string id="sector_dialog_texnik_skupka_1_text">
<text>Show what you have there.</text>
</string>
<string id="sector_dialog_texnik_skupka_nyka_text">
<text>Well, show what you have there?</text>
</string>
<string id="sector_dialog_texnik_skupka_xorosho_text">
<text>Fine.</text>
</string>
<string id="sector_dialog_texnik_skupka_kaknibyd_text">
<text>Somehow next time.</text>
</string>
<string id="sector_dialog_texnik_skupka_9090_text">
<text>And what is so cheap bought up?</text>
</string>
<string id="sector_dialog_texnik_skupka_90901_text">
<text>Well, I need spare parts, but there is not so much money to scatter them ... But, I do not buy all guns. All these new, sophisticated trunks - I do not need ... But if you have something interesting, maybe I'll buy it.</text>
</string>
<string id="sector_dialog_texnik_skupka_90901488_text">
<text>Clearly.</text>
</string>



<string id="cit_k54_dialog_medic_task_one_0_text">
<text>Listen, you seem to be a physician, and your assortment of medicines is some kind of very meager. You can find out why?</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_k54_dialog_medic_task_one_1_text">
<text>Hah! But I have nothing to trade. The other day, I had to bring a whole container with medicines, but the couriers did not appear. And this is strange, the guys are sensible! Always brought everything in time. MGX ... so think ... how to be now.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_k54_dialog_medic_task_one_2_text">
<text>And you did not accidentally still have their contacts? Throw them on the PDA. I will try to find couriers.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_k54_dialog_medic_task_one_3_text">
<text>Hmmm, okay, here. I would be very grateful - if you find my container. I will not offend the reward.</text>
</string>


<string id="cit_k54_dialog_medic_task_two_0_text">
<text>I found a container ... Couriers too ... They are dead, the controller is to blame.</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_k54_dialog_medic_task_two_1_text">
<text>What?! Eh ... The guys were sensible, always cautious, they delivered everything in time, but here it is ... Thank you for figuring out my misfortune. Well, since you brought medications - now they will appear on my sale. As I promised, I will not offend the reward. Eh, there would be couriers to find new, normal ...</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_k54_dialog_medic_task_two_2_text">
<text>Well, hold the container.</text>
</string>


<string id="cit_b106d_sich_quest_dialog_txt_0"> 
<text>I'm about work.</text> 
</string> 
<string id="cit_b106d_sich_quest_dialog_txt_1"> 
<text>Do you say work? Hmm ... I have one task. It is necessary to go to the anomaly that nearby and withdraw the indicators from one device, the work is nonsense, and I do not promise much money. Well, I agree?</text> 
</string> 
<string id="cit_b106d_sich_quest_dialog_txt_11"> 
<text>I will do it. Give only the coordinates of the place.</text> 
</string> 
<string id="cit_b106d_sich_quest_dialog_txt_12"> 
<text>Hmm, no, thanks. Not now.</text> 
</string> 
<string id="cit_b106d_sich_quest_dialog_txt_112"> 
<text>Great, I'm waiting. Here are the coordinates. You are only more careful there, hell knows what is going on now ... you will receive a reward after I have data.</text> 
</string>
 
 
<string id="cit_b106d_sich_quest_dialog_txt_2"> 
<text>Yes. Well, did what I asked?</text> 
</string> 
<string id="cit_b106d_sich_quest_dialog_txt_4"> 
<text>No, I work on it.</text> 
</string> 
<string id="cit_b106d_sich_quest_dialog_txt_3"> 
<text>Yes. Everything is done. Here are the results.</text> 
</string> 
<string id="cit_b106d_sich_quest_dialog_txt_331"> 
<text>Great, let me check ... Super, the indicators are removed. The work is done successfully.</text> 
</string> 
<string id="cit_b106d_sich_quest_dialog_txt_332"> 
<text>What is there with my reward?</text> 
</string> 
<string id="cit_b106d_sich_quest_dialog_txt_333"> 
<text>Here is your reward. As agreed, he did not promise much.</text> 
</string> 
<string id="cit_b106d_sich_quest_dialog_334"> 
<text>Uhh. Goodbye.</text> 
</string> 


<string id="cit_a71_wounded_man_dialog_0_text">
<text>Um-mh ... blah, hit ...</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_a71_wounded_man_dialog_1_text">
<text>What happened to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_a71_wounded_man_dialog_2_text">
<text>Oh and pain ... Damn it, I never wanted to bend like that ...</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_a71_wounded_man_dialog_3_text">
<text>Let me help you. I will fix the first -aid kit and not far from the camp! Not a drift!</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_a71_wounded_man_dialog_4_text">
<text>I'm just won't help me, I'm living the last minutes ... You're helping me, I ask ... Find the freak who threw me ... Chien ... his nickname, we, we made their way to army warehouses ... Together ... we got it, moved to the camp, and he had a bullet in my stomach, well, I didn't need it, and I didn't have it for my partners. To take a newcomer, I showed up from nowhere, I proposed help ... on business to me ... Eh, I die ... Let the last minute to spend alone ...</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_a71_wounded_man_dialog_5_text">
<text>I will find this scum, I promise. He will be responsible for everything.</text>
</string>

<string id="cit_a71_wounded_man_dialog_55_text">
<text>Sorry. I would do the same.</text>
</string>	
	
	
<string id="city_a2_gero_dialog_12_0_text">
<text>Alive? It seems to be ... okay. I went to my post. You, you get acquainted with our boss, how time will be. His name is gracious. By the way, the forester came, asked about you, he is here in the camp. I asked you to come up.</text>
</string>	
<string id="city_a2_gero_dialog_1_1_text">
<text>Where am I?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_a2_gero_dialog_1_11_text">
<text>Who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_a2_gero_dialog_1_111_text">
<text>What's happening?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_a2_gero_dialog_1_1488_text">
<text>Wait! I will shoot! Who is it? Where am I? And what is happening?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_a2_gero_dialog_1_1489_text">
<text>Now you shoot me! Less questions and more adequate, okay? Or can I hear badly?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_a2_gero_dialog_1_1490_text">
<text>Okay. Calmly!</text>
</string>

<string id="city_a2_gero_dialog_12_12_text">
<text>Mercenary, talked to our superiors?</text>
</string>	
<string id="city_a2_gero_dialog_2_1_text">
<text>Yes, I will talk with Shcherban, and he clarified the situation to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_a2_gero_dialog_2_11_text">
<text>What do you have to do?! Deer...</text>
</string>
<string id="city_a2_gero_dialog_2_111_text">
<text>You talk to me here, garbage. You are nobody here and call you, understand? Therefore, answer briefly and clearly. Have you talked to the main one?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_a2_gero_dialog_2_1111_text">
<text>Yes, I talked to him.</text>
</string>

<string id="city_a2_sich_disccusion_dialog_1_0_text">
<text>A mercenary came to your senses? I hope that I will be glad to meet our acquaintance. Everyone is called me here, and as I understand you, a gloomy?</text>
</string>	
<string id="city_a2_sich_disccusion_dialog_1_1_text">
<text>My respect. Yes. I would like to know what happened to me?</text>
</string>	
<string id="city_a2_sich_disccusion_dialog_1_2_text">
<text>And hell knows you! My people found you near the radar - "Dome". In time, they came up, a little more and your turntable would have rushed to hell with dogs - I do not think that something living would have left from you after that. And therefore, we made you a service - it means that the return should be from you. I do not care who you are - mercenaries, military, or stalkers! You will work out all together and honestly. If you want to increase the reputation among us, then talk with stalkers in the camp, perhaps one of them needs your help. And yes, if you want to earn extra money, right at the entrance, the board of ads, there will always be tasks for such as you.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_a2_sich_disccusion_dialog_1_22_text">
<text>Yeah. OK. Nice to meet you. Thanks, of course, for the jacket, water and food ... And of course thanks to your people for not leaving us to their own fate.</text>
</string>


<string id="a_r_atr_about_self_0">
<text>Tell us about yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="a_r_atr_about_self_1">
<text>I am Professor Voronov. I am engaged in the study of abnormalities in the Choso. He used to work on this topic behind the perimeter, in Kyiv. But, I decided to be, so to speak, closer to the source. After a recent super-scope in the vicinity of the dome, we were transported here to discover new research. The conditions here are good, the place seems to be protected ... \n the truth offers to work at the outskirts of the zone, in some new laboratory ... Here - I think. Maybe in the future I agree to the proposal. In the meantime, I have enough work here.</text>
</string>
<string id="a_r_atr_about_upgr_0">
<text>Tell us what modifications of artifacts can be done.</text>
</string>
<string id="a_r_atr_about_upgr_1">
<text>The most popular type of change is the removal of the radiation component. I specialize in this. As you know, many artifacts are radioactive, but there is a way to fix it. During modernization, we try to first remove all the radiation from the object, and there, if possible, make its basic properties a little better. Well, as they say - they knocked out a wedge with a wedge.</text>
</string>
<string id="a_r_atr_trader_start_11">
<text>Hello. It's nice to see new faces. If you want to change the properties of artifacts, then you came to the address.</text>
</string>

<string id="a_r_atr_trader_start_21">
<text>Your order is ready. Take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="a_r_atr_trader_start_31">
<text>Yes.</text>
</string>

<string id="contract_hello_dialog_girl_afina_0_text_start">
<text>Hello, gloomy ...</text>
</string>

<string id="atr_actor_start">
<text>I want to change the properties of my artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="atr_next_time_general">
<text>Another time.</text>
</string>		
<string id="atr_radiation_trader_3">
<text>\n here ... Now let's take a look at which of your artifacts I can, so to speak: pump.</text>
</string>
<string id="atr_radiation_trader_4">
<text>\n hmm ... Unfortunately, you do not have artifacts whose properties I can change. %C[255,238,153,26] Could you have poured artifacts in the container?</text>
</string>	
<string id="atr_mixer_trader">
<text>%C[255,238,153,26] Under local conditions, I can make not any changes in artifacts. The price for changing the properties of a determined artifact varies in the region of 25-35 thousand. If you do not have a given amount, then unfortunately we cannot improve your artifact. Let's see what artifacts you have.</text>
</string>
<string id="atr_trader_come_later">
<text>Great. Come after three hours. If you want, you can rest for now on the mattress, to the left of me. %C[255,238,153,26] When everything is ready - I will tell you, do not worry.</text>
</string>	
	
</string_table>

