<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>	
	<string id="out_start_mod_skyff_dialog_0">
		<text>In, a new face in the zone. Another hunter for artifacts came? Well, how is your well -being, hunter?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_mod_skyff_dialog_1">
		<text>Thank you, it seems to be better already, the controller still pretty well patted. And yes, I arrived here for adventures, and it will not hurt to earn extra money.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_mod_skyff_dialog_2">
		<text>That's good. But you should not thank, we helped each other - I distracted the mutant, and you finished off. Mutual assistance. Only then, for some reason, you chopped off, so you had to carry you to the base.
 And I, too, on earnings here, so to speak. Rather, I thought I would work. I'll be a bit, I will scatter, and for one money they have a subsour and home. But it wasn't there. You know, the energy here is some special-as if honey is smeared here, and for some reason it does not pull home at all. Here everyone who came, they said just like you, they say, I'll be a bit, I will work with the money and go home. Who needed the apartment to whom for a car, someone just to solve personal problems and an amendment of the financial situation, and so on. But in the end, so everyone here is now hanging out. (Laughs) Of course, not everything here for earnings or adventures, there are a lot of those who are not in the widespread, so they have found a secluded place. But they hold on isolated. However, it is impossible to say that this is a bunch of nonsense. Some of their groups are organized better than the famous warriors of the debt or anarchists of freedom. But these are their problems. In our camp, all the guys are normal, however, some with cockroaches are in their heads, but who does not have them? Just someone has more, someone has less. So here ... if anything, then my name is Scythian. Stalkers consider me here for the main one, but this is not entirely true. We have no bosses and subordinates. Although if I say something, then they listen to me and help me in business and undertakings.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_mod_skyff_dialog_3">
		<text>Nice to meet you. My name is Klim. I just came to the zone, but the basics of safety was already explained to me ... True, they forgot to warn about the insidious controllers ... And if it weren't for your timely help, Scythian, I don't even know what I would have to represent myself now ...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_mod_skyff_dialog_4">
		<text>This is good, it means that once again you will not have to look after you. You won't climb into the anomaly, you will not want to stroke the animal animal. In principle, if you have any questions, then you can safely ask them. Now we are in our camp, the place is relatively safe.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_mod_skyff_dialog_5">
		<text>Can I somehow thank you for help?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_mod_skyff_dialog_6">
		<text>It's not worth it, why not a good person just help? Let me better tell you something about the local environment, and I won't load more conversations, otherwise I see you tired, while here, to Chernobyl-1, I got, and this controller is even.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_mod_skyff_dialog_7">
		<text>It would be nice, tell me.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_mod_skyff_dialog_8">
		<text>There are enough anomalies here, but if there are bolts, then there will be no problem to pass. There are plenty of mutants, it is better to get the nose where it was not to poke. Moreover, you can find both a small individual and a large one. The guys recently said that the chimeras were discovered. Of the stalkers, in addition to us, there is still a duty. You yourself understand, without them nowhere ... Recently mercenaries appeared. You know, we try to live with everyone peacefully, so that if you die, it was not offensive that it was killed in such a place in such a place. So briefly the picture is like this.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_mod_skyff_dialog_9">
		<text>The picture is clear. Is there a technician, a merchant, a physician in the camp?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_mod_skyff_dialog_10">
		<text>Certainly. The camp, although not as large as on the sprout, you will buy a couple of loaves and a first -aid kit with a bandage, you will fix PMKU. We have two mechanics - the leader of the debt navigator and the local stalker puck. By the way, on the ground floor of this building there is a bar. Look, it is fun there!</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="out_start_mod_skyff_dialog_11">
		<text>Thank you, Scythian. Perhaps I will rest a little now, otherwise something has been tired.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_mod_skyff_dialog_12">
		<text>Of course, rest, not every day you get under the controller. If I need it, then I will be here so far. But just look, let's talk about that about ... maybe what a job will turn up.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_mod_skyff_dialog_13">
		<text>Hands.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_0">
		<text>I wanted to ask, Scythian, and you have been here for a long time?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_1">
		<text>It depends on what to compare. For 4 years I have been hanging around here, and it feels that I came only a month ago.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_2">
		<text>Where will you come from? And what brought you here?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_3">
		<text>I am from Chernigov. You know, by nature I am extreme. I like the risk. Before the arrival here, he was engaged in a digger, a mountain Kayakeker, climbed the mountains, and everything is in this spirit.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_4">
		<text>So you want to say that you exchanged all these charms of life for a radiation zone where bullets fly that those flies around a dung pile?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_5">
		<text>Eh, Klim, is your case, not a scanner in the skull? Yes, your truth - sounds funny. Of course, it was not quite so. Our family was big - I, for the elder, two sisters, two younger brothers and mother. Father somewhere in Afghanistan disappeared. Neither the funerals for him, nor any other information ... As if there was no person in the world ... Mother and younger peanut sat, so that the care of the family was lying on me. After the college, I got a job on the foundry, but since I still had no experience, they gave me a small salary. If there were alone, it seems to be normal, but in my case there was very little money. Well, I decided to engage in a "business" in order to feed the family and put on. And in the 80s, the entire petty "business" was reduced to only an anger - jeans, different trinkets are overseas, vinyl ...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_6">
		<text>And how did you take it to her? You did not go out into the street and began to scream: take me to speculators.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_7">
		<text>No, of course. Everything is much easier here. My school friend had a second cousin, whose father worked at the USSR Embassy in England. The brother was a kind of supplier, but we are in the role of sales. You know ... I don't regret it. He walked in jeans, Fantu with Pevi drank, and it became easier for the family to live. It is dangerous, of course, all this was, but in your youth you don't think about the bad.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_8">
		<text>Well, then what?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_9">
		<text>And then ...? We wandered the eyes of the cops pretty much, but we managed to establish a “contact” with them, and they did not touch us, although they hinted that in the end we would play out. And so it happened ... Our activity has long gone beyond the borders of Chernigov, and got close to Kyiv. And either we interfered with anyone, or the authorities themselves initiated work on us, but ...
 In the yard stood 1990. Vitka died. They gathered in the apartment to remember him, everything was the rank of chinar until the cops with the KGB officers came. Not local. They took everyone. True, then they had to let us go ... It turns out that they had nothing to do with us except the denunciations from our "well -wishers". Well, the case helped us - the whole product was sold, and the new delivery was delayed ... So they took us to take us, but they could not prove anything - they did not have material evidence of our involvement in illegal activity. Later, we learned that it was a personal initiative of the Gabesh roof of the Kyiv collar, and therefore neither their authorities nor local bodies were informed. However, surveillance of us was then for a long time. I really did not want to sit down, let my life be a slope and leave the family to the mercy of fate ... So this activity had to be stopped ... probably it is for the better, because they got off with only a slight fright ...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_10">
		<text>Yes ... Here you are, grandmother, and "Yuryev Day". And then what?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_11">
		<text>That's for sure. Again I got a job, but, as before, the salary was not so hot, and I had a word for more free life and some prosperity. After the collapse of the Union, I went to St. Petersburg, but it did not work out there. And I decided to try my luck in the south, I went to Astrakhan. Considering that the farms in me developed some entrepreneurial vein, one fine day I met a “necessary” person who was engaged in the craft of sturgeon in the Caspian. Here, once again, I began to have a new life, now as a smuggler. Just don't think about me too badly, you still didn't trade in drugs, but, it turns out, a “flash” for wealthy customers - caviar black. First, there were deliveries only in Russia, and then my “business partner” proposed to expand my client base, and start deliveries to Ukraine. I agreed. In the beginning, everything went well. But everything that is illegal, sooner or later attracts attention. So here. Only this time it was no longer the "lawyers" ran, but some kind of punks. They figured it out with the squint, but a certain person appeared and said that the leader of their brigade would not forgive this for us. The most interesting thing is that they all knew about me and my family ... I did not want to substitute my family ... I had to turn my activities here. There was nothing to do, and the family demanded. I had to get a job again, now in the locomotive depot with a handy. I traveled with road repair teams, helped them - the work was hard, but they paid normal for that time. So ... Once they repaired a distillation at the Yanov station. The station itself is not valid, but once a week there were trades in transit there. This business trip was planned for two days. We spent the night in a sleeping car. It was summer, very hot and I could not sleep. He left the car at night. He walked at the beginning of the composition, then back. And passing opposite the station itself, I saw some kind of reflection inside. Well, I think it seemed. And he flashed again. I didn't even know what to think about. Maybe one of ours settled in a push, maybe someone also just can't sleep, like me, and therefore examines this attraction. It is incomprehensible - an abandoned station, and suddenly the lights blink ... I am not a timid dozen, so I decided to see what it is. I go into the building ... Surprisingly, there were quite a lot of left from the situation, it feels like only yesterday they left the station. A strange feeling took possession of me ... And then, among some kind of collapse on the floor, something flashed again. He came closer, and there some beacon flashes, as if he was giving an alarm. I picked it up, I looked, and he has a screen, on which only three words are written, but one pretext.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_12">
		<text>And what was the year? Such a know-how, but in such a hole, would not have been left just like that.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_13">
		<text>The year was 2004, just a couple of years before the second disaster. Well, this is not quite a know-how: there was already a cellular connection, but this one was more like a pager, only a larger screen.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_14">
		<text>And what was written?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_15">
		<text>"You will find me in Pripyat." Since then, I seemed to be replaced ... who left it, to whom the message is addressed, and how did this communicator end up on Yanov? All this interested me very much, but the concern for the family was more important than any “interests”, so gradually this story was forgotten. And when the second accident occurred, then somehow that story surfaced in memory. Not immediately, but I managed to find out that after the second disaster, Pripyat is not so uninhabited, as well as the entire territory of the alienation zone, as they say and write about it.
 Having thought a little, and considering that I am not afraid of risk, I decided to take a walk here, especially since I found with whom. And at the same time, Khabar also hoped to find which one to sell profitably ... I came here in 2008, and for four years now I've been trying to find a habar and sell it, but only here it is not possible to do this, but the zone "does not let go home.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_16">
		<text>Well, did you find the owner of that "Page" and the addressee of the message?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_info_skyff_dialog_17">
		<text>No, I'm not getting to Pripyat yet - it's very dangerous there ... If you wish, when you go there to go there, you can take it from me, maybe you will find the owner with the addressee. Something I really started talking too much. Not everyone loves to remember his past, but I won't stop me with how to tell me.</text>
	</string>	
	
    <string id="out_skyff_hunting_dialog_0">
		<text>Scythian, I'm used to taking a bull by the horns: you said something about work. Is there something to take?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_hunting_dialog_1">
		<text>We have the following thing: "Big hunt." After emissions, we arrange joint raids on large abnormal clusters in order to search for artifacts. So come with our guys, we are just going, especially if you find something, you can calmly sell the merchant found and not bad to earn.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_hunting_dialog_2">
		<text>Interesting. Moreover, it never interferes with replenishing financial resources.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_hunting_dialog_3">
		<text>Great. The group will wait for you at the exit from the base.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="actor_koldun_dialog_0">
		<text>Great, stalkers. Klim is crying, Scythian suggested participating in a "big hunt", so why not?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_koldun_dialog_1">
		<text>Glad, acquaintance, Klim! You can call me a sorcerer. So the plan is this: we move closer to the abnormal area, take out the bolts and the detector, and look for nishtyaki. Look, Klim, an abnormal cluster is located in the distance. We call it "spiral", because It has peculiar "corridors" by which you can go. “Corridors” are a kind of passage limited by anomalies and leading to the “heart” of an anomalous zone where you can find a non -hut artifact. If you want to look there, then be extremely careful, especially when you start to get out.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_koldun_dialog_2">
		<text>I will take into account, thank you for the warning.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_koldun_dialog_3">
		<text>Then let's go.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="out_skyff_after_hunt_dialog_0">
		<text>Wow, Scythian, an interesting hunt here is arranged here, I did not think that I would get so much adrenaline!</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_after_hunt_dialog_1">
		<text>Like? That's great. Just keep in mind - in such raids, if experience is not enough, one better do not go. And then he will twist so that you won't get out, and maybe at least a partner will help out. If he does not spin. Come on, Klim, take a serious mask from your face that does not change your face - I'm joking, but in every joke there is a share of truth.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_after_hunt_dialog_2">
		<text>Thank you. Scythian, I see you a serious and respected man, you can safely trust you. Can you tell you something if I ask?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_after_hunt_dialog_3">
		<text>For trust, thank you. And what do you want to find out?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_after_hunt_dialog_4">
		<text>Yes, a lot of things. Maybe you guessed that I was here for a reason, that is, not quite a "hunter for Khabar"? I want to resolve one riddle here.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_after_hunt_dialog_5">
		<text>I did not guess, but not surprised. This is in the order of things.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_after_hunt_dialog_6">
		<text>Then listen. Once, even before the accident, I lived in a small town called Chernobyl-1, that is, here. A few days before the disaster, I witnessed the appearance of a certain group of people, with very strange equipment and ammunition. Turned around for some time in the station area, as if studying something. They had portable probes that they directed towards the station and made some measurements. At least it was like that. And the most amazing thing was that these people distributed information about a terrible disaster around the city, which, supposedly, should happen in the near future and repeat in twenty years. I, having received a letter with this information, although I understood little in it, still decided to leave the city with my family. A few days later a predicted disaster occurred, and the group disappeared unless. And twenty years later, the second disaster occurred that formed this zone. That's when I decided to go back, find my house and the very letter. It wrote in detail about some anomalies and phenomena. But you yourself understand that we are not always stronger than circumstances, so although the decision was made almost immediately, and managed to bring it to life only now. Moreover, it was necessary to prepare - leave the family funds for life, get information about the zone itself and all that is connected with it. In general, the time was not for nothing anyway. But now the chances of finding a solution to those unknowns who saved more than one life with their warning, much higher than at the time of the decision ...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_after_hunt_dialog_7">
		<text>Ah here it is. It turns out that those people knew what would happen. And, perhaps, they could also prevent a disaster? Or maybe they themselves arranged it? I wonder who it was?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_after_hunt_dialog_8">
		<text>These are the same questions and brought me here. One to one. We must try to find out. Moreover, their appearance changed my fate. So for me this is more than a simple interest.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_after_hunt_dialog_9">
		<text>I understand you. Well, if, if there is what information that your question will pop up, then I will definitely tell you. Moreover, I was now interested in it. In the meantime, I recommend going to Stepanych, ours, you can and money to earn extra money, and sell your art.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_after_hunt_dialog_10">
		<text>Fine. I'm going, I'll talk. It is necessary to establish contact with the local population.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="out_first_trader_dialog_0">
		<text>Hi, how is trade? Boyko is going?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_first_trader_dialog_1">
		<text>It happens differently. A good day with stalkers, then trade will be, if they pass, it will still be - they will come for vodka. Hehe.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="out_first_trader_dialog_2">
		<text>So you are in the plus in a kind?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="out_first_trader_dialog_3">
		<text>Yes, only the difference is what it will be - ordinary or fat!</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="out_first_trader_dialog_4">
		<text>Everything is clear with you. Is there any work for me?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="out_first_trader_dialog_5">
		<text>There is always work, only usually I do not entrust it to anyone. And for the first time I see you, and I don't know if you can trust you with such a thing?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_first_trader_dialog_6">
		<text>As for the work, the Scythian advised me to contact you. So I am not "who hit."</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_first_trader_dialog_7">
		<text>Scythian, you say ... Then it changes the matter, I trust the Skif, as myself. If he said that you can, then listen: I need some documents from one secretary, I will give you the coordinates. You will bring safe and safety - I will pay well, I won't offend.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_first_trader_dialog_8">
		<text>Well, excellent, the money is never superfluous.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_first_trader_dialog_9">
		<text>So listen. Recently, our guys of the PDA of one stalker broke. Well, the information, accordingly, went to me. In the PDA, a certain landmark was given: "I diverted in Chernobyl-1, in the building on the ground floor. There is a staircase on the roof on the building, and a bunch of anomalies are nearby, but you can pass." Well, to direct this tip in the right direction, but find a cache. If I agree, then forward and with the song. Good luck.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_first_trader_dialog_10">
		<text>There are no questions. As I find something, I will immediately beacon.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="out_found_trader_dialog_0">
		<text>I found it. There were "eyewitnesses" of the first catastrophe.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_found_trader_dialog_1">
		<text>Ehh, this is always the way ... On a tip on a large manner, you get the next prehistoric junk, which can only be poisoned by tourists and historians, and even then for a penny.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_found_trader_dialog_2">
		<text>Well, what can you do. There was nothing more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baron_wounded_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey stalker, help, brother, I feel .... my end will come soon ...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="baron_wounded_dialog_1">
		<text>I only have a first -aid kit with me, I will bandage you and drag you to the camp.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="baron_wounded_dialog_2">
		<text>You can't drag me ... alive ... a ..., I feel how cold it becomes ... blah ...</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="baron_wounded_dialog_3">
		<text>What did you even happen?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="baron_wounded_dialog_4">
		<text>A deal was appointed at this place. I had to transfer some documents with information about the events that occurred here in 1986 and about the group that was engaged in the experimentation, here, in the zone, well, in the form in which it was before these events. Everything went as always. I came alone with documents, as I agreed. Here is a fool ... It was necessary to leave them in the cache. You look, there wouldn't be so many holes in me now ... they came up and just opened the fingertips ... They took the brought documents and left ...</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="baron_wounded_dialog_5">
		<text>And who was at least?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="baron_wounded_dialog_6">
		<text>Mercenaries ... Their base is located in the bunker, not far from the stalker camp ... This bunker is still called the "refuge" ... You just won't go there ... security there ... constantly ... uh ... ar-r-th.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="baron_wounded_dialog_7">
		<text>Well, rest in peace, friend. Um ..., that means where the mercenaries, which the Scythian mentioned, now live, now I know ... It is strange all this ... For some old papers, they easily take and kill, violating all the agreements. It would be necessary to tell the Scythian, maybe some kind of mess is planned.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="out_start_technik_dialog_0">
		<text>Salam in half! Here I walked near the base and found PDA, almost not rusty, which means I was recently lost. I wanted to climb it, and there everything is under passwords. Can you hack him?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_technik_dialog_1">
		<text>And you don't get sick. Why do you need it?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_technik_dialog_2">
		<text>A strange question ... maybe there is something sensible there or just interesting. For example, a tip on a cache or photo of the girls naked, it is boring here without a female.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_technik_dialog_3">
		<text>Well, you bent. Believe my experience of the techie - no one has yet found PDA, in which there would be something interesting, and even more useful, and even more so with the girls beautiful! Although ..., given that you are not so long ago in the zone, how do you know.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_technik_dialog_4">
		<text>M-daa ... And I thought that you can spit it again .. After all, everyone is praised, that, they say, a great specialist! Well, no, no ..., maybe someone else will take ...?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_technik_dialog_5">
		<text>What are you? Do you doubt my abilities?! Well give me here and blow from here. When I finish everything, I will inform you on the PDA. But keep in mind, there will be a request for you.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_technik_dialog_6">
		<text>When I finish everything, I will inform you on the PDA. But keep in mind, there will be a request for you.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_technik_dialog_7">
		<text>Hold it. Do not be afraid, we count - although I am new here, but I study quickly.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="skyff_killer_base_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello, Scythian. There is an urgent conversation to you.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_killer_base_dialog_1">
		<text>Directly urgent?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_killer_base_dialog_2">
		<text>Well ..., not so much, but, I think, important and he will interest you!</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_killer_base_dialog_3">
		<text>Intrigued! Did you really dug something in its business?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_killer_base_dialog_4">
		<text>In the letter found, nothing new was found. But there is, as it seems to me, something more important. Returning from his apartment to the camp, he stumbled upon a wounded stalker. He provided him first aid, but, apparently, the wounds were too serious, and he still died. However, before the death of the poor fellow I was able to tell something. Something strange ... You have been living here for quite some time, tell me, what kind of bunker, called the "refuge" is in the city? By the way, in this bunker itself, according to that stalker, mercenaries were settled.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_killer_base_dialog_5">
		<text>Yes, hell knows. No one has ever been there, and it can be for the better.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_killer_base_dialog_6">
		<text>Everything is very incomprehensible. Looks like things here are quite serious.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_killer_base_dialog_7">
		<text>Yes ..., it's strange ... but I still thank for the information. Okay, until they are hiring us, we will not touch them either. However, it will be necessary to notify everyone so that they are more careful with them, and in general it is not known for what they are here.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_killer_base_dialog_8">
		<text>Do you know how to get into this bunker?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_killer_base_dialog_9">
		<text>Is it tired of living?! Better do not stick there - go around this place a hundred miles! Especially in the light of new information.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_killer_base_dialog_10">
		<text>I have a matter for them. We must find out something.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_killer_base_dialog_11">
		<text>You want to believe, Klim, you want not to believe, but I am not an assistant to you in this matter. I have never sent stalkers to the faithful death and now I will not.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_killer_base_dialog_12">
		<text>How difficult everything is ... Okay, and any of the locals has been there?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_killer_base_dialog_13">
		<text>No, it seems. Before that, there was no case to this "shelter". Although ... wait a minute, like Guevara was somehow interested in this "refuge", but has long abandoned this matter. At least he did not say anything about this. Yes, and be with a gueve on the alert, although he is a good stalker, he is a former KGBSHNIK, but there are no former ones! So good luck!</text>
	</string>

    <string id="out_wave_gevara_dialog_0">
		<text>Gevara, can you tell me on one question? What do you know about the “shelter” located nearby, in which mercenaries settled?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_wave_gevara_dialog_1">
		<text>Here you have: neither hello you, nor the wishes of prosperity to my family. Looks like a fan of freebie? Okay, do not strain, I'm starting with everyone like that, it immediately becomes clear what a person is. If normal, then he will apologize and improve, if the greyhound, it will begin to perform. I remember in the training in 1983 ... Ah, hmm, what am I talking about? I will not load, somehow I will tell later. What is your interest in this place?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_wave_gevara_dialog_2">
		<text>Sorry, Gevara, my name is Klim. Scythian advised me to contact you. It can sound strange, but this applies to my past life, or rather youth. So you need your help. I met one stalker. The poor fellow already darkened, but said something before he "left." He mentioned some "mercenaries", in any case, he christened them so much that are based in "shelter" and are interested in some documents of the 1986 model.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_wave_gevara_dialog_3">
		<text>Well, well done, you quickly grasp! The Scythian told me about you that you were a small miss, and I spoke only positively. And a man, you see, serious, since you immediately go to business. Therefore, I would be glad to help you, but I have no information on your question. But I know how to get it. So if you really need it, I can voice my plan.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_wave_gevara_dialog_4">
		<text>Once there is no other option, then I listen very carefully to your proposal.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_wave_gevara_dialog_5">
		<text>I have a very interesting document of one, let's say, a “trustee”, or rather one stalker who worked for mercenaries, until I disappeared in anomaly. I buried it, and I took the document to myself, what to disappear good, well, and so ..., just in case. So this case was not long in coming. You are very on time. Most likely, hires do not know that he died. So your legend: you are it! What will you tell them there about where you have been worn for so long, this is your problem. In any case, you act secretly and imperceptibly. Install my device in their lair. The device is old, but in good condition. Allows you to intercept not only sound waves, but also radio signals in a certain radius. Tuning is quite simple. At the very bottom, the device has a mood scale and sliders. After each displacement of the slider, it is necessary to turn on an increase to scan the air for the presence of a signal. After finding the main signal frequency, it will be enough to make three additional amendments for a more accurate tuning. Is everything clear?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_wave_gevara_dialog_6">
		<text>There is nowhere more clearly. Come on your device, we will not pull the time.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="killer_guard_dialog_0">
		<text>Stand, your mother! Where are you going?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="killer_guard_dialog_1">
		<text>Uh ... did you not recognize me or what? Eh, and so every time. It's me, sleeping!</text>
	</string>
    <string id="killer_guard_dialog_2">
		<text>Hm. Yeah. Then go through. I will give documents at the output, you know the rules myself.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="killer_guard_dialog_3">
		<text>Certainly.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="out_killer_ksiva_name">
		<text>Personality certificate.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_killer_ksiva_descr">
		<text>Similar xiva use mercenaries to distinguish "their" from "strangers." The document belongs to no sleep.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_0">
		<text>That's all. Habar threw off, handed over the order. Will I go?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_1">
		<text>Opan is not a damn. Vaska, are you? Something I did not recognize you at first, sorry. I didn't recognize - it means you will be rich. And when did you manage to become our confidant?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_2">
		<text>No, you identified - I'm not Vaska. I gave all the necessary hook and again to the raid.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_3">
		<text>Strange, usually you have a rest after the raids for a couple of days. And then you haven't been to you for so long, I really thought at all for a week you will stick out. Just came, and just an hour later you are already leaving. Something does not fit.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_4">
		<text>What difference do you have? I still have business. You will rush with you here, so you will stay with a bare ass.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_5">
		<text>Something I don't like you today. And before I have seen you somewhere before. Well, Vaska from Kyiv by God, then you sold me to the sour apples, and praised that it was sweet. Do you really not remember - in 1987 it was?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_6">
		<text>Well, you have a memory! I sometimes forget to fasten the fly, and you dived into memories. Look, do not fail.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_7">
		<text>And you know, something you are smart through the chur, and you behave like a fool. After all, we let you here, and you live only at the expense of us. So why do you get? Not order. Since it's so smart, it means this: I ask you a control question, each of ours knows. You guess, you can safely come to the base, you will not guess, you will get lead. Do you understand me?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_8">
		<text>But what can not be understood here. Understood.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_9">
		<text>Who walks in the morning on 4 legs, during the day on 2, and in the evening on 3?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_10">
		<text>This is a human life cycle: a baby, an adult and an old man with a cane.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_91">
		<text>I, from Bodun, my wife and "beloved" mother -in -law.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_11">
		<text>And you are smart, comrad, not over the years. Well, okay, go for now. Sorry, that with claims to you, something I'm out of spirit today.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_92">
		<text>Heh. I see you like to joke, shit a piece. Well, I didn't want to scold my hands today, but apparently I would have to.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_set_oscill_dialog_93">
		<text>Stop. What are you doing ...</text>
	</string>

    <string id="actor_gevara_inf_dialog_0">
		<text>Gevara, I did everything according to your instructions. Is there anything?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_gevara_inf_dialog_1">
		<text>There is nothing to please yet. We work further, without rushing anywhere. As the results will be, I will inform you.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="out_skyff_med_dialog_0">
		<text>I said so that you do not climb where it is not necessary. Gevara told me everything, so do not worry about my awareness. They shot at you from the IEV. The bullet went through, along the tangent, without touching the vital organs. So, consider, under a happy star you were born. Rarely someone survived after a shot from a differential. You were also lucky with the fact that Sherlock and his group, returning from walking, stumbled upon you and provided first aid in time, and then dragged here. And the paramedic clasped properly. Otherwise, my whitish skeleton would lay there now and smiled sweetly.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_med_dialog_1">
		<text>Scythian, how long have I stayed in a shutdown? An hour or two?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_skyff_med_dialog_2">
		<text>It was covered in you. Yes, you, brother, have been crushing the mattress here for a week ... Well, nothing, let's go nherish. And yet ... you really wanted to see Gevara, said that I had "heard" important information for you. Yes ..., and Sherlock with a paramedic do not forget to thank.</text>
	</string>	

	<string id="actor_lekar_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello, Doc! Here, I went to thank for my salvation. Do you need any help?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_lekar_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Hello, Klim! How is the wound? I look, are you again in the ranks, and ready for exploits? And as for help, so it would be very useful now. Recently, it has become tight with medicines, so you have to master the beneficial properties of artifacts. I already have many, but I can't get one in any way.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_lekar_start_dialog_2">
		<text>The wound heals, it almost does not hurt. And at the expense of the artifact I will try to help, after all, in non-payment debt in front of you. He pulled out of the other world.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_lekar_start_dialog_3">
		<text>Then listen, it is necessary to get an artifact transmutat, namely the "fountain". A very useful artifact, especially with injuries.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_lekar_start_dialog_4">
		<text>Not a question. In the near future this gut will be with you.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_lekar_start_dialog_5">
		<text>It would be nice, I really count on you, Klim.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="actor_lekar_final_dialog_0">
		<text>So I returned! Yes, not empty ...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_lekar_final_dialog_1">
		<text>Klim! Did you really get it?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_lekar_final_dialog_2">
		<text>I won't go into details, but I will say that it was not easy.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_lekar_final_dialog_3">
		<text>Klim, you can't even imagine what a great matter did. This artifact will save many lives, and all thanks to you, Klim.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_lekar_final_dialog_4">
		<text>Well, that's great! Good luck, Doc, was glad to help.</text>
	</string>
	
	    <string id="actor_sherlock_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Great, Sherlock. I wanted to thank for my salvation.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sherlock_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Ah, it's you, Klim! Required?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sherlock_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Yes, thanks to you, I will trample the land more. Maybe you need some help? If so, then I am the first to sign up and is ready to start at least now.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sherlock_start_dialog_3">
		<text>Well, if the dock has clasped you, then yes, there is one business.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sherlock_start_dialog_4">
		<text>Tell me.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sherlock_start_dialog_5">
		<text>One of my courier, went with an instruction to the customer. But a couple of hours ago I received the news that, they say, the courier has not yet reached the customer. Two days have passed, and the assignment was not fulfilled. You can't pull, you need to urgently correct the situation. It is necessary to find out where the courier was stuck, and why has not yet been reached the customer.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="actor_sherlock_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Without problems, only I need to know the approximate route of your messenger.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sherlock_start_dialog_7">
		<text>I will throw off all the information available to you.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sherlock_start_dialog_8">
		<text>Let's.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="actor_barsuk_dialog_0">
		<text>Well, how are you, stalker? Not patted?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_barsuk_dialog_1">
		<text>I don't know how to thank you. A little more and probably could not stand it, broke. Local bandits have already been brutally brutalized. If only they were killed, but no, they put it with mines and left to die. My nerves decided to check. Moreover, they argued whether I immediately break off or not.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="actor_barsuk_dialog_2">
		<text>You will thank Sherlock. It was he who sent me in your search. He said that you disappeared and do not get in touch, and the order has not been fulfilled. By the way, everything is fine with the load?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_barsuk_dialog_3">
		<text>Yes, everything is fine with the load. I managed to hide it, but the brothers did not notice. Now I will continue my way. The bandits have gone in a different direction, so you can not shake especially.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_barsuk_dialog_4">
		<text>In this case, good luck to you.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="actor_sherlock_final_dialog_0">
		<text>I found your courier. He says, they say, the bandits took away the whole of the habar, they put it with the mines so that you can't move from the place.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sherlock_final_dialog_1">
		<text>Well, how? Is he still there? What about the load?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sherlock_final_dialog_2">
		<text>The cargo is safe and unharmed, he hid him, the brothers did not notice. I had to sweat a lot to pull out your courier from that trap. Now he is already on the way and, I think, will deliver the cargo as intended.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="actor_sherlock_final_dialog_3">
		<text>Well. Great, Klim. I hope there will be no more problems on the way. What I thought, you do not want to join our small detachment? In large strings, there is less risk, and the good is always divided equally.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sherlock_final_dialog_4">
		<text>I need to solve one problem here, so I'm sorry, I can't with you. Sherlock, and I thank you again for my salvation.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_0">
		<text>Gevara, hello! Scythian said that you have information for me from the "our" bunker. Well, what did you find out interesting? Is there anything worthwhile?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_1">
		<text>You are not in a hurry. I'll tell you everything. You understand what placement is loosening - you are looking for what many people from the Great Earth have been interested in many years: Mi -8, Massad, CIA, Russian FSB, Belarusian KGB, etc. Just don't think that the Soviet state security is asleep - we have an interest in this priority.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_2">
		<text>Yeah, so you are a "former agent" with us?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_3">
		<text>Well, the former is not a former, but I know all the insubifications not only about the special services I mentioned, but also about the entire zone. He was familiar with the shooter. Well, okay, and you already heard a lot, so you can already kill you without hesitation, which, perhaps, will do now ...</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_4">
		<text>Uh, gevara, what are you?! It's me, Klim!</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_5">
		<text>Direct when scary? That's it, and then in the camp they say that Gevara, although "agent", but no one is afraid of him. And that's right - why be afraid of me? You know, I was not always like that. Before entering the service in the KGB - it was in the seventies, I lived in Pripyat, studied at school, ran with friends in construction, drove pigeons on the roofs, and dragged apples with plums from the gardens. He was in love with his neighbor, her name was Anya, though she had already forgotten her name, I remember that on "A". So they lived. And then she left for Kyiv, and then to the east.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_6">
		<text>On the neighbor?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_7">
		<text>Yeah, on distant. She left for Moscow. Well, it remained there, at least I think so, and there who knows where fate enters us. That's not the point. It just seems to me that I still love her. And at that time it was hard to forget her. But then life rushed ... After school, radio engineering entered the technical school, then at the Moscow Institute in the specialty, and then the service in the ranks of the Soviet Army. He studied, served and got a job at the KBO. At first, he was a student, and then they gave the position of an electrician. He worked there for about a year until he met his comrade, who at that time worked in the KGB. We went to the cafe to mark the meeting. We sat, drank the seagull, talked for life. And then he told me that now there is a recruitment to the new unit of the KGB of the USSR, just related to electronics and information security. So, he says, come to us, and I will talk to whom it is necessary so that there are no obstacles. His relative, you see, was a high -ranking person. I thought, and agreed. And what is it? Moreover, according to my profile, and indeed, working for the good of the Motherland is pride. I went through all the necessary procedures and took it. He worked at first in Odessa, then in Lviv, but how he advanced along the service stairs, he was able to knock out a place closer to the house, in Kyiv. Here, after all, to Pripyat, a stone's throw.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_8">
		<text>And then? How did you go to those I are looking for now?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_9">
		<text>This strange group appeared as unexpectedly as later disappeared. Everything happened very quickly, there were practically no witnesses. By the way, you are one of those few who have become an eyewitness to this event. At that time, nothing could be concealed from the gaze of state security, especially since the protection and maintenance of strategic objects. However, in this case, we found nothing and nobody. Then, in order not to raise a panic, it was decided to hide this fact within the walls of the KGB. We have significantly strengthened the security of the station. Although ..., as subsequent events showed, this did not help. Then there was an accident .... For the townsfolk, a version of the explosion of the 4th power unit was controlled and the switchmen were assigned. But this is for the townsfolk. For us, the work has just begun. You just can't imagine how many employees were here. In the strictest secret from all over the Union, the best operatives and investigators from almost all departments and services, as well as employees of various closed research institutes related to the study and study of something “new and unusual” were sent here. For a very long time to list everything, and to know, Klim, this is useless to you. As a result of active searches, we managed to find strange laboratories stuffed with incomprehensible equipment. Moreover, all laboratories were underground. But the most interesting was found in one document. It said that all this is intended for a serious experiment with the noosphere. And if everything goes according to plan, then the project will be implemented after 5 years.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_10">
		<text>With the noosphere ..? I thought that this still applies more to science fiction and is not applicable in practice.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_11">
		<text>I thought so too. The most interesting thing is that attempts to find at least one member of that group were unsuccessful. For that time, this was unthinkable, everyone "stood on the ears", but the fact remains. And four years later, in connection with a coup in the country, more important and primary tasks appeared, so it was not to some mysterious groups, hidden laboratories and everything else that was connected with this strange and mysterious business, politics in a word. After some time, political passions subsided. The KGB was disbanded, but I did not go to the SBU - the oath is given once in my life. Friends helped to issue a retirement, for which I am very grateful to them, otherwise I don't even know where I would have been and what I was doing. The thought of a mysterious group and her work never left me. I am even grateful to her in something, because allowed me to forget my "failed love."
 I did not lose my friends with my friends. And after some Verem, they shared with me some information that, supposedly, the work of that mysterious group was resumed, and the campaign of things with even greater zeal, since new conditions contributed to large -scale experiments. As a result, in 2006 an experiment was conducted, which formed the zone. Therefore, I decided to return here, and to bring the case to the end once, and find out what really happened. True, as you see, in a different status. So it's even good that the fate is connected with this. You know, together it will be easier to figure out what's what.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_12">
		<text>Gevara, you are wise with experience, this is visible. Do you think it will work to get to the bottom of the truth?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_13">
		<text>The level of preparedness of our "enemy" is incredibly high, so who knows how everything will turn out. But you should not lose heart: a negative result is also a result. As long as you were not, I still learned something with the help of our "technical means". So this is: one type appeared in the bunker, which transmitted PDA and reported on the elimination of a stalker with important information.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_14">
		<text>So this sniper, a lover of differentials, is associated with the team from the bunker. Now it becomes slowly understanding where the wind blows from.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_15">
		<text>Klim, here I thought, let's take a walk in the suburbs, there is one place there, it would be necessary to check it. It was a temporary building of the KGB. I think that something should stay there. Indeed, in that building, the information was not only on the tables, well, the documents there are all kinds of, etc., but also a lot of things, which was of particular interest, was removed to the safe, but not flooring, but "disguised", so that from prying eyes, let's say so. I know such "hires of our", maybe something is left there. Any information can be useful to us now. And besides, you need to check something else, so I will need your help.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_16">
		<text>Gevara, but without problems, we do one thing, so we need to act at the same time, the more it is not yet clear what or with whom we are dealing.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_start_gevara_dialog_17">
		<text>Your truth. Here we need not only attentiveness and judgment. The main thing is caution.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="out_gevara_kgb_building_dialog_0">
		<text>Well, what do you have there? Did you take a rifle?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_gevara_kgb_building_dialog_1">
		<text>Yeah, as you see. Have you dug up something?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_gevara_kgb_building_dialog_2">
		<text>No. After the disaster, everyone was taken away, even the furniture was pulled out. However, I checked all this for a long time. Immediately, as soon as it appeared in the zone. And you were not brought here in order to search this building, excuse me. There is much more serious matter, I have to check my one theory. But no one should know about this. You see, no one! And your task is to provide.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_gevara_kgb_building_dialog_3">
		<text>Something while I do not know what exactly is required of me.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_gevara_kgb_building_dialog_4">
		<text>To begin with, followed me. Rifle with you ..., hold the cartridges. It's not far here.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_gevara_kgb_building_dialog_5">
		<text>As you know.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="out_gevara_place_dialog_0">
		<text>Here we are in place. So so. You see that five -story building that is to the right of us? Climb and go out onto the balcony, you will cover me.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_gevara_place_dialog_1">
		<text>Maybe you can still explain what what?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_gevara_place_dialog_2">
		<text>Then I'll tell you when we do it. And while here we will talk about you and we will talk, mutants will run.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_gevara_place_dialog_3">
		<text>So what, from mutants or something to cover?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="out_gevara_place_dialog_4">
		<text>First of all from people. You must make sure that no one, whether it is a mercenary or a stalker, does not matter that no one approaches the distance closer than fifty meters. Shoot the defeat right away. And as for the mutants, do not strain, if they run, then those anomalies in an instant scatter everyone.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_gevara_place_dialog_5">
		<text>Then we will not wait. I take a position, and you get to your work.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="skyff_final_dialog_0">
		<text>Scythian, here are the bastards of these mercenaries, everything smells like jackals. Only Gevara and I began to collect information, as these are the same as it is. Well, I filled them all up, here my conscience is clean, but where the gurecknar went, I don't understand.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_final_dialog_1">
		<text>So ... So, mercenaries go into the active phase of their actions. This is not good.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_final_dialog_2">
		<text>The most interesting of what I managed to find out is that the one who is now leading the mercenaries is here in the zone, and not in the “shelter”, this is the very person who was in the very group that suddenly appeared in 1986 and then disappeared as suddenly. So the answers to questions can be obtained from the source, while it is still alive. But how to go to him? And without a fight, I think, you can't approach them. And here in the camp the people are peaceful, hardly anyone will agree to the storm of their positions?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="skyff_final_dialog_3">
		<text>Here you are right, Klim, no one will go for it. But I know who can help you with this. Yes ... and something else, first you need to take the hire camp in the north of the location. As far as I know, from there all the supply of equipment and provisions to the "shelter" go. So first you need to deal with them.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="skyff_final_dialog_4">
		<text>OK. You know better. You said something about help. I listen carefully, since support will be needed, but not frail.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="skyff_final_dialog_5">
		<text>Try to contact the leader of the duty, they have sharpened the tooth for a long time, and they have always been with them in counterattacks. But they think they think that time has not yet come to deal with them, or maybe they just save the forces. So I think your proposal will interest their chapter.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="skyff_final_dialog_6">
		<text>Do you think he live like this, you live great, and agree?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_final_dialog_7">
		<text>I think it will not refuse. They began to rummage about you here, and in a good light. If you find the right approach to the issue, then the navigator will immediately raise its fighters.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="skyff_final_dialog_8">
		<text>Thank you, Scythian, I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_0">
		<text>Greetings, there is a serious thing.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_1">
		<text>Hello, Stalker. And what kind of serious business is it, but I know nothing about it?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_2">
		<text>They say that you are going to storm hires?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_3">
		<text>Oh, you are nimble, we are not going to storm anyone. Who told you such stupidity?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_4">
		<text>Scythian, the leader of stalkers in the camp, he advised you to turn to you.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_5">
		<text>Ah, okay. Scythian is a good man, repeatedly helped us with provisions. He can be trusted. And then I already thought that you were some kind of provocateur, Cossacks sent. Now the environment is becoming stressful, so vigilance is above all. What did you want, specifically?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_6">
		<text>I need help with the assault on the hiring base. “There is a matter,” let's say, to the leader of the local.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_7">
		<text>Starrels in the ranks, to conduct such an operation, seems to be enough.
 But why did you get the idea that we will agree to storm the mercenaries base, and even under the guidance of a person unknown to us? The fighters will not go into battle under a strange banner ...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_8">
		<text>I do not mind going under the leadership of your fighter and under your banner. But with you. You yourself understand that I can't cope there alone.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_9">
		<text>Send you to hell, but you have a spark of a brave person. Not every fighter of our group can boast of this. An extra trunk in such a responsible business will not hurt. But look, so that later there were no complaints, as if I would not warn you if you are folded with a haru or you can break a couple of bullets.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_10">
		<text>Haru is folded, this is the half of trouble. If only they did not go into the soul.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_11">
		<text>Yes, I see you are still that joker.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_12">
		<text>So we are together?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_13">
		<text>Together. Listen here. You meet with the commander of the group of our intelligence and sabotage detachment. I will inform him now in the radio so that you are not shot when you come. In the beginning, try to eliminate as many opponents as possible without noise. As soon as the maximum possible amount of "remove" in a quiet way, you immediately begin an active assault. Well, there only luck will choose the winner. Is everything clear?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_leader_final_dialog_14">
		<text>Everything is extremely clear.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="shturm_grach_dialog_0">
		<text>Stand! Who is coming, the devil would have blessed you!</text>
	</string>
    <string id="shturm_grach_dialog_1">
		<text>Klim. The navigator was supposed to report my parish.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="shturm_grach_dialog_2">
		<text>Yes, he spoke. Invidence approaches.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="shturm_grach_dialog_3">
		<text>Well, what is your plan?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="shturm_grach_dialog_4">
		<text>Plan? Such a plan - I will only coordinate all the actions. You only listen to me in everything. I will not suffer amateur performances! All actions are only on command. Are there any questions?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="shturm_grach_dialog_5">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="shturm_grach_dialog_6">
		<text>Then we are advanced.</text>
	</string>
	
    <string id="after_shturm_grach_dialog_0">
		<text>Well done guys, perfectly coped! What are our further plans?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="after_shturm_grach_dialog_1">
		<text>Yes, but this is only half the age. Now we are moving to the "shelter".</text>
	</string>
    <string id="after_shturm_grach_dialog_2">
		<text>Went.</text>
	</string>	

    <string id="skyff_last_out_dialog_0">
		<text>Scythian, this story is becoming more and more clear, but its mystery does not become less from this. I'm going to Pripyat. We must act in hot pursuit. The fact is that when we stormed the northern camp, in the PDA commander of the northern supply base I found a message in which the opponent indicates some information that fell into the hands, and therefore he urgently goes to Pripyat. And with the assault on the "shelter", I did not see the hook, the head of the "shelter" base, which was there when I installed wiretap.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_last_out_dialog_1">
		<text>Klim, listen, maybe you should not do this? At least alone?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_last_out_dialog_2">
		<text>And what, someone expresses a desire to participate in this? So I'm only "for"! It's a pity Gevara disappeared ... now I would have compiled me a company.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_last_out_dialog_3">
		<text>Klim, you are a good man, it will be a pity if you disappear.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_last_out_dialog_4">
		<text>Do not bury me ahead of time.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_last_out_dialog_5">
		<text>Be careful - in Pripyat the monolith is a sprinkle. These fanatics do not spare anyone. Yes, now also hired there rushed there. So there is now more dangerous there, although there was not a resort before there.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_last_out_dialog_6">
		<text>Okay, Scythian, don't dissuade it. I'll go anyway. Thank you for everything as I will return, so a box of vodka is from me.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_last_out_dialog_7">
		<text>Klim, I catch a word. But still, I have to disappoint you - during the last release, the transition that everyone used was overwhelmed, so there is no road there yet.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_last_out_dialog_8">
		<text>How not? Scythian, you want to say that I have to sit here now and wait until that mercenary is hidden, and then we will not know anything! Never! I do not believe that this is the only way - I have heard many times about the fact that stalkers do not go the same road. Is there really an exception? Surely there is another way to Pripyat, but not one ..., especially since the mercenary from the "shelter" directly said that he was leaving for Pripyat. So there are paths ...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_last_out_dialog_9">
		<text>Yes, Klim, there are a lot of paths to Pripyat, but units know about them. Everyone else is used by the safest beaten paths, and such a well -known path has now become inaccessible. We have one very serious person who probably knows not only a general path. However, you will not approach him from the bay of the barack. If he does not like you the first time, then you can not even show in your eyes anymore.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_last_out_dialog_10">
		<text>And who is he and where now?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_last_out_dialog_11">
		<text>Yes, he just returned from the raid, resting in the bar. His name is a screwess.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_last_out_dialog_12">
		<text>Okay, I'll go talk to him, the attempt is not torture. I still have no choice.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_last_out_dialog_13">
		<text>I wish you good luck. Little advice: if he asks to help in anything, then do not refuse - this may be your way to success.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_0">
		<text>Greetings, you are stalker. My name is Klim.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_1">
		<text>And, well, since I decided to say hello, then something is needed from me. I give my hand to the cut off, if not?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_2">
		<text>Um ..., well, since you immediately went to business, I won't get out. Yes, I'm on business!</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_3">
		<text>Well then, what is needed?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_4">
		<text>They say that you know the bypass to Pripyat.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_5">
		<text>AND? What, should you just take and tell you about him like that ???</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_6">
		<text>Well, do not get excited, I have not finished yet. I offer an exchange: you, I am to you. Everything will be honest, all the more I can also help in some business.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_7">
		<text>Where are you all so smart on my head? This path was given to you. Wait until the main one is clear. Stalkers are nimble people, they will manage in a couple of months ... Ha ha ha !!!!</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_8">
		<text>A couple of months ??? Your mother ... Yes, today or tomorrow I already need to be in Pripyat. EEH ... I thought you were a business man, and you are just empty -bearing.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_9">
		<text>Get out of here, and no longer come to me with questions. Guten slip, bitch.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_10">
		<text>Sadly ... Scythian told me something else. He said that such a trace in the afternoon with fire in the zone will not be seen.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_11">
		<text>Wait a minute, what, right said so? What else did you say? I respect the Scythian, more than once I helped me out with provisions and the necessary information. Don't think bad. It's just that I cut off unnecessary people, so that my neck is not turned off somewhere, you can say I protect them from a rash step. Well, since you are "working" with the Scythian, then I will help you. I don't need much. I will give you information about this transition for only 60 thousand. I can tell right now, only ... I live according to the formula: in the morning money, in the evening chairs. So the grandmothers are forward.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_12">
		<text>60000 ??? Are you crazy or something? Do you think that I have a financial collapsed here? The money is enough only to bite the supplies a little, but the barrel is to be repaired ... Yes, and the Scythian did not mention anything about the money, and even in such quantities ...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_13">
		<text>There are no problems, there is another option ...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_14">
		<text>Which? Probably go there, I don't know where, bring it, I don't know what?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_15">
		<text>Yes, I would not say that, everything is much easier. I do not offer cooperation to every stalker, so consider that the stars are smiling today.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_16">
		<text>Okay ... let's say in business.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_17">
		<text>Well then let's get down. A very dangerous mutant - chimera lives in the vicinity of the camp. Have you heard at least about this?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_18">
		<text>Heard. And I saw. While I got here, I had a chance to help Gont to kill the chimera. Have you heard of such a hunter for mutants?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_19">
		<text>You offend ... It was I who taught the hin to hunt them correctly. So my school. Yes, it is not so difficult to hunt them. The main thing is to do this together. One stalker distracts the attention of the beast, and the second, at this time, should be on the side. The one that distracts her must shoot her between her eyes, and the second finishes the shot from the side. Everything is simple. But one to go to the chimera is just suicide. Well, another moment, hunting for them only at night.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_20">
		<text>Everything is clear, but what is the need to kill her right now?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_21">
		<text>Well, firstly, she had already become close enough to the camp, and secondly, I promised Stepanych her claw. The deadlines are settled, so this must be done now. So we wait for the night and in battle!</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="first_vintorez_dialog_22">
		<text>Agreed. Then until the evening.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="after_himera_vintorez_dialog_0">
		<text>So -so hunting. I have seen better.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="after_himera_vintorez_dialog_1">
		<text>Well, you see, nothing complicated. According to my "technology" the destruction of mutants, everything at the "hurray" turned out. Thank you for your help.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="after_himera_vintorez_dialog_2">
		<text>That's wonderful. Talk about the bypass.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="after_himera_vintorez_dialog_3">
		<text>What is the way?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="after_himera_vintorez_dialog_4">
		<text>So, a screw cutter, do not strangle. He said that I help you, and you give me this information.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="after_himera_vintorez_dialog_5">
		<text>Did I say that I need help only in one business? No, I didn't say it. So do not blame. When I appreciate your merits, then you will receive the right one. Do not lose heart, everything will be fine, and you'll get into your primeting even before the stalkers are cleared the main path ...</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="after_himera_vintorez_dialog_6">
		<text>Mmmm ... khe-khe ...</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="after_himera_vintorez_dialog_7">
		<text>In the meantime, listen further: one stalker annoy me very much. He intercepts my work, and says all sorts of nasty things about me. In general, he must "disappear." Forever. But there is one small “but” - he is not a green beginner, so it will not be easy to track down and cope with him.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="after_himera_vintorez_dialog_8">
		<text>And then I go out onto the stage ...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="after_himera_vintorez_dialog_9">
		<text>Oddly enough, but you guessed. I already worked on this issue and came up with something. Guevara threw me a couple of mini-scanners, with which you can sang the PDA of any stalker. If you install a similar mini-scanner at a high point, for example, on the roof of a building, a high tower, a pillar, a tree, and so on, then you can track the victim. So you have already heard the task. Forward! I set up a mini-scanner in a certain way, and he will react only to the right person, so you can not worry about this about this</text>
	</string>
    <string id="after_himera_vintorez_dialog_10">
		<text>The only thing I am experiencing now is for a fucking path to Pripyat.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_0">
		<text>That's it, your stalker-competing and Klyatznik sprinkled. Rather, when I found him, he was already a "dead" ... on his feet, but with scorched brains.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_1">
		<text>I am glad that everything worked out that way, to be honest, I thought he would fill you up. Um ... well, since everything worked out, then listen further ...</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_2">
		<text>Pintorez, your mother, did you send me to the faithful death? And I survived. So you are not satisfied yet ???</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_3">
		<text>Do not boil. I told you that he is far from a beginner. I thought that this would be enough. He seemed more agile to me, but since it happened, then my thought flickered ...</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_4">
		<text>You would also organize a totalizer from Stepanych.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_5">
		<text>Okay, it was a joke ... I see a stalker not bad. Hehe. No wonder the Scythian has common things with you. He's with anyone and you will not live for a great job. Yes ... we continue the conversation. This task will be more important and more difficult than the previous ones. I know that there is a detailed map of the zone with marks of important zones, including the transition you need.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_6">
		<text>So you don't even know where he is? What a garbage?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_7">
		<text>Listen further and do not mandrail. Of course, I know where he is, but I am not a cartographer. And this is a ready -made card with all the notes. So she will come in handy, and I can not fuck from this bad. Look, if you don't like something, then I can now dump 60,000, and find out the coordinates of this transition.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_8">
		<text>Everything is clear. Let's do business, not play offended.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_9">
		<text>So not offended here. There are very stubborn and impatient personalities here, but this is not on the inside.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_10">
		<text>Sporal, let's get closer to business. Yes, and why this task, as you say, will be more important and more difficult? In my opinion, the task is as a task, nothing outstanding.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_11">
		<text>Where are you all in a hurry? Can you listen to the end? So, what we have on this problem - a month ago one "sinner" wandered into the vicinity of the camp.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_12">
		<text>Wait, so this group has gone for a long time.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_13">
		<text>Do not interrupt. This is the same as saying that there is no duty or freedom. Sin still exists, they just now lay down on the bottom. They strongly "owed" the mercenaries, and the debt for them announced the hunt. It's just that there are few of them now, so rarely someone about them in the know. At least in the near future we will definitely not see them. Well, and figs with them, the essence is different. This "sinner" claimed that he broke with his past and took the path of correction. But, nevertheless, ordinary stalkers shunned him, although he tried his best to help them. In general, stalkers did not accept him in their circle.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_14">
		<text>Well, this story is familiar to me: at one time I knew the former monolith, his name was the tramp. So he tried to gain confidence from debt and freedom, but never received. He went to Pripyat. Maybe again in a monolith, or maybe not. But the man was good.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_15">
		<text>Or maybe I put a gag to you so that you are not distracted? Maybe then you will let me agree, otherwise we will now share memories, and then no one will ever go anywhere! I heard that story about the "lost" group of the monolith that came to Jupiter and did not remember anything ...
 So, one day this sin -breeder was found dead. Who and for what is so with him is incomprehensible. Of course, no one began to dig to the truth. But we found a note with him with information about the cache. The note spoke about a certain cache: "He left a detailed map of the zone and Khabar where he was forgiven for all his sins." Are there any considerations, where is this cache?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_16">
		<text>Rebus again. How I do not like these riddles.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_task_vintorez_dialog_17">
		<text>That is why this task will be more difficult, and I have already said about its importance. This is the last thing I ask you about. Then you can calmly go to Pripyat. So try.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="provodnik_vintorez_dialog_0">
		<text>All, hold your card. There, in the cache, the brand new span cutter was found, but I will leave it to myself.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="provodnik_vintorez_dialog_1">
		<text>Well, that's glorious, we found her, his homeland. Well, you proved that worthy of knowing the bypass. You fulfilled your part of the contract of our "cooperation". And so let's go, I will show you where the transition to Pripyat is. As you suggested: you, I am to you!</text>
	</string>
    <string id="provodnik_vintorez_dialog_2">
		<text>Excellent when we leave?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="provodnik_vintorez_dialog_3">
		<text>The best time is early in the morning, about five hours. And in Pripyat is more or less calm and there are fewer extra eyes.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="provodnik_vintorez_dialog_4">
		<text>In this case, I'm waiting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_sokol_dialog_0">
		<text>Klim, a small request for you. Are you going towards the bar now?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="actor_sokol_dialog_1">
		<text>Hmm, are we familiar? What is the matter?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="actor_sokol_dialog_2">
		<text>Yes, there is only one in the bar, he needs to pass the barrel.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sokol_dialog_3">
		<text>Why you don't give it yourself, there's fifty meters here. And besides, where do you get such confidence in a stranger?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sokol_dialog_4">
		<text>Here is such a thing, Stepanych does not like me. And once again, you should not catch your eye.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sokol_dialog_41">
		<text>These are your problems. Understand yourself.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sokol_dialog_5">
		<text>Well, I'll tell you, all the same along the way. Who needs to give?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_sokol_dialog_6">
		<text>Stalker alone, responds to the name of the gloomy. Eternally dissatisfied with something, a severe face, a serious look. Finding it will not be difficult.</text>
	</string>
	 <string id="actor_hmur_dialog_0">
		<text>Are you calling this gloomy?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_dialog_1">
		<text>Yes. What did you want?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_dialog_2">
		<text>There is one stalker, probably your friend, asked to convey the parcel. Hold it.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_dialog_3">
		<text>What? Where ... kh ... where did you get it? Answer vividly! Who are you at all? Where did you get this trunk from?</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="actor_hmur_dialog_4">
		<text>Calm, for this, because in the face you can grab it. One man asked you to convey, they are crying with a falcon.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_dialog_5">
		<text>No, this cannot be, this is some kind of setup! Someone wants to play, trap in a trap!</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_dialog_6">
		<text>What is the matter? Can you explain normally?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_dialog_7">
		<text>Sorry to run around like that. Just nerves are already at the limit. Here is such a thing - I understand the falcon a year ago from this very pistol and he was overwhelmed. We went to the huckk then, there were five of us, but only Sokol and I got alive. The artifact was very valuable. And then something like that found me - I took out this personalized barrel and shot right in my head. I had debts, I somehow need to pay, and half the cost of the artifact is clearly not enough. Well, ... I did not do not go, not humanly.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_dialog_8">
		<text>I will not poison my soul, I see and so shit. But you understand that after what you did, no one will trust you. You would leave the zone, according to someone you did not tear your head for this.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_dialog_9">
		<text>I have the last request for you. Although ... horseradish with her. Goodbye, stalker.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="last_sokol_dialog_0">
		<text>What was it? After I gave the gun, I had the feeling that I should kill this gloomy. With every minute, it became stronger and stronger ... I was ready to kill him right in the bar ... I wanted to be distracted, but it did not pass ... And when he left the bar and went to church, I no longer controlled himself ... I killed him ... Explain! Why did you do this, why did you choose me?!</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_sokol_dialog_1">
		<text>Sorry, Klim, that it turned out so bad. Probably I had to tell and tell the truth ... But now it is no longer important. And myself, as you know, I could not do this.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_sokol_dialog_2">
		<text>Falcon, you are so called, I did not subscribe to this. Why did you get me into this story?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_sokol_dialog_3">
		<text>Know that there is no sin in your actions, not of your own free will you have done it. And remember again - if you hear a phone call that cannot be, then raise the phone, answer ...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="last_sokol_dialog_4">
		<text>Wait! What...</text>
	</string>	
	
    <string id="actor_faradey_dialog_0">
		<text>Eh, that's how it happens in the zone. Do you want to roll two hundred grams?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_faradey_dialog_1">
		<text>Sorry, Stalker, I don't drink, and I don't advise you, especially for this reason. It can tighten it and tighten that you won't get out at all. Anomalies will be smoked nervously on the sidelines ... I need to bring some of their affairs to the end. But then you can relax and drink a seagull.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_faradey_dialog_2">
		<text>A friend would remember. Not humanly, everything somehow happened. If I knew that this would happen, then I would generally refuse this contract.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_faradey_dialog_3">
		<text>Sorry. Can what help is needed?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_faradey_dialog_4">
		<text>Yes, yes! If you can help, I will not stay in debt. I will give you one very rare artifact, which my friend and I somehow found.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_faradey_dialog_5">
		<text>Thank you, but can you still explain what's what?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_faradey_dialog_6">
		<text>You see, we took the contract from the scientists from the Polesie. Recently, you will practically not get rich on simple artifacts, but here is such a chance. It was necessary to come on the given coordinates, and pick up a device. Payment was promised a huge one. We were delighted like children: business, come and take it! And for this they promised a bunch of grandmas! We were not unacceptable ... Scientists - they are strange, well, nothing alerted us. On the way, we agreed that the partner would climb into the subway behind the device, and I would cover on the outside. Yes, it is only unknown from where the controller came from, and prevented him from bringing the matter to the end. I barely got old, and as I got to the camp and I don't remember at all ... But the friendly was stuck ..., I didn't have time to get out, well, I fell under the controller in full. M-daa, we never fulfilled the contract ... I beg you very much, find my friend and shot him. This is not the old friend whom I knew, this is not even a person. And I myself can't do it myself, my hand does not rise.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_faradey_dialog_7">
		<text>Fine. Do you drop the approximate place where you had to pick up this device?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_faradey_dialog_8">
		<text>Certainly. Now, already ready.</text>
	</string>	

    <string id="actor_faradey_final_dialog_0">
		<text>The issue is resolved. Now it needs to be buried humanly. But this is already without me.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_faradey_final_dialog_1">
		<text>Thank you, take it ..., from a pure heart, as promised.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_faradey_final_dialog_2">
		<text>Thank you. And remember for the future: only a fool will agree to big money for an insignificant and not difficult contract. And in the zone, as you know, fools do not live long.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="follow_from_skyff_to_base">
		<text>New life: Follow the Scythian to the base</text>
	</string>
    <string id="start_talk_with_skyff">
		<text>New Life: Talk to Scythian</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_start_skyff_follow">
		<text>"Finally, I return to Chernobyl-1. I think this stalker, nicknamed Skif, can be trusted."</text>
	</string>
	
    <string id="actor_hmur_in_church_dialog_0">
		<text>Who is here?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_in_church_dialog_1">
		<text>This is me, Klim.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="actor_hmur_in_church_dialog_2">
		<text>Ah, again you. So, you are not only a messenger, but also the executioner ... well, so, so be it - do what you should.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_in_church_dialog_3">
		<text>What are you talking about, Stalker? What are you carrying, what executioner?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_in_church_dialog_4">
		<text>Yes, stop, Klim. You know very well what I mean, otherwise why would you follow me? Kill me, Klim. Free me from these worms that bite my soul. Maybe I will redeem my sin. I myself cannot put my hands on myself in these walls, you should help me. And remember, you are not a killer, you are a deliverer! Just please, don't pull.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_in_church_dialog_5">
		<text>Is this the only way out?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_in_church_dialog_6">
		<text>Now yes. You talked with the falcon ...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_in_church_dialog_61">
		<text>Well, if so ... goodbye, stalker ...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_in_church_dialog_62">
		<text>No. I will not do it.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_in_church_dialog_7">
		<text>Then I will make you!</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_hmur_in_church_dialog_8">
		<text>Uh, what have you thought up there?</text>
	</string>

    <string id="skyff_after_sokol_information_dialog_0">
		<text>Scythian, do not think that I went with a head or smoked, but I talked with a dead stalker, and even fulfilled his assignment. Everything was very financially, terribly financially, but then he disappeared, having finally given a strange advice. How to explain all this?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="skyff_after_sokol_information_dialog_1">
		<text>Do not beat your head with attempts to understand and explain ... In this irritated information field of the zone, where everything is like a nervous nerve, such things have a very right to happen. I will not ask you about the assignment, I feel it was quite delicate ... Consider what I spoke with the spirit. You say, the advice gave in the last? Then here is another one - do not pretend with this advice on occasion, I think this is not without reason.</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="skyff_after_sokol_information_dialog_2">
		<text>Yeah. Such advice is unlikely to forget ...</text>
	</string>

    <string id="actor_first_step_dialog_0">
		<text>Well, great! So I decided to look, relax, so to speak.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_first_step_dialog_1">
		<text>For the first time I see you here. Well, and so always glad to new faces.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_first_step_dialog_2">
		<text>I would have a drink and eat.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="actor_first_step_dialog_3">
		<text>The first time - at the expense of the establishment.</text>
	</string>	
</string_table>	
