<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	
<string id="city_npc_army_kep_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Stop! Drop your weapon. You are under arrest. You will come with me for questioning. They will sort it out there.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_army_kep_start_dialog_1">
    <text>I'm coming, soldier. Don't worry, I won't run.</text>
</string>

<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, well! Look who's here! Long time no see, my friend Savan. A lot of water has passed since then! So, tell me, how did you end up here? And where's your buddy? Borland, if I remember correctly?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_1">
    <text>It started out so well... Just me, a citizen chief. I was just passing by, not bothering anyone. I don't know anything.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_2">
    <text>Ah, you'll tell that to the prosecutor. This is serious, brother: you're a criminal. And you're here illegally, on a restricted military facility. Do you know how many years you'll get? Fifteen. Or I could shoot you right now if you try to escape. That's another option.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_3">
    <text>Hey, hey, don't get hot-headed, chief! Maybe we can come to an agreement?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_4">
    <text>Bribing me? You've lost it! I'm on duty. Don't worry, you'll live. Though not for long. Just kidding. I know why you're here. While you were running around the Cordon collecting the ransom, your buddy Borland told me a lot of interesting things. Specifically about some unusual artifact and the reward for it. And where to find it. He thought I wouldn't believe him, that I had drunk away my brain. Fool. It's a shame he's not with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_5">
    <text>Oh wow! He didn't tell me about that.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_6">
    <text>Of course not! I think he was trying to use you in the dark. He gave me false leads, and several of my guys got killed. And you think I care about rotting on the Cordon for 10 years until demobilization? And then? A miserable Ukrainian pension for the rest of my life? Why would I want that? Here’s an opportunity that’s falling right into my hands. I’ve checked through my channels where they're hiding that artifact. And my guys and I decided to take the risk. You only live once! If you're here, then my sources aren't lying.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_7">
    <text>I was expecting to find the artifact in the dungeon, at the exit of which I was caught by your soldiers.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_8">
    <text>That’s a false lead. We checked, there’s nothing there. Just monsters. And soldiers from SPECTRUM who catch stalkers who make it there and kill them outright. They constantly patrol that laboratory. My guys were waiting for them to head back up. And then you showed up. An unexpected surprise. You should be thankful that they didn't shoot you right away. They could have. Anyway, let's get to the point: according to my sources, the artifact is at the Spectrums' base in the House of Culture building. That’s on the other side of this district. We're preparing for an assault. And an extra gun wouldn't hurt. If you help me, I’ll let you go when it's all over. You’ll be free and alive. I give you my officer's word.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_9">
    <text>So, I have no choice, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_10">
    <text>There’s always a choice. Either join me for the assault, or I’ll line you up against the wall right now. What, you’re pale? Just kidding. Listen to your first combat task: we know the frequency on which SPECTRUM is communicating, but our radio station is ancient Soviet junk. We quickly arranged for the necessary radio parts to be delivered from the mainland to the Cordon. This kit will allow us to modify our radio station. A few hours ago, there was an attempt to deliver the parts here by helicopter. It came under fire. Thankfully, everyone is alive, and the helicopter is back at base. The pilots reported that they dropped the cargo, so now we need to get it. I don't want to send my guys; there are no extras. You showed up just in time. Go scout the area, search the district, and try to find the crate with the parts. I'll send the approximate drop zone to your PDA. You have one hour. Don't even think of making a joke with me—you won’t even have time to be surprised. My snipers are watching you.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_meeting_dialog_11">
    <text>May I run, citizen chief?</text>
</string>

<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_0">
    <text>They nearly killed me there! It was an ambush—right after I grabbed the crate, they immediately opened fire on me.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_1">
    <text>Did you think you were in a fairy tale? This isn’t the Cordon, where you shoot boars! You’re lucky to be alive. I see you weren’t even hurt. So, we’ve got the parts. Let’s start listening to their channel.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_2">
    <text>What are the next orders?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_3">
    <text>Our scout, Sidorenko, crawled back from his mission barely alive. I thought he was done for. But he’s still moving, so he’s tough. He’ll survive—at least until the next wedding. Or the next funeral. Just kidding, he’ll make it. Probably.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_4">
    <text>What was his mission, if it’s not a military secret?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_5">
    <text>Don’t rush, you’ll find out everything. Here’s the deal: somehow, the SPECTRUMs got a BTR. How? No idea. Actually, I know. The soldiers from Zapolye sold it to them, for a crate of vodka! So, this BTR is a serious threat to us.\nThe scout's task was to plant explosives on the BTR. We planned to blow it up remotely at the start of the assault to throw off the enemy's plans.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_6">
    <text>I guess he didn’t plant the explosives, did he?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_7">
    <text>Exactly. He ran into an ambush and had to escape through the back alleys. He didn’t manage to plant the explosives, so he dumped them somewhere near a playground. He said under some giraffe. There are plenty of those playgrounds around here. You need to find the charge and install it on the rear of the BTR. You’re an experienced fighter, you can do it. Get to work.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_mportant_cargo_dialog_8">
    <text>Got it!</text>
</string>

<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_0">
    <text>Mission complete.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_1">
    <text>I knew you could do it. While you were gone, we intercepted an important conversation. Tomorrow morning, SPECTRUM is going to transport its high command out of the Zone. And, as it turns out, they’re currently here, in the city. You get it? I think this is for transporting the artifact by air. They’ve ordered two helicopters, which indirectly supports my theory. We need to intercept the artifact. According to our info, the helicopters' withdrawal will be covered by sniper fire and the BTR we’ve already taken care of. Your task: provide cover for my assault team.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_2">
    <text>You’re planning to capture the artifact and then sell it?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_3">
    <text>You’re understanding it correctly. If everything goes as planned, once the operation is complete, you’ll have full freedom. And we’ll never see each other again.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_kolyazin_sabotage_end_dialog_4">
    <text>I really hope so.</text>
</string>

<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_0">
    <text>Savan, Savan, stop!!! .... Don’t kill me. I know what you need!</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_1">
    <text>Speaking Russian now?! How do you know my name?!</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm a Russian German. I speak five languages. If that’s important. I know your name because we know all the experienced stalkers in the Zone. We’re a private military company, SPECTRUM. We were planning to establish control over the Exclusion Zone and continue the experiments that the OSOZNANIE scientists couldn’t finish.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_3">
    <text>What kind of nonsense is this? Don’t try to talk me into it. Where’s the artifact, bastard?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_4">
    <text>No artifact exists! We spread the rumor about this artifact. We announced a huge reward for something that doesn’t exist. All to get all the experienced stalkers to rush to find it. And we would capture them here and recruit them to guard our labs.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_5">
    <text>I’ve seen how you recruit. With bullets to the head. I saw them. Dead. You just killed anyone who posed a threat to you. Last time I’m asking: where’s the artifact, you bastard?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_6">
    <text>It doesn’t exist! Take... Take this case, there’s a lot, a lot of money in it. It’s much more than the reward we announced for the non-existent artifact. Just let me go alive. Tell them you didn’t find anyone here... please! I’ll disappear from the Zone forever, just let me go.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_sp_leader_dialog_7">
    <text>You’ve convinced me! Give me the case.</text>
</string>

<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Show me what you’ve got.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_final_dialog_1">
    <text>Here, the case with the money. I estimate there’s about 3 million euros there. Or something like that. Here you go. There’s no artifact here. So, what now? How do we get out of here?</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_final_dialog_2">
    <text>You’re dumber than I thought.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_npc_kolyazin_final_dialog_3">
    <text>What?!</text>
</string>

    
</string_table>
