<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="yan_scientist_hello_dialog_11">
    <text>Yes, I don’t often see new faces here! So, what would you like to know? Ask away, I’m listening!</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_hello_dialog_12">
    <text>How are things going?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_hello_dialog_13">
    <text>I’m glad we could help each other. Is there anything you’re interested in?..</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_hello_dialog_14">
    <text>Head over to Levsha. He’s waiting.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_go_diggers_1">
    <text>The group went missing in the northwest part of the complex. It’s full of zombies there. I can’t send perimeter guards, we’re barely holding off the attacks as it is. The SOS signal is still coming from there. Try to rescue the stalkers if they’re still alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_bring_documents_1">
    <text>It’s a shame about the guys. I’d like to believe they didn’t die in vain. Alright, let’s take a look at these documents... Very interesting! Some of my theories are confirmed... No, this is just incredibly interesting!.. This is great. Great!... This gives us answers to many questions, though it will take time to fully understand what’s going on...</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_bring_documents_111">
    <text>In this case, we’re dealing with a man-made installation! These documents are instructions for controlling the cooling system of some device located in the underground part of the complex. Wow... the power it consumes!.. So, it seems like everything is becoming clear... Apparently, the bursts of psi-activity are caused by malfunctions in the cooling system... If we can fix it, the psi-radiation levels will drop significantly. Alright... I need some time to think about a few details. Head toward the complex: that’s where Levsha’s group is. I’ll give you more information once you're on the road.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_about_zombie_1">
    <text>They’ve been troubling us since the lab was established. The walls are strong, of course, but those howls and screeches outside are incredibly distracting: they pull us away from our research and prevent us from sleeping. Plus, we occasionally need to leave the bunker to collect samples.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_about_zombie_111">
    <text>We spent a long time trying to figure this out. No matter how much the military worked on the area, zombies kept appearing again and again. Everything became clear when one of the zombies turned out to be my former lab assistant, who went missing during measurements near the factory... It’s the psi-field. Anyone who gets within its range loses their mind and turns into a zombie. Their higher brain functions are irreversibly damaged. They’re no longer humans: these creatures are incapable of thinking, only primitive animal instincts remain...</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_about_strelok_1">
    <text>Yes, a stalker like that has been here. He knew surprisingly much, more than the others. He even claimed to have been at the center of the Zone! I don’t really believe him, although he showed me some photos...</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_about_strelok_111">
    <text>We made a deal with him. He volunteered to conduct field tests of one of our promising developments – a psi-radiation blocker. In exchange, we promised to give him a fully adjusted model. Strelok believed that this device would allow him to pass through the so-called Brain Burner. We gave him an unadjusted prototype, and he went to the complex area. But since then, neither Strelok nor the prototype have been seen. For a while, we received psi-radiation intensity measurements, but now the signal from the prototype is lost. Apparently, Strelok was caught in a powerful burst of radiation.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_about_strelok_11111">
    <text>It’s possible that Strelok is still alive and somewhere within the factory area, but it’s nearly impossible to enter there without a psi-protection device. We’ve been studying the psi-radiation phenomenon here for a long time. It has a distinct pulsating nature, and during low-intensity periods, a person can be on the factory premises relatively safely. However, we can’t predict when the next burst will occur. Trying to infiltrate the factory is like playing Russian roulette. If you decide to go after Strelok, you’ll probably just add yourself to the ranks of the local zombies. But maybe I can help you. Recently, a group of stalkers infiltrated the complex and found some technical documents there. Just as they were about to leave, they contacted me and managed to tell me about their find, but then they were hit by a psi-radiation burst. It’s possible that these documents will shed light on the cause of such strong psi-radiation. Find them, and I may be able to help you get into the factory area.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_about_stalkers_1">
    <text>It’s all about the factory complex... It attracts stalkers like a magnet. The thing is, it’s one of the last untouched buildings. There are rumors about rare artifacts and unique equipment, so naturally, stalkers are always trying to get in, hoping to find something valuable. But it’s practically a suicide mission. Psi-radiation is very unstable, its intensity bursts are unpredictable. At maximum radiation levels, brain cells simply break down.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_levsha_hello_dialog_11">
    <text>Mercenary, I’ve received information from Sakharov. What a mess we’ve got here! See that crack in the wall? That’s where we’re going: the shortest path to the installation. Follow me and don’t rush ahead, understood? We’ve already got a team that knows what they’re doing, and you’ll just get in the way.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_levsha_hello_dialog_111">
    <text>Got it.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_about_stalkers_0">
    <text>What are the stalkers doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_about_stalkers_11">
    <text>And Levsha?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_about_stalkers_111">
    <text>Levsha is more capable than many other stalkers. He and his team work for us, helping with measurements and collecting samples. In exchange, we provide them with quality medical care. I think if it weren’t for this mutually beneficial cooperation, both we and they would have been dead long ago.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_about_strelok_0">
    <text>I know Strelok was here. What do you know about him?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_about_strelok_11">
    <text>Where is Strelok now?</text>
</string>

	<string id="yan_scientist_about_strelok_1111">
    <text>How do I find Strelok?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_about_zombie_0">
    <text>Do zombies often attack you?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_about_zombie_11">
    <text>Interesting, where do the zombies come from then?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_bring_documents_0">
    <text>The stalkers were dead. But I brought the documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_bring_documents_11">
    <text>Professor, can you be more specific?</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_go_diggers_0">
    <text>I agree to get the documents. Tell me everything you know.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_start_frase_1">
    <text>I'll be right there!</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_scientist_start_frase_2">
    <text>One moment!</text>
</string>

<string id="saharok_ystanovka_reward_0">
    <text>We did it. The psi-radiation source is shut down!</text>
</string>
<string id="saharok_ystanovka_reward_1">
    <text>Great job! We thank you on behalf of our entire expedition and proudly present you with this reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="saharok_digger_start_0">
    <text>Wait, my friend... Could you spare me another minute of your attention?</text>
</string>
<string id="saharok_digger_start_1">
    <text>Yes? What interests you?</text>
</string>
<string id="saharok_digger_start_2">
    <text>Recently, a group of stalkers infiltrated the complex and found some technical documentation. On their way out, they contacted me and managed to tell me about their discovery, but then they were hit by a psi-radiation burst. It's possible these documents will shed light on the cause of such intense psi-radiation. Find them.</text>
</string>
<string id="saharok_digger_start_3">
    <text>Alright, I’ll think about it.</text>
</string>


</string_table>
