<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_name">
		<text>Investigate the complex</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_name_1">
		<text>Return back</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_name_2">
		<text>Kill the Controller</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_name_3">
		<text>Talk to Fatty</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_name_3_0">
		<text>Return to the village</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_2_text">
		<text>Today we're going with Fatty to investigate the mysteries of the factory complex. Who knows what awaits us there? Important: we should hurry before morning.</text>
	</string>			

	<string id="pole_factory_doc_1">
		<text>Security Chief's Records</text>
	</string>			
	<string id="pole_factory_doc_1_desc">
		<text>Completely useless records containing the names and signatures of all employees, who were repeatedly marked at the start and end of the workday. However, the dates suggest that this complex was used after the first explosion.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="pole_factory_doc_2">
		<text>Production Information</text>
	</string>			
	<string id="pole_factory_doc_2_desc">
		<text>Also of no particular value, nothing supernatural occurred here, apparently the employees of this plant were mainly engaged in energy issues.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="pole_factory_doc_3">
		<text>Accounting Book</text>
	</string>			
	<string id="pole_factory_doc_3_desc">
		<text>This contains the main information about accountable persons and the material structure of the new enterprise. The lion's share of the funds is allocated by the government. Unfortunately, no strange materials were found under management, weapons were definitely not a concern here.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="pole_factory_doc_4">
		<text>PDA of a dead stalker</text>
	</string>			
	<string id="pole_factory_doc_4_desc">
		<text>The PDA is in a damaged state, but a note was attached under the cover, apparently duplicating the last message for just this occasion: "Stalker, if you’re reading this – better leave while you still can. If you came here hoping to loot, know that there’s nothing here, though by the time you find this PDA, I think you’ll have figured that out. Don’t know if we’ll survive this night, but I have a really bad feeling. It’s like something is reading my thoughts and mocking us. We can’t go on with the guys, we’re falling down from exhaustion, taking a short break here. I’ll hide the PDA just in case, so mutants don’t tear it apart."</text>
	</string>	

	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_name">
		<text>Find the rookie’s weapon</text>
	</string>			
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_1_text">
		<text>The stalker named Fatty asked me to find his weapon, which he dropped during a careless investigation of the anomalous substation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_name">
		<text>Find the nuisance</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_name_1">
		<text>Kill Alpha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rookie_pole_task_3_text">
		<text>Someone is annoying Fatty and he wants them gone. We need to help him with that.</text>
	</string>	

	<string id="st_plz_save_rookie">
		<text>Fatty: \nHey, stalker? Stalker! Help me please, there’s a bloodsucker trying to eat me from the neighboring house!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_plz_save_rookie_done">
		<text>Fatty: \nThanks, man, come over here, I’ll open the door!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_pole_main_build_factory">
		<text>Fatty: \nListen, I think there’s something in that workshop, and also in this building in the middle of the complex.</text>
	</string>	

	<string id="st_pole_meet_controller">
		<text>Fatty: \nI’ve got a bad feeling, like someone’s messing with my brain...</text>
	</string>	

	<string id="st_pole_entrance_factory">
		<text>Fatty: \nI’ve got chills from this place. Let’s check the checkpoint booth.</text>
	</string>	

	<string id="st_pole_out_here">
		<text>Fatty: \nLet’s get out of here as quickly as we can!</text>
	</string>	

	<string id="st_pole_here_zero_staff">
		<text>Fatty: \nListen, I don’t think there’s anything here, let’s leave before we end up like those poor guys.</text>
	</string>	

	<string id="st_pole_dead_stalkers_camp">
		<text>Fatty: \nHoly shit, what a nightmare… who did this to them? Let’s check if they left any traces.</text>
	</string>	


</string_table>
