<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<!-- Voland -->
	<string id="st_bomber_outfit_name">
		<text>Combine "Combat Outfit"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bomber_outfit_description">
		<text>A variety of combat costume made and collected personally to Woland to order. The suit includes a normal body armor with a light helmet. Alas, the material of the costume and helmet is not protected from electricity, besides, they do not help from psi-resistance. However, there is even a built -in container for artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	
    <!-- Light -->
    <string id="milstalk_outfit_name">
        <text>MilStalker Light Suit</text>
    </string>
    <string id="milstalk_outfit_description">
        <text>Light armour used by MilStalker units. Excellent mobility and low encumbrance, offering basic ballistic protection and minimal environmental sealing. Best suited for reconnaissance, quick assaults and urban operations.</text>
    </string>

    <!-- Medium (Spec Ops) -->
    <string id="milstalk_specops_outfit_name">
        <text>MilStalker Spec-Ops Suit</text>
    </string>
    <string id="milstalk_specops_outfit_description">
        <text>Special operations suit combining balanced protection with enhanced stealth features and integrated communications gear. Moderate weight with improved resistance against fragments and light anomalies. Favoured by squad-level specialists.</text>
    </string>

    <!-- Heavy (Military) -->
    <string id="milstalk_millitary_outfit_name">
        <text>MilStalker Military Heavy Suit</text>
    </string>
    <string id="milstalk_millitary_outfit_description">
        <text>Standard heavy combat suit for MilStalker frontline troops. Reinforced ballistic plates and layered padding provide high protection at the cost of mobility. Good for sustained engagements and hazardous zones.</text>
    </string>

    <!-- Nosorog (assault variant) -->
    <string id="milstalk_nosorog_outfit_name">
        <text>MilStalker Nosorog Assault Suit</text>
    </string>
    <string id="milstalk_nosorog_outfit_description">
        <text>Assault-grade heavy armour with additional frontal reinforcement and tactical load-bearing attachments. Designed for breaching and direct assaults; includes extra pouches and hardpoints for grenades and gear. Reduced stealth and agility.</text>
    </string>

    <!-- Prototype Exoskeleton -->
    <string id="milstalk_proto_exo_outfit_name">
        <text>MilStalker Prototype Exoskeleton</text>
    </string>
    <string id="milstalk_proto_exo_outfit_description">
        <text>Prototype powered exoskeleton developed for MilStalker heavy teams. Greatly enhances carrying capacity, strength and endurance while providing substantial protection. Fragile electronics and limited availability — expensive and rare.</text>
    </string>

</string_table>

