<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>

<string id="st_esc_sidor_talk_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Savan, swing by when you're nearby — I've got something for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_quest_fee_sms_1">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]How's it going, radioactive meat? You have one more day to get the money, or you know what happens.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_quest_fee_sms_2">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]Where’s the money you promised? Fine, I’ll give you 12 more hours — if you don’t make it, that’s on you!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_quest_fee_sms_3">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]Your time’s up. We fed your buddy to the dogs, and you won’t be running much longer either.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_sms_wolf_quest_trimming">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Hey Savan, still need some cash? I’ve got a job just for you — swing by and I’ll tell you what’s what.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_sms_wolf_quest_insurance">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]It’s me again. I need your help — you know where to find me.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_sms_wolf_quest_talk_wolf_work">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Drop by if you want — I’ll always have work for you…</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_sms_logoped_predlog">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]Well, well! Look who’s rolling into our turf! You’re on my crew’s territory, drifter. Come over and let’s talk. Might even have a job for you — for the good of the brotherhood.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_sidor_esc_quest_serious_business_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Savan, I’ve got serious work for you. Waiting.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_sidor_esc_quest_dangerous_business_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Ready or not? Get over here — time’s ticking.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_nps_wood_goblin_quest_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Savan, keep up!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_borland_quest_line_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Savan, when you’re free, find me — we need to talk.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_sms_borland_posle_napadenia">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Where the hell did you go?! Get over here, quick — I’m in the Rookie Village, waiting for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_sms_borland_assistance_conditional">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Don’t worry, Savan — we’re gonna get you out.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_sms_logoped_gopstop_fail">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]You moron, couldn’t even handle a simple job!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_borland_underground_1_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Keep up, Savan!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_borland_underground_2_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]We need to stick together!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_sidor_underground_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Savan, great news — through my contacts, I got the master access code to the lab. Here it is: 7200</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_shaman_group_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Hey Savan, I’m ready to welcome you into our ranks.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_nps_student_quest_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Where are you going? Wait up!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_nps_student_quest_sms_2">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Wow! Some guide you turned out to be.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_shaman_worke">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Hey Savan, I heard you’re looking to make some cash. Come over and we’ll talk — I might have just the right gig for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_sms_wolf_quest_conductor">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Need money? Come by — I’ve got the perfect job for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_risovalshik_open_zakaz_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Buying any weapons in any condition for parts. Good price guaranteed!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_borland_bar_surget_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Savan! We need to stick together!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_esc_borland_bar_surget_2_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Savan! Hurry up! Or we’re dead!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_bar_sidor_new_details_sms_1">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Savan, how are you? Still alive? Not a word from you — no news, no bones! I’ve been told you're already in the Bar. If you found anything interesting... like the X5 lab documents I asked for, bring them to the Barman. And ask him about that very artifact — he’s got useful info.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_bar_sidor_new_details_sms_2">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Savan, how are you? Still alive? Not a word from you — no news, no bones! I’ve already received word from the checkpoint at the Garbage...</text>
</string>

<string id="st_bar_barmen_new_details_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Savan, I’ve got a job for you — remember? Come over and we’ll talk.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_bar_send_5_time">
	<text>5h 12m have passed.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_bar_expectation_barmen_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Savan, time’s up. It’s time to make a decision. If you're ready, come talk.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_bar_dangerous_duty_voronin_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Savan, the time has come. Head to the checkpoint and speak to the guard commander — he’ll brief you on what’s next.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_bar_azot_work_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Hey stalker, want to earn some cash? Come see me. I’m at the Duty base.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_bar_barmen_work_arena">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]You can try your luck in the Arena — just be careful.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_bar_end_barmen_sms">
	<text>%c[255,0,255,0]Still alive? Changed your mind? Before heading underground, drop by — I’ve got something for the road.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_city_sms_genarmy_1">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]Attention all fighters! The main SPECTRUM forces are on the central square. We attack from the front. Savan, cover the flank. That’s an order.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_city_sms_genarmy_1_1">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]TRAITOR!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_city_sms_genarmy_2">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]Savan, get closer to the APC, you’re too far — the detonator won’t work.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_city_sms_genarmy_3">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]Those bastards launched a chopper. Savan, get to the rooftop — don’t let them escape!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_city_sms_genarmy_3_1">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]You let them get away!!!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_city_sms_genarmy_4">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]Attention! Combat helicopter detected — approaching the square. Savan, take it out. My men will cover the evacuation.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_city_sms_genarmy_5">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]Everyone, storm the Culture House! Mercenaries and SPECTRUM leaders are holed up there. No prisoners!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_city_sms_genarmy_5_1">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]Savan, check the second floor!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_city_sms_genarmy_5_2">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]Savan, check the basement!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_city_sms_genarmy_6">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]Savan, do you have the case? Bring it to me. Now!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_city_sms_genarmy_7">
	<text>%c[255,255,128,128]What the hell are you up to, bastard?! You're dead! Attention all units — I order you to eliminate the traitor!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_bar_send_12_time">
	<text>12h 08m have passed.</text>
</string>


</string_table>
