<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>

<string_table>

	<string id="st_wpn_9a91_sn_descr">
	<text>The compact automatic carbine 9A-91 was developed in 1992 as a more technologically advanced analogue and competitor to the SR-3 “Vikhr” at the Tula Instrument Design Bureau. The 9A-91’s action is based on gas blown from the barrel channel. Locking is achieved by rotating the bolt into four locking lugs. The trigger group is a hammer type, allowing for semi-automatic and fully automatic fire. The safety/selector is located on the left side of the receiver above the trigger guard (in the modernized variant — on the right, as a Picatinny rail for optics was added on the left). Early versions of the weapon had a muzzle brake-compensator, but this was later abandoned. The stock folds up and forward. Except for the plastic pistol grip and handguard, most parts are made of steel. In the folded configuration the carbine is suitable for concealed carry. For ease of concealed carry the charging handle is also made folding. Unlike Kalashnikov-pattern rifles, the charging-handle slot is permanently open.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All red-dot/holographic sights for Picatinny and dovetail mounts, ACOG, ELCAN SpecterDR \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor for 9A-91 / VSK-94\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_ak9">
	<text>AK-9</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_ak9_descr">
	<text>The AK-9 is a shortened assault rifle developed by Izhmash designers based on the AK-74M for use by Russian special forces and Interior Ministry units. In creating the new weapon the designers sought to outperform existing competitors such as the KAK Val and SR-3M. The AK-9 is a compact automatic weapon based on the service AK-74M. Its main differences from Kalashnikov rifles are a shortened gas system and barrel. Another difference is a new pistol grip with significantly improved ergonomics. The rifle uses subsonic 9?39mm cartridges — SP-5, SP-6, PAB-9. Unlike other 9?39 weapons, the AK-9 handles the more powerful and cheaper PAB-9 cartridge without issues. A quick-detach suppressor can be attached to the barrel.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All Picatinny and dovetail optics.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: ATG\n </text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_snag">
	<text>AKS-74U "Koryagi"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_snag_sn_descr">
	<text>The compact AKS-74U was developed as the primary weapon for Spetsnaz, Airborne, and special units, as well as for armoured vehicle crews who require a compact yet powerful personal automatic weapon. The AKS-74U is far more maneuverable in tight spaces and vehicles than a full-size AKS-74, however its short barrel and much lower muzzle velocity result in a reduced effective aiming range. This particular specimen previously belonged to the stalker Koryaga.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Integrated Kobra EKP-8-18 reflex sight\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Integrated tactical foregrip\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Integrated PBS-4 suppressor\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_asvk">
	<text>ASVK</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_asvk_descr">
	<text>ASVK (“army large-caliber sniper rifle”; GRAU index 6V7 with optical and night sights) — a Russian large-caliber sniper rifle developed in 2004 by a team at the Degtyaryov plant in Kovrov, based on the KSVK and the SVN-98 designs. The ASVK is currently used only by Russian military forces. Some of these rifles have appeared in the Zone with several PMC teams, which may imply that at least some of the mercenary groups in the Zone have ties to the Russian government. It is relatively rare in the Zone and is typically used by mercenaries and duty teams to eliminate dangerous mutants from a safe distance, since its powerful rounds can kill virtually any type of mutant.\n \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: integrated muzzle compensator of original design.\n
	%c[0,93,0,116] • %c[0,140,140,140] ATTACHMENTS: Sights: All sniper and night optics for Picatinny and dovetail mounts. \n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_bizon_sn">
	<text>PP-19 "Bizon" 2-01</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_bizon_sn_descr">
	<text>A modification of the PP-19 "Bizon" 2-01 (9?19mm) with the option to be upgraded to .357 caliber and equipped with a laser designator.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All Picatinny and dovetail optics.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: PBS-1\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_famas3_sn_descr">
    <text>The FAMAS G2 rifle, developed in 1994, differs from its FAMAS F1 predecessor primarily by adopting a magazine well compatible with NATO/STANAG magazines (similar to the American M16) and by a changed rifling twist. It has the highest rate of fire of any rifle found in the Zone.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] NATO suppressor\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All Picatinny and dovetail optics.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_sn_descr">
	<text>This futuristic-looking weapon is a production rifle from Belgian firm FN Herstal. Despite its bulky appearance it is highly ergonomic, comfortable to fire in all modes, and very reliable.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Standard sight: All Picatinny optics.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] NATO suppressor\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_fs2000_gl">
	<text>FN FS2000 GL</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_fs2000_gl_sn_descr">
	<text>This futuristic-looking weapon is a production rifle from Belgian firm FN Herstal. Despite its bulky appearance it is highly ergonomic, comfortable to fire in all modes, and very reliable. The FS version is equipped with the underbarrel FN40GL grenade launcher, based on the GL1 launcher used on SCAR platforms but also adapted for the FN F/FS2000. It features a longer 443 mm barrel, which benefits accuracy and increases bullet energy. \n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All Picatinny optics.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] NATO suppressor\n 
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Underbarrel FN40GL-S grenade launcher (integrated) \n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_tact">
	<text>FN F2000 "Tact"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_tact_descr">
	<text>This weapon looks futuristic — it is a mass-produced assault rifle made by the Belgian firm FN Herstal. Despite its bulky appearance, it is highly ergonomic, comfortable to handle in all firing modes, and very reliable. This particular example has been heavily modified by Zone craftsmen: the standard handguard was replaced with a tactical grip and a Picatinny rail mount was installed for reflex sights. The weapon was clearly modernized with a bias toward close-quarters combat due to an increased rate of fire.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] sight: standard, All Picatinny sights.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] NATO suppressor\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_groza_4">
	<text>OC-14-4A "Groza-4"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_groza_4_descr">
	<text>One of the variants of the OC-14-4A complex. In the "Groza-4A" version the rate of fire, ballistics and magazine capacity were improved thanks to the use of the lighter 9x39mm cartridge. This type of rifle was produced only in small experimental batches. Some of these rifles found their way into the Zone, but it never became especially popular due to its unremarkable performance compared to other rifles of the same caliber. As a result, traders started replacing the standard 30-round magazine with a 60-round sector magazine and equipped the rifles with a Zenit LED flashlight "KLESHCH-2PS+LCU", which slightly increased their popularity and demand.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] scope PO4x34, All Picatinny sights.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] suppressor: 9A91 suppressor.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] underbarrel grenade launcher GP-25 (integrated).\n
	%c[ui_gray_2]Included in the kit:\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Picatinny/Weaver adapter rail,\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] LED flashlight "KLESHCH-2PS+LCU".\n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_groza_nimble_60">
	<text>OC-14-1A "Groza-1"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_groza_nimble_60_descr">
	<text>One of the variants of the OC-14-1A. In the "Groza-1" version the rate of fire, ballistics and magazine capacity were improved thanks to the use of the lighter 7.62x39mm cartridge. This type of rifle was produced only in small experimental batches. Some of these rifles reached the Zone, but it never became particularly popular because its characteristics were not outstanding compared to other rifles of this caliber. Consequently, traders began replacing the standard 30-round magazine with a 60-round sector magazine and equipped the rifles with a Zenit LED flashlight "KLESHCH-2PS+LCU", which slightly increased their popularity and demand.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] scope PO4x34, All Picatinny sights.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] suppressor: ATG.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] underbarrel grenade launcher GP-25 (integrated).\n
	%c[ui_gray_2]Included in the kit:\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Picatinny/Weaver adapter rail,\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] LED flashlight "KLESHCH-2PS+LCU".\n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_groza_545">
	<text>OC-14-2A "Groza"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_groza_545_descr">
	<text>The OC-14-2A is an experimental bullpup variant of the "Groza" assault rifle chambered for the 5.45x39mm round. It was never completed due to a preference for the more powerful 7.62x39mm cartridge with that barrel length. In this case we are dealing with a Zone-customized weapon that simulates the experimental variant by carefully replacing the barrel, allowing the weapon to fire the more common 5.45x39mm cartridge. It was also modified to use the more common PSO-1M sight.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All reflex (collimator) sights for Picatinny and dovetail.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] underbarrel grenade launcher GP-25 (integrated) \n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_ksvk">
	<text>KSVK 12.7</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_ksvk_descr">
	<text>The KSVK is a Russian anti-materiel rifle of .50 caliber (12.7?108mm), developed at the Degtyaryov factory in the late 1990s. It was designed to engage vehicles and enemy snipers, as well as to destroy targets in heavy armor or behind thick cover. The KSVK is a bullpup-type rifle with a manually operated rotating bolt (or a straight bolt, depending on the variant). It is said to be moderately accurate, similar in some respects to the American Barrett M82. Its advantages are very high power and long effective range, but it is very heavy and bulky. The KSVK is currently used primarily by Russian military forces. Some of these rifles have appeared in the Zone with a few PMC teams, which may hint that at least some merc groups in the Zone have ties to the Russian government. It is relatively rare in the Zone and is usually used only by mercenaries and guard detachments who employ it to eliminate dangerous mutants from a safe distance, since its powerful rounds can kill any type of mutant.\n \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] suppressor: integrated muzzle compensator and flash hider of original design.\n
	%c[0,93,0,116] • %c[0,140,140,140] ATTACHMENTS: Scopes: All sniper and night scopes for Picatinny and dovetail. \n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_lr300_sn_descr">
	<text>The shortened LR-300ML is a new stage in the development of the famous AR-15 family. Broadly speaking, the changes affected only the upper half of the receiver with the barrel, gas system and bolt group, resulting in improved ergonomics and reliability and a reduced weight. This rifle is characterized by high combat accuracy, although its high sensitivity to fouling makes it less suitable for use in the harsh conditions of the Zone.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] NATO suppressor\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All Picatinny sights.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] underbarrel grenade launcher M203 (after modification)\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_mk14_sn_descr">
	<text>The United States Navy Mark 14 Enhanced Battle Rifle (Mk 14 Enhanced Battle Rifle) is an American marksman rifle developed by U.S. Navy Special Operations based on the M14 rifle. It is used by several U.S. special operations units, including the SEALs.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] NATO suppressor\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All Picatinny sights.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_pp2000_sn_descr">
	<text>The PP-2000 is a Russian 9mm submachine gun developed by a team at the Tula Instrument Design Bureau under V.P. Gryazev and A.G. Shipunov. The PP-2000 is positioned as a weapon for law enforcement units operating in urban environments, as well as a personal self-defense weapon for certain categories of military personnel. Serial production for the Russian Interior Ministry began in 2006. The body is made of high-strength plastic. The bore is chrome-lined; it can also be fitted with a suppressor, a reflex or optical sight, and serial PP-2000s have a universal sight rail on the receiver cover.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All reflex (collimator) sights for Picatinny, ACOG, ELCAN SpecterDR, PN-23.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] 9mm suppressor\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_evo_a">
	<text>CZ Scorpion EVO 3 A1</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_evo_descr">
	<text>The Scorpion EVO 3 is a modern Czech submachine gun developed by ?esk? zbrojovka in 2009. Its name references the older vz. 61 "Skorpion", but it is not mechanically related and belongs to a different category, being closer to submachine guns like the MP5 or UMP. The Scorpion EVO is considered one of the best modern submachine guns. It is made of very high-quality materials, is very light, compact and easy to shoot, allowing long bursts with minimal recoil. Several countries have adopted the EVO for police, counter-terror and special units, including the Czech Republic, Finland, Poland, Serbia and Argentina. In the Zone the EVO is mainly used by mercenaries and those who need a light, compact weapon when carrying heavy loot or bulky primary weapons, or by those who need something for close-range defense while carrying a heavy main rifle.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All Picatinny sights. \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] 9mm suppressor \n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_scar20m">
	<text>FN SCAR SSR Mk.20</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_scar20m_descr">
	<text>The FN SCAR SSR (Sniper Support Rifle) is the "sniper" variant of the FN SCAR-H Mk.17 Mod.0 — a 7.62mm rifle used by U.S. special operations forces.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] suppressor: AAC 7.62 SDN-6 \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Scope: "Schmidt & Bender" (integrated)\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Underbarrel grenade launcher: M203 \n \n</text>
</string>


<string id="st_wpn_sv98_sil_kzrzp_descr">
	<text>The SV-98 is a Russian bolt-action sniper rifle developed in 1998–2000 by a team led by Vladimir Stronsky and produced serially by the Izhevsk Concern (Izhmash). The SV-98 is intended to engage exposed, moving, revealed, unarmored, and lightly protected enemy personnel at ranges up to 1000 m. The rifle is in service and used by units of the Interior Ministry (MVD).\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Scopes: All sniper and night optics for Picatinny.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: KZRZP\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_sv98_sil_descr">
	<text>The SV-98 is a Russian bolt-action sniper rifle developed in 1998–2000 by a team led by Vladimir Stronsky and produced serially by the Izhevsk Concern (Izhmash). The SV-98 is intended to engage exposed, moving, revealed, unarmored, and lightly protected enemy personnel at ranges up to 1000 m. The rifle is in service and used by units of the Interior Ministry (MVD).\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Scopes: All sniper and night optics for Picatinny.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: ROTOR-43\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_svd_ghillie">
	<text>SVD Ghillie</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_svd_ghillie_descr">
	<text>Originally intended for infantry snipers in every Soviet infantry squad, the SVD was not a weapon of separate specialist sniper units. Being relatively light for a sniper rifle, well balanced and semi-automatic, the SVD shows good but not exceptional accuracy. Effective range up to 800 meters. This particular model has been fitted with a ghillie camouflage covering, making the user harder to identify. \n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Scope: PSO-3 (integrated)\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: KZRZP (integrated)\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_svdk">
	<text>SVDK</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_svdk_descr">
	<text>The SVDK (GRAU index 6V9) is a large-caliber Russian sniper rifle developed and adopted as part of the "Vzlomshchik" R&D program. Based on the SVD, it uses the large 9.3?64mm 7N33 cartridge — the Russian military variant of the older 9.3?64mm Brenneke hunting round. A shot from the SVDK produces muzzle energy on the order of 4900 J and provides roughly 80% chance to penetrate 10 mm of armor at 100 m.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Scopes: All optics for Picatinny and dovetail.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: 9.3x64 KIBA.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_svu_sn_descr">
	<text>The TOC-03 SVU is a modernized version of the SVD sniper rifle, originally designed for Soviet airborne forces but never mass-produced. Later, in the early 1990s, the rifle was adopted by the Russian Ministry of Internal Affairs. Built in a compact bullpup configuration, the SVU is fitted with a powerful muzzle brake/compensator that reduces recoil and muzzle blast.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: KZRZP.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Scopes: All optics for Picatinny and dovetail\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_svu_alt_sn">
	<text>SVU-AS "PMC"</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_svu_alt_sn_descr">
	<text>A shortened sniper rifle with an increased rate of fire — the most compact variant in the SVU/SVD family. Its unique feature is an automatic fire mode added at the request of the Russian MVD. Although the weapon is not primarily intended for close-quarters combat, the automatic mode can be useful in emergency situations when a sniper is discovered by the enemy. The reduced dimensions come at the cost of lower accuracy and reduced bullet velocity. To compensate for the strong recoil in automatic fire, the SVU-AS is equipped with an integrated suppressor–flash hider that also functions as an effective muzzle brake.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: KZRZP.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Scopes: All Picatinny optics\n
	%c[ui_gray_2]Included in the kit:\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] universal bipod,\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] SAG MK1 chassis modified for SVU\n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_svu_nimble_sn">
	<text>SVU "Sniper"</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_svu_nimble_sn_descr">
	<text>A unique version of the SVU-AS "PMC" specially rebuilt to order: fitted with a full-match barrel with a 320 mm twist, a completely reworked trigger group, and replacement of stamped hammer linkages with tubular ones — changes that significantly improved trigger feel and shot precision. Overall, these modifications turned the rifle into a true precision sniper weapon: accurate and powerful. This example once belonged to Max, the legendary keeper of the "Freedom" faction.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Scopes: All magnified optics compatible with Picatinny (i.e., except reflex sights). \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: ROTOR-43 \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]Included in the kit:\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] universal bipod,\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Adapter for the ROTOR-43 muzzle device,\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Universal NcStar angle rail allowing mounting of an auxiliary optic at 45° with an Aimpoint Micro T-1 reflex sight installed on it,\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] SAG MK1 chassis modified for SVU\n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_tigr9">
	<text>Tigr-9</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_tigr9_descr">
	<text>A variant of the Dragunov sniper rifle — the SVD "Tigr". Developed from the SVD and chambered for the large 9.3?64mm 7N33 cartridge, the Russian military version of the older 9.3?64mm Brenneke. Very popular among hunters for large game such as bear, elk, and wild boar. In the Zone it is encountered among scavengers and members of Clear Sky.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Scopes: All optics for Picatinny and dovetail\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: 9.3x64 KIBA.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_trg_sil_descr">
	<text>A sniper rifle manufactured by the Finnish company SAKO. The TRG-42 is not a modified version of an existing rifle but a model developed from scratch. Its consistently high accuracy and reliability have made it popular in shooting competitions and military operations requiring sniper support.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Scope: FINDOT (integrated)\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: PBS M700 .338LM (BaS)\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_tiss">
	<text>OC-12 "Tiss"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_tiss_descr">
	<text>The OC-12 "Tiss" is a Russian assault rifle developed by the Tula Central Design Bureau for Sporting and Hunting Weapons (TsKIB SOO) based on the AKS-74U. The key difference is the use of special subsonic 9x39mm cartridges (SP-5 and SP-6), which required changes to the barrel, muzzle device, bolt mirror dimensions and magazine. The sight and muzzle brake/compensator were also modified. Production was planned at the Tula Arms Plant (TOZ) but never realized. The bullpup "Groza" rifle, developed a year later based on this design, became more popular.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Scopes: All dovetail-mounted optics except PSO models with rubber eyecup and the 1P59 Hyperon.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: GZV-SR2\n </text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_tkpd">
	<text>TKPD Sturm</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_tkpd_descr">
	<text>The TKPD Sturm carbine — an assault modification of the SVDK made to order for the PMC B.E.A.R. by SniperArms Dynamics. Based on the SVD, it uses the large 9.3?64mm 7N33 cartridge, the Russian military variant of the 9.3?64mm Brenneke hunting round. A single direct hit from a TKPD is likely fatal. It is used as a precise and powerful suppression weapon at medium ranges. Effective firing range up to 800 meters.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All reflex (collimator) optics for Picatinny and dovetail.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: 9.3x64 KIBA.\n </text>
</string>


	<string id="st_wpn_tkpds">
	<text>TKPD-S</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_tkpds_descr">
	<text>Carbine TKPD-S, Conversion Modification of TKPD, chambered in 7.62x54 7h1, equipped with a modified trigger mechanism for automatic fire, supplied with extended 20-round magazines. The barrel is reinforced and match-grade. Effective firing range up to 800 meters.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All collimator sights for Picatinny and dovetail mounts.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Hexagon suppressor.\n </text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_val_sn_descr">
	<text>The special-purpose assault rifle “VAL” was created on the basis of the suppressed sniper rifle VSS “Vintorez”. It was developed for arming special units of the Soviet Army and the Ministry of Internal Affairs. Its main purpose is to effectively engage targets using modern body armor without revealing the shooter’s position. Thanks to the integrated suppressor and 9x39 cartridge with a heavy subsonic bullet, the sound and muzzle flash are minimized.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All sights for Picatinny and dovetail mounts.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: VSS (integrated)\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="AS_VAL_MOD3_CW">
	<text>AS “VAL-MOD3”</text>
</string>
<string id="AS_VAL_MOD3_CW_descr">
	<text>The special-purpose assault rifle “VAL” was created on the basis of the suppressed sniper rifle VSS “Vintorez”. It was developed for arming special units of the Soviet Army and the Ministry of Internal Affairs. Its main purpose is to effectively engage targets using modern body armor without revealing the shooter’s position. Thanks to the integrated suppressor and 9x39 cartridge with a heavy subsonic bullet, the sound and muzzle flash are minimized.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All sights for Picatinny and dovetail mounts.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: VAL upgraded (integrated)\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_vihr_sn_descr">
	<text>The SR-3 “Vikhr” is a compact Russian assault rifle developed at the Klimovsk TsNIITochMash by designers A.D. Borisov and V.N. Levchenko in 1994. It was finalized by designer A.I. Tashlykov and entered serial production in 1996. It was created based on the suppressed AS “VAL” rifle, with which it shares most components, making production and maintenance more efficient. The SR-3 uses a gas-operated system with a rotating bolt featuring six locking lugs. The later SR-3M variant was designed to allow suppressor use, 30-round metal magazines, optical and night sight installation, a left-folding skeleton stock (borrowed from the AS “VAL”), an SVD-type safety lever, and a new handguard.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All sights for Picatinny and dovetail mounts.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: SR-3M\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_vihr_m2">
	<text>SR-3MT “Vikhr”</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_vihr_m2_sn_descr">
	<text>The Duty modification of the SR-3MT “Vikhr” is equipped with a tactical handguard manufactured by special order for the Duty faction, improving ergonomics and expanding accessory compatibility.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All sights for Picatinny and dovetail mounts.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: SR-3M\n
	%c[ui_gray_2] Included in the package:\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Tactical handguard “Zenitka”,\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Tactical grip Zenit “RK-1”,\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Tactical flashlight with laser “Zenit 2PS + Klesh LCU”. \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_vityaznew">
	<text>PP-19 “Vityaz”</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_vityaznew_descr">
	<text>PP-19-01 ver.10 is a Russian submachine gun developed in 2004 by Izhmash. Depending on the version, it is based on the AKS-74U (“Vityaz”) or the AK-105 (“Vityaz-SN”). It is a standard submachine gun used by the Russian Ministry of Internal Affairs, police, National Guard, FSIN, and other law enforcement agencies. It is a further development of the PP-19 “Bizon”. One of the main differences from the base PP-19-01 is the use of AK-105 components instead of AKS-74U — including a new receiver, trigger group from the AK-100 series, standard handguard, and gas tube cover from the AK-74M line, as well as replacing the AKS-74U flip rear sight with an open sector sight.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: ACOG, Barska ES AC10632, EOTech, C-MORE\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: PBS-1\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_vityaz_sn">
	<text>PP-19-01 ver.20 “Vityaz-SN”</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_vityaz_sn_descr">
	<text>The PP-19-01 ver.20 “Vityaz-SN” with a 30-round magazine for 9x19mm cartridges was created in 2003 based on the PP-19 “Bizon-2” submachine gun for the MVD special forces unit “Vityaz” by order of the “Special Equipment and Communications” division of the Russian Ministry of Internal Affairs. It is produced in series and supplied to various law enforcement agencies in Russia.\n One of the main differences from the base PP-19-01 is the use of AK-105 components instead of AKS-74U — including a new receiver, trigger group from the AK-100 series, standard handguard, and gas tube cover from the AK-74M line, as well as replacing the AKS-74U flip rear sight with an open sector sight.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All collimator sights for Picatinny, ACOG, ELCAN SpecterDR, PN-23\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: Hexagon Sound Moderator 5.45/7.62x39/9x19\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_vsk94_sn_descr">
	<text>The suppressed sniper rifle VSK-94 was developed at the Tula Instrument Design Bureau (KBP) based on the compact 9A-91 assault rifle as a cheaper alternative to the special-purpose VSS “Vintorez” sniper rifle chambered in 9mm.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All sights for Picatinny and dovetail mounts.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor for 9A-91/VSK-94 (integrated)\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_addon_scope_1p69_ghilli">
	<text>Ghillie Set</text>
</string>
<string id="st_addon_scope_1p69_ghilli_descr">
	<text>Camouflage accessory set for Russian-made weapons equipped with the Hyperon 1P69 scope, featuring an anti-glare honeycomb filter.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_addon_scope_hamr">
	<text>Leupold Mark 4 HAMR</text>
</string>
<string id="st_addon_scope_hamr_descr">
	<text>The tactical Leupold Mark 4 HAMR 4x24mm CM-R2 with DeltaPoint matte 3.5 MOA Dot is a fixed 4x24mm optic. Designed for precision shooting and quick target acquisition, it offers multiple features beneficial to military professionals, law enforcement officers, and tactical shooters. These include a CM-R2 illuminated ballistic reticle, fast-focus eyepiece, and advanced Xtended Twilight Lens System technology. Additionally, the DeltaPoint red dot sight can be mounted on the HAMR, providing instant close-range aiming capability. (DeltaPoint and HAMR set).</text>
</string>

<string id="st_addon_scope_mark4">
	<text>Leupold Mark 4 CQ/T</text>
</string>
<string id="st_addon_scope_mark4_descr">
	<text>The Leupold Mark 4 1–3x14mm CQ/T reflex sight is a simple, reliable, and compact optic system ideal for mid- to long-range shooting, law enforcement, and military use. The 2x and 3x magnification provides a clear and accurate image of the target. It was designed in close cooperation with the military for use on AR-15 and M16 rifles. Low cost, shock resistance, and waterproof design made it popular among hunters and law enforcement officers.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_addon_wpn_fn2000scope">
	<text>FN F2000 Scope</text>
</string>
<string id="st_addon_wpn_fn2000scope_descr">
	<text>Standard FN F2000 scope with 1.6x magnification. Supplied as part of the FN F2000 rifle kit.</text>
</string>


<string id="st_addon_scope_1p87">
	<text>1P87 Valdai PK120 Sight</text>
</string>
<string id="st_addon_scope_1p87_descr">
	<text>1P87 Valdai PK120 EKVD.201214 collimator sight. Designed to reduce target acquisition time and increase shooting accuracy. Part of the DPNK experimental "Ratnik" kit.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_addon_scope_v0rtex">
	<text>Vortex AMG UH-1 Sight</text>
</string>
<string id="st_addon_scope_v0rtex_descr">
	<text>Vortex Razor AMG UH-1 holographic sight combines a sturdy body, high efficiency, and clear optics with a precision reticle.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_addon_scope_aimpmag">
	<text>"Aimpoint Micro T-2 Lens" Kit</text>
</string>
<string id="st_addon_scope_aimpmag_descr">
	<text>Collimator + magnifier kit including rail, Aimpoint Micro T-2, and EOTech G33 STS lens.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_addon_scope_e0tmag">
	<text>"EOTech Lens" Kit</text>
</string>
<string id="st_addon_scope_e0tmag_descr">
	<text>Collimator + magnifier kit including rail, EOTech EXPS3-4 sight, and EOTech G33 STS lens.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_addon_scope_1p87mag">
	<text>"1P87 Lens" Kit</text>
</string>
<string id="st_addon_scope_1p87mag_descr">
	<text>Collimator + magnifier kit including rail, 1P87 "Valdai" sight, and EOTech G33 STS lens.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_addon_scope_vortexmag">
	<text>"Vortex Lens" Kit</text>
</string>
<string id="st_addon_scope_vortexmag_descr">
	<text>Collimator + magnifier kit including rail, Vortex AMG UH-1, and EOTech G33 STS lens.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_addon_scope_compsmag">
	<text>"Aimpoint CompM4s Lens" Kit</text>
</string>
<string id="st_addon_scope_compsmag_descr">
	<text>Collimator + magnifier kit including rail, Aimpoint CompM4s, and EOTech G33 STS magnifier.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_addon_sil_kiba">
	<text>KIBA 9.3x64mm Suppressor</text>
</string>
<string id="st_addon_sil_kiba_descr">
	<text>KIBA Arms suppressor, specially designed for 9.3x64mm rifles to effectively reduce muzzle report.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_grenade_vog25h">
	<text>VOG-25 Hattabka</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_vog25h_short">
	<text>VOG-25 Hattabka</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_vog25h_descr">
	<text>A popular Russian and Chechen name for a homemade hand grenade. Typically made from VOG-25 or its variants for the GP-25/GP-30 grenade launchers, using standard grenade fuzes.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_grenade_vog17h">
	<text>VOG-17 Hattabka</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_vog17h_short">
	<text>VOG-17 Hattabka</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_vog17h_descr">
	<text>A popular Russian and Chechen name for a homemade hand grenade. Typically made from VOG-17 or VOG-17M cartridges for the AGS-17 launcher with standard grenade fuzes.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_fn_gl-1">
	<text>FN GL-1 Grenade Launcher</text>
</string>
<string id="st_fn_gl-1_short">
	<text>FN GL-1</text>
</string>
<string id="st_fn_gl-1_descr">
	<text>\n \n%c[ui_gray_2]COMPATIBILITY:\n \n%c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] FN 2000\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_1]GL-1 is a precision grenade launcher designed for FN 2000 rifles. Developed by FN Herstal in 2001, it increases firepower and provides tactical advantage in combat scenarios.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Ammunition: %c[ui_gray_1]M203 40mm grenade\n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_ar15_vss">
	<text>AR15-VSS</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ar15_vss_descr">
	<text>Deeply modified AR15, turned into a VSS-Vintorez analog. Mounted accessories allow stealthy fire, but the rifle is expensive due to non-standard components.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: All Picatinny-compatible sights.\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: Integrated\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_mcx_tac">
	<text>SIG MCX "Tactical"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_mcx_tac_descr">
	<text>The SIG Sauer MCX line, available in semi-auto and full-auto, features a short-stroke gas piston system inherited from the SIG MPX.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[d_green] Sights: %c[0,250,250,0]All Weaver/Picatinny-compatible\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[d_green] Tactical Grip: %c[d_blue]Zenit RK-5\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[d_green] Suppressor: %c[d_orange]KAC "PRS/QDC"\n \n</text>
</string>


<string id="st_wpn_ksh23">
	<text>KSh-23 "Beast Slayer"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_ksh23_descr">
	<text>A unique Zone weapon crafted by Gunsmith Den from parts of the ASH-12 and KS-23 barrel. Uses special ammo, reinforced ASH-12 body handles 23mm rounds, semi-auto only. The advanced stock reduces recoil. Beast Slayer lives up to its name, destroying monsters like chimeras and pseudogiants.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[d_green] Sights: %c[0,250,250,0]All Weaver/Picatinny-compatible\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[d_green] Tactical Grip: %c[d_blue]Zenit RK-5\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[d_green] Suppressor: %c[d_orange]Hryak 23mm\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_m16a4">
	<text>M16A4</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_m16a4_descr">
	<text>Gas-operated 5.56x45mm assault rifle. Latest AR-15 variant used by US forces. Features a flat-top receiver with MIL-STD-1913 rail and M5 Adapter Rail System for accessories. Standard issue for USMC and select Army units. Semi-auto preferred by special forces over M16A4, though still in use.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] NATO Suppressor\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: ACOG, Colt3x, PN23, Mark-4 CQ/T\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Underbarrel Grenade Launcher: M203\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_m16">
	<text>M16</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_m16_descr">
	<text>American 5.56x45mm assault rifle, derived from the AR-15. Adopted in the 1960s, replaced M14. Initially unreliable, became effective by the 1970s. High single-shot accuracy, comfortable handling, requires quality ammo and maintenance. Remains a primary weapon for US infantry.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] NATO Suppressor\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights: ACOG, Acog-Trijicon, Colt, Mark-4 CQ/T\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Underbarrel Grenade Launcher: M203\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_kedr">
	<text>PP-91-01 "Kedr-B"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_kedr_descr">
	<text>PP-91-01 "Kedr-B" submachine gun, 9x18mm PM, integrated suppressor. Designed by Yevgeny Dragunov in early 1990s for USSR Interior Ministry. 120mm fixed barrel, chrome-lined chamber, single or full-auto, 800–1000 RPM, effective range up to 50m, max ~100m.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Laser designator "Pion-M"\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="st_wpn_eft_rsh12">
	<text>RSh-12 Heavy Revolver 12.7x55mm</text>
</string>
<string id="st_wpn_eft_rsh12_descr">
	<text>RSh-12 is a rare large-caliber revolver for special units. Fires powerful 12.7x55mm rounds capable of penetrating heavy armor and dealing devastating close-range damage. High recoil, low fire rate, heavy weight, but massive stopping power. Ideal for mutant hunting and close-quarters combat.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_2]ATTACHMENTS: \n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Sights (rare): Micro T1, DeltaPoint, or RMR via rail adapter\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Suppressor: PB-12.7 or custom "heavy suppressor"\n \n</text>
</string>


</string_table>