<string id="st_signaller_toolkit_1_descr">
    <text>Designed for high-quality field repair of military equipment.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_signaller_toolkit_1">
    <text>ORK-42 Army Tools</text>
</string>
<string id="st_signaller_toolkit_2_descr">
    <text>Intended for adjustment and calibration of military equipment.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_signaller_toolkit_2">
    <text>RKB-86u Army Tools</text>
</string>
<string id="st_special_helicopter_key">
    <text>Universal Pilot Key</text>
</string>
<string id="st_special_helicopter_key_descr">
    <text>Designed to provide emergency access to helicopters.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector_modify_toolkit_descr">
    <text>Professional toolset for fine repair and modification of detectors. The included items are sufficient for any work related to adjustment and upgrading of all types of detectors.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector_modify_toolkit">
    <text>Detector Work Tools</text>
</string>
<string id="st_important_science_docks">
    <text>Scientific Report No. 1264</text>
</string>
<string id="st_important_science_docks_descr">
    <text>Several A4 pages stapled together. Cover inscription:\n"Fusion of Anomalous Rocks"\nS/N 1264</text>
</string>
<string id="st_flash_avoid_witnesses_name">
    <text>SBU Data Cell No. 15764</text>
</string>
<string id="st_flash_avoid_witnesses_descr">
    <text>Attached information: A mercenary group detained our agent near Jupiter. There is reason to believe the agent is still alive. Your objective is to rescue the agent and neutralize the resisting mercenaries. For safe entry into the camp, use the "Mercenary Suit".\nTo upload data into the PDA, usage is required.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_flash_top_secrets_name">
    <text>Item No. 1964</text>
</string>
<string id="st_flash_top_secrets_descr">
    <text>Top secret information: As locations are visited, additional transit channels will be unlocked:\n %c[255,238,153,26]Ģ %c[default] Zaton - Jupiter\n %c[255,238,153,26]Ģ %c[default] Jupiter - Zaton\n %c[255,238,153,26]Ģ %c[default] Jupiter - Pripyat\n %c[255,238,153,26]Ģ %c[default] Pripyat - Jupiter\n %c[255,238,153,26]Ģ %c[default] Jupiter - Underground\n %c[255,238,153,26]Ģ %c[default] Pripyat - Underground\n %c[255,238,153,26]Ģ %c[default] Pripyat - Zaton\n %c[255,238,153,26]Ģ %c[default] Zaton - Pripyat\n %c[default]To upload data into the PDA, usage is required.\n%c[207,155,80,255]This action is irreversible. Think carefully before using!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_letter_from_agent">
    <text>Letter from the Liaison</text>
</string>
<string id="st_letter_from_agent_descr">
    <text>The letter reads: To Major Degtyaryov. You must urgently meet with the liaison at the power plant territory. Call sign - "Siren Wailing".</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_flash_light">
    <text>Messler Optic Flashlight</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_flash_light_descr">
    <text>Halogen flashlight combined with an optical sight in a single housing.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_arms_case">
    <text>Case with Ruger GP100</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_arms_case_descr">
    <text>The case contains a disassembled Ruger GP100 and a repair kit for it.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_heavy_medkits">
    <text>CCA72 Medkit</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_heavy_medkits_descr">
    <text>Used by the Ministry of Emergency Situations, a universal medical kit with a defibrillator.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_photo_device">
    <text>Suzanna Camera</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_photo_device_descr">
    <text>Medium-format analog camera with a rigidly attached tripod.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_quest_soldier_medallion">
    <text>KhemulÆs Medallion</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_soldier_medallion_descr">
    <text>Inscription on the medallion: Group B117.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_drink_beylis">
    <text>ōBaileysö</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_drink_beylis_descr">
    <text>A rare drink, at least within the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_frequency_radio">
    <text>High-Frequency Radio ōGrundigö</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_frequency_radio_descr">
    <text>Used for communication over vast distances. Made in Germany.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_sharpshooter_binocular">
    <text>ōPathfinderö Binoculars</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_sharpshooter_binocular_descr">
    <text>Specialized military binoculars. Standard issue for military snipers.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_live_water">
    <text>Living Water</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_live_water_descr">
    <text>Another miracle born within the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_medic_medkit">
    <text>V98 Medkit</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_medic_medkit_descr">
    <text>Large medical kit. Excellent for treating any wounds or bleeding.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_bloodsucker_letter_1">
    <text>Strange Note 1</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_bloodsucker_letter_1_descr">
    <text>The letter reads: "...youÆre the first to see me... I saved your life... in exchange for silence and... and help. Help me... I canÆt appear among people, but I know the scientists surely have what I need... NG-7. Bring me this medicine. It will help me. And I will repay you."\nTo upload data into the PDA, usage is required.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_bloodsucker_letter_2">
    <text>Strange Note 2</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_bloodsucker_letter_2_descr">
    <text>The letter reads: "Thank you. Check my locker at the end of the corridor. Your reward is there."</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_bloodsucker_vaccine">
    <text>NG-7 Vaccine</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_bloodsucker_vaccine_descr">
    <text>Ozersky said nothing about this medicine, but I assume this medicine stops the mutation.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_alfa_commander_novice">
    <text>Alpha Squad CommanderÆs PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_alfa_commander_novice_descr">
    <text>%c[255,238,153,26]Commander of the Auxiliary Group.%c[default] Order to all auxiliary groups! Provide support to special forces groups or, if possible, capture alive or dead Alexander Grigoryevich Degtyaryov, born 1978, native of Pripyat, USSR. Description: slender build, looks 25-30 years old, height 179 cm, wavy light brown hair. Highly dangerous, SBU Major. All items found on him must be delivered immediately to headquarters. Pay special attention to the preservation of PDAs, paper and electronic data carriers. Five times the reward for successful completion!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_alfa_commander_regular">
    <text>Alpha Squad CommanderÆs PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_alfa_commander_regular_descr">
    <text>%c[255,238,153,26]Commander of the Special Purpose Group.%c[default] Order to all special purpose groups! Capture alive or dead Alexander Grigoryevich Degtyaryov, born 1978, native of Pripyat, USSR. Description: slender build, looks 25-30 years old, height 179 cm, wavy light brown hair. Highly dangerous, SBU Major. All items found on him must be delivered immediately to headquarters. Pay special attention to the preservation of PDAs, paper and electronic data carriers. Ten times the reward for successful completion!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_alfa_commander_experienced">
    <text>Alpha Squad CommanderÆs PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_alfa_commander_experienced_descr">
    <text>%c[255,238,153,26]Commander of the Special Purpose Group.%c[default] Order to all auxiliary and special purpose groups! Capture alive or dead Alexander Grigoryevich Degtyaryov, born 1978, native of Pripyat, USSR. Description: slender build, looks 25-30 years old, height 179 cm, wavy light brown hair. Highly dangerous, SBU Major. All items found on him must be delivered immediately to headquarters. Pay special attention to the preservation of PDAs, paper and electronic data carriers. Fifteen times the reward for successful completion!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_alfa_commander_veteran">
    <text>Alpha Squad CommanderÆs PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_alfa_commander_veteran_descr">
    <text>%c[255,238,153,26]Commander of the Special Elite Unit.%c[default] Order to all special elite unit groups! Capture alive or dead Alexander Grigoryevich Degtyaryov, born 1978, native of Pripyat, USSR. Description: slender build, looks 25-30 years old, height 179 cm, wavy light brown hair. Highly dangerous, SBU Major. All items found on him must be delivered immediately to headquarters. Pay special attention to the preservation of PDAs, paper and electronic data carriers. Twenty times the reward for successful completion!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_alfa_commander_master">
    <text>Alpha Squad CommanderÆs PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_alfa_commander_master_descr">
    <text>%c[255,238,153,26]Commander of the Special Ultra-Elite Unit.%c[default] Order to all special ultra-elite unit groups! Capture alive or dead Alexander Grigoryevich Degtyaryov, born 1978, native of Pripyat, USSR. Description: slender build, looks 25-30 years old, height 179 cm, wavy light brown hair. Highly dangerous, SBU Major. All items found on him must be delivered immediately to headquarters. Pay special attention to the preservation of PDAs, paper and electronic data carriers. Thirty times the reward for successful completion!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_b1_commander">
    <text>Bulldog PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_b1_commander_descr">
    <text>PDA containing valuable information for stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_b1_renegade_1">
    <text>Renegade PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_b1_renegade_1_descr">
    <text>PDA containing valuable information for stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_b1_renegade_2">
    <text>Renegade PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_b1_renegade_2_descr">
    <text>PDA containing valuable information for stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_b1_renegade_3">
    <text>Renegade PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_b1_renegade_3_descr">
    <text>PDA containing valuable information for stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_kasilov">
    <text>KasilovÆs PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_kasilov_descr">
    <text>PDA containing unknown information.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_cherniy">
    <text>ōChernyö PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_pda_cherniy_descr">
    <text>PDA of the mercenary leader. PDA info: Our password is "IÆm in distress".</text>
</string>
<string id="st_monolith_intercepted_case">
    <text>ōLeonö Case</text>
</string>
<string id="st_monolith_intercepted_case_descr">
    <text>Case intercepted by a Monolith agent from mercenaries. Leon requested the case to be delivered to Pripyat unopened.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_jup_thief_voron_pda">
    <text>ōVoronö PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_jup_thief_voron_pda_descr">
    <text>PDA contains an archived file protected by a password. My PDA does not support this archiver version. It must be given to Gromoboy Ś he might be able to extract the information.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_shakal_weapon">
    <text>Personalized ōBeretta92FSö</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_shakal_weapon_descr">
    <text>Personalized weapon. Custom made, with the inscription "Chapa" on the grip.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_af_acid_star_name">
    <text>"Acid Infusorium"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_acid_star_descr">
    <text>Unique artifact with excellent protective properties. It must be delivered to the Transmuters... what a pity.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_postman_parcel">
    <text>Parcel for the Saver</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_postman_parcel_descr">
    <text>According to stalker Petka Razmandyay, inside is a subscription fee. Recipient Ś Markovich, saver on Skadovsk.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_danger_parcel">
    <text>Parcel for Kanevsky</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_danger_parcel_descr">
    <text>What the Avenger dismissively called "fireworks" actually looks like a neatly packed C-4 charge with a detonator. Recipient Ś "Duty" Kanevsky.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_shustriy_ingram_m10">
    <text>Trophy "Ingram Mac-10"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_shustriy_ingram_m10_descr">
    <text>The submachine gunÆs grip is engraved. It can only be partially read: "For excellent ... service..." and someoneÆs initials "A.S. P.shk.n".</text>
</string>
<string id="st_shustriy_ak47">
    <text>Trophy "AK-47"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_shustriy_ak47_descr">
    <text>Old worn-out assault rifle, with claw marks on the stock. A weapon of legend. They say Marked One himself killed the last person in the Zone of "fracture" with it.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_shustriy_mossberg_590mk">
    <text>Trophy "Mossberg 590Mk.L"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_shustriy_mossberg_590mk_descr">
    <text>Judging by its appearance, this weapon has been pressed into the ground for a long time Ś most likely near the "Agroprom". The factory marking on the stock says it is a limited batch shotgun with superior bluing.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_shustriy_steyr_aug_ss190">
    <text>Trophy "Steyr AUG SS190"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_shustriy_steyr_aug_ss190_descr">
    <text>A weapon for true special forces. A technician who knew his job worked on this weapon, significantly improving its combat characteristics. Rumor has it this was Shurup Ś the legendary craftsman from the "Military Warehouses".</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector_serafim">
    <text>"Seraphim" Detector</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector_serafim_descr">
    <text>A special scientific development. Equipped with a locator for anomalous formations and an LED display showing the direction to an unknown specimen. It can detect specimens and measure their distance. The specimen search mode activates by lifting the antenna-lid on the front panel.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_prodigy_danger_name">
    <text>"Unknown Artifact"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_prodigy_danger_descr">
    <text>Radioactive. Almost nothing is known about the artifact's properties.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_prodigy_1_processed_name">
    <text>"Sample No. 768"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_prodigy_1_processed_descr">
    <text>An organic artifact. Composed of deformed animal tissues. When exposed to chemical contamination zones, it "extracts" chemicals from the air, converting them into a thick viscous mass.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_prodigy_2_processed_name">
    <text>"Sample No. 815"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_prodigy_2_processed_descr">
    <text>It has been established that radiation pulses from the thickened parts of this sample cause blood in open wounds to clot very quickly.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_prodigy_3_processed_name">
    <text>"Sample No. 862"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_prodigy_3_processed_descr">
    <text>An organic artifact with unique properties. Somehow increases overall healing speed after injuries of any nature, without accelerating toxin buildup.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_prodigy_4_processed_name">
    <text>"Sample No. 874"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_prodigy_4_processed_descr">
    <text>An artifact of electrostatic nature. Capable of sharply increasing the muscle tone of the wearer.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_prodigy_5_processed_name">
    <text>"Sample No. 895"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_prodigy_5_processed_descr">
    <text>Generates a sphere of directed gravitational field around itself. Very effectively reduces the weight of the wearerÆs backpack contents.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_prodigy_6_processed_name">
    <text>"Sample No. 934"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_prodigy_6_processed_descr">
    <text>Organic artifact. Generates an invisible sphere around itself that boosts the wearerÆs immunity.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_shram_quest_pda_with_info_wpnupg_name">
    <text>"PDA with Assault Rifle Modification Data"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_shram_quest_pda_with_info_wpnupg_desc">
    <text>Contains detailed instructions for repair and upgrade of various mechanisms, such as the long-rod trigger system, roller-delayed blowback semi-free bolt system, and more. Data for weapons like AEK971, Famas F1, Colt M4A1.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_shram_quest_flash_with_info_outupg_name">
    <text>"Flash Drive with Power Armor Modification Data"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_shram_quest_flash_with_info_outupg_desc">
    <text>This storage device contains information on installing additional modular systems that provide high levels of protection against radiation and psychic effects on the wearer, such as the army insulating armor "Gagarin" and the heavy stalker armor "Voskhod".</text>
</string>

	<string id="st_jup_shram_quest_flash_with_info_wpnupg_name">
    <text>"Folder with Sniper Rifle Modification Data"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_jup_shram_quest_flash_with_info_wpnupg_desc">
    <text>Contains detailed descriptions of improvements to muzzle brakes, barrels, and electronic stabilizers for sniper rifles: Barrett M82, CheyTac Intervention M200, and KSVK.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_maypon_quest_note_desc">
    <text>"Damn it! Beetle left no other clue but this piece of paper, so donÆt blame me. When you find it in the stashŚeat it right away... Just kidding. Now seriously. Archer fulfilled his part of the dealŚretrieved the cargo. Seems he did it cleanly. DidnÆt bring any tail, I hope. I checked the caseŚall as agreed. I left it at the VNZ KrugŚas always. You can take it, weÆll settle the rest tomorrow. Damn, whatÆs that ringing in my ears, now IÆll check... cont..."</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_maypon_quest_note_name">
    <text>"Note from Maypon"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_maypon_quest_case_desc">
    <text>"A very heavy case with unknown cargo. Seems itÆs not radioactive and doesnÆt cause headaches. Possibly some kind of device or part of equipment."</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_maypon_quest_case_name">
    <text>"MayponÆs Case"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_jup_azot_quest_papka_with_info_grenade_name">
    <text>"Folder with Blueprints"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_jup_azot_quest_papka_with_info_grenade_desc">
    <text>This folder contains various information and blueprints needed to upgrade grenades.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_jup_azot_quest_instruments_for_grenade_name">
    <text>"Special Tool Set"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_jup_azot_quest_instruments_for_grenade_desc">
    <text>Includes various tools necessary for assembling grenades into a cluster.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_stalker_fantom_pda_name">
    <text>"PhantomÆs PDA"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_stalker_fantom_pda_desc">
    <text>PDA of the stalker nicknamed Phantom. All personal notes and information are under special protection.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_danger_parcel2_name">
    <text>"Cargo for Varg"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_danger_parcel2_descr">
    <text>A fairly heavy crate. Contents unknown. Intended for the Duty saboteur Varg.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x1_name">
    <text>"Data Carrier for Laboratory X1"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x1_descr">
    <text>Main laboratory, the most important facility of the "O-Consciousness" project. It was the largest scientific complex. Its task was to control the noosphere (the studied project) and modify it if possible. Control was to be carried out directly by a Scientific Staff member trained in Laboratory X6 (all who participated directly in the X1 and X2 experiments), in stasis. It consisted of 6 devices, prototypes located in Laboratory X16. They performed the main work, each ensuring sequential noosphere control during scientistsÆ consciousness implantation into the information shell. Laboratory X1 was located on the Chernobyl NPP territory. An underground complex near the unfinished 6th power unit was chosen. After construction was halted, underground rooms remained, which had to be completed but were relatively convenient for the laboratory."</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x2_name">
    <text>"Data Carrier for Laboratory X2"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x2_descr">
    <text>Also located on the NPP territory, directly connected with Laboratory X1, but situated under the 4th power unit. It housed scientific staff who conducted experiments to study and modify the noosphere. To cover the labs, an energy installation was created within the station to alter the consciousness of all under its control. This installation was soon called Monolith. It was reprogrammed many times to create a more advanced program. After the accident in Laboratory X1, attempts were made in X2 to fix the situation and take control, but unsuccessfully. Later, when armed forces appeared at Chernobyl NPP, measures were taken to alter consciousness of everyone in the area using the Monolith. This was the first human experiment, but surprisingly, not everyone came under controlŚthose who didnÆt died. When the experiment succeeded, the program worked, and people were made like guards for the complex, named after the Monolith device. Over time Monolith improved and reached full power, able to control Monolith forces."</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x6_name">
    <text>"Data Carrier for Laboratory X6"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x6_descr">
    <text>Laboratory complex X6 was the center for training scientific staff to manage the noosphere. It was a relatively small lab on the outskirts of the former city Limansk. Unlike other labs, it was not meant for long-term work, so after training, operations ceased and staff were transferred to X1. Its location required no choice: before the 1986 accident, a research station "Radiovolna" operated there, with an antenna nearby unrelated to the experiment. Necessary experimental equipment was also there, origins unclear to staff. The X6 lab program was closed in 2001.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x7_name">
    <text>"Data Carrier for Laboratory X7"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x7_descr">
    <text>This scientific complex developed technical equipment for all labs. The chief designer was Professor S.I. Kaimanov. Thanks to his work, devices like the "Duga" radar and "Control" SVI were designed. These were intended for various labs and further experiments. The lab was in the buildings of the former "Jupiter" factory. The location was chosen because existing equipment and conditions suited work. The lab operated until the last 2006 accident at the X1 complex. Afterwards, no news about the X1 complex; personnel likely perished during the accident.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x8_name">
    <text>"Data Carrier for Laboratory X8"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x8_descr">
    <text>The research and engineering complex X8 was one of the main labs of the "O-Consciousness" project. Many scientists worked here; it also trained people who would participate in X1 and X2 experiments. Trainees went to labs X6, X1, or X2 depending on direction. Engineers also trained here, later sent to other labs including X9. The complex was mostly a retraining center for specialists before their deployment. Other personnel worked on engineering development. The last engineer decision from X8 was to create from the "Duga" radar a device to reduce aggression near antennas. The engineering complex was led by senior researcher Professor N.A. Lebedev. The lab was closed in 2003 for unknown reasons; personnel were dispersed to various labs. Some went to X12, others (mostly engineers) to X9.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x9_name">
    <text>"Data Carrier for Laboratory X9"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x9_descr">
    <text>A little-known complex staffed partly by scientists from secret defense research institutes rather than their original groups. Their goal was to create superweapons based on energy elements. Their only development was "Item No. 62", known as the "Gauss Gun". The project was stalled for a long time due to battery flaws. Though partly successful, it consumed too much power for battery charging. The project was closed in 2004; some personnel returned to defense institutes, others sent to other labs. Project leaders were sent to X1 with weapon samples for further development.</text>
</string>

	<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x10_name">
    <text>"Data Carrier for Laboratory X10"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x10_descr">
    <text>
        Scientific complex initially represented by transmitter towers, but later transformed after changes in X8 and eventual conversion of underground storage into Laboratory X10. After reequipment, X10 became an aggression suppression station. The antennas were built on a small area of a former construction plant. The project was partially controlled by a secret defense research institute. Early experiments yielded disappointing results, the installation failed its objectives. After commission and observers left, the project continued with renewed efforts. Extensive work adjusted the antennas toward intended operation. In 2006, during a test, a second NPP accident caused the last tower antenna to tilt, resulting in equipment failure and the emergence of a psi-barrier intended to suppress aggression but instead amplified it, driving all under its influence insane. The first affected were all personnel working there. Over time, the installation was nicknamed "Brain Burner" for its zombifying effect within the complex.
    </text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x12_name">
    <text>"Data Carrier for Laboratory X12"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x12_descr">
    <text>
        Essentially, this complex was not a real complex but a fa?ade to divert attention from commissions of other institutes. It served as a large archive for all documentation of the "O-Consciousness" project. Located on the former "Agroprom" research institute territory, staffed partly by personnel transferred from various labs. Its activity was limited to collecting documents and materials on conducted research and experiments. Fortunately, before the second NPP catastrophe, all primary documents were removed outside the Exclusion Zone; other materials were destroyed. After the accident, scientists did not return to X12, leaving the lab abandoned.
    </text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x16_name">
    <text>"Data Carrier for Laboratory X16"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x16_descr">
    <text>
        This laboratory complex was one of the most important in the "O-Consciousness" project. Many staff worked here conducting experiments on the SVI "Control" installation. The project was complex: prototype development, building the lab and installation took much time and effort. The installation started working only in 1996. The main element caused overheating, requiring constant cooling supervision. Frequent malfunctions and technical design errors were observed, too late to fix. The installation consumed much energy, causing network overloads requiring constant attention. Staff complained of headaches attributed to the installation. During the NPP accident, a power surge caused irreversible damage in X16; everyone present lost their minds, zombified, or died.
    </text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x18_name">
    <text>"Data Carrier for Laboratory X18"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_secret_lab_x18_descr">
    <text>
        The last complex mentioned in the "O-Consciousness" project documents. Created when project leaders aimed to build the "Monolith". To maintain its state, living functional matter capable of various functions such as power support was needed. Since the installation was created using the noosphere, it required such elementsŚenergy clusters obtained and created by different means. This source was proven inexhaustible. Energy was transformed using special devices designed by Laboratory X7's Professor Kaimanov. Eventually, living organisms were used as the most reliable element, sent in special incubators to Lab X2 for integration into Monolith's control complex. After filling the cells and studying stability, the decision was made to halt further production. Equipment was conserved, staff transferred to Lab X7 until new energy cells would be needed.
    </text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_about_shram_paper_name">
    <text>"Directive on Objects One and Two of the S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Project"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_about_shram_paper_descr">
    <text>
        Kharon. The experiment likely succeeded. Results should be expected soon. Per Krechet's directive: Object #1Śalso known as ShooterŚmust be delivered to the checkpoint at Cordon; Object #2Śknown as ShramŚmust be delivered to the checkpoint near Military, close to the Barrier. Use the death truck and two reliable mercenaries for delivery. After operation completion, all witnesses including executors must be eliminated. Nothing should stop us now...
    </text>
</string>
<string id="zat_anomalies_1_scanner_name">
    <text>"Thermal Anomaly Scanner"</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_anomalies_1_scanner_descr">
    <text>Specialized anomaly activity scanner, model series 18.4798. Used by scientists to study processes occurring in thermal anomalies.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_anomalies_2_scanner_name">
    <text>"Psi-Static Anomaly Scanner"</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_anomalies_2_scanner_descr">
    <text>Specialized anomaly activity scanner, model series 16.4451. Used by scientists to study processes occurring in psi-static anomalies.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_anomalies_3_scanner_name">
    <text>"Gravitational Symbiont Scanner"</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_anomalies_3_scanner_descr">
    <text>Specialized anomaly activity scanner, model series 14.2321. Used by scientists to study processes occurring in gravitational anomalies.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_anomalies_4_scanner_name">
    <text>"Chemical Anomaly Scanner"</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_anomalies_4_scanner_descr">
    <text>Specialized anomaly activity scanner, model series 12.1150. Used by scientists to study processes occurring in chemical anomalies.</text>
</string>

	<string id="st_zat_stalker_zubr_pda_name">
    <text>"Zubr's PDA"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_stalker_zubr_pda_desc">
    <text>"PDA of the stalker-hunter named Zubr. Last entry: 'Observing those creatures southwest of Sosnodub. About ten individuals behaving aggressively but not attacking each other. Strange. Their behavior resembles Chernobyl dogs more than ordinary blind ones. And their looks Ś like Cerberus but with one head. Need to get closer, maybe I can quietly take one down...'"</text>
</string>

<string id="st_pri_csky_kalancha_pda_name">
    <text>"Professor Kalancha's PDA"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_pri_csky_kalancha_pda_desc">
    <text>"Last entry: 'Could we really have made a miscalculation? If so, we're all doomed here. Neither Shram nor anyone else will help now. We should have tried to eliminate Strelok earlier. But now it's pointless... Monolith followers are everywhere... They killed Gandalf, that's it... this is the end...'"</text>
</string>

<string id="st_pri_csky_lebedev_pda_name">
    <text>"Professor Lebedev's PDA"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_pri_csky_lebedev_pda_desc">
    <text>"Last entry: 'Shram got to Strelok too late. I doubt it will change anything now. Our forces are running out. This decision was suicide, even if we had ten times more fighters... ItÆs already too late... Shram broke through Strelok's psi-shield... but what is this... an emission... no... what... aa... '"</text>
</string>

<string id="st_all_about_lebedev_paper_name">
    <text>"Directive on Objects Three and Four of the S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Project"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_about_lebedev_paper_descr">
    <text>"Guron. The experiment likely succeeded. Results should be expected soon. Per Krechet's directive: Objects #3 and #4, also known as Lebedev and Kalancha, must be transported to the Tesla facility for further processing. All traces of their presence in the lab must be destroyed. Personal belongings of the objects should be delivered to the surface of Pripyat. Create a stash near the river port close to your base. They may still be useful..."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_pri_kardan_quest_gauss_pistol_shema_name">
    <text>"Schematic of the Reduced Gauss Coil"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_pri_kardan_quest_gauss_pistol_shema_desc">
    <text>"A set of blueprints and schematics for the main component of an experimental pistol ¢ the Gauss coil. Without it, creating the necessary parts for the Gauss pistol is unlikely."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_pri_kardan_quest_gauss_pistol_prototype_name">
    <text>"Item #58"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_pri_kardan_quest_gauss_pistol_prototype_desc">
    <text>"Non-working prototype of a Gauss pistol."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_jup_kardan_quest_gauss_pistolet_transistor_name">
    <text>"Box of Transistors"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_jup_kardan_quest_gauss_pistolet_transistor_desc">
    <text>"Ordinary electronic components Ś field-effect transistors. Required to build the Gauss coil."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_jup_kardan_quest_gauss_pistolet_wire_name">
    <text>"Gauss Coil"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_jup_kardan_quest_gauss_pistolet_wire_desc">
    <text>"A reduced version of the Gauss coil used in the weapon of the same name. Necessary for generating the electromagnetic field of the accelerator Ś the core component of both the Gauss rifle and Gauss pistol."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_jup_chapay_quest_paket_with_narkota_name">
    <text>"Package with Cargo"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_jup_chapay_quest_paket_with_narkota_desc">
    <text>"A small compact polyethylene package containing white powder. Could be heroin or something else."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_jup_chapay_quest_case_with_narkota_name">
    <text>"Case with Cargo"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_jup_chapay_quest_case_with_narkota_desc">
    <text>"By weight, it seems to be a sizable batch of narcotics. Worth at least half a million."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_zat_chapay_quest_flash_with_info_narkota_name">
    <text>"Flash Drive with Files"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_chapay_quest_flash_with_info_narkota_desc">
    <text>"Several text files containing names, phone numbers, and addresses. Looks like a database of couriers and middlemen in a criminal network. Not much use to me Ś IÆm not in narcotics control."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_jup_azot_nano_outfit_quest_2_case_name">
    <text>"Case with Nanokevlar"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_jup_azot_nano_outfit_quest_2_case_desc">
    <text>"Sturdy, convenient, fireproof case containing cargo belonging to scientists Ś a unique nanokevlar."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_jup_azot_nano_outfit_quest_2_shema_name">
    <text>"Schematic of Servomotors and Hydraulic Boosters"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_jup_azot_nano_outfit_quest_2_shema_desc">
    <text>"Highly valuable information necessary for technicians working with both hydraulic boosters and servomotors."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_pri_azot_nano_outfit_quest_3_flash_name">
    <text>"Flash Drive with Data"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_pri_azot_nano_outfit_quest_3_flash_desc">
    <text>"Professor Mironov's flash drive containing copies of files on the creation of semi-invisible items."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_pri_azot_nano_outfit_quest_3_case_name">
    <text>"Case with Documents"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_pri_azot_nano_outfit_quest_3_case_desc">
    <text>"Professor Mironov's case containing documents and research results in the field of partial mimicry."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_zat_dolg_kanevsky_pda_name">
    <text>"Kanevsky's PDA"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_dolg_kanevsky_pda_descr">
    <text>"Dolg operative Kanevsky's PDA. All information is locked."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_zat_dolg_kanevsky_documents_1_name">
    <text>"Folder with Kanevsky's Notes"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_dolg_kanevsky_documents_1_desc">
    <text>
        "Space on Yanov is running out. 'Freedom' is too firmly entrenched here, and we have too few men to try to push them out. Voronin refuses to send reinforcements Ś they have something similar going on, mutants pouring from the Dark Valley by the masses, plus mercenaries trying to hold the bar. It's bad. Varg said we need to look for new zones of influence. ThereÆs no better place than Zaton. Scouts report that all possible spots for a stronghold are taken by loners. They wonÆt leave peacefully, and you canÆt drive them out by force Ś donÆt need loners as enemies too. ThereÆs an abandoned ship on Zaton where stalkers set up a base. A local trader called Sych runs things there, bartenderÆs nickname is 'Beard'. We tried to negotiate. Promised them everything Ś money, artifacts, supplies from Dolg warehouses Ś but no deal. TheyÆre experienced bastards, not to be fooled. They decided theyÆre better off on their own. We gathered a council and decided: hire bandits to handle the loners Ś theyÆve lost all fear. In 2-3 days they should attack Skadovsk and clear out all the stalker scum. Then, a week or two later, when loners cry out, Sultan will crush them hard. WeÆll have the 'liberation' march, wipe out the bandits, and Dolg will have a base in Skadovsk."
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_zat_dolg_kanevsky_documents_2_name">
    <text>"Folder with Kanevsky's Documents"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_zat_dolg_kanevsky_documents_2_desc">
    <text>
        "Started negotiations with bandits. They agreed, glad to finally get revenge. At first, they didnÆt believe us Ś suspicious after all the shooting Ś but then fully supported us and even brought gear on a silver platter. We convinced them the Zone is changing, plans change, former enemies become best friends. There are two of us from the Zaton HQ Ś me and Morgan. Morgan manages our warehouses and arranges supply of gear to bandits. The deal was supposed to happen already, they met at the Forestry. IÆm negotiating with SultanÆs ambassador. Sultan himself is a bastard, afraid to show up. IÆve held three meetings with his rep, Kaban. What a jerk. We scheduled a fourth meeting. Yesterday we waited and saw not Kaban, but another bandit Ś called himself Avenger Ś say that Kaban was killed by loners and now heÆs chief negotiator for the bandits. Also said Morgan was shot dead by stalkers at the Forestry during the deal. Those bastards found out somehow! Still, the deal was made, and tomorrow AvengerÆs rep will bring a suitcase of money to pay for gear. He canÆt come himself, suspects free stalkers are onto them. WeÆll wait."
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_geo_quest_skladovsk_defence_name">
    <text>"Ammo Crate"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_geo_quest_skladovsk_defence_descr">
    <text>"A very heavy crate packed to the brim with cartridges."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_geo_3_name">
    <text>"Kanevsky's PDA"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_geo_3_desc">
    <text>"PDA belonging to Dolg operative Kanevsky. Data is password protected and encrypted."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_pri_pogect_istocnik_killer_pda_1_name">
    <text>"Teuton's PDA"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_pri_pogect_istocnik_killer_pda_1_desc">
    <text>"Last message: 'SerbinÆs group died, but according to new data X8 is declassified. XavierÆs group was supposed to back them up, but IÆm not sure they managed what Serbin couldnÆt. Go there and extract everything from the lab that can point to the "Source" project.'" </text>
</string>

<string id="st_pri_pogect_istocnik_killer_pda_2_name">
    <text>"Xavier's PDA"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_pri_pogect_istocnik_killer_pda_2_desc">
    <text>"Last message: 'Fagot, mission complete. We have the data on the "Source" project. Set up a meeting with Richards. Preferably somewhere remote to avoid prying eyes.'" </text>
</string>

<string id="st_pri_pogect_istocnik_alfa_pda_1_name">
    <text>"Captain Richards' PDA"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_pri_pogect_istocnik_alfa_pda_1_desc">
    <text>"Last message: 'The mercenary contacted us. Xavier will wait near the plant, not far from Yanov station. I hope the meeting wonÆt take long. If something goes wrong, my teams will kill Xavier and retrieve the documents. After that, our mission will be complete.'" </text>
</string>

<string id="st_pri_pogect_istocnik_alfa_case_name">
    <text>"Case with Documentation"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_pri_pogect_istocnik_alfa_case_desc">
    <text>"Case containing information about the 'Source' project."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_all_quest_greh_3_pda_name">
    <text>"Mirovoy's PDA"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_quest_greh_3_pda_desc">
    <text>"Last entry: We identified what the sinners use. Some new drug. I donÆt know what it does to the psyche. The sinners were unloading large quantities near the container warehouses. Their leader who brought the drug was called Demonologist. He mentioned to another man named Osiris that the next batch would arrive in a few days. Damn, are those Controllers? Looks like psionics... damn, weÆre out, they spotted us..."</text>
</string>

	<string id="st_all_quest_greh_6_pda_name">
    <text>"Demonologist's PDA"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_quest_greh_6_pda_desc">
    <text>"Last entry: Osiris, we need to retreat. Lead most of the people to Jupiter, I will join you soon. This is just the beginning. The Inspirer is already here. The Masters know what to do..."</text>
</string>

<string id="st_all_quest_greh_osiris_name">
    <text>"Osiris' Documents"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_all_quest_greh_osiris_desc">
    <text>"Entry: It looks like we were simply used. We mean nothing to the Masters. Anubis is their watchdog, ready to go all the way. What he wants is unclear. And it no longer matters. Greh has fallen, but they will pay for it. And Anubis first of all..."</text>
</string>

	