<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
----Stories from the Zone----


---- Northern Rush----

<string id="barkeep_north_0_0">
		<text>You seem to have a full-house here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_0_1">
		<text>And all thanks to you! By disabling the Brainscorcher you opened up the north for anyone who dares to go! 
			You triggered a rush for the north - and people gather here to buy supplies before setting off! Here, a drink on the house - you deserved it! \n \n
			If you're looking to make some money, now is a great opportunity! Prices are soaring, I hope you don't need any supplies as demand is huge at the moment.</text>
	</string>

<string id="barkeep_north_1_0">
		<text>What is further north from here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_1_1">
		<text>Well... first you got the Army Warehouse. Freedom sits there for now, but be careful going up further north from it. 
		The Monolith is pressing them pretty hard, and some forward elements of their squads can slip through. Even further there is the Red Forest... I only saw it once when I came here, and I knew never to step a foot in that!
		A forest, stained red from the victims of the mutants lurking in the shadows! But that isn't your biggest problem! The brainscorcher will turn your brain into mush! People say that's how zombies are made! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_1_2">
		<text>What is north of the Red Forest?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_1_3">
		<text>There is Yanov and Zaton! But these places are now forgotten by god himself... I hear of brothers turning their blade on their own! 
		Murder is rampant, and some even say that they resorted to eating their own! Cannbalism, can you imagine! Well that's the stories, I don't know if they are true...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_1_4">
		<text>Why are they lost?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_1_5">
		<text>There is no path to them anymore! The brainscorcher blocks it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_1_6">
		<text>What do you mean?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_1_7">
		<text>Ah, you're new here... Do you know about the Monolith?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_1_8">
		<text>Yeah, of course I know about them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_1_9">
		<text>The Monolith?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_1_10">
		<text>The Monolith... a bunch of crazy fanatics protecting the center of the Zone. No one is sure what exactly they protect there, but rumors tell that it's the Wish Granter! What else is there to protect! 
		But be careful! These guys are crazy, they fight without any regard of their life! Well, these guys have a base near the Red Forest, and in it this machine from hell: the Brainscorcher! 
		That machine fries the brain of any Stalker getting to close to them, and it makes any crossing of the Red Forest impossible without protection. 
		For a long time it has been turned off, but recently the Monolith managed to recapture their base and reactivate their machine. Now the north is cut off from us...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_1_11">
		<text> Well, these guys have a base near the Red Forest, and in it this machine from hell: the Brainscorcher! 
		That machine fries the brain of any Stalker getting to close to them, and it makes any crossing of the Red Forest impossible without protection. 
		For a long time it has been turned off, but recently the Monolith managed to recapture their base and reactivate their machine. Now the north is cut off from us...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_1_12">
		<text>So there is protection against the Brainscorcher?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_north_1_13">
		<text>There is... the scientists managed to craft a protective helmet, but these things are expensive and rare... it's very difficult to get your hands on one...</text>
	</string>

---- Scamlok ----

-- Barman --


<string id="barkeep_scamlok_believe_0">
		<text>Hey, I just met Strelok!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_scamlok_believe_1">
		<text>Strelok? Here? Are you sure?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_scamlok_believe_2">
		<text>Yes! And he is gathering a team to reach the Wishgranter! The participation fee was a bit steep, but it will be worth it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_scamlok_believe_3">
		<text>Strelok who is recruiting strangers? For a fee? Hahahaha \n \nYou got scammed my friend. Strelok would never do that!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_scamlok_believe_4">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_scamlok_believe_5">
		<text>The Zone is full of scammers, it can happen to anyone... but I have to say, you belong to the more naive ones - Strelok asking for money, hahaha. \n \nDon't be sad, here a drink on the house.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="barkeep_scamlok_scammer_0">
		<text>Hey, I just met a man saying he is Strelok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_scamlok_scammer_1">
		<text>Strelok? Here? What did he want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_scamlok_scammer_2">
		<text>He said that he is gathering a team to reach the Wishgranter! Was asking for 10000 roubles particitpation fee...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_scamlok_scammer_3">
		<text>Ah a scammer. Happens sometimes that a man comes around pretending to be Strelok. The true one would never trust strangers and ask them money. I hope you didn't give him anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_scamlok_scammer_4">
		<text>No, I was not feeling it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barkeep_scamlok_scammer_5">
		<text>Well done. I'll warn the customers and have my guys look for that imposter.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	

<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello Stalker, you look experienced!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_1">
		<text>I just took down the Brain Scorcher, of course I'm experienced!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_2">
		<text>You could say that...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_3">
		<text>What makes you say that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_4">
		<text>No, I'm still a rookie learning the ropes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_5">
		<text>DDDDAMN! You're the guy! It's an honour meeting you! I'm Sorokin! \n \nAre you also here to join Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Nice to meet you! I'm Sorokin. I'm looking for the services of an experienced Stalker such as you. I need to go to Yanov Station, could you help me? 
		I'm somewhat new here, so I don't have a team... yet, but I have money! It would mean a lot, I have a golden opportunity which I can't miss. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_7">
		<text>Of course the gear, but most of all your expression. I'm Sorokin, nice to meet you! \n \nListen, I need an experienced Stalker to bring me to Yanov Station. I'm somewhat new here, so I don't have a team yet, but I have money!
		It would mean a lot, I have a golden opportunity which I can't miss. Are you interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_8">
		<text>Oh, me too! i thought with all your gear, you looked like a veteran. \n \nI'm Sorkin, nice to meet you! Are you also here to find a guide to Yanov?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_9">
		<text>Strelok? Have you seen him? Where is he?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_10">
		<text>Why do you need to go to Yanov?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_11">
		<text>Yanov? Maybe, at some point. Why are you asking?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_12">
		<text>Well... I'm not supposed to tell this to anyone, but I guess you're a hero of the Zone now. 
		Yes, I've met him. He doesn't want to attract attention, but yes he's here, in Rostok! He's putting together a team! You should meet him! I'm sure that you're the perfect candidate.  </text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_13">
		<text>... Ok, I'm not supposed to tell this, but considering you're a veteran you'd make a great addition to the team. I suppose you know who Strelok is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_14">
		<text>... Ok, I'm not supposed to tell this, but as we're both new here we have to stick together. Do you know who is Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_15">
		<text>Where is he?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_16">
		<text>Of course I know who he is. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_161">
		<text>Of course I know who he is. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_17">
		<text>I'll tell you, but remember me, and please take me with you to Yanov! He's in the hangar north of the Arena.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_18">
		<text>Of course. Well he's recruiting at the moment for a huge mission to the heart of the Zone. The Wishgranter, can you believe it?
		There are trials and so on, but that shouldn't be a problem for you! Come see me before you go though, I want to join you! I'll pay of course, that's not a problem. You'll find him in the hangar north of the Arena.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_start_dialog_19">
		<text>Of course, the guy is legend, right? Well he's recruiting at the moment for a huge mission to the heart of the Zone. The Wishgranter, can you believe it? 
		There are trials though and an entry fee... But if you go, take me with you! I'm sure we'd make a great team! You'll find him in the hangar north of the Arena.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_sorokin_0">
		<text>Hey man, about the expedition...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_1">
		<text>Did you meet Strelok? He's great, right? And? Will you join us? Will you take me with you to Yanov?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_2">
		<text>Yes I will join the expedition, and I'll bring you to Yanov with me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_3">
		<text>No I won't join the expedition, but I can bring you to Yanov nevertheless.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_4">
		<text>I hate to break it to you, but that guy wasn't Strelok...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="nr_sorokin_5">
		<text>Great! Tell me when you're ready to leave, I already am!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_6">
		<text>Oh...alright, you certainly have your reasons...but thanks for escorting me to Yanov! Tell me when you're ready to leave, I already am!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_7">
		<text>What? How... how do you know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_8">
		<text>That guy was super sketchy, he certainly was a scammer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_9">
		<text>I talked to the barkeeper, he told me that there is no chance that the guy was legit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_10">
		<text>What? No fucking way, you're trying to cut me out in order to have less competition! Fuck you, I thought I could trust you! I'll find another way to go to Yanov!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_11">
		<text>What? I mean... if the barkeeper is convinced... Fuck, this is horrible! I... I took a loan in order to join Strelok, I mean, whoever that was... Fuck, I'm screwed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_12">
		<text>I need some time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_13">
		<text>Alright, but don't take too long, Strelok won't be waiting for us!</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_sorokin_1_0">
		<text>About the escort to Yanov.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_1_1">
		<text>Yes, are you ready, can we leave?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_1_2">
		<text>We can leave.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_1_3">
		<text>I need some more time to prepare.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_1_4">
		<text>Alright, you lead the way!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_1_5">
		<text>Alright, but don't take too long, Strelok won't be waiting for us!</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_sorokin_2_0">
		<text>We arrived.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_2_1">
		<text>Thanks alot! Here is the money. I'll have a rest at the bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_2_2">
		<text>Alright, I'll ask around if someone saw Strelok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_2_3">
		<text>See you soon!</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_sorokin_3_0">
		<text>I just talked to Hawaiian, apparently the guy we met wasn't Strelok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_3_1">
		<text>How would he know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_3_2">
		<text>Well, he says that Strelok would not organise a team out of strangers and ask them to pay. Hawaiian thinks that we got scammed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_3_3">
		<text>That... that cannot be! But the guy fitted the description of him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_3_4">
		<text>Hawaiian made a valid point, everyone knows Strelok's gear and could dress the same...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_3_5">
		<text>Fuck! Oh no! I'm fucked!!! I ... - I ... I made a loan to pay my fee! I ... I am fucked!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_3_6">
		<text>[8.000 roubles] Sorry mate... Here, I can give you the money back you paid me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_3_7">
		<text>Sorry mate... Seems like we have been scammed...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_3_8">
		<text>Th-thanks... I guess that helps out a bit... but I still owe that creditshark 50.000 roubles... even if I sell everything I have, I will never reach that sort of money...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sorokin_3_9">
		<text>Fuck...</text>
	</string>


<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_0">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Strelok? I've been looking for you!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Strelok? I've heard that you're putting together a team.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_3">
		<text>Are you really Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_4">
		<text>Pssht, not so loud! No need to attract the attention of whole Rostok! \n \nSo, you have been looking for me? Why? And how did you find me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_5">
		<text>Pssht, not so loud! No need to attract the attention of whole Rostok! \n \nWhy are you asking about a team?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_6">
		<text>If you need to ask, you don't need to know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_7">
		<text>What is the problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_71">
		<text>What is the problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_8">
		<text>Why? Because I'm Strelok! My enemies seek me, even my admires bother me! You have no idea how tedious it is to operate here when everyone tries to get something from you.
			\n \nBut answer my question, you have been looking for me? Why? And how did you find me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_9">
		<text>Why? Because I'm Strelok! My enemies seek me, even my admires bother me! You have no idea how tedious it is to operate here when everyone tries to get something from you.
			\n \nWhy are you asking about a team?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_10">
		<text>I want to find the Wishgranter - Sidorovich told me you've done it before. I thought you were somewhere north of here, I even disabled the Brainscorcher in order to find you. And now, by coincidence, a guy at the bar told me where to find you. Can you help me get there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_11">
		<text>A guy at the bar told me. He also told me that you want to go to the Wishgranter. Is it true?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_12">
		<text>I mean, I never met you, how do I know it's you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_13">
		<text>The Wishgranter? You're in luck, that is indeed where I'm planning to go. I'm putting together a team for exactly that purpose - you wish to join me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_14">
		<text>I told them to keep quiet about me and the team. Who was it? \n\n Ah fuck it, doesn't matter. 
			Yes, I'm gathering a team, and yes - we're going after the Wishgranter. Are you interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_15">
		<text>Hmm, you're new here? Alright, see this tattoo? I'm the guy you're looking for. What is it you want?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_16">
		<text>Don't you already have a team? Why do you need strangers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_17">
		<text>Of course I'm interested - when do we leave?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_18">
		<text>Don't you already have a team? Why do you need strangers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_19">
		<text>Of course I'm interested - when do we leave?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_20">
		<text>Alright, I believe you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_21">
		<text>But...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_22">
		<text>Of course I already have a team - the most grizzled veterans you could imagine... but finding the Wishgranter is no walk in the park. 
	We need more people, and that's why I'm here to recruit candidates. \n\nMaybe you'd make a good fit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_23">
		<text>Not so fast. You see, this enterprise is no walk in the park - I'm here to find worthy men and not rookies. So there will be a test and a fee.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_24">
		<text>A fee?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_25">
		<text>A test?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_26">
		<text>Then tell me, what do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_27">
		<text>No "but"! Either you accept it or you fuck off. In the end, remember, you came to me, not the other way around! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_28">
		<text>Yes a fee. We need supplies, weapons and armor to assault the CNPP. I know some guys who sell premium stuff, but it also comes with a premium price.
	So, everyone who wishes to join has to put 10.000 roubles in the pot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_281">
		<text>Yes a fee. We need supplies, weapons and armor to assault the CNPP. I know some guys who sell premium stuff, but it also comes with a premium price.
	So, everyone who wishes to join has to put 10.000 roubles in the pot. \n\nWhat do you say? You seem to be perfect for the job, I'm sure you'll make the cut.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_29">
		<text>Of course. I cannot take rookies with me, so there will be a test in order to weed out the weak and unreliable. 
		The first test is to reach Yanov Station to the north. There we will proceed to further tests to see if you're worthy to join our final assault.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_291">
		<text>Of course. I cannot take rookies with me, so there will be a test in order to weed out the weak and unreliable. 
		The first test is to reach Yanov Station to the north. There we will proceed to further tests to see if you're worthy to join our final assault.
		\n\nWhat do you say? You seem to be perfect for the job, I'm sure you'll make the cut.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_30">
		<text>[10.000 roubles] Count me in!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_31">
		<text>I don't know, I need time to think.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_32">
		<text>Excellent, I knew you would not miss such an opportunity! Keep this conversation quiet - I don't want everyone to know my plans. See you in Yanov!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_33">
		<text>I hate to break it to you, but there is no time to think about it. I will leave in the next hours, this is your last opportunity to grab the occasion of your life!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_34">
		<text>Count me in!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_35">
		<text>Then I have to refuse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_36">
		<text>Get lost poor fool, you missed the opportunity of your life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_37">
		<text>Go fuck yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_371">
		<text>Fuck you, Tushkan fodder.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_38">
		<text>Relax, I believe you! I was looking for you for a long time - I want to go to the Wishgranter with you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_39">
		<text>I don't know... are you really Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_40">
		<text>What the fuck? Of course I'm Strelok! The Marked One who disabled not only the Brainscorcher, but also the Kaymanov emitter! Here, do you see this tattoo?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_41">
		<text>A tattoo? What does a tattoo have to do with Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_42">
		<text>I found a stash of yours - can you tell me where you hid it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_43">
		<text>Can you show me your Psi-helmet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_44">
		<text>I'm sorry - of course I believe you. I want to come with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_45">
		<text>Wh-what? You don't know shit about me, and yet you dare to question me? Fuck off fool!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_46">
		<text>What a moronic question, I have stashes all over the Zone - why would I tell you the location of even one of them? Fuck off scammer!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_47">
		<text>Are you trying to mug me for my Psi-helmet? Fuck off thief!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_48">
		<text>Alright, I forgive you. But for your insolence, you pay double!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_49">
		<text>[20.000 roubles] All right, here is the money!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_50">
		<text>I need time to gather the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scamlok_start_dialog_51">
		<text>I changed my mind, I won't join.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_hawaiian_scamlok_0_0">
		<text>Hawaiian, did you see Strelok around?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_scamlok_0_1">
		<text>Strelok? Not since quite some time. Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_scamlok_0_2">
		<text>I was supposed to meet him here. He is putting together a team and the first step of the trial was to join him in this Trainstation. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_scamlok_0_3">
		<text>Is that so? You might want to talk to the guy over there, Osyol, he is also looking for... Strelok... and he told me the same story... Did you also pay "Strelok" 10.000 roubles?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_scamlok_0_4">
		<text>Yes. Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_scamlok_0_5">
		<text>*Sigh* Then I'll tell you the same I told Osyol - I think you have been scammed. I highly doubt that the person who you were talking to was Strelok, as I can't see Strelok hiring strangers and asking them money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_scamlok_0_6">
		<text>Shit! Are you sure?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_scamlok_0_7">
		<text>I've been around here for quite some time, and what you and the other guy are telling me simply doesn't sound like Strelok. On top of that, Strelok is not here so...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_scamlok_0_8">
		<text>But he looked like the description of Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_scamlok_0_9">
		<text>Strelok is quite the legend around here, everyone knows the description. Likely, someone who resembles him decided to impersonate him and scam unsuspecting rookies... Sorry that it happened to you.</text>
	</string>
	

-------- Alyosha ---------

<string id="st_alyosha_making_trouble_1">
		<text>Alyosha Shyogolov: Warning to all Bandits, Delinquents, Miscreants, Freebooters and scum of that sort! Dr. Alyosha Shyogolov is in town - beware! I advise you to cease with your ways or feel my ire!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_alyosha_making_trouble_2">
		<text>Vova the Flea: Who the fuck are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_alyosha_making_trouble_3">
		<text>Alyosha Shyogolov: Dr Alyosha Shyogolov you illiterate gopnik! An elite member of the Ecologists!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_alyosha_making_trouble_4">
		<text>Pasha the Brawler: Did you confuse the shores, Alyosha Khuiyolov?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_alyosha_making_trouble_5">
		<text>Alyosha Shyogolov: What? How dare you, you keyboard warrior! You don't know who you're insulting!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_alyosha_making_trouble_6">
		<text>Vova the Flea: Indeed I never heard of you Yebolov.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_alyosha_making_trouble_7">
		<text>Alyosha Shyogolov: Don't fuck around, or you'll find out how it is to eat worm shit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_alyosha_making_trouble_8">
		<text>Pasha the Brawler: Well come on, answer for your bazar!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_alyosha_making_trouble_9">
		<text>Alyosha Shyogolov: I'm not afraid of you, you scum! Let's meet on the field south of the Station! Bring your friends, I'll teach all of you not to fuck with Dr Alyosha Shygolov! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_alyosha_making_trouble_10">
		<text>Pasha the Brawler: Come on Vova, gather your boys and let's teach this shithead a lesson!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_alyosha_making_trouble_11">
		<text>Vova the Flea: He'll regret the day his father met his mother.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_alyosha_making_trouble_12">
		<text>Pasha the Brawler: Where are you Khuiyolov? We're here!</text>
	</string>

<string id="st_alyosha_making_trouble_13">
		<text>Alyosha Shyogolov: Hey mate, I'm over here! Right behind the wall of this ruin!</text>
	</string>

<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_4_0">
		<text>Alyosha, what the fuck are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_4_1">
		<text>Ah, %s, great that you are here! I knew someone would not stay indifferent to how they were talking to me! Can you believe it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_4_2">
		<text>Alyosha, this is madness! You cannot provoke these gopniks in such a way! We have to leave, now!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_4_3">
		<text>Hmm, you're right, this is madness! This is by far beneath me! These gopniks are not worth my time, I have much more important problmes to solve which are worthy of my rank! 
		\n\nGood that you are here, I'll delegate this bagatelle to you, while I'm putting my talents to better use! Find me at the Station when you finished with these worms!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_4_4">
		<text>Alyosha, wait that's not what I meant! I'm...</text>
	</string>

<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_5_0">
		<text>What the fuck Alyosha?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_5_1">
		<text>Ah, you're back! I see you're still high on that adrenaline! Well, I need you too calm down rapidly, you have to be cool headed to understand the complexity of the situation I'm about to explain you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_5_2">
		<text>Not so fast.</text>
	</string>

<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_0">
		<text>Did you really find the fence?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_1">
		<text>Silence my friend, not here! Meet me at the small guard house near the eastern entry of the Jupiter Factory complex tonight at 22 o'clock! Then I'll explain everything!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_2">
		<text>Why do you sound surprised? Of course I did! I made him come out of his mousehole right into our little trap!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_3">
		<text>What is your plan?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_4">
		<text>The plan is simple but efficient! You're going to meet him under the bridge, and when you verified that he has the goods, you put him under arrest! 
		The signal for me will be "In the name of the law, you're under arrest!". I'll wait in the background, if he tries to run away I'll cut off his path!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_5">
		<text>Why me? I thought I was the backup? It's your plan, you should meet him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_6">
		<text>I gave him your name of course, he is expecting you! If he sees me approaching he will think that there is something fishy and he'll run away. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_7">
		<text>WHAT? Why the FUCK did you do that? Why did you involve my name?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_8">
		<text>My man, isn't it obvious? I couldn't give my name, no one would believe that I - Dr Alyosha Shyogolov would be able to do such a thing! 
		I had to use your name, considering that you're of a more... pragmatic reputation!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_9">
		<text>What if this is a trap and he's going to rob us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_10">
		<text>Bullshit! The guy is a corrupt scientist, most likely some poor clerk, not some gangster. Besides, I will be there, if it is a trap one glimpse of my Nosorog will make them scatter like pigeons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_11">
		<text>Let's assume everything goes according to your plan - what would be next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_12">
		<text>First we proceed to an interrogation - of course only when we catch him alive that is. If he dies during the arrest, things are more complicated... 
			We'll need to search his corpse and hope we'll find something pointing us to any potential associates or loot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_13">
		<text>What if he runs or resists?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_131">
		<text>I don't think he will - I believe he's some clerk who is more afraid of you than you of him. But if he does something, the priority is of course to catch him alive - lethal force is only to be used if no other means are possible. 
		If he runs we have to pursue him - I'll be waiting in an opportune place to cut him off. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_14">
		<text>How did you bait him out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_141">
		<text>That was the product of my devilish plan, although quite simple! I got the word around that you were looking to buy some "surplus" supplies from the Ecologist stock! 
		Discreetly of course, so that it would only find the way to the right ears for such an underhanded endeavour, and it did! Only after a couple of days I got a message on my burner PDA (which I passed as yours) and we set up this meeting! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_15">
		<text>Alright, I'll be the bait. But don't fuck it up, get into a good position to cut him off if he's running.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_16">
		<text>Perfect! Don't be afraid, you know you can count on me! Remember, the signal is "In the name of the law, you're under arrest!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_17">
		<text>Fuck this, I won't play the bait in your stupid plan.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_18">
		<text>I'm afraid this is impossible, not when we have the fence right under our nose! What do you think should I tell in the future when someone is asking why the guy was not caught even though we had him right under our fingers?
		Do you really want me to tell them "Sorry, but %s was too proud to help me catch this asshole"? Can you imagine what people would think of you? \n\nBesides, think of the glory (and the reward) when we catch him! Sakharov will be so happy, you'll be able to ask anything!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_19">
		<text>So you plan to throw me under the bus if I don't help you? You don't leave me any choice asshole. Fine, I'll do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_6_20">
		<text>My man, relax, that's only the tension before a big catch speaking, not you. Don't fret, I'll be right there to intervene when something goes sideways. </text>
	</string>


----- Northern Rush - comms
<string id="nr_corruption_army_0">
		<text>Erast Fandorin: Attention! The Stalker %s is wanted for criminal conspiracy to steal state property! He is to be turned in immediatly! Any Stalker providing safe harbour or any assistance to him will be regarded as co-conspirator. </text>
	</string>
<string id="nr_corruption_army_1">
		<text>Colonel Masahiro Sibata: Attention! The Stalker %s is wanted for criminal conspiracy to steal state property! He is to be turned in immediatly! Any Stalker providing safe harbour or any assistance to him will be regarded as co-conspirator. </text>
	</string>	
<string id="nr_corruption_coward_1">
		<text>Erast Fandorin: He tries to run away! Men, seize him!</text>
	</string>
<string id="nr_corruption_self_1">
		<text>Fuck, I need to run!</text>
	</string>
<string id="nr_corruption_self_2">
		<text>I made it out! But fucking hell, I'm in deep shit!</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_corruption_self_3">
		<text>Fuck my life, I cannot go back to the Ecologists without proving my innocence!</text>
	</string>	
<string id="nr_corruption_self_4">
		<text>I need to find a way to exonerate myself!</text>
	</string>
<string id="nr_corruption_self_5">
		<text>Maybe there is someone who knows more about this shit than fucking Alyosha. I should look for help.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_corruption_self_6">
		<text>FUUUUUUUCK!!!!</text>
	</string>		
----- Northern Rush - Corruption - other dialogue	

---Spirit	
<string id="nr_spirit_corruption_0">
		<text>There is alot of talk about corruption among the Ecologists...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="nr_spirit_corruption_1">
		<text>And why are you talking to me about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_spirit_corruption_2">
		<text>Well, I know about your inclination to trade stuff you don't own.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="nr_spirit_corruption_3">
		<text>What is that supposed to mean? Do you suspect me? Do I need to remind you that it's the Lab in Yanov being problematic, and I'm sitting here talking with you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_spirit_corruption_4">
		<text>How convenient for you... But only the muscle needs to be in Yanov, not the brain...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="nr_spirit_corruption_5">
		<text>Fuck you.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="nr_spirit_corruption_6">
		<text> No, but you know the saying: "It takes a thief to catch a thief". I'd like some informations. 
		Apparently the situation got really worse in Yanov after the reinforcment. Do you know anyone suspicious who got transferred around the time following the desactivation of the Brainscorcher?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="nr_spirit_corruption_7">
		<text>Hmm, yeah... there was that one guy, Erast I believe he's called. He was a new comer, always asking if we knew a way to make some fast money. 
		Shortly after he arrived they send him north - maybe that's the guy you're looking for?</text>
	</string>	
---Rydzik
<string id="nr_ecologist_rydzyk_0_0">
		<text>What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_ecologist_rydzyk_0_1">
		<text>Working. I'm organizing supply for the Yanov Station - our boys are cut off and we need to help them out somehow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_ecologist_rydzyk_0_2">
		<text>They are cut off? Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_ecologist_rydzyk_0_3">
		<text>Are you new around here? The Brain Scorcher is active again and will fry any brain that tries to cross the Red Forest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_ecologist_rydzyk_0_4">
		<text>How are you resupplying them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_ecologist_rydzyk_0_5">
		<text>That's the tough part. In the past helicopters were an easy option if we were careful enough to scan the anomalies beforehand.
		Now it's either the Red Forest or the Mercenaries route. For the Red Forest we have to give expensive equipment to our guys and he path has become very dangerous these past few weeks.
		Another option are the Mercenaries by bringing it through their routes, but they ask an enormous amount of money. 
		All of this is a huge drain on our resources... some more budget cuts will be needed, or else we won't be able to send anything up north anymore...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_ecologist_rydzyk_0_6">
		<text>Why are you not evacuating your northern bunker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_ecologist_rydzyk_0_7">
		<text>And abandon everything we build up this far? No, the situation is bad but not desperate.</text>
	</string>

--- Ecologist 1

<string id="nr_ecologist_1_0_0">
		<text>What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_ecologist_1_0_1">
		<text>Waiting for the Brain Scorcher to be turned off I suppose. 
		Me and my friend have been hired to replace some guys in the Yanov Bunker, but as we arrived to the Zone, these guys from Monolith managed to take back their Radar outpost and turned their infernal machine back on.
		A shame too, they promised us a good payroll to work that deep in the Zone, but as we are stuck here they barely give us anything. 
		It's not our fault that we have to sit on our asses, waiting for the Machine to go down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_ecologist_1_0_2">
		<text>They don't have any jobs for you here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_ecologist_1_0_3">
		<text>We are not the only ones waiting for the way to be free again, there is a surplus of manpower sitting around here at the moment.
		Besides, I'm neither a scientist nor a fighter, I'm a maintenance guy. Not much I can really do here.</text>
	</string>

--- Ecologist 2

<string id="nr_ecologist_2_0_0">
		<text>What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_ecologist_2_0_1">
		<text>Drinking and waiting for the sunset I guess? I have been hired to go up north, promised me a shitton of money too for going that far.
		Now we can't go, the Brainfryer is in the way, and I don't get the northern premium. Even worse, they are cutting our wages! Some fucking budget cuts apparently in order to supply our boys up north, but I'm also a living person! 
		I also need some money to survive. Well at least I can sit on my ass and enjoy my drink - sure is better than being cut off from the rest of the world.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_ecologist_2_0_2">
		<text>They don't have any jobs for you here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_ecologist_2_0_3">
		<text>I wish, that would allow me to earn more! But no, not much to do for someone of my experience. And I am sure as hell not going out there to dig around in mud risking my life!
		I signed up for an indoor job.</text>
	</string>	
--------- Strange Meat --------


<string id="st_nr_execution_warn_0">
		<text>Guys, they are executin Akhat!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nr_execution_warn_1">
		<text>In front of the door, quick!</text>
	</string>

<string id="st_nr_execution_0">
		<text>Barka: Akhat, you are sentenced to death for your crimes. Any last words?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nr_execution_1">
		<text>Akhat: And who are the judges? You? No one here is innocent!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nr_execution_2">
		<text>Akhat: What happened to Jester's cans Mizinets? Did you get a cut for distracting him Tacker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nr_execution_3">
		<text>Barka: Enough!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nr_execution_4">
		<text>Akhat: And you, how did you survive Barka? What happened to Yak?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nr_execution_5">
		<text>Akhat: Eaten by dogs? Or eaten by...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nr_execution_6">
		<text>Barka: I said enough! Go meet your maker Akhat, you will not be missed.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_barka_0_0">
		<text>What is going on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_barka_0_1">
		<text>Stay out of this Stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_barka_0_2">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_barka_1_0">
		<text>Why did you shoot him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_barka_1_1">
		<text>He murdered a Stalker in cold blood in order to steal his food. We cannot tolerate thiefs and murderers among our community, especially not in times like these.</text>
	</string>



<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_0">
		<text>How was the situation here, cut off from the rest of the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_1">
		<text>You mean the Siege? Honestly, quite bad. Monolith reactivating the Brainscorcher took us by surprise and we weren't sufficiently prepared such that we were lacking in everything. 
		Mostly we got our food from Trapper and his men - weapons and supplies we either had to scavenge or craft ourselves with our limited capabilities. 
		But even that became very difficult after some time: the wildlife made the territory very difficult to operate in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_2">
		<text>What about resupply from the south?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_3">
		<text>Occasionally a Stalker who had a psy protection helmet made it through and brought us some stuff... But these became rarer and rarer. Mostly because the routes became more dangerous as less Stalkers walk them... 
		that and the precarious situation here makes people more dangerous... murders and theft were rampant, and if someone with a helmet made it here, well... he became a prime target for a Stalker who wished to leave. 
		Well that and the Monolith and mutants which made the path through the Red Forest very difficult to cross. 
		\n \nLuckily all that is over now... well for the most part.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_4">
		<text>What about the Ecologists?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_5">
		<text>The Ecologists? Well they were well provisioned and in the beginning they were inclined to help us. But when it became clear that the Siege would not last weeks but months, there was an incident...
Some Stalkers marched down to the Mobile Lab with guns and demanded that the Ecologists turn over their Psy Protection Helmets. The situation got out of hands and the Ecologists gunned most of them down.
Since then they shut down acces to the Mobile Lab, and reopened it only after the Brainscorcher was turned off...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_6">
		<text>What about the Bandits?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_7">
		<text>I don't know much about their situation, but I do believe they had it worse than us. You know, bandits tend to live day by day. 
			Nevertheless, banditry became rampant! It became very dangerous to wander to far south, as they would murder anyone on sight.
			They still hold the Southern Checkpoint and make supply from the south difficult...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_8">
		<text>If the situation was bad for the bandits, how come they are still so numerous?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_9">
		<text>Many Stalkers here turned to the bandit lifestyle during the Siege...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_10">
		<text>Why do you not dislodge the bandits from the Southern Checkpoint?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_11">
		<text>You have to ask Ashot, he is managing security here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_12">
		<text>What about the Mercenaries?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_13">
		<text>The Mercenaries were quiet during the Siege, they likely had as much trouble resupplying as everyone else here. They also had a deal with the Skadvosk - the Skadvosk supplied them with food and they supplied the Skadovsk with weaponry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_14">
		<text>What about the Skadovsk?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_15">
		<text>The Skadovsk was much more lucky than we were. They got resupplied shortly before the Brainscorcher went up again and apparently they found some Monolith supply stashes. 
		They mostly used their supplies to trade with the Mercenaries who were sitting on too much weaponry and too little food.
		But this does not mean that they had an easy time - quite on the contrary, the constant attacks by Monolith were very hard on them. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_16">
		<text>Couldn't the Skadvosk have helped you during the Siege?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_17">
		<text>They could yes, they could... listen, I don't want to blame them, they also had to make choices - the situation was difficult for everyone. 
		And they also had to fight of the Monolith - thanks to the Skadovsk we didn't have that problem too. 
		But yes, they introduced a strict rationing policy and forbade trading with us, which I think was uncalled for. Luckily some Stalkers from there broke the policy and sold us some food - for an exorbitant price sure - but food was food.
		I understand them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_18">
		<text>Let's change the topic.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_0_19">
		<text>I agree.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_hawaiian_1_0">
		<text>I just saw Stalkers execute a man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_1_1">
		<text>Ah yes... Akhat... sad story. Before this disaster he was quite a nice guy - always ready to share what he had. But then the hunger got to him and he lost his nerves - strangled a Stalker for his food.
			Fucking shit, the day before the Brainscorcher was turned off, can you imagine? Had he only endured a bit longer... As soon as we found out he had to be executed, there is no way around it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_1_2">
		<text>In his last words he accused the others of being no better than him. Something about Barka and someone called Yak?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_1_3">
		<text>Eh... you see, the athmosphere here was that of general mistrust and suspicion, so don't take everything at face value. The whispers went as this: \n \nBarka and Yak went out one day to do some scavenging, but only Barka returned... he told that they got seperated, and to his defence, there indead was a suuden blowout here.
			Nevertheless, people started to tell stories... how Barka seemed to have food he wasn't telling about, how Barka seemed to have been lucky during this expedition with Yak, how Barka this and that. To be clear - I also believe that Barka found something which he didn't want to share, but he certianly was not the only one. 
			I mean, hell, he even sold me some of food, so obviously he was lucky! But yeah, because he went out with Yak and returned without him, people started to tell some stories... some worse than others you know... But I don't belive that he killed Yak, for whatever reason. That is pure paranoia, paranoia we will take some time to forget.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_1_4">
		<text>Have there been other executions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_1_5">
		<text>Yes... For a long time we did not have to resort to such measures. But as the situation dragged out and hope made place to desperation unrest grew too.
		At some point a rumour spread according to which I was hiding food in my reserves "for the bosses". There was a mutiny which got out of hands, and they stormed my reserves... only to see that the situation was much more dire than they thought. 
		\n \nOf course we couldn't let such a mutiny stand and we shot the leaders. But the damage was done, the men knew how little food really was left and murders and theft became rampant, so there were more executions... and false accusations!
		Stalkers started to spread false accusations and rumours about other Stalkers in order to frame them or even worse, in order to have less competition for food... fewer mouths to feed you know...
		\n \nHorrible, horrible times. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_1_6">
		<text>Let's change the topic...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_1_7">
		<text>I absolutely agree!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_1_8">
		<text>Do you want me to investigate Yak's disappearance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_1_9">
		<text>To be honest, no. We lived through too much of this already, it's time to forget, forgive and move on. I think everyone here had to do some stuff he regrets in order to survive... some obviously worse than others, but it will do no good to dig in old wounds. 
		Besides, I think Barka had nothing to do with Yak's disappearance, he had only the bad luck to have left the base with him... now his name will forever be associated with that of Yak's...</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_0">
		<text>I found Yak's body.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_1">
		<text>For real? And?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_2">
		<text>His flesh has been torn away... not much is left... I found him in a snork den.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_3">
		<text>So Barka's story holds true?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_4">
		<text>Impossible to say - he could have left the body to mutants after butchering him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_5">
		<text>True true... but that is speculation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_51">
		<text>Well, the body was inside the snork pit in Zaton... That's a strange place to wind up...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_52">
		<text>So either he fell inside the pit... was pushed into it... was thrown into it after he died... damn, there are so many scenarios I can think of! Although most need a "helping hand"... are you trying to tell me that... it was Barka?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_6">
		<text>There is something else - Yak was shot. I found this bullet inside him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_7">
		<text>WHAT??? So he was murdered? By Barka??? And he left the body to the mutants in order to make it look an accident?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_8">
		<text>That seems to be a plausible theory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_9">
		<text>It's a theory, but I prefer to continue my investigation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_10">
		<text>Then it's settled! I'll have Barka arrested and shot for murder! *no need to mention the other stuff to the guys...* \n \nWe will settle your reward after the dirty stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_11">
		<text>Alright, I'll keep an eye on Barka in the meantime!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_12">
		<text>Yes, we caught our Hannibal!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_13">
		<text>No, not yet! I prefer to continue my investigation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_14">
		<text>Not neccesarily. I talked to Nitro, and he was able to identify the bullet as a 7.62x51. Furthermore, he knows the weapons used by Stalkers here and he claims that Barka does not have such a gun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_15">
		<text>Damn, excellent work Stalker! So... what could have happened? Yak got seperated from Barka and was murdered afterwards by someone... by our... guy? Impossible to know, although it would be too much of a coincidence...
			At least we know that Barka is innocent!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_barka_0_16">
		<text>Perfect! Well done Stalker, well done! Let's shoot the bastard!</text>
	</string>

<string id="st_strange_meat_taste_1">
		<text>This... tasted very strange...</text>
	</string>
<string id="st_strange_meat_taste_2">
		<text>This definitely tasted very strange... I should not eat more of it.</text>
	</string>


<string id="hawaiian_strange_meat_0_0">
		<text>[Unusual Meat] What is with this meat? From which animal is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_strange_meat_0_1">
		<text>I don't know and I don't care. Probably it's best not to know. Can't expect gourmet food now, can you?</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_0_0">
		<text>[Unusual Meat] Is it possible to run some tests? I'd like to find out what kind of meat this is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_0_1">
		<text>That is quite a strange request, most of the time people don't want to know what they eat around here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_0_2">
		<text>I have a suspicion, but I want to be sure. Can you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_0_3">
		<text>Well yes I can, but you know... not for free! Let's say, 10.000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_0_4">
		<text>10.000 roubles?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_0_5">
		<text>That's not an unreasonable amount Stalker, I will need to use my material and equipment. Do you want tax money to pay for it? Hahaha, besides, you also have to pay me - I don't work for free either you know. Now what do you say?  </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_0_6">
		<text>[10.000 roubles] Alright, alright... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_0_7">
		<text>I need to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_0_8">
		<text>Good! You can come back tomorrow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_0_9">
		<text>No problem, come back if you changed your mind! Bon appetit in the meanwhile hahaha.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_1_0">
		<text>Did you run your tests?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_1_1">
		<text>Stalker, where the fuck did you get that meat from?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_1_2">
		<text>Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_1_3">
		<text>It's not every day that someone brings human fucking meat here! It's even packaged like food!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_1_4">
		<text>Human? What the fuck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_1_5">
		<text>That's exactly what I am saying! So where did you get it from?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_1_6">
		<text>Some random Stalker sold it to me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_1_7">
		<text>Hawaiian sold it to me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_1_8">
		<text>You have to find that man and get some explanations!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_scientist_strange_meat_1_9">
		<text>Hawaiian? Hawaiian is selling human meat now? Well, thanks, now I know from whom not to buy anymore...</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="hawaiian_strange_meat_1_0">
		<text>I talked to Hermann! Your meat is human meat!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_strange_meat_1_1">
		<text>What? You're fucking kidding right? You're pulling my leg?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_strange_meat_1_2">
		<text>Absolutely not. You can ask Hermann to confirm.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_strange_meat_1_3">
		<text>No, no, I'm believing you... Fuck! How is this possible? \n \nNo word to anyone about this Stalker, we... we need to keep this quiet. If anyone would know that I was selling human meat! Fuck! \n\nPeople would believ I did this on purpose! 
		You... You belive me right? I didn't know, you understand that, right? I would never sell something like that!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_strange_meat_1_4">
		<text>Relax Hawaiian, I believe you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_strange_meat_1_5">
		<text>I don't know Hawaiian, maybe you could convince me by showing your good will *open hands*.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_strange_meat_1_6">
		<text>I don't know Hawaiian, this seems very strange to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_strange_meat_1_7">
		<text>I knew you would! Listen Stalker, we need to find out who is behind this! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_strange_meat_1_8">
		<text>I understand... I can provide you some</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hawaiian_strange_meat_1_9">
		<text>I... but... </text>
	</string>


<string id="nr_hawaiian_lyoshik_0_0">
		<text>The paper around the unusal meat has been written on. Most is unreadable, but there are different words you still can make out, see?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_lyoshik_0_1">
		<text>Indeed! And this Lyoshik fellow is mentionned on it! Do you think he is our guy?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_lyoshik_0_2">
		<text>Nitro also mentionned that Lyoshik had a Galil... the same caliber Yak was shot with...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_lyoshik_0_3">
		<text>That seem to be too many coincidences! I think we have our guy!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_lyoshik_0_4">
		<text>Patience! It would be good to find him and ask him why his name appears here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_hawaiian_lyoshik_0_5">
		<text>That will be difficult, he left as soon as the Brainscorcher went down... maybe Loki knows where he went to, considering he's with Freedom and all.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_ashot_lyoshik_0_0">
		<text>Do you know where I can find Lyoshik?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_ashot_lyoshik_0_1">
		<text>Lyoshik? He's not here anymore. He asked to be transfered back to the mainbase as soon as the Brainscorcher went down. Initially I refused, considering we are undermanned here,  but I got the impression nothing would keep him here after all this... 
		I saw the glint of desertion in his eyes, so I preferred to agree to his wish.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_lukash_lyoshik_0_0">
		<text>I'm looking for someone... Do you know where I can find Lyoshik?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_lukash_lyoshik_0_1">
		<text>Lyoshik? He should be in Jupiter, why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_lukash_lyoshik_0_2">
		<text>In Jupiter? No, Loki allowed him to transfer here after that the Brainscorcher turned off?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_lukash_lyoshik_0_3">
		<text>What? He never reported to me? Are you sure?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_lukash_lyoshik_0_4">
		<text>That's what Loki told me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_lukash_lyoshik_0_5">
		<text>What? Let me check with him... \n \n... \n \nShit, it's true! Well, maybe he got killed on his way here? \n \nAh wait... Loki tells me he suspects him to have deserted if he's not dead... Fuck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_lukash_lyoshik_0_6">
		<text>So death or desertion?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_lukash_lyoshik_0_7">
		<text>Death or desertion... Listen Stalker, if you can find out more about his fate, I would appreciate it... especially if he turns out to be alive...</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_snitch_lyoshik_0_0">
		<text>I'm looking for a potential Freedom deserter by the name of Lyoshik. After I turned off the Brainscorcher, he should transfer from Jupiter, but he never went back to his designated post.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_snitch_lyoshik_0_1">
		<text>You're in luck... I might have the information you seek... for a price of course. Let's say, 8.000 roubles?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_snitch_lyoshik_0_2">
		<text>8 fucking thousand???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_snitch_lyoshik_0_3">
		<text>[8.000 roubles] Information ain't cheap nowadays... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_snitch_lyoshik_0_4">
		<text>My friend, when you are in my business, you have a lot of expenses. So, for the information you seek, it's 8.000. But if you don't want to, you can of course look for the information yourself...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_snitch_lyoshik_0_5">
		<text>I will think about it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_snitch_lyoshik_0_6">
		<text>The guy you mention showed up here a couple of days ago. He still was in his Freedom uniform, so he was questioned by Duty. 
		They let him go, as he made clear that he had enough from this place, and tried to escape. He went south to Cordon, and he plans to escape from this place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_snitch_lyoshik_0_7">
		<text>As you wish. You know where to find me.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_barkeep_lyoshik_0_0">
		<text>I'm looking for a potential Freedom deserter by the name of Lyoshik. After I turned off the Brainscorcher, he should transfer from Jupiter, but he never went back to his designated post.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_barkeep_lyoshik_0_1">
		<text>That's much to vague my friend, people like that show up a lot. I cannot help you. Although, if he was a Freedom guy, it seems strange that the Duty guys would let him in freely? Maybe he never came here?</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_duty_lyoshik_0_0">
		<text>I'm looking for a potential Freedom deserter by the name of Lyoshik. After I turned off the Brainscorcher, he should transfer from Jupiter, but he never went back to his designated post.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_duty_lyoshik_0_1">
		<text>Yes, we interrogated him a couple of days ago. The guy was totally fucked up from his time in Jupiter, and his only wish was to leave the Zone, so we let him go. He went south, probably to Cordon.</text>
	</string>

--- Rookie Village and Lyoshik

<string id="nr_fanat_lyoshik_0_0">
		<text>I'm looking for a Freedom deserter. Goes by the name of Lyoshik.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_fanat_lyoshik_0_1">
		<text>Yes, he arrived here not long ago. What is it you want from him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_fanat_lyoshik_0_2">
		<text>He's suspected in the murder of at least one Stalker in Jupiter, maybe more and maybe even worse. I came to interrogate him and arrest him if my suspicions turn out true.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_fanat_lyoshik_0_3">
		<text>That are... serious accusations. You can find him in the building over there. I will keep an eye on him if you want to? Prevent him from escaping and such.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_fanat_lyoshik_0_4">
		<text>Thanks, that would be appreciated.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_lyoshik_start_0">
		<text>What is it Stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_lyoshik_start_1">
		<text>Lyoshik? I have some questions for you about your time in Jupiter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_lyoshik_start_2">
		<text>... I'm not interested in talking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_lyoshik_start_3">
		<text>I'm afraid that is not a choice. I found Yak's body </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_lyoshik_start_4">
		<text>... I'm not interested in talking.</text>
	</string>



-- Nitro
<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_0">
		<text>[Yak's bullet] Can you identify this bullet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_1">
		<text>For 5.000 roubles I can.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_2">
		<text>[5.000 roubles] What can you tell me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_3">
		<text>Maybe later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_4">
		<text>Luckily it didn't get too deformed. It's a 7.62x51 ball, not very common. Mostly used for some snipers or assault rifles, like the Galil, FAL or SCAR.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_5">
		<text>As you wish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_6">
		<text>Interesting. Do you know if Barka has such a gun?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_7">
		<text>Barka? No, Barka trusts in soviet weaponry. Are you looking for the user?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_8">
		<text>Maybe I am. Is there someone around here who uses such weapons? Or maybe a faction which could use it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_9">
		<text>No... most of the guys around here are my customers and no one uses it now, and the few who did changed to more common calibers because the ammo was unfindable. 
		As for factions, Freedom has some of these rifles, although not around here. I think the Mercenaries have it sometimes too? Monolith - maybe, I don't know their arsenal very well. Bandits? Could have looted it from a victim.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_10">
		<text>Do you remember anyone using such a caliber in the last month?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_11">
		<text>Damn, you really want to find that guy! My memory is a bit weak at the moment, why don't you come back later when it recovers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_12">
		<text>[5.000 roubles] Maybe this will help your memory?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_13">
		<text>It certainly does, although I'm not sure it will help you. The caliber was never very popular, most weapons using it have equivalents with more abundant ammo. Nevertheless, there were few people using it, let me think...
		\n \nYes, there was that one Stalker, one of Trapper's hunters - Fasan was his name. Left one day to hunt or scavenge and never came back - his GA3 probably ran out of ammo. Then there was that one guy, a Freedom fellow - Lyoshik. 
		Swore by his Galil, but after an expediation I never saw him with it again. Finally there was that guy from the Skadovsk, a trader - didn't tell us his name. He was very proud about his SCAR - bragged all the time about how good a deal he made with the Mercenaries. One day he came back without it and didn't want to tell what happened to his prized possession.
		Didn't brag around either - someone must have fucked him up.\n \nThat's all of them I think. Are you satisfied?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_14">
		<text>Where did Fasan go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_15">
		<text>Shit, what do I know? Ask Trapper, he worked with him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_16">
		<text>Where can I find Lyoshik?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_17">
		<text>Lyoshik left as soon as the Brainscorcher went down. Where to? I don't know. Ask Loki, he should know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_18">
		<text>Where can I find this trader?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_19">
		<text>What do I know? The Skadovsk? Ask Hawaiian, he always dealt with him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_20">
		<text>I'll be back when you recovered your wits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_21">
		<text>Depends on the weight of your pockets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_22">
		<text>That would be all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_nitro_barka_0_23">
		<text>Jeez, you certainly got your moneys worth. Well good luck finding your person, hope he is worth your trouble.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_nitro_barka_1_1">
		<text>[5.000 roubles] Does this help you remember your customers?</text>
	</string>

--- Strange Meat Stalker	
	
	
--- Trapper
<string id="trapper_intro_0_0">
		<text>How was it being cut off from the South?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_intro_0_1">
		<text>Quite hard... The Zone never was a hospitable place, and these months showed us how precarious our situation here really is. 
		I lost good Stalkers to the Zone - preventable deaths I do believe. But the lack of food, supplies and men made us took risks which we wouldn't have taken otherwise...
		And with each day we were cut off, the Zone grew more hostile and we grew weaker... mutants populated areas again which formerly were firmly in our hands, and it became increasingly harder to compete, such that in the end, we had to avoid these areas entierly.
		Nevertheless, many of my men showed bravery and faced the dangers in order to bring back some food for their fellow men, knowing that they might not return. 
		It brings me great sorrow that I cannot find some the bodies of my missing hunters and give them the burrial they deserve.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_intro_0_2">
		<text>What kind of competition are you talking about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_intro_0_3">
		<text>Chimeras! Yes, the devils spawn... We are troubled by three of them... One of them is lurking around in the northern parts, although we don't know where exactly that one has it's lair... very slippery bastard. 
		\nAnother one took up residence in the Volkhov complex to the south west, but I have special plans for her, so don't kill that one!
		\nAnd the third, well the third is the Devil himself. Killed my friend Fox... \nWe need to get rid of them, one at the time, but they are though beasts which require a lot of preparation and we have other pressing matters on our hands.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_intro_0_4">
		<text>Why can you not find some bodies?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_intro_0_5">
		<text>Mainly because we have other priorities now - we need to rebuild our lifes here, and for that I need every man I have. You see, the problem with my missing men is twofold: 
			\nWe don't know eactly where they are and something killed them which was neither a dog nor a boar. 
			They were experiences hunters and they would not have succumbed easily. So in order to find them we would need to form large search parties, and I simply lack the men for that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_intro_0_6">
		<text>I have another question.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_intro_0_7">
		<text>Sure, what do you want to know?</text>
	</string>

--- Missing Men
	
<string id="trapper_missing_men_0_0">
		<text>I can help you find your missing men.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_0_1">
		<text>Such help would be hugely appreciated! I only need to know their location, my men can bring back the corpses later. I have three missing men: Seryoga Lesun, Fasan Bedovy and Andrey Lopast.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_0_2">
		<text>Where did Seryoga Lesun leave for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_0_3">
		<text>Seryoga left for the Cement Factory three weeks ago and never came back. Some of my men went looking after him when he failed to return in three days, but were not able to find him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_0_4">
		<text>Where did Fasan Bedovy leave for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_0_5">
		<text>Fasan was very bold and went to the east, intending to explore some of the tunnels in the hope to find some supplies. We tried to dissuade him but he always was very stubborn. 
		Sadly he never returned, and none of my men dared to go after him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_0_6">
		<text>Where did Andrey Lopast leave for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_0_7">
		<text>Andrey went to the west and wanted to scavenge around Kopachy. He too never returned, and my men failed to find his corpse...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_0_8">
		<text>I will look out for them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_0_9">
		<text>My sincere thanks Stalker, this means alot for me! I will talk to my men, we should be able to gather some money in order to reward you for your troubbles! But be careful, these men died by something which still might be there!</text>
	</string>

<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_0">
		<text>About your missing men.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_1">
		<text>Yes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_2">
		<text>Where did Seryoga Lesun leave for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_3">
		<text>Seryoga left for the Cement Factory three weeks ago and never came back. Some of my men went looking after him when he failed to return in three days, but were not able to find him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_4">
		<text>Where did Fasan Bedovy leave for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_5">
		<text>Fasan was very bold and went to the east, intending to explore some of the tunnels in the hope to find some supplies. We tried to dissuade him but he always was very stubborn. 
		Sadly he never returned, and none of my men dared to go after him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_6">
		<text>Where did Andrey Lopast leave for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_7">
		<text>Andrey went to the west and wanted to scavenge around Kopachy. He too never returned, and my men failed to find his corpse...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_8">
		<text>I found Seryoga Lesun. He died in the canalization under the Cement Factory by the hand of Bloodsuckers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_9">
		<text>Damn what a place to find your death... thanks Stalker! We will make sure that he will lie in an appropriate place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_10">
		<text>I found Fasan Bedovy. He died in the Train Deposit near the Eastern Tunnels. He had no chance - there was a Pseudogiant and Burers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_11">
		<text>Fasan was a great hunter and he faced impossible odds. If Valhalla exists, he earned his place amongst the warriors... My respect that you managed to kill these mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_12">
		<text>I found Andrey Lopast. He lies in one of the other house ruins. A controller and some snorks got him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_13">
		<text>Poor Andrey... one can only imagine the pain he went through for us... My thanks Stalker, we will take care of his body.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_14">
		<text>I believe that I found all your men.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_15">
		<text>You did, and for that we are grateful! Let's drink a toast to my men! They died doing what was right, and we should honor them for that!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_16">
		<text>To Seryoga!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_17">
		<text>May his bones rest in peace.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_18">
		<text>To Fasan!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_19">
		<text>May he drink in Valhalla!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_20">
		<text>To Andrey!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_21">
		<text>May he find peace where the mortal world failed him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_22">
		<text>Now we have to turn to the world of the living.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_missing_men_1_23">
		<text>I agree.</text>
	</string>
--- Chimeras

<string id="trapper_chimera_0_0">
		<text>I want to help you with your Chimera problems.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_0_1">
		<text>Glad to hear it. So the first step is rather a simple one: we need to assemble the bait.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_0_2">
		<text>The bait?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_0_3">
		<text>Yes, the bait! You see, during our time on our own we adapted our hunting strategies. Instead of hunting the predator, we attract them to a place of our choosings - a trap!
The bait itself is rather simple: we fill a backpack with some boar meat and attach a sound device with a recording of boar grunting. 
A Chimera in the vicinity will catch the smell and sound. The Chimera of course will approach the bait - and will stumble into your trap.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_0_4">
		<text>What do you need for the bait?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_0_5">
		<text>From you I will need boar meat - lots of it! I will take care of the backpack and the electronics and I'll fashion the bait out of it.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_0_6">
		<text>Alright, I will gather the meat.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_0_7">
		<text>Perfect. Come see me when you're ready.</text>
	</string>


<string id="trapper_chimera_1_0">
		<text>[Boar Meat] I gathered the meat.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_1_1">
		<text>Nice! Give me a minute. \n \n... \n \nThere, it's done! You will see, it's rather easy to use. 
Simply drop it to the ground and it will do all the work for you! Maybe a word of caution, if you still didn't know it - Chimeras are rapid bastards! 
After setting up the bait you don't have a lot of time to set up, so I would advise you to placing it after having done all your preparations!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_1_2">
		<text>Understood. So where can I find this Chimera?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_1_3">
		<text>Your target has chosen the northern parts as it's hunting grounds, close to the Cooling tower! I already know the perfect spot to set up the trap, so listen carefully!
\n \nOn the northern side of the cooling tower is a small area enclosed by a fence. There is a gate opening to the north - place the bait inside this area in front of the gate!
You will be able to take position on either side of the complex - there are stairs leading up to higher positions! \n \nUnderstood?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_1_4">
		<text>Understood.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_1_5">
		<text>Alright. Remember, Chimeras are nocturnal predators, so prepare yourself for a night hunt. And try to bring back the bait, we can use it later... \n \nGood hunt Stalker!</text>
	</string>

<string id="trapper_chimera_2_0">
		<text>Can you remind me of the spot for the bait?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_2_1">
		<text>Of course. On the northern side of the cooling tower is a small area enclosed by a fence. There is a gate opening to the north - place the bait inside this area in front of the gate!
You will be able to take position on either side of the complex - there are stairs leading up to higher positions!</text>
	</string>

<string id="trapper_chimera_3_0">
		<text>Your hunting competitor is dead!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_1">
		<text>Good job Stalker, good job! Let's have a drink in order to celebrate this! \n \nAnd of course the bounty on the Chimera!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_2">
		<text>So what about the other Chimera?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_3">
		<text>That will be more tricky, but before we begin - were you able to recover the bait?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_4">
		<text>Yes.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_5">
		<text>Excellent. Hold onto it until the mission. I will explain to you the plan in detail before the mission, but the essence is this:
\n \nI asked you to spare the Chimera because I needed something from her in order to hunt down Chyort - and I need you to spare her a bit longer. Chyort, as you may have understood, is a skirt chaser. 
Your job will not be to kill the Chimera, at least not for now, but to plant a recording device in her lair in order to record her... well her mating calls. And that's where the bait comes into play. 
You will setup the bait outside of her lair, and while she is out, you sneak inside and plant the recording device. We wait a day, and then you can kill her and recover the device.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_6">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_7">
		<text>Then I'm afraid you will have to gather some boar meat again before proceeding to the next step. But the essence of your mission will be this:
\n \nI asked you to spare the Chimera because I needed something from her in order to hunt down Chyort - and I need you to spare her a bit longer. Chyort, as you may have understood, is a skirt chaser. 
Your job will not be to kill the Chimera, at least not for now, but to plant a recording device in her lair in order to record her... well her mating calls. And that's where the bait comes into play. 
You will setup the bait outside of her lair, and while she is out, you sneak inside and plant the recording device. We wait a day, and then you can kill her and recover the device.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_8">
		<text>... This is madness.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_9">
		<text>That sounds risky, but it might work.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_10">
		<text>Why cannot we use the bait for Chyort instead of... this plan?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_11">
		<text>Madness, I understand why you think that, but it's our only plan in order to attract Chyort! If you don't want to do it I understand completely.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_12">
		<text>No, I'll do it.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_13">
		<text>Excellent! Make your preparations and most important - don't kill the Chimera in the Volkhov Complex!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_14">
		<text>I'm not comfortable with the plan...</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_15">
		<text>No problem! If you change your opinion, you know where to find me.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_16">
		<text>Of course it will work! Make your preparations and most important - don't kill the Chimera in the Volkhov Complex!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_17">
		<text>Ah that old devil is much to shrewd to walk into our bait! Believe me, only the prospect of humping will make him drop any caution!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_chimera_3_18">
		<text>I'll take my leave and prepare.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_3_19">
		<text>You do that! I'll see you when you're ready. And don't forget the bait!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_chimera_3_20">
		<text>Ehm, I might already have killed that Chimera...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_chimera_3_21">
		<text>Damn! Well that only delays our plan but doesn't alter it. I'll have my spies watch that place, at some point a new Chimera will choose it as it's lair. 
		Come see me in a couple of days - maybe there will be a new resident. In the meantime you can prepare for the task.</text>
	</string>

<string id="trapper_chimera_4_0">
		<text>Can you fashion me a new bait?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_4_1">
		<text>Of course, do you have the meat?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_4_2">
		<text>[Boar meat] Sure.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_4_3">
		<text>Excellent! I will prepare the bait! \n \n... \n \nThere, it's done!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_4_4">
		<text>Not yet.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_4_5">
		<text>Then come back when you have it.</text>
	</string>

<string id="trapper_chimera_5_0">
		<text>[Trapper's bait] I'm ready for the mission.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_1">
		<text>Alright my friend! So listen carefully to the plan! \n \nThe lair of the Chimera female is inside the Volhov complex to the south west of here. My scouts report that her precise "sleeping chamber" is in the room to the right of the garage! That's where you need to drop the recording device!
The recording device works like the bait, you only need to drop it on the ground. Now the neat part is that on the left side of the garage are stairs which lead outside with and exit to the left of the barracks! That's your way in!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_2">
		<text>Noted. Where should I set up the bait?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_3">
		<text>We believe that the optimal spot to place the bait is the eastern entry to the Complex, next to the checkpoint! It is on the opposite site of the stairs and should give you precious seconds in order to place the recording device. 
You will have a bit of time before the Chimera catches the sent of the bait, and a bit more for her to eat it. Nevertheless, you have to be fast - very fast.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_4">
		<text>Alright. Anything else?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_5">
		<text>Yes. The Volkhov complex is also a hotspot for Zombies and other mutants. It would be in your best interest to clean the complex before baiting the Chimera - obviously silently in order not to attract the Chimera before it's needed.
I would advise a long range rifle with silencer. On the other hand, you also need to be swift on your feets, so don't pack what you don't need. Any questions?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_6">
		<text>Where is the lair again?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_7">
		<text>The lair of the Chimera female is inside the Volhov complex to the south east of here. My scouts report that her precise "sleeping chamber" is in the room to the right of the garage! That's where you need to drop the recording device!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_8">
		<text>Where is my entrance again?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_9">
		<text>To the left of the barracks are stairs which lead to the garage.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_10">
		<text>Where should I place the bait again?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_11">
		<text>The optimal spot to place the bait is the eastern entry to the Complex, next to the checkpoint!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_12">
		<text>Alright. I'm ready to leave!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_13">
		<text>Excellent! Here is the recording device! Now remember, the bait will only work at night as Chimeras are nocturnal creatures! And above everything else - don't kill the Chimera!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_14">
		<text>I need some more time.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_15">
		<text>No problem! Come find me when you're ready!</text>
	</string>

<string id="trapper_chimera_5_0_alt">
		<text>[Trapper's bait] I'm ready for the mission.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_5_1_alt">
		<text>Good, but we still need to wait for a new Chimera female to take residence there. Come see me in a couple of days.</text>
	</string>



<string id="trapper_chimera_6_0">
		<text>Can you remind me of the plan again?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_6_1">
		<text>Of course! What do you want to know?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_6_2">
		<text>Where is the lair again?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_6_3">
		<text>The lair of the Chimera female is inside the Volhov complex to the south east of here. My scouts report that her precise "sleeping chamber" is in the room to the right of the garage! That's where you need to drop the recording device!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_6_4">
		<text>Where is my entrance again?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_6_5">
		<text>To the left of the barracks are stairs which lead to the garage.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_6_6">
		<text>Where should I place the bait again?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_6_7">
		<text>The optimal spot to place the bait is the eastern entry to the Complex, next to the checkpoint!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_6_8">
		<text>Alright, that's all.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_6_9">
		<text>Weidmannsheil!</text>
	</string>

<string id="trapper_chimera_7_0">
		<text>It is done!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_7_1">
		<text>Excellent! Now we have to wait a day. I'll send you a message when you can recover the device!</text>
	</string>

<string id="trapper_chimera_8_0">
		<text>[Recording device] I recovered the device!</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_8_1">
		<text>Excellent, most excellent! Let's have a drink to the demise of Chyort!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_chimera_8_2">
		<text>I also killed the Chimera. Was there a bounty on her?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trapper_chimera_8_3">
		<text>Of course - there is always a bounty on a dead Chimera.</text>
	</string>

<string id="trapper_chimera_9_0">
		<text>I lost the device...</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_9_1">
		<text>Ok no problem, we can start again.</text>
	</string>

<string id="trapper_chimera_10_0">
		<text>I killed the Chimera...</text>
	</string>
  <string id="trapper_chimera_10_1">
		<text>Fuck! Well now we have to wait until a new Chimera sets up her lair again... I will send you a message when my scouts report a new resident.</text>
	</string>

<string id="st_trapper_chimera_2_recording_done">
		<text>Trapper: I believe we waited long enough. You can recover the recording now.</text>
	</string>



<string id="st_trapper_chimera_2_chimera_back">
		<text>Trapper: The lair is inhabited again. We can proceed with the plan.</text>
	</string>
<string id="st_trapper_chimera_recover_failed">
		<text>Trapper: I believe something went wrong with the recording. We have to start anew.</text>
	</string>

-----



---- Random Events

--- Controller Ambush

<string id="nr_primakov_help_1">
		<text>Someone: Please help! I'm inside the building!</text>
	</string>
<string id="nr_primakov_help_2">
		<text>Someone: Stalker, please help me! I'm in terrible pain!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_primakov_help_3">
		<text>Someone: I beg you, please come help me!</text>
	</string>
<string id="nr_primakov_help_4">
		<text>Someone: Stalker, the pain! Please come help!</text>
	</string>

---- Sasha Baltun
<string id="st_nr_sahsa_baltun_round_1">
		<text>Sasha Baltunov: Listen here boys, I'm paying a round! Barkeep, hand out the bottles!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nr_sahsa_baltun_round_2">
		<text>Everyone: Hurrah!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sahsa_baltun_start_0">
		<text>Did you get your bottle Stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sahsa_baltun_start_1">
		<text>Not yet, but I will, thanks! That's quite nice of you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sahsa_baltun_start_2">
		<text>I did, thanks! That's quite nice of you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sahsa_baltun_start_3">
		<text>Well I struck gold today, I'm a rich man now! I finally can leave this place, but before I want to have a fucking party!
		No more shivering in the cold, no more ducking under bullets, no more mutants trying to rip open my belly! I'm fucking free!</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="nr_sahsa_baltun_barkeep_0">
		<text>Can I have the bottle please?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_sahsa_baltun_barkeep_1">
		<text>Here you go Stalker.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_nr_sahsa_baltun_murder_1">
		<text>Shit, is that not the guy who gave out a round of booze?</text>
	</string>
	
---- Murder of Starik	
	
<string id="st_nr_starik_murder_1">
		<text>Someone: You moron, you killed him!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_nr_starik_murder_2">
		<text>Someone else: Not my fault! He should have talked!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_nr_starik_murder_3">
		<text>Someone: And now he cannot talk at all!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nr_starik_murder_4">
		<text>Someone: How shall we find out where he hid his stash now?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_nr_starik_murder_5">
		<text>Someone else: Maybe he has a clue in his pockets?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_nr_starik_murder_interrupted">
		<text>Someone: Shush, someone is outside!</text>
	</string>
---- Bezsnoik


<string id="nr_bezsonik_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Stalker, I cannot sleep with these fucking dogs howling! Can you take them out for me? They are driving me crazy! I'll give you 5.000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_bezsonik_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Sure, no problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_bezsonik_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Great! Be quick about it, I want to catch some sleep before the sun is rising. From what it sounds like, they should be to the west of here, near the path to the Truck Cemetery.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_bezsonik_start_dialog_3">
		<text>Not for 5.000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_bezsonik_start_dialog_4">
		<text>Dude, 5.000 roubles for a couple of dogs is more than fair pay. Ok, listen, I'll throw in some food and booze. Will that cut it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_bezsonik_start_dialog_5">
		<text>Deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_bezsonik_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Great! Be quick about it, I want to catch some sleep before the sun is rising. From what it sounds like, they should be to the west of here, near the path to the Truck Cemetery.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_bezsonik_start_dialog_7">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_bezsonik_start_dialog_8">
		<text>Ah fuck it, I'll find someone else to do the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_bezsonik_start_dialog_9">
		<text>No, I'm not interested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_bezsonik_start_dialog_10">
		<text>Ah fuck it, I'll find someone else to do the job.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="nr_bezsonik_0_0">
		<text>The dogs are dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_bezsonik_0_1">
		<text>Great! Here is your cash. Now let me go back to sleep.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_bezsonik_0_2">
		<text>Great! Here is your reward! Now let me go back to sleep.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_bezsonik_0_3">
		<text>You took your fucking time Stalker! The sun will rise soon. Here is some cash for your troubles, but obviously I cannot pay you in full.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_bezsonik_0_4">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>


<string id="nr_bezsonik_info">
		<text>Freedom guy: Hey Stalker! Yes you! Do you want to earn some quick cash?</text>
	</string>

--- Gutalin

<string id="meet_gutalin_info_1">
		<text>Stalker: Stalker! Turn back! Save yourself from this sinful lands!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="meet_gutalin_info_2">
		<text>Gutalin: For the white steed is saddled and his rider has put his foot in the stirrup. And the prayers of those who have sold themselves to Satan are in vain.</text>
	</string>
<string id="meet_gutalin_info_3">
		<text>Gutalin: You, children of man who were seduced by the devil, who play with the devil’s toys, who dig up Satan’s treasures -- I say unto you: you are blind!</text>
	</string>
<string id="meet_gutalin_info_4">
		<text>Gutalin: Awake, you bastards, before it’s too late! Trample the devil’s trinkets!</text>
	</string>
<string id="meet_gutalin_info_5">
		<text>Gutalin: Awake, blind ones, you’re falling into the pit and taking others with you.</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_gutalin_start_dialog_0">
		<text>My brother! You still have time to repent! Turn back and leave the Zone, this place put on earth by Satan himself in order to tempt us! Nothing good will come from here! Believe me, I know, I've seen!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gutalin_start_dialog_1">
		<text>What happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gutalin_start_dialog_2">
		<text>I tell you, these Satan's toys, these .. Artifacts ...they are not here to help us, no, they are here to tempt us! I've seen what they makes to people... what they make people do... 
		How the greed fills their hearts and how it makes them turn on their brothers! \n \n... \n \nI have to warn them... I have to save the lambs from the temptation, or there will be another Schuhart... \n \nTurn back now and save your soul Stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gutalin_start_dialog_3">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>


<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_0">
		<text>I see that you have a preacher now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_1">
		<text>Don't get me started. That man is spoiling my business! Fucking asshole, a friend of him gets killed and now everyone has to go back home? \n \nHe's scaring away all the manpower I need. 
		\n \nBut do you know what is the worst?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_2">
		<text>No?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_3">
		<text>Let me guess... he doesn't take bribes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_4">
		<text>The madman fucking buys Artifacts and fucking burries them! The toys of Satan he says! Can you imagine!!! 
		He gets fucking donations from some loosers, and then buys Artifacts for a premium price!!! AND - FUCKING - BURRIES THEM! \n \nNo, I cannot live with him, he has to go... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_5">
		<text>Aaargh, if only he would! No, he doesn't take any, and he fucks up my business! 
		\n \nThe madman fucking buys Artifacts and fucking burries them! The toys of Satan he says! Can you imagine!!! He gets fucking donations from some loosers, and then buys Artifacts for a premium price!!! 
		AND - FUCKING - BURRIES THEM! \n \nNo, I cannot live with him, he has to go... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_6">
		<text>Such is life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_7">
		<text>Is this ... a contract?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_8">
		<text>No, fuck life! Listen to me... that man has to go... I will pay you well if he doesn't bother me anymore... if you understand my drift...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_9">
		<text>My friend, it is... if for some reason this... if Gutalin finds his early demise... I would be very grateful. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_10">
		<text>I understand. Consider the problem resolved.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_11">
		<text>I don't care, he's your problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_12">
		<text>Good. Take care of him, and you will dine like a king!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_13">
		<text>My friend, don't you see? He's a threat to our lifestyle! He has to... take a vacation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_14">
		<text>Alright, I understand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_15">
		<text>No Sidorovich, he is your problem, not mine. I don't want anything to do with it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_16">
		<text>My man! Take care of him, and you will dine like a king!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_17">
		<text>Urgh, there is no loyalty in this place! Fine, go!!! I will take care of the problem myself.</text>
	</string>

<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_1_0">
		<text>Gutalin uttered his last sermon. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_gutalin_1_1">
		<text>Excellent! No longer will the ears of Stalker be poisoned by his words. Here Stalker! I believe I promised you a royal feast? 
		Ah, some money is also in order. But don't go spend it in some knock-off thrift shop - I'm sure you will find something to your liking in my hand picked assortment. Our economy is suffering after all.</text>
	</string>


<string id="fanatic_gutalin_0">
		<text>You have a preacher now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_gutalin_1">
		<text>Yeah... he is a bit peculiar, but he doesn't harm anyone. The man in the bunker is less happy about it though.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_gutalin_2">
		<text>What is Sidorovich's problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_gutalin_3">
		<text>Well you see, Gutalin here is trying to convince rookies to turn back and save their souls and bodies. 
			Much to the dislike of Sidorovich who would prefer to employ these men... and pay them accordingly. 
			But to be honest, only few men turn around and go home, most people here a desperate and don't have much of a choice. 
			\n \nI believe Sidorovich's problem is more of a philosophical nature.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_gutalin_4">
		<text>How so?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_gutalin_5">
		<text>Our preacher here buys Artifacts from Stalkers wishing to leave without haggling... and burries them during the night. 
		And not to make staches no, he simply wants them gone, or how he puts it "return the seed to their father". You can see how that conflicts with Sidorovich's approach.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_gutalin_6">
		<text>No shit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_gutalin_7">
		<text>No shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_gutalin_8">
		<text>Where does he get the money from?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_gutalin_9">
		<text>Mostly donations. You see, even though his methods are a bit eccentric, many veterans have symphaty for his ideas - we all lost part of our soul here.
		So there are Stalkers who would preserve others from doing the same, and some try to attone for their sins by supporting him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_gutalin_10">
		<text>Does no one try to follow him when he burries the Artifacts?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_gutalin_11">
		<text>It's not exactly common knowledge. But yeah, some did but lost track of him in the dark. And he doesn't return twice to the same location, he obviously is no fool.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_gutalin_12">
		<text>Let's change the topic.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_gutalin_13">
		<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>



<string id="nr_miha_shout_0_0">
	<text>Someone: Is... is someone there?</text>
</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_shout_0_1">
		<text>Someone: Stalker! You're godsend! Please help me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_shout_0_2">
		<text>Mihal: Fuck you!!! Burn in hell asshole.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_miha_0_0">
	<text>Stalker, please - you have to help me! I'm fucking dying here *cough*. Do you have anything with you? Bandages? *cough* A medkit?</text>
</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_1">
		<text>[Bandages] I have only bandages on me. Let me bandage you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_2">
		<text>[Medkit] I have a medkit. Let me help you. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_3">
		<text>And what is in it for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_4">
		<text>I don't think so...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_5">
		<text>Thank you Stalker! \n \n... \n \nAt least I won't bleed out immediatly! Thank you kind Stalker! Without you I would have become food for mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_6">
		<text>Thank you Stalker! \n \n... \n \nI already feel somewhat better! Thank you kind Stalker! Without you I would have become food for mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_7">
		<text>Shit man, I don't have time for that! *cough* Please, hurry up, my vision is already getting blurred... I... *cough* I have enough to make it worth it! *cough* but please, help me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_8">
		<text>What? Wait!!! Help me, please!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_9">
		<text>[Bandages] Alright, I will patch you up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_10">
		<text>[Medkit] Alright, I'll use this medkit. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_11">
		<text>Thank's Stalker! \n \n... \n \nAt least I won't bleed out immediatly! \n \nNow don't get angry, but I don't have any reward on me. 
		I came here on an expedition, but it went sideways... I ran into a Monolith squad, and these fuckers don't miss. They shot me in my arm, and now I cannot use my weapon... I managed to pull myself into this shelter, but I was to weak to make it back to a safe haven... 
		\n \nLong story short, I left anything of value in a stash... but if you bring me to the Laundromat, I'll give you the coordinates... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_12">
		<text>Thank's Stalker! \n \n... \n \nI already feel somewhat better... \n \nNow don't get angry, but I don't have any reward on me. 
		I came here on an expedition, but it went sideways... I ran into a Monolith squad, and these fuckers don't miss. They shot me in my arm, and now I cannot use my weapon... I managed to pull myself into this shelter, but I was to weak to make it back to a safe haven... 
		\n \nLong story short, I left anything of value in a stash... but if you bring me to the Laundromat, I'll give you the coordinates... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_13">
		<text>That was not part of the deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_14">
		<text>I see... I hope your stash is worth it, or I'll have to drag you back here with a bullet in both of your legs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_15">
		<text>Sorry, but it is now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_16">
		<text>I don't think so. I'll better finish you off now and take what's on your body.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_17">
		<text>Great, we have a deal...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_18">
		<text>Fuck you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_19">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_20">
		<text>How did you end up in this situation?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_21">
		<text>I came here on an expedition, but it went sideways... I ran into a Monolith squad, and these fuckers don't miss...
		They shot me in my arm, and now I cannot use my weapon... I managed to pull myself into this shelter, but I was to weak to make it back to a safe haven... during the scramble I also lost my PDA, so there was no way to ask for backup... I was stuck until you came by divine intervention, and saved me.
		\n \nI hate to ask another favour, but would it be possible for you to bring me back to the Laundromat? I'm not able to use my weapon and I need some proper medical intervention... I'll give you a reward of course!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_22">
		<text>Of course, no problem!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_0_23">
		<text>Great, thank you Stalker!</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_miha_1_0">
	<text>We arrived.</text>
</string>
	<string id="nr_miha_1_1">
	<text>We did indeed, thank you! Here, these are the coordinates to one of my stashes - I hope you find it satisfying. Now please excuse me, I have to get some medical attention.</text>
</string>







</string_table>
