<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
----Stories from the Zone----

---Butcher---

-- Bellerophon
<string id="butcher_bellerophon_0">
		<text>Who is the Nosorog guy on the floor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_bellerophon_1">
		<text>Bellerophon? He joined us a couple of weeks ago - I'm training him in the art of hunting, and he became quite efficent in it. 
		Well, he already has some experience, you see, technically he's military, but he got screwed over by hierarchy. They ordered him to kill a Chimera - alone. Quite a story to be honest, worthy of a greek drama.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="about_bellerophon_0">
		<text>[Stolichnaya] I have a bottle, do you want to tell me the story?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_1">
		<text>Sure mate. Get cosy and take a sip. Here. \n \nWell where to start? I'm a Podpolkovnik... well I was a Podpolkovnik in the SSO. Now I'm only a Lieutenant... I was about to be promoted to Polkovnik for outstanding service for the Fatherland.
			But before the ceremony there was the annual Old New Year celebration. Not the strash kind for basic Ivans but for the higher brass. Well the General was there too, and his wife. You have to understand, that guy is what? 60 years old, and his wife, well she was in her twenties. 
			You understand? No, I didn't sleep with her, but we will get to that part. Even though it wasn't an Ivan event, we got torched - normal no? It's the Old New Year after all. During the dinner I saw her looking at me all-the-time. And I understood "shit that's a bad omen.". 
			</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_2">
		<text>Another glass?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_3">
		<text>My friend, you can read my eyes.\n \nWell there I was, that girl eating me with her eyes. And I have to admit, she was exactly my kind of girl! But I knew that if I did anything, I would be screwed, so I resorted to the old forbidden technique. 
			You know it? I know it's a risky one, but if you can control yourself for long enough it always works. So basically, you get super drunk - then every girl will loose interest. 
			So I was hammering away, shot after shot.\n \nAfter a couple of hours my plan was almost perfect - almost. At some point I went to the toilet and she followed me. When I stepped out she stood before me and glued her mouth to mine. 
			I needed some time to understand what was happening - when I did I pushed her away. Didn't help, she jumped right back to my mouth. So I did the best I could think of - I slapped her. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_4">
		<text>Damn!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_5">
		<text>Yeah! Trouble is, at that moment two other officers entered the hallway. She was quicker to recover her wits, well she was also less drunk... well she started to scream that I tried to push myself on her and as she refused I tried to force her.
			You can imagine the situation! And considering that we are talking about the Generals wife, even if they believed me, that never could be the official version! So I was tried before the military courts, but instead of dismissing me and throwing me into prison, for some reason I was send here.
			Very strange, right? Well not that this place couldn't be seen as punishment, but nevertheless. So I arrived and - hey, you want another glass?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_6">
		<text>Sure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_7">
		<text>So I arrived here and the lads were some proper lads - they welcomed me with a bottle and they took heart at my sorrows. After a couple of days, Major Kuznetsov ordered me to him and gave me a mission: 
		apparently there is a Chimera somewhere in Yantar making some trouble for the Ecologists, and he ordered me to kill it - alone! No squad, no support, I'm supposed to do it on my own! My friend, I never heard about such an animal before, and when I joined back with the lads, they were shocked!
			Turns out that it's probably the deadliest animal around here! Well that's when they gifted me this armor - fine lads I can tell you! But that didn't solve my problem yet, and as I didn't have any experience hunting mutants, I came to Butcher in order to learn the ropes of the business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_8">
		<text>Why didn't you kill it yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_9">
		<text>I would have tried, but there is this psy field in the industrial parts of Yantar, and I don't manage to get inside without my brain melting like lava.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_10">
		<text>Can't the Ecologists provide you with a protection helmet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_11">
		<text>Apparently not, they say they ran out of stock. Well, there is this guy, Spirit I belive, who says that they are supposed to have some left, but I don't know, that guy was visibly drunk when he told me that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_12">
		<text>Sounds like they want you dead mate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_13">
		<text>The lads were telling me the same, but that can't be true. I mean, I'm a good fighter, why kill me when I can be useful? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_14">
		<text>Kuznetsov cleary wants you dead. Why don't you run away?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_15">
		<text>I'm a soldier my friend. I don't run away, I complete my mission. Besides, where should I run to? I would be tried for desertion - that's a death sentence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_16">
		<text>You know what? Fuck Kuznetsov - I like you and I'll help you. I'm going to turn off that fucking machine, and then we'll go hunt the Chimera together!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_bellerophon_17">
		<text>Wow that's super cool of you. Cheers to that mate!</text>
	</string>


<string id="bellerophon_5_1">
		<text>I desactivated the miracle machine - we can go hunt your chimera.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_5_2">
		<text>That's great my friend! But first I want to see through this snork problem for Butcher. I owe it to him. When it's finished we'll take care of the Chimera.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bellerophon_6_1">
		<text>The miracle machine is down - we can go hunt your chimera.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_6_2">
		<text>Thanks a lot my friend! Meet me in the Yantar bunker, we'll move out from there during the night.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bellerophon_7_1">
		<text>Are you ready to hunt?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_7_2">
		<text>I feel nervous but yeah, I'm ready. What about you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_7_3">
		<text>I'm ready. Shall we go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_7_4">
		<text>I have a bottle of Stolya ready for afterwards. Lead the way, I'm right behind you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_7_5">
		<text>I'm ready. Shall we go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_7_6">
		<text>Butcher told me that Chimeras are night creatures - we should set out during the night in order to catch it out in the open.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_7_7">
		<text>Not yet - I still need to make some preparations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_7_8">
		<text>Alright - come find me in the night when you're ready.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bellerophon_8_0">
		<text>We killed the beast!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_8_1">
		<text>Yes indeed! Damn my heart is racing like crazy! Let's get back to the Lab - then we can get drunk!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bellerophon_9_0">
		<text>We are back!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_9_1">
		<text>Yes we are! Take this, we'll drink to our successful hunt!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_9_2">
		<text>What are you doing now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_9_3">
		<text>Now that we killed the beast, my task is done! I'll go back and report to Kuznetsov... well after I recover from my hangover hahaha. And then we will see!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_9_4">
		<text>Do you think Kuznetsov will be content? As I understand the situation, he wanted you dead?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_9_5">
		<text>We'll see about that... but I accomplished my mission, so that should count for something, no? \n \nCome on my friend, another glass! To friendship! Let Kuznetsov be the worry of tomorrow!</text>
	</string>
--Quest1 now 3--
	
<string id="butcher_1_start_0">
		<text>You said there was a lost cargo?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_1_start_1">
		<text>Yeah - a scientist, Vybegallo, over in Agroprom contacted me because his order got lost in the marshes. A substantial food delivery apparently - the smell probably attracted a dogs 
		and the delivery guy decided his life was more important than the job and threw the cargo to them in order to distract the pack. Everything happened quite fast, so he doesn't remember the exact size of that pack, but he said there were a shit ton of them, so I guess there should be a dozen.
		\n \nDo you think you can recover the package and deliver it to that scientist?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_1_start_2">
		<text>Sure, I’m up for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_1_start_3">
		<text>Thanks, but I’m not ready yet.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_1_start_4">
		<text>Alright. According to his report he got jumped by them near an old construction site. The guy made his way past the Pump Station and kept the village with the water tower to his left, and the mechanic's yard to his right. Your job is to recover the package, there is no bounty on the dogs.
	If you found the package, deliver it to Vybegallo, he is somewhere in the Agroprom factory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_1_start_5">
		<text>No problem, come back later.</text>
	</string>	

<string id="butcher_1_time_0">
		<text>About your lost package.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_1_time_1">
		<text>Yes, are you ready?</text>
	</string>

<string id="butcher_1_done_0">
		<text>I delivered the package.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_1_done_1">
		<text>Well done! Keep the reward money, you deserve it. If you're ready, the snork problem requires some more attention.</text>
	</string>
	
-- Quest 2 --

<string id="butcher_2_start_0">
		<text>Do you have some special jobs for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_2_start_1">
		<text>I heard of some of your exploits, you seem like the capable kind… \n \nYou see, Duty pays me to keep the road from Cordon to Rostok free from particularly dangerous mutant threats – the sort the rookies wouldn’t be able to handle. You know, good for business and so on. Luckily the really dangerous mutants are rather rare in these parts. 
		\n \n Most of the times my problems here are rather that packs of animals grow to a threatening number -  and exactly such a problem emerged. A sow gave birth to a litter of piglets a couple of months ago, reports vary on their number. Some say three, others believe to have seen six. 
		Be as it may, I need you to put and end to them before the piglets grow to adult boars – I don’t need to tell you what a problem that would be. So what do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_2_start_2">
		<text>Consider it done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_2_start_3">
		<text>I need some time to prepare.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_2_start_4">
		<text>That’s the spirit! They inhabit the small wood in the south eastern sector, behind the Witches Jelly anomaly. Here take these, they should come in handy! Come see me when they’re dead, I’ll have put some vodka put to the side for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_2_start_5">
		<text>No problem, come see me when you’re ready!</text>
	</string>		
	
	<string id="butcher_2_time_0">
		<text>Concerning that job.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_2_time_1">
		<text>Are you ready to take on the boars?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="butcher_2_done_0">
		<text>The boars are no more.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_2_done_1">
		<text>Well done! Here, have some booze and some food – on the house! And of course, a reward for your troubles. Have a rest and if you want more work – there is something urgent.</text>
	</string>
	
	
-- Quest 3 --

<string id="butcher_3_start_0">
		<text>You said there was an urgent task?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_3_start_1">
		<text>Indeed. \n \n A group of snorks got lost and wandered over here from Agroprom. This happens sometimes, but in the past it always was one or two who found a way here - this time the reports talk about four! We can't let them dwell there, they pose too large a threat to the rookies. So what do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_3_start_2">
		<text>They are as good as dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_3_start_3">
		<text>I need some time to prepare.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_3_start_4">
		<text>Alright! They took up residence south west from here,near the southern path to Agroprom... Here take this, they should come in handy! Come see me when they’re dead, we'll raise a glass to your deeds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_3_start_5">
		<text>No problem, come see me when you’re ready!</text>
	</string>		
	
	<string id="butcher_3_time_0">
		<text>Concerning that job.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_3_time_1">
		<text>Are you ready to take on the snorks?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="butcher_3_done_0">
		<text>The snorks are dead.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_3_done_1">
		<text>Well done! Here, have a drink and some food. Here, have a smoke too. And of course, a reward for your troubles. Have a rest and come see me - I have a job for you concerning some lost cargo in the Swamp.</text>
	</string>	
	
	
	
-- Quest 4 --

<string id="butcher_4_start_0">
		<text>You said you wanted to talk to me about the snork problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_start_1">
		<text>Yes. \n \nYou see, this snork incursion worries me. It sometimes happened in the past, but never in these numbers! I've been thinking, probably the snork population in Agroprom grew too much and that's the reason why they come over in larger numbers now... Can you have a look and if my suspicion is right - cull them? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_start_2">
		<text>I will take a look.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_start_3">
		<text>I need some time to prepare.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_4_start_4">
		<text>Alright! Don't go alone, Bellerophon over there will accompany you - fear not he's a capable fighter. Travel over to Agroprom, if my suspicions are true, they should be somewhere between the southern and the northern path to Garbage. 
		There is a hill there, chances are good that's where you'll find them. Take this, you will need it. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_start_5">
		<text>No problem, come see me when you’re ready!</text>
	</string>		
	
	<string id="butcher_4_time_0">
		<text>Concerning that job.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="butcher_4_time_1">
		<text>Are you ready to cull the snork population?</text>
	</string>
	
--- Bellerophon lives

<string id="butcher_4_done_0">
		<text>The snork problem has been taken care off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_done_1">
		<text>Well done! Here, have a drink and a bite. So tell me, how bad was the snork situation over there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_done_2">
		<text>Horrible! It was a massacre... After killing one two more took their place! There had to be at least a dozen of them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_done_3">
		<text>A dozen of these pieces of shit? On the same spot? Fuck... good that I send both you and Bellerophon to take care of the problem... We will have to keep an eye on this situation - this is very strange...
		I'll have to send some guys to investigate... Maybe Orion... yes...
		\n \nTake a rest, and if you feel able to do some work again, I would like you to go meet Aspirin, the Duty medic. He contacted me, seems they need some discrete help.</text>
	</string>

--- Bellerophon dies

<string id="butcher_4_alt_done_0">
		<text>The snorks are dead, but... sadly  Bellerophon fell during the battle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_alt_done_1">
		<text>Bellerophon? What a shame! I took a real liking to that guy! This place is cruel indeed... Let's raise a glas to him! He would have liked that!
		\n \n \n \nNow tell me, how bad was the situation?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_alt_done_2">
		<text>Horrible! It was a massacre... After killing one two more took their place! There had to be at least a dozen of them! I'm glad I made it out alive...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_4_alt_done_3">
		<text>A dozen of these pieces of shit? On the same spot? Fuck... good that I send both you and Bellerophon to take care of the problem... We will have to keep an eye on this situation - this is very strange...
		I'll have to send some guys to investigate... Maybe Orion... yes...
		\n \nTake a rest, and if you feel able to do some work again, I would like you to go meet Aspirin, the Duty medic. He contacted me, seems they need some discrete help.</text>
	</string>
	
---- Quest 5 ----
<string id="st_butcher_5_help_info">
		<text>Butcher: My friend, we need your urgent help. Bellerophon has been wounded in Agroprom and the other hunter, Orion, is missing in action. Please, go as soon as possible to Agroprom and find Bellerophon in the factory - he will be able to give you details.</text>
	</string>

<string id="st_butcher_5_alt_help_info">
		<text>Butcher: My friend, we need your urgent help. Sarpedon has been wounded in Agroprom and the other hunter, Orion, is missing in action. Please, go as soon as possible to Agroprom and find Sarpedon in the factory - he will be able to give you details.</text>
	</string>

<string id="butcher_5_start_0">
		<text>I got your message, what is going on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_start_1">
		<text>Good that you're here - Bellerophon set off with another hunter, Orion, to find the cause of that Snork infestation. They were able to trace it back to the Agroprom Underground - 
		apparently something in there drives the Snorks out. Both of them undertook the mission to explore the Underground, but Bellerophon got wounded. They returned, but Orion set off again... young fool... that was yesterday and since then we haven't heard of him.
		I now this is a lot to ask, but can you go down there and check the situation out? We expect the worst, but we can't leave a brother behind. \n \nWould you be ready for such an undertaking?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_start_2">
		<text>Yes, of course, I'll head over there now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_start_3">
		<text>I don't know, that sounds very dangerous. I will have to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_start_4">
		<text>Great! Find Bellerophon, he is recovering from his wounds in the Agroprom Factory. And here, take this - you will need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_start_5">
		<text>Understandable - but I'm afraid to insist on the urgency of this matter. Go find Bellerophon if you believe you're up to it.</text>
	</string>

<string id="butcher_5_alt_start_0">
		<text>I got your message, what is going on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_alt_start_1">
		<text>Good that you're here - Sarpedon set off with another hunter, Orion, to find the cause of that Snork infestation. They were able to trace it back to the Agroprom Underground - 
		apparently something in there drives the Snorks out. Both of them undertook the mission to explore the Underground, but Sarpedon got wounded. They returned, but Orion set off again... young fool... that was yesterday and since then we haven't heard of him.
		I now this is a lot to ask, but can you go down there and check the situation out? We expect the worst, but we can't leave a brother behind. \n \nWould you be ready for such an undertaking?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_alt_start_2">
		<text>Yes, of course, I'll head over there now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_alt_start_3">
		<text>I don't know, that sounds very dangerous. I will have to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_alt_start_4">
		<text>Great! Find Sarpedon, he is recovering from his wounds in the Agroprom Factory. And here, take this - you will need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_5_alt_start_5">
		<text>Understandable - but I'm afraid to insist on the urgency of this matter. Go find Sarpedon if you believe you're up to it.</text>
	</string>

--- Bellerophon ---
<string id="bellerophon_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello Stalker, how can I help you?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bellerophon_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Hello, who are you?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bellerophon_start_dialog_2">
		<text>I'm Bellerophon and somewhat new here... well not exactly, but it's complicated.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_start_dialog_3">
		<text>Where did you get the Nosorog?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_start_dialog_4">
		<text>Well technically I'm military, so... well some mates gave it to me when I left for my mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_start_dialog_5">
		<text>You're military? What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Well yes, but don't worry, I don't have any animosity towards you. Why I'm here? Well that's a long story and not necessary my favourite one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_start_dialog_7">
		<text>I have time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_start_dialog_8">
		<text>Alright, I don't want to push you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_start_dialog_9">
		<text>I believe we need some Stolya for that. If you can find a bottle, I'll tell you the story.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_start_dialog_10">
		<text>Yeah, that's more a story to be told with a bottle of Stolya. If you ever find one, I can tell you the story.</text>
	</string>

<string id="bellerophon_1_0">
		<text>Are you ready to go hunt some snorks?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bellerophon_1_1">
		<text>Yeah, Butcher told me to give you a hand. Lead the way, I'm behind you.</text>
	</string>

<string id="bellerophon_2_0">
		<text>That was brutal!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bellerophon_2_1">
		<text>Yeah, I never saw that many Snorks in one spot! This is very very strange - I will have to investigate. Thanks a lot for your help - you're quite good at this!</text>
	</string>


<string id="bellerophon_3_0">
		<text>I got the message from Butcher, what is going on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_3_1">
		<text>Good that you're here - we ran into some trouble and I'm wounded... I will make it, don't worry, but I'm incapacitated. I came here with another hunter - Orion, the young blood, to find the cause of that Snork infestation. We noticed that during the night, a lot of these bastards came pouring out of the Underground.
		There is something down there that drives them out - something nefarious... We went down there and it was brutal... our heads began to hurt and suddenly we were surrounded by Snorks and I got bitten in the arm and leg - luckily Orion was there to carry me out! But... that fool went back! I begged him to wait, but he was eager, how young people are!
		Shit, and now I haven't heard of him. My friend, please go down there and find him! I would like to come with you, but my leg won't carry me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_3_2">
		<text>Don't worry, I'll find Orion and bring him back here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_3_3">
		<text>I don't know, I don't think I'm ready to head down there yet!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_3_4">
		<text>I know I could count on you! And here, take this - I'm afraid you might need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_3_5">
		<text>Understandable - but please hurry! And here, take this - if you're ready to go down there, I'm afraid you might need it.</text>
	</string>
	
--- Rescue Orion

<string id="hunter_orion_help_1">
		<text>Someone: My head!!! Get out you bastard!!!</text>
	</string>
<string id="hunter_orio_help_2">
		<text>Someone: Fucking hell!!! The pain!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_orio_help_3">
		<text>Someone: Help!!! The pain!!! My head!!!</text>
	</string>
<string id="hunter_orio_help_4">
		<text>Someone: Relive me!!! Get it out my head!!!</text>
	</string>


<string id="bellerophon_4_0">
		<text>I found Orion...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_4_1">
		<text>I understand... What got him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_4_2">
		<text>I... I'm not sure. I fought through hordes of snorks and other monsters... at the end I found him, clutching his head and weeping. When I tried to talk to him I saw his eyes... he was a Zombie and he attacked me. I had to kill him. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_4_3">
		<text>Shit... do you know what happened to him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_4_4">
		<text>No... there was a large room behind him, but the gate was closed. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_4_5">
		<text>Hmmm... maybe the answer lies therein... we! No, I sadly cannot help you in my state... You have to find a way into that room! You have to find what got Orion in the end... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_4_6">
		<text>You can count on me - I will find Orion's bane and put an end to it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_4_7">
		<text>Go Brother and do that!</text>
	</string>

<string id="bellerophon_10_0">
		<text>Do you how I could get into that room?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_10_1">
		<text>To be frank, no. But this Underground had to be build by someone, maybe you can find some old plans lying around somewhere?</text>
	</string>

<string id="bellerophon_11_0">
		<text>I didn't find any plans, but I found a construction file!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_11_1">
		<text>Excellent work! The author of the document is complaining about some workers who got drunk and started digging not according to plan...
			From his explanations, it seems to be somewhere to the very south of here... maybe the entrance is still open?</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bellerophon_12_0">
		<text>What do you think got Bellerophon?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bellerophon_12_1">
		<text>I really don't know... but it seems very strange... maybe Butcher knows it?</text>
	</string>
--- Butcher Legendary ---

<string id="butcher_legendary_0_0">
		<text>Forester told me about the Calydonian Boar. What do you know about him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_1">
		<text>Did he now? And let me guess, you want to hunt him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_2">
		<text>Maybe.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_3">
		<text>Hunting that boar is a dangerous undertaking - much more so than anything you hunted until now. 
He took the lifes of many hunters of great reputation: Sigurd One-Eye, Boris the Blade and Irontooth Aslan to name a few. Those who survived did so by running away - like me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_4">
		<text>So you faced him? What is your story?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_5">
		<text>During the time I'm here, I pursued many different occupations, anything that payed money to be frank - a bit like you if I'm not mistaken. Of some activites I'm more proud than others. 
After some time, I found out that from all the possible jobs in the Zone, hunting was most to my liking. You see, I was good at it and hunting mutants tends to not make you enemies here. 
I rapidly made a name for myself, and - in my hybris - started to seek out mutants "normal" hunters didn't dare to face. 
One evening I shared the campfire with some Clear Sky guys who told me about a rumor amongst their hunters that there is a patron saint of the boars in the Great Marshes and that I should avoid to hunt them in order not to attract his ire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_6">
		<text>The Calydonian Boar?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_7">
		<text>Exactly - although back then he didn't carry that name yet. \n \nI dismissed it as an urban legend, but one week later I met a stalker who swore that he saw the beast! He told me how he was hunting boars in the heart of the Great Marshes. 
		After killing off an especially large pack of them, according to his own account, the ground started to shake and out of the bushes came charging four immense boars, and leading them a dreadful one! The guy was wise, as he understood that facing him would spell his doom. 
		So he ran away. \n \nOf course my curiosity was sparked, and I started to make inquiries in the marshes. I found some other survivors and all told me the same story.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_8">
		<text>So you sought him out? How?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_9">
		<text>It turns out that contrary to the urban legend, the Calydonian boar only protects his own tribe! A huge tribe to be sure, but only them. 
		So I waited until an abnormal large pack of them was sighted and I started to kill them. Sure enough, the ground suddenly began to shake and out came charging four huge boars with the Calydonian one leading them! 
		What a sight! A dreadful boar! — He has burning, bloodshot eyes which seemed coals of living fire, a rough neck which was knotted with stiff muscles, and thick-set with bristles like sharp spikes. 
		A seething froth dripped on his shoulders, and his tusks were like that of an elephant! 
		Discordant roars reverberated from his hideous jaws! It seemed like lightning — belched forth from his horrid throat — and was scorching the green ground! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_10">
		<text>What a dreadful picture!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_11">
		<text>Indeed it was... I still shiver from the mere thought of it. \n \nAfter my initial shock I started blasting with my trusted Saiga! Pumped magazines of lead into them while dodging their charges! His companions dropped alright, although it seemed to me that other boars rushed in to replace them. 
		But the Calydonian one, my god, that beast took the lead like Bellerophon drinks Vodka - even after twelve shots they don't waver. I understood that I came unprepared and I took off faster than a lover when the husband comes home. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_12">
		<text>Forester mentionned that you faced him off twice?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_13">
		<text>Yes... my pride was hurt, but I still had enough left to blinden me to the reality that is this boar. After having run off I could only think about how to kill that devil. So I put together a team - in the end we were four. Peleus, Eurytion and Sigurd!
			Sadly, the hunt was a disaster! Sigurd fell the first - a boar blindsided him and he was trampled, his missing eye spelling his doom. In the resulting confusion Peleus made a terrible mistake and shot Eurytion while trying to cover him! Horrible fate struck us! \n \nI rushed to Eurytion to save him, but I dropped my guard... I heard a horrible shriek, and when I turned around I saw the Calydonian Boar charging me!
			 I failed to jump out of his way in time... it felt like he ripped my leg off, but it "only" crushed every single bone in it. Luckily Peleus managed to distract it and managed to carry me off to savety.
			Obviously I'm not able to walk properly anymore - that's also the reason why I no longer hunt and content myself with staying here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_14">
		<text>That boar seems to be quite the force of nature...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_15">
		<text>What happened to Peleus?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_16">
		<text>It quite certainly is... do you understand why you should refrain from hunting it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_17">
		<text>He was devastated that he killed Eurytion... after he cured me back to the living he left for the north and went missing. His son went after him, but by then Peleus already found his demise... Achilles only found his corpse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_18">
		<text>I understand the danger, but I want to continue where you left off. Can you tell me how to find him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_19">
		<text>Yes, maybe I still need to gather some experience before going after him...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_20">
		<text>Alright. I have to admit that you have quite a talent for the hunt! And you're unafraid as if you were a cat with nine lives! I'll give the word out to my friends to keep a look out for the Calydonian Boar's tribe. 
		When they find his pack I will write you, but it can take some days! Until then I suggest you prepare - remember, you have to be swift on your feet and you need to have enough firepower to wrangle him and his brethren to death! And remember - running away is always an option.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_0_21">
		<text>I agree! Don't rush this! There are easier ways to make money here than to hunt him.</text>
	</string>

<string id="st_calydonian_boar_spawned_1">
		<text>The ground trembles and the air is filled with angry growls. The Calydonian Boar seeks revenge for his fallen brethren.</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="st_calydonian_boar_fleed_1">
		<text>I was unprepared for the Calydonian Boar. Next time I'll come back with more firepower. I should talk to Butcher to keep an eye out for that beast.</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="st_butcher_legendary_hunting_season_1">
		<text>Butcher: My friends tell me that there is an unusual amount of boars roaming about in the heart of the marshes. The hunting season is open.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_butcher_legendary_hunting_season_2">
		<text>Butcher: You will find them between the Pump Station, the Village ruins and the Machine Yard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_butcher_legendary_hunting_season_3">
		<text>Butcher: They are split into three groups.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_butcher_legendary_hunting_season_4">
		<text>Butcher: Remember: he will fight for them, and they will fight for him! Good luck!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="butcher_legendary_1_0">
		<text>About the Calydonian Boar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_1_1">
		<text>Yes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_1_2">
		<text>I decided I'm ready to hunt it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_1_4">
		<text>Can you tell me the story again how you faced the boar?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_1_5">
		<text>Do you have any advise for hunting him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_1_6">
		<text>Take only the very essentials for the fight! You need to be able to dodge not only his charges, but that of his companions too! And you will need a shit ton of ammunition! And remember - running away is always an option.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_1_7">
		<text>Let's talk about something else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_1_8">
		<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_1_9">
		<text>I want to try again. This time the Calydonian Boar will find his demise.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_1_10">
		<text>Alright Hunter! I'll give the word out to my friends to keep a look out for the Calydonian Boar's tribe. Make your preparations in the meantime.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="butcher_legendary_2_0">
		<text>You were right, that Boar was too much. I had to flee!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_2_1">
		<text>You made the right decision to run away. You can always attempt it later.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="butcher_legendary_3_0">
		<text>I did it! I killed that beast!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_3_1">
		<text>Tremendous work! Stalkers will tell your tale for a very long time! Let's drink to that!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_3_2">
		<text>Let's drink!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="butcher_legendary_3_3">
		<text>I have to admit, I didn't thought it feasible! But here you are! Damn, son! Here take this - I no longer need it and I think you will make better use of it. My old hunting rifle, Cyclops!\n \nAnd, yes of course! 
			There is a bounty on that damn boar, although only few Stalkers payed into it believing that it was more legend than truth... well either way, here is the money!</text>
	</string>
--- Hunter Duty ---	
	
<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_0">
		<text>Butcher told me you might have a job for me.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_1">
		<text>Ah right! Thanks for coming.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_2">
		<text>No problem, how can I help?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_3">
		<text>Right. To make it short, the boys here have some trouble on their hands. Voronin recently went to a meeting with Sakharov and Kuznetsov to discuss some general matters. During that meeting, Sakharov asked Voronin to help them by clearing the Bloodsucker Village, a proposition Kuznetsov apparently laughed at, saying Duty wasn't able to manage that and he proposed the help of his soldiers instead.
			Voronin took that very badly, and started to boast about our boys capabilities. Nothing bad at defending the honour of our soldiers, but he lost any touch to reality and promised Sakharov to clear out the Bloodsucker Village for them. Problem is, he wants to do it overnight in order for the Ecologists to show up in the morning and find a safe village... Over fucking night! Can you imagine? 
		He wants to show off in front of the military, you understand - and this asshole doesn't care about the fact that some of them won't survive the night. \n \nOf course the boys are less than enthusiastic to lose their lifes for the General's ego, they are soldiers after all, no Spetsnaz.
		So they came to me, and I promised to see what I can do - I thought of Butcher and asked if he couldn't send us an experiencied hunter who is up to the job. Of course you need to be discrete, Vornonin can't know anything about this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_4">
		<text>I'm all ears.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_5">
		<text>Clearing out the Bloodsucker Village during night? That's suicide!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_6">
		<text>"We are not to reason why, we are but to do and die." Orders are orders, I don't condone insubordination!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_7">
		<text>I'm glad to hear that, it is always nice to talk to professionals. Of course we don't expect you doing it for free, the boys will pitch in to reward you for your help! 
		They even managed to bribe Mangun to give them a nightvision device - so you won't have to go in blind like a mole. So you're in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_8">
		<text>Yes it's tough, but think about it - if someone can do it, it's certainly you! Butcher told me about your skills hunting mutants - that's more than I can say about our boys. Of course we don't expect you doing it for free, the boys will pitch in to reward you for your help! 
		They even managed to bribe Mangun to give them a nightvision device - so you won't have to go in blind like a mole. Will you help us? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_9">
		<text>I understand the need for a soldier to follow orders of his superiors, but this is objectively not a sane mission! These are actual people being send for a mission they haven't trained for! Think of it! You on the other hand have experience in these matters, 
		at least Butcher told me that you are skilled in hunting mutants. And of course we don't expect you doing it for free, the boys will pitch in to reward you for your help! 
		They even managed to bribe Mangun to give them a nightvision device - so you won't have to go in blind like a mole. So you're in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_10">
		<text>Alright, I will do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_11">
		<text>I can do it, but I want Voronin to know it was me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_12">
		<text>I need some time to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_13">
		<text>No way, they can do it themselves!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_14">
		<text>God bless you. Come see me the night you want to do it, I'll give you the nightvision device and warn the boys they should pretend to leave for the raid.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_15">
		<text>That's not possible, Voronin wants it to be the guys designated by him. Can you not do it for them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_16">
		<text>Alright, but please don't take too long, Voronin grows impatient.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_17">
		<text>Are you sure? Think about it, the guys would really appreciate it!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_time_0">
		<text>About the Bloodsucker Village.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_time_1">
		<text>Yeah? Are you up to it?</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_no_1">
		<text>Yeah? Did you change your mind?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_no_13">
		<text>I decided, I will certainly not do it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_no_17">
		<text>*Sigh* A shame, I had high hopes for you, but alright... I'll ask Butcher if he can send me someone else...</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_0">
		<text>About the Bloodsucker Village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_1">
		<text>Yes, what about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_2">
		<text>I am ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_3">
		<text>I am ready.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_4">
		<text>I am not ready yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_5">
		<text>Good to hear that, come see me this night before you set off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_6">
		<text>Perfect. Here is your nightvision device - I also packed some batteries so that you won't find yourself in the middle of night without juice. Take these medics too, hopefully you won't need them, but better safe than sorry.
		You have to finish this before sunrise! Before the Ecologists will set off! Good hunting Stalker, and thanks for helping us out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_yes_7">
		<text>Alright, come see me when you are ready.</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_1_0">
		<text>The job is done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_1_1">
		<text>Excellent work! I knew you would pull through!</text>
	</string>	

<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_2_0">
		<text>I'm sorry, I couldn't get the job done in time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_2_1">
		<text>Don't worry Stalker! We will get some scolding from Voronin, but at least no life is lost.</text>
	</string>	
	

<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_0">
		<text>What happened in the Bloodsucker Village?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_1">
		<text>You ratted us out, that's what happened. Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_2">
		<text>I believe in following orders.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_3">
		<text>I wanted to see what would happen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_4">
		<text>I did it for the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_5">
		<text>You're an asshole. You could simply have ignored this and we would have hired someone else - instead three of our boys are dead and Artyom is in a critical condition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_6">
		<text>You wanted to see what would happen? Three dead - one wounded - that's what would happen! You're an asshole - get lost.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_0_snitch_7">
		<text>For the money? You're an asshole - your greed cost the life of our boys!</text>
	</string>

<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_0">
		<text>What happened to the guy on the floor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_1">
		<text>Artyom - a collateral of your ratting. Artyom is the only survivor - he managed to run away when everything went to shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_2">
		<text>Will he make it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_3">
		<text>Probably yeah, I managed to stabilize him. But he still is in great pain and he seems to be badly traumatized - he has panic fits and I have to give him Morphine in order to calm him down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_4">
		<text>I'm sorry for what happened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_5">
		<text>Humpf. Your regret will not bring back Vadim, Sasha and Sergey, but at least you admit to your fault.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_6">
		<text>Don't try to pin this on me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_about_artyom_7">
		<text>Fuck off asshole, this is your fault. </text>
	</string>

<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_0">
		<text>I need to tell you something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_1">
		<text>What are you waiting for, speak up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_2">
		<text>Your men tried to pay me to clear the Bloodsucker village for them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_3">
		<text>Nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_4">
		<text>What? Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_5">
		<text>Then stop wasting my time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_6">
		<text>They are afraid to do it - they say that they are not trained for such a night mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_7">
		<text>These cowards... I will beat bravery into them - thanks for telling me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_8">
		<text>It was me who cleared the Bloodsucker Village - your men payed me to do the job in their stead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_9">
		<text>What? Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_10">
		<text>They were too afraid to do it - they said that they are not trained for such a night mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_snitch_11">
		<text>These cowards... I will beat bravery into them - thanks for telling me! 
		Here have a "fee" to keep your mouth shut, we can't have this disgrace be known in the Zone.</text>
	</string>

<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_0">
		<text>You wanted to see me?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1">
		<text>Yes... I'm afraid that the mission failed. Of the four men I send only one made it back - badly wounded and out of his mind. 
				We barely got anything out of him, but it seems that it went to shit the moment they set foot into that Village.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_2">
		<text>What happened?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_3">
		<text>Artyom wasn't able to give a full report...  from what I understood, they didn’t follow protocol and separated which resulted in a mission failure. 
		He's with Aspirin at the moment, maybe you can get something out of him. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_4">
		<text>What do you want me to do about the situation?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_5">
		<text>No one can know about this failure and my men refuse to go back to that Village during night. 
			I need someone to sneak into the village during night and swap the fallen men's Duty patch with Mercenary ones... </text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_6">
		<text>What? Are you fucking kidding me?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_7">
		<text>Understandable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_8">
		<text>Not at all, this is vital for the reputation of Duty - we can not be allowed to show weakness!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_9">
		<text>I'm glad that we are on the same page - the reputation of Duty is after all paramount.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_10">
		<text>Can you not simply recover their bodies?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_11">
		<text>Out of question! That would draw too much attention to the failure - I cannot allow it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_111">
		<text>But these man died in the line of duty! You have to recover them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_112">
		<text>These men knew for what they signed up. Besides, the reputation of Duty is larger than the memory of a few men.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_12">
		<text>Why Mercenary patches?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_13">
		<text>Isn't it obvious? To make it look as if some Mercenaries dressed as Duty soldiers in order to bypass Rostok without unnecessary attention, but got caught in the Bloodsucker Village. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_14">
		<text>Alright, I will help you clean up the evidence.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_15">
		<text>I have to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_16">
		<text>I don't want to be involved in this.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_17">
		<text>Good. Prepare for the mission and come see me during the night before you set off.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_18">
		<text>Then do it fast, the more time passes the more people will notice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_19">
		<text>Are you sure? I'm ready to pay a good price for this, let's say 20.000 roubles?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_20">
		<text>For that price I can do it.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_21">
		<text>No forget it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_22">
		<text>Good. Prepare for the mission and come see me during the night before you set off.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_23">
		<text>Think about it.</text>
	</string>

<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_0">
		<text>About the mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_1">
		<text>Yes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_2">
		<text>I am ready. Tell me about the details.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_3">
		<text>Perfect. The mission is rather simple, you find the bodies of Vadim, Sergey and Sasha and replace their Duty patch with these ones. But be careful to finsih the job before sunrise, we can't have anyone seeing you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_4">
		<text>I need some more time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_5">
		<text>Alright, but please hurry up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_6">
		<text>I have changed my mind - I will assist you with your cover up...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_7">
		<text>Alright, good to hear! Come see me when you are ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_8">
		<text>Nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_9">
		<text>Okay...?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_10">
		<text>I am ready, tell me about the details.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_1_11">
		<text>Good, come see me during the night beofre setting of.</text>
	</string>

<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_2_0">
		<text>It is done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_2_1">
		<text>Excellent work Stalker - now no one will be able to pin anything on Duty. Here is your reward - I hope I can count on your discretion.</text>
	</string>

<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_3_0">
		<text>It is done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_bloodsucker_botched_3_1">
		<text>You mean you failed - there is chatter about a Stalker fumbling with Duty bodies in the Bloodsucker village. Here some compensation, but I believe it's also in your best interest to keept your failure secret.</text>
	</string>	

	
<string id="st_dolg_voronin_bloodsucker_news_0">
		<text>Voronin: Stalker, we have a problem on our hands. Please come see me as soon as possible!</text>
	</string>
<string id="st_dolg_aspirin_bloodsucker_news_0">
		<text>Aspirin: Stalker, come see me - we have a job proposition for you.</text>
	</string>	
<string id="st_dolg_aspirin_bloodsucker_news_1">
		<text>Aspirin: Stalker, come see me - we got a problem for which we need your help.</text>
	</string>	
<string id="st_freedom_voronin_bloodsucker_news_0">
		<text>Yo guys, there is a Stalker looting... Duty soldiers? Dead Duty soldiers in the Bloodsucker Village? What are they doing there?</text>
	</string>	
	
	

<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_0">
		<text>You said you have a job offer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_1">
		<text>Yes - the boys want to get vengeance on these Bloodsuckers and considering that you have... 
	experience with that Village, they would like you to join them on their expedition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_2">
		<text>So you're not taking it badly that I told Voronin and accepted his job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_3">
		<text>Well... obviously that was not very cool of you - we could have hired someone else who would have done it instead of you.
	But... I - We understand that the Zone is not very conductive for morals and that people like you are here for... their personal gains.
	Water under the Bridge, you didn't kill Sasha, Sergey and Vadim, these fucking Bloodsuckers did it... now we would like to hire you for payback. 
	A lot of money Stalker, the boys didn't clutch their wallets in order to get payback.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_4">
		<text>No bad feelings about Artyom?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_5">
		<text>Artyom, yes, that was - to be frank - quite stupid of you to give him that much morphine. Poor Artyom... He didn't deserve to die like this. 
	But life goes on ... let's not talk about Artyom, yes? His death is still very painfull to me.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_6">
		<text>What is the plan? Isn't a night raid too dangerous?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_7">
		<text>No night raid needed Stalker, the plan is quite different. We bought all the explosives we could get our hands on, and we will set them up in different locations of the village showing Bloodsucker activity.
		When they creep out during the night, we will blow them up like firework!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_8">
		<text>Alright, I'm in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_9">
		<text>I have to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_10">
		<text>No, I think I will not help you out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_11">
		<text>We are glad to hear that! Come see me when you're ready, and I tell you the details!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_12">
		<text>Alright, but please hurry! The boys are getting restless waiting for their vengeance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_13">
		<text>Are you sure? There is a lot of money to be made and the job is quite easy if I dare to say so.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_14">
		<text>Let me think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_15">
		<text>No, my answer is final.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_16">
		<text>Alright, take your time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_3_17">
		<text>Please consider the job offer! We will be waiting if you change your mind.</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_0">
		<text>About the payback mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_1">
		<text>Yes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_2">
		<text>I am ready. Tell me about the details.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_3">
		<text>Good, very good. Ilya Kovalyov is your contact person - you will meet him in Army Warehouse in the farm south of the path leading here.
	Wait for him there - he will explain the rest of the mission to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_4">
		<text>I need some more time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_5">
		<text>Alright, but please hurry up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_6">
		<text>I have changed my mind - I will assist you taking vengeance on these Bloodsuckers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_7">
		<text>Alright, the boys will be happy to hear that! Come see me when you are ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_8">
		<text>Nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_4_9">
		<text>Okay...?</text>
	</string>

<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_5_0">
		<text>You asshole set me up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_5_1">
		<text>Fuck you, you deserve it asshole!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_5_2">
		<text>Your friends were about to kill me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_medic_hunter_5_3">
		<text>I told them to only fuck you up, but I can't blame them for hating your guts. Now fuck off asshole!</text>
	</string>

	
<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_0">
		<text>Good day asshole.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_1">
		<text>What? What is your problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_2">
		<text>Was it not enough for you to rat us out? 
	Did you have to accept Voronin's request and let our boys lie abandoned in that fucking Village while everyone is supposed to pretend they are mercenaries?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_3">
		<text>Relax, it was not personal, only business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_4">
		<text>Aspirin told us to give you a good beating, but you don't deserve that. This is for the boys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_5">
		<text>Woah what are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_7">
		<text>What? And Artyom? Did you have to kill that poor soul? You're scum!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_ilya_bloodsucker_start_8">
		<text>I - it was not my intention!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Ah ah ah... it hurts... please help me...</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_0">
		<text>Artyom, I need to ask you something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_1">
		<text>Ah ah ah...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_2">
		<text>Where can I find the bodies of the other soldiers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_3">
		<text>Ah ah ah... my leg, it hurts. Mother please! I want to go home...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_4">
		<text>[Morphine] Here take the morphine, it will help with the pain. Can you remember what happened during that night?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_5">
		<text>Aaaaah... fuck... \n \n... \n \nWhere am I, what happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_6">
		<text>Relax, you're back in the base. I need you to remember what happened during the raid.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_7">
		<text>What? The raid? ... Yes the raid ... \n \n ... \n \nfuck the raid ... it was a massacer, we should never have gone into that Village. We entered from the south-west, and everything was quiet - we even made it across the dirt road without incident...
			But when we approached the wooden house everything... everything... oh my god Vadim! Vadim! Aaaaah!!! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_8">
		<text>Relax Artyom, relax! Tell me what happened next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_9">
		<text>I believe that is enough... rest well Artyom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_10">
		<text>Vadim! Aaah it hurts... Vadim!!! Sergey!!! Mother!!! HELP! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_11">
		<text>[Morphine] Here take the morphine... Artyom, what happened after Vadim died?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_12">
		<text>Aaaaah... \n \n ... \n \nWhat? Ah yes... after the Bloodsucker slaughtered Vadim we turned around and ran for our lifes... Sergey was first ... faster than Sasha and me ... he ran into the first house he saw... \n \n ... \n \n
			We heard ... we heard a horrible screach ... followed by a scream! They got Sasha ... they got Sasha... oh my god, why? Why? Ohhhhhhh...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_13">
		<text>Artyom relax! We are nearly done Artyom! What happened next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_14">
		<text>Aaaaah!!! They're everywhere! Help! Please help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_15">
		<text>[Morphine] Here some more morphine... Artyom, we nearly finished, what happened after Sergey died?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_16">
		<text>Oh... aaaaah... \n \n ... \n \n yes the raid... we ... we didn't follow Sergey into that ... house. Sasha went totally mad ... went off towards the heart of the village... I... didn't think ... followed him ... we ... ran ... until we ... north of village...
			There we found... a house ... empty... we rested... yes rested ... I'm tired ... I need to rest ... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_artyom_bloodsucker_0_17">
		<text>Artyom! Artyom!!! Don't fall asleep!!! Artyom, wake up!!!</text>
	</string>
	
------ Forester -------
<string id="forester_mutanthammer_0">
		<text>[Mutanthammer] I found this gun on Orion.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_mutanthammer_1">
		<text>Ah yes, the Mutanthammer. I remember this gun, it was me who modified it! 
			Mainly I fluted the barrel and replaced some of it's components with a lighter material to cut off some weight. Of course it also comes with a downside - the gun will wear faster than a standard Saiga.
			Took me some time, but I'm really proud of it. So you're the new owner - I hope it will serve you well! Here, let me clean it for you and repair it in order to make it pristine again. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_mutanthammer_2">
		<text>Thank you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_mutanthammer_3">
		<text>No problem! \n \n...\n \n Here, as good as new! Good hunting with it!</text>
	</string>

<string id="forester_legendary_0_0">
		<text>What's the story behind that Bloodsucker trophy?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_1">
		<text>Oh that's Moloch - the brother of Vlad and Drakul.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_2">
		<text>Moloch? Vlad? Drakul? Since when do mutants have names?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_3">
		<text>Since I gave a name to these mutants. Of course they are not any Bloodsuckers - they are very ancient beings... they've been around since the earlier days of the Zone - and around here, being old means something.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_04">
		<text>Vlad and Drakul? That doesn't sound very original for Bloodsuckers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_05">
		<text>I don't care if it's original, what matters to me is that it suits them. Besides, if you believe you're more creative - find a mutant deserving a name and prove it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_4">
		<text>Brothers? How do you know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_5">
		<text>I don't know - but for me they are brothers. I met them together - here in this forest. The first Bloodsuckers I've ever seen, I didn't know that such devils could even exist... but they do...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_6">
		<text>What is the story behind them?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_7">
		<text>Where to begin? From where they came - I don't know... But I still remember the first time I met them. It was not long after the second great explosion, the one which created this hell. 
			I picked up a distress radio call of survivors - a military scout squad which got lost in the Zaton swamps. Apparently their commander walked into a Vortex and with him their only map got shredded. 
			Imagine giving only one map for a whole squad - but it seems some things didn't change since the old days. Nevertheless, I found the two survivors and promised to lead them back to their headquarters - back in the days the Military still had a presence in the Army Warehouses.
			We reached this forest at dusk - I wanted to overnight at this complex, but these boys were eager to rejoin their base. Nowadays, crossing the forest at night would mean certain death, but you know back then most of these mutants were quite rare and didn't yet reach the southern parts of the Zone. 
			So we made a compromise - we were to take a rest and have something to eat and continue our journey after having warmed our bellies with food and our spirit with vodka. We entered the forest to gather some firewood and cooked some meat on a clearing. I don't know what attracted them - the smell of food or maybe the laughter...
			I left the fireplace to take a piss while the two soldiers continued fooling around. When returned to the fire I saw one of them lying on the ground - hissing from laughter I thought... it was only when I stood next to him that I noticed the blood gurgling out of his throat. I looked up - the other stood there with wide eyes and behind him...
			I don't know which of the brothers it was, but that was the first Bloodsucker I saw in my life. I didn't understand - I simply froze. That's when I felt tentacles grapling around my neck - strong and hot was that grip! I wasn't thinking - I grabbed a piece of burning wood and struck behind me! 
			The Bloodsucker immediately let go of me, and I scrambled off, running for my life! That's how I met Moloch, Vlad and Drakul! 
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_8">
		<text>Damn... but you managed to shoot Moloch? How did that happen?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_9">
		<text>I met the brothers many times since then! At first I shunned that forest, until I noticed that they are night creatures. I started to track them, gather informations on this new danger lurking in my wood. I tried to lay traps - the first worked but I wasn't able to capitalise on it, but the brothers also learned and started to avoid them.
			Sometimes I managed to wound one - sometimes they managed to wound me. I tried to find their lair by following their foodsteps - to no avail, I never found the exact location. This continued until one day, some bandits tried to jump me. They tried to extort me - I refused. It escalated and they ended up dead - except one! He was wounded and out cold - bleeding to death. 
			So I decided not to let a good corpse go to waste and I carried him into the forest as bait. I tied him to a tree and waited in ambush for the brothers. And sure enough they came - surrounding that poor fellow. Yes, it was not right for me to do that to a fellow man - to expose him to such horros without giving him a fighting chance... But back then I thought it was a good idea.
			While they were gulping on their easy prey, I took aim and patiently waiting for my shot. And I shot - it went right through Moloch's heart. Vlad and Drakul screached up in fright and took off - and I took my trophy. \n \n
			Since then I never saw them again, they retreated deep into the forest and rarely come out anymore - they let most of their hunting be done by their conspecifics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_10">
		<text>Tell me where to find them - I will hunt them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_11">
		<text>I believe that is enough - I still want to be able to sleep.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_12">
		<text>Then you are a fool! They mean certain death - don't be so rash as to believe you'll be able to master them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_13">
		<text>They are mutants, Forester, you don't honestly believe they stopped killing, do you? They have to be destroyed - especially if they are as dangerous as you say!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_14">
		<text>You're right - patience is in order. We have to wait for an opportune moment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_15">
		<text>Of course I don't believe they stopped murdering - but it's not your duty putting an end to them! Maybe I wasn't clear enough - they are not your normal Bloodsuckers, they are much worse. They are like a force of nature - we have to live with them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_16">
		<text>I protest - I have proven myself, I'm a capable hunter! I faced and mastered many terrors here - I can do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_17">
		<text>I know - you're valant and your skills are great! But this is an order of magnitude which you haven't faced yet - you're overestimating your own strenght - you're rash and want to hurry and this makes you prone to mistakes. 
		Don't ask of me to be guilty of your death - keep your strength for other mutants, don't waste away your life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_18">
		<text>Forester, have trust in younger people! At some point they have to be stopped, and our chances are better if you would help instead of trying to shelter me. Tell me, how to prepare and I will!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_19">
		<text>Aah, young people... so overconfident. You don't understand - you will not only face them, but also their brethren! \n \n... \n \nBut I can see it in your eyes, you're determined.
		Tell you what, bring me the hearts of five Bloodsuckers, and I'll tell you how to find them... at least you will have experience facing these devils... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_20">
		<text>I will not disappoint you! Consider it done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_21">
		<text>Be careful out there young Stalker! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_22">
		<text>Yes, I'm glad you're seeing reason.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_0_23">
		<text>Well said, let's turn our minds to more pleasant things.</text>
	</string>

<string id="forester_legendary_1_0">
		<text>About Vlad and Drakul. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_1">
		<text>What is it? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_2">
		<text>I want to hunt them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_3">
		<text>Tell me the story again how you first met them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_4">
		<text>Tell me the story again how you shot Moloch.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_5">
		<text>It was not long after the second great explosion, the one which created this hell. 
			I picked up a distress radio call of survivors - a military scout squad which got lost in the Zaton swamps. Apparently their commander walked into a Vortex and with him their only map got shredded. 
			Imagine giving only one map for a whole squad - but it seems some things didn't change since the old days. Nevertheless, I found the two survivors and promised to lead them back to their headquarters - back in the days the Military still had a presence in the Army Warehouses.
			We reached this forest at dusk - I wanted to overnight at this complex, but these boys were eager to rejoin their base. Nowadays, crossing the forest at night would mean certain death, but you know back then most of these mutants were quite rare and didn't yet reach the southern parts of the Zone. 
			So we made a compromise - we were to take a rest and have something to eat and continue our journey after having warmed our bellies with food and our spirit with vodka. We entered the forest to gather some firewood and cooked some meat on a clearing. I don't know what attracted them - the smell of food or maybe the laughter...
			I left the fireplace to take a piss while the two soldiers continued fooling around. When returned to the fire I saw one of them lying on the ground - hissing from laughter I thought... it was only when I stood next to him that I noticed the blood gurgling out of his throat. I looked up - the other stood there with wide eyes and behind him...
			I don't know which of the brothers it was, but that was the first Bloodsucker I saw in my life. I didn't understand - I simply froze. That's when I felt tentacles grapling around my neck - strong and hot was that grip! I wasn't thinking - I grabbed a piece of burning wood and struck behind me! 
			The Bloodsucker immediately let go of me, and I scrambled off, running for my life! That's how I met Moloch, Vlad and Drakul!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_6">
		<text>I started to track the brothers, gather informations on this new danger lurking in my wood. I tried to lay traps - the first worked but I wasn't able to capitalise on it, but the brothers also learned and started to avoid them.
			Sometimes I managed to wound one - sometimes they managed to wound me. I tried to find their lair by following their foodsteps - to no avail, I never found the exact location. This continued until one day, some bandits tried to jump me. They tried to extort me - I refused. It escalated and they ended up dead - except one! He was wounded and out cold - bleeding to death. 
			So I decided not to let a good corpse go to waste and I carried him into the forest as bait. I tied him to a tree and waited in ambush for the brothers. And sure enough they came - surrounding that poor fellow. Yes, it was not right for me to do that to a fellow man - to expose him to such horros without giving him a fighting chance... But back then I thought it was a good idea.
			While they were gulping on their easy prey, I took aim and patiently waiting for my shot. And I shot - it went right through Moloch's heart. Vlad and Drakul screached up in fright and took off - and I took my trophy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_7">
		<text>[Bloodsucker Hearts] I brought proof that I'm able to hunt Bloodsuckers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_8">
		<text>I killed the Calydonian Boar! And Vlad and Drakul will meet the same fate if you tell me where to find them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_9">
		<text>Impressive... I'm reluctant to tell you this, but I believe a promise is a promise... So listen carefully - their lair is deep in the forest to the east of here - in the proximity of an old soviet tank. Where exactly - I don't know but that doesn't matter.
			You will have to bait them out, and I believe to know how to do it but you won't like it... You will have to dress my old overcoat - it's the one I had while I was hunting them in the old days, it will have my smell and they will believe that it's me who dares to meet them. 
			It's old - so don't expect good protection... I did some repairs and added two fasteners so you can use two attachments - so choose wisely! And of course you will have to do it during the night, when they feel confident in the protection the dark provides - else they will not dare to affront "me"...
			\n \nAre you still up to it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_10">
		<text>Impressive... I might have underestimated your skill and experience! I'm reluctant to tell you this, but you might be ready... Alright, so listen carefully - their lair is deep in the forest to the east of here - in the proximity of an old soviet tank. Where exactly - I don't know but that doesn't matter.
			You will have to bait them out, and I believe to know how to do it but you won't like it... You will have to dress my old overcoat - it's the one I had while I was hunting them in the old days, it will have my smell and they will believe that it's me who dares to meet them. 
			It's old - so don't expect good protection... I did some repairs and added two fasteners so you can use two attachments - so choose wisely! And of course you will have to do it during the night, when they feel confident in the protection the dark provides - else they will not dare to affront "me"...
			\n \nAre you still up to it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_11">
		<text>I believe that is enough.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_23">
		<text>Yes, I still am.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_24">
		<text>To be honest I have to think about it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_25">
		<text>Alright, then come see me the night you want to set out - shortly after sunset. Prepare for a prolonged battle, it's very likely that you will have to affront their brethren too! Stock up on shells, medicine and so on. Don't underestimate this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_26">
		<text>There is no shame in being afraid of mortal danger! Take your time to think about it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_1_27">
		<text>Alright, let's talk about something else.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
<string id="forester_legendary_2_0">
		<text>About the hunt for Vlad and Drakul. </text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_2_1">
		<text>What is it? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_2_2">
		<text>I am ready for the hunt.</text>
	</string>
<string id="forester_legendary_2_3">
		<text>I am ready for the hunt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_2_4">
		<text>I need more time.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="forester_legendary_2_5">
		<text>Can you tell me about the plan again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_2_6">
		<text>Sure, listen carefully: You will have to do it during the night, when they feel confident in the protection the dark provides. Their lair is deep in the forest to the east of here - in the proximity of an old soviet tank. Where exactly - I don't know but that doesn't matter.
			You will have to bait them out, and I believe to know how to do it but you won't like it... You will have to adone my old overcoat - it's the one I had while I was hunting them in the old days, it will have my smell and they will believe that it's me who dares to meet them. 
			It's old - so don't expect good protection... I did some repairs and added two fasteners so you can use two attachments - so choose wisely! And I have the strong suspicion that you will not only have to face them, but their brethren too!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_2_7">
		<text>Alright, I see you're adamant. Here is the coat - you will not have to wear it on your way there, but try to put it on shortly before reaching the tank. Do you remember the way? It's deep in the forest, 
		east of here, but to reach it you have to pass through an old mine tunnel a bit to the south. After passing it you turn north again an you walk for quite some time. The tank is hidden by a small hill - ready yourself there and approach the tank carefully.
		I'm not sure how they will react, but maybe they will send some of their brethren first to tire you out. Remember - you have to do it by night! If the sun rises, they will retreat. You will need to set out shortly after sunset...\n \nNow good luck young Stalker - may the night be in your favour.</text>
	</string>
<string id="forester_legendary_2_8">
		<text>Very good. Come see me after shortly after sunset - I'll give you the coat then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_2_9">
		<text>No problem - you know you don't have to do this. Let's talk about something else.</text>
	</string>	

<string id="forester_legendary_3_0">
		<text>Are there other named mutants?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_1">
		<text>Yes there are... there is the Calydonian Boar. Butcher named him, the scourge of any hunter in the Great Swamp region. Then there is Moby Dick - the white Pseudogiant. Gonta is intimately acquainted to him. Finally there is Chyort - the Chimera male.
			Evasive fucker - the only known survivor is Trapper.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_2">
		<text>Tell me more about the Calydonian Boar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_3">
		<text>Tell me more about Moby Dick.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_4">
		<text>Tell me more about Chyort.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_5">
		<text>Thank you for these informations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_6">
		<text>He's the patron saint of any boar in the Great Swamp - many hunters are known to have died by his tusks when they hunted for his brethren. His hide is said to be as thick as scales of Zmei Gorynich. Butcher tried to hunt him in the past - according to him he met that beast twice - and twice that boar shrugged off his shotgun blasts as it were nothing!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_7">
		<text>Moby Dick - Gonta's nemesis. He carries that name because he's large as a whale - and an albino! That Pseudogiant killed his childhood friend, and since then Gonta is hunting him, and for years he eluded his vengeance. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_8">
		<text>Yes, Chyort... the devil himself. They say one strike would be enough to even cleave Sidorovich in half! Not that I ever met Sidorovich, but according to the rumors, it sounds like quite a feat! No one knows where his lair is, but he sometimes wanders into different regions to either eat or procreate! 
		Trapper says that the stronger Chimeras are his offspring - considering the amount of strong chimeras, you can imagine that Chyort's hunger for flesh is only surpassed by his lust.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_3_10">
		<text>No problem, I hope this will serve as a cautionary tale - don't fuck with these mutants!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="forester_legendary_4_0">
		<text>I didn't manage to kill the Bloodsuckers in time - dawn was upon me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_4_1">
		<text>Don't worry young Stalker, the most important is that you're still alive! You will have another chance another night. Come see me if you wish to give it another shot.</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="forester_legendary_5_0">
		<text>Good news! Vlad and Drakul won't hunt these forests anymore!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forester_legendary_5_1">
		<text>Excellent! Great work! You did a great deed tonight! Let's drink to your accomplishment!</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="st_forester_legendary_1_info">
		<text>Forester: You are getting close to their hunting spot. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_forester_legendary_2_info">
		<text>Forester: My wounds start aching again, Vlad and Drakul are coming out of their hiding. Good luck Stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_forester_legendary_3_info">
		<text>Forester: You  managed to kill the younger Bloodsuckers, but the sun is already rising and Vlad and Drakul will not dare to fight during the day. You will have to try another time. Come see me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_forester_legendary_4_info">
		<text>Forester: Remember that you have to confront the brothers on their own territory. You might need to get closer to the tank again.</text>
	</string>
	
---- Doctor Alyosha Shyogolov ----	
	
<string id="st_shyogolov_trouble_1_info">
		<text>Alyosha Shyogolov: Emergency! I request help of any nearby Stalker. I'm Doctor Alyosha Shyogolov - I'm surrounded by a horde of Snorks in the Agroprom Train tunnel. I request emergency extradition by any nearby Stalker.</text>
	</string>
<string id="st_shyogolov_trouble_2_info">
		<text>Alyosha Shyogolov: This is an Emergency! I request urgent help. I'm Doctor Alyosha Shyogolov - I'm surrounded by a horde of Snorks in the Agroprom Train tunnel. Please, they are getting closer.</text>
	</string>
<string id="st_shyogolov_trouble_3_info">
		<text>Alyosha Shyogolov: I'm Doctor Alyosha Shyogolov - I'm surrounded by a horde of Snorks in the Agroprom Train tunnel. Make haste - they have trapped me!</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_0">
		<text>A-a-are they gone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Who?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_2">
		<text>The Snorks of course!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_3">
		<text>I guess so - I only saw a couple at the entrance, but I have no idea where the others went.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_4">
		<text>Ah, I must have scarred them off! You're welcome!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_5">
		<text>Right... Are you Alyosha?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Doctor Alyosha Shyogolov - for you Doctor Shyogolov - proper etiquette has to be kept after all, even in such a forsaken place like this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_7">
		<text>Alright ... Doctor Shyogolov, what are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_8">
		<text>Whatever Alyosha, what are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_9">
		<text>I was on an expedition for Sakharov concerning the recovery of a very important document for our research! We are scientists after all. Suddenly I heard a terrible screech and I turned around - a horde of Snorks! I immediately retreated into the tunnel to fend them off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_10">
		<text>I will allow these familiarities, considering we fought together and forged a bond in blood together. 
			I was on an expedition for Sakharov concerning the recovery of a very important document for our research! We are scientists after all. Suddenly I heard a terrible screech and I turned around - a horde of Snorks! I immediately retreated into the tunnel to fend them off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_11">
		<text>Hmm, alright. What would you consider to be an appropriate reward for my troubles?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_12">
		<text>For your troubles? You just said that there were no Snorks outsides!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_13">
		<text>Ah I see. I'll be on my way then, I lost enough time with you - good luck with your mutant samples.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_14">
		<text>What the fuck? You were begging on the channels for help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_15">
		<text>Wait! Considering your altruistic - although unrequired - inclination to help me, I will return the favor!
				I'll be escorting you back to the Agroprom Factories!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_16">
		<text>Begging for help? Me? I protest: Doctor Alyosha Shyogolov never calls for backup! I was simply informing the other Stalkers not to get close in order to not be caught in the crossfire - like any professional would do.
			\n \nBut you're right, considering your altruistic - although unrequired - inclination to help me, I will return the favor!
			I'll be escorting you back to the Agroprom Factories!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_17">
		<text>Ehm, that's kind of you, but I don't need to go there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_18">
		<text>Alright, I wanted to go there either way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_19">
		<text>I insist! The Zone is dangerous out there - you'll be safer with my trusted Nosorog and Scar as your companions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_20">
		<text>I see... well then let's get going, I don't have all day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_start_dialog_21">
		<text>Excellent! Lead the way!</text>
	</string>
	
	
<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_0">
		<text>Seems that we arrived.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_1">
		<text>Indeed, now that you reached safety you won't need my help anymore.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_2">
		<text>Right... well good luck in the future.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_3">
		<text>Wait! I just noticed, my Nosorog suit was damaged while escorting you here! Ah what a shame, now I can't go on an fullfil Sakharov's order...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_4">
		<text>For real? How did that happen?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_5">
		<text>No idea, probably one of the Snorks damaged an hydraulic pump while I was fighting them off...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_6">
		<text>Hmm, I don't see anyting wrong with your suit...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_7">
		<text>Of course not, this is not a Primus after all! And what do you know about Nosorogs?! Luckily I always carry tools for an emergency repair with me, but that will take some time... Do you know what? 
		Maybe you can recover the documents while I proceed with the repairs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_8">
		<text>Will you pay me this time?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_9">
		<text>Of course I will repay you for your troubles! Don't worry!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_10">
		<text>Alright, where can I find these documents?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_11">
		<text>In the possession of Mozgotlen... or what is left of him. You see, he was member of an expedition to the Great Swamps when an Emission hit. The poor guy didn't make it to a safeplace and turned into a zombie. 
		Shame I wasn't there, on my watch nobody would have suffered such a fate. But what can I do, I cannot be everywhere and once, now can I? Nevertheless, the guy turned zombie and walked off... with the possession he was carrying. You will have to recover it! He has a Sapphire suit, so he should stand out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_12">
		<text>Alright, and where can I find him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_13">
		<text>Ah right, I forgot not everyone is as an experienced tracker as I am. \n \nHis PDA continued to work and we were able to see his movement from the Great Swamp to this sector, but then the PDA became static. 
		I would advise you to check the region between south of here and the Great Swamps. He should be somewhere - and with him the documents. Don't fret my friend, a zombie's aim is even worse than yours! I would have been glad to show you how it is done, but you know - my will is strong, but my armor is weak.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_14">
		<text>Whatever, as long as the pay is fine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_0_15">
		<text>The pay? Ah, you mean the reward. Don't worry, it will be invaluable. Now excuse me, I need to find some Stalkers whom I can regale with my tales.</text>
	</string>

<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_2_0">
		<text>I found your documents.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_2_1">
		<text>Marvelous! I knew a mere zombie wouldn't stop you! You're made out of harder wood - not yet an equal to my natural prowess, but you're on the best way to become one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_2_2">
		<text>Yes, sure... what about the payment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_2_3">
		<text>Yes of course! Let me give you an invaluable insight into my knowledge! Listen:  \n \nConfidence is a key tool in every Stalker’s arsenal. Confidence leads to opportunity. It makes a Stalker take that impossible shot. Makes us accept the hardest missions, reach farther into an anomaly field for artifacts, or lure an angry bloodsucker from a den. 
		Confidence makes me venture out on an easy bandit extermination without even needing to wear my Nosorog. Makes me tell about my achievements while sitting on a throne of my enemies. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_2_4">
		<text>I'm listening...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_2_5">
		<text>What the fuck? Are you kidding me? I want money not a story.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_2_6">
		<text>Stalkers who are content to defend their little corner of the Zone will be safe, but they will inevitably rarely venture beyond that little corner. 
		Brave Stalkers can, and will, do incredible things. Strelok himself found the strength to take on the entire Zone and defeat the C-Consciousness, all while suffering the effects of trauma-induced amnesia.
		Of course, that could have just been started because Sidorovich reportedly threatened to break Strelok’s kneecaps for not paying him back in Roubles for saving his life. We may never know. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_2_7">
		<text>Alright, thank you! That was very interesting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_2_8">
		<text>What the fuck? This is not payment!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_2_9">
		<text>Nice story, but where is the money?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_2_10">
		<text>Thanks, I plan to write it down some day. Maybe give it a catchy title, like "The Stalkers Testament" or something like that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="alyosha_shyogolov_2_11">
		<text>My pupil, don't you realise it? This knowledge is invaluable, it's worth more than mere money! Stalkers would kill to get their hands on this! 
		Maybe you're still to green behind your ears to realise what gift I just made you... don't worry, I have a forgiving nature, I won't hold a grudge! 
		\n \nAlas we have to finish our conversation now - I must make preparation for my expedition back to the bunker.</text>
	</string>
	
--- Vybegallo and the Scientists---

--Quest 1--

- Vybegallo-

<string id="vybegallo_start_0">
		<text>What to you want? I'm busy!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_1">
		<text>Greetings Vybegallo. I got your Tuna Bag.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_2">
		<text>Nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_3">
		<text>Then might I ask you to not stand in the way of science?</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_111">
		<text>Ah marvelous! Thank you mon cher! Science will not forget your contribution to progress! I believe a reward is in order.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_112">
		<text>Thanks. Why is that much tuna important to science?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_113">
		<text>Thanks. I'll be on my way then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_114">
		<text>That's food for my satis... no that doesn't concern you, mon cher. But yes ... maybe you can help me out? You work with Butcher, right? So you must be a hunter too...
		Well, very well... you can be discrete, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_115">
		<text>Yes, yes ... ah wait, wait mon cher! Maybe you can help me out? You work with Butcher, right? So you must be a hunter too...
		Well, very well... you can be discrete, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_4">
		<text>Ah yes, so you work with Butcher? Well, very well... you can be discrete, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_5">
		<text>Yes of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_6">
		<text>I don't like the direction this is going. What do you want?</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_7">
		<text>Excellent! You see mon cher, I need some mutant parts - for scientific reasons of course! For the sake of progress, mon cher. 
		I would need two fracture hands, one Bloodsucker heart and a sample from a Pseudogiant, doesn't matter what, a hand, an eye, it's hide. Bring it to me and I'll compensate you for your troubles. Let's say... 10.000 for everything? What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_8">
		<text>Mon cher, why this attitude? I'm a scientist, a man dedicated to science! I need some mutant parts - for strictly scientific reasons of course! For the sake of progress, mon cher. 
		I would need two fracture hands, one Bloodsucker heart and a sample from a Pseudogiant, doesn't matter  what, a hand, an eye, it's hide. Bring it to me and I'll compensate you for your troubles. Let's say... 10.000 for everything?</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_9">
		<text>Alright, I see what I can do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_10">
		<text>I don't know, I have to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_11">
		<text>Perfect!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_start_12">
		<text>Think, but don't take too long, time is of an essence for me!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="vybegallo_time_0">
		<text>Concerning that job.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="vybegallo_time_1">
		<text>Oui mon cher, will you help science out?</text>
	</string>	


<string id="vybegallo_2_0">
		<text>About your mutant parts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_1">
		<text>Oui mon cher? Did you find something?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="vybegallo_2_2">
		<text>I found a pseudogiant eye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_3">
		<text>I found a pseudogiant hand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_4">
		<text>I found a pseudogiant hide.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_41">
		<text>I found the fracture hands.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_42">
		<text>I found the Bloodsucker heart.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_5">
		<text>No I have to look further.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_6">
		<text>What are you waiting for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_7">
		<text>This is marvellous, mon cher! Your contribution to science will not be forgotten!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_71">
		<text>I believe that was everything. Can you hand me the finders fee?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_72">
		<text>Absolutely mon cher! Here take this, for your troubles!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_73">
		<text>About the other parts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_8">
		<text>I've talked to your collegues Vybegallo. This letter is for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_9">
		<text>Wha-what? What did you do? What did you tell them? What is this??? \n \n...\n \nHow dare he! The tsarist gendarmerie did not frighten me, and Sakharov will not frighten me!! \n \n And you, you traitor!!! You rat!!! Out of my sight!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_2_10">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>

<string id="vybegallo_3_0">
		<text>You wanted to see me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_1">
		<text>Yes mon cher, we... we have a problem. My experiment was on the way to become a tremendous success, oui mon cher, truly a scientific revolution! But...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_2">
		<text>...but?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_3">
		<text>But he's not there anymore! I went down to check upon him, and he's gone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_4">
		<text>"He"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_5">
		<text>What happened, did someone steal your experiment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_6">
		<text>Yes, the Partially Satisfied Man - the necessary intermediary to the Fully Satisfied Man! Ah, imagine a man who is able to satisfy all his needs by himself! 
		Wouldn't that be a scientific marvel mon cher? \n \n And now he's gone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_7">
		<text>An eventuality which should not be ruled out, but... I rather believe he broke out... Maybe I didn't give him enough food?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_8">
		<text>Broke out? How is that possible?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_9">
		<text>How it is possible? By being a colossal scientific success mon cher, that's how it is possible!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_10">
		<text>Is "he" dangerous?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_11">
		<text>Barely mon cher, barely. But we cannot allow him to run off, that would attract unwarranted attention... n'est-ce pas?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_12">
		<text>What exactly is "he"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_13">
		<text>The Partially Satisfied Man, mon cher! You need to pay attention when I'm telling you about this!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_14">
		<text>No I mean, what is he really? What does he look like?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_15">
		<text>Difficult to say, I never saw him after he hatched... He should probably resemble me, as he has part of my DNA? But these are details mon cher, don't bother about it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_16">
		<text>What do you want me to do about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_17">
		<text>Mon cher, it's with a heavy heart that I have to ask you to liquidate my experiment. 
			What a shame, what a loss for science! But we cannot allow him to run off - that would only attract unnecessary attention to my experiments!
			You wouldn't believe how reactionary some of my collegues are. But at least I should be able to gather his remains in order to conduct further experiments - progress cannot be stopped, n'est-ce pas mon cher?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_18">
		<text>Where can I find "him"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_19">
		<text>He should still be somewhere in the Underground.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_20">
		<text>What is the pay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_21">
		<text>Always so materialistic! But yes, don't worry about the pay - it will be more than enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_22">
		<text>Alright, I'll do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_23">
		<text>I have to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_24">
		<text>Excellent mon cher, excellent! Make your preparations and come see me before setting off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_3_25">
		<text>Then hurry up mon cher, time is running out!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="vybegallo_4_0">
		<text>About your "experiment".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_4_1">
		<text>What is it, mon cher?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_4_2">
		<text>I'm ready to set out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_4_3">
		<text>I need more time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_4_4">
		<text>Excellent! Don't make him suffer!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_4_5">
		<text>Then hurry up mon cher, time is running out!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="vybegallo_5_0">
		<text>I killed your "experiment".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_1">
		<text>Marvellous, excellent work mon cher!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_2">
		<text>You didn't fucking tell me that you were breeding a fucking Pseudogiant!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_3">
		<text>Ah very interesting, so the Pseudogiant DNA took the overhand? This is extraordinary! It was only supposed to improve his resilience in this climate, but the Pseudogiant took completely over?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_4">
		<text>What the fuck are you doing? There are enough dangers in the Zone - why are you creating new ones?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_5">
		<text>Mon cher, this is scientific progress! Some risks have to be taken! Marie Curie took risks for humankind - Yuri Gagarin too! The list is long, mon cher! Now we know more, and we won't repeat the mistakes! Consider it a scientific success!
			But I see that you're new to the scientific method - and I believe that I owe you a reward. Take this! I... borrowed it from the institute after a disagreement. It's a prototype - but I believe it should be quite useful to... more practical oriented people. Thank you very much mon cher!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_6">
		<text>Yes, now please give me the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_7">
		<text>Straight to the point as always. Alright, here are the funds. Enjoy - and thank you for helping me... cover up this incident!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_8">
		<text>Fuck you - don't contact me again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vybegallo_5_9">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>		



	
-the others-
<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_0">
		<text>Do you know a fellow scientist called "Vybegallo"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_1">
		<text>Vybegallo? Well, yes I know him… is there something with him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_2">
		<text>No, I only met him recently.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_3">
		<text>Okay… did he tell you something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_4">
		<text>No, we barely spoke.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_5">
		<text>Alright… Please tell me if you know something about what he is up to. He himself is not dangerous, but his scientific research on the other hand… My advice to you, don’t get caught up in his dealings.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_6">
		<text>He asked me to help him with his science experiment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_7">
		<text>He asked you for help? No offence, but you don’t look like a lab assistant. Why would Vybegallo need a Stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_8">
		<text>He asked me to find some artifact for him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_9">
		<text>An artifact? This seems unusual for him, but maybe he finally found a normal research topic…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_10">
		<text>He asked me to find some mutant parts for him.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_101">
		<text>What... what kind of mutant parts?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_102">
		<text>Fracture, Bloodsucker and Pseudogiant parts. Why?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_11">
		<text>What? This is horrible!!! \n \n… \n \nYou see, years ago Vybegallo got into his head to create the “ideal man” – or the “fully satisfied man” as he calls it, but his experiments were one disaster after another. I'm not talking about the ethical aspects, my god, although they are bad enough. His first version, the fully unsatisfied man, was a miserable creature who dwindled away under our very eyes... But Vybegallo was not discouraged and continued his experiments.
		\n \nAfter one especially egregious attempt which nearly cost the life of half his department, his research institute kicked him out. But Vybegallo somehow managed to pull some strings and wound up here! I’m afraid he didn’t give up on this experiment… Who knows what he will unleash?  \n \nI implore you, don’t help him out! \n \n No this is not enough, here take this order to him and make him understand that he has to cease any dangerous experiments immediately. I don’t know how much he promised you, I can’t put much on the table at the moment, but I will find some reward. \n\nWill you help us out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_12">
		<text>Sure, I will deliver the letter and not help him out any further.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_13">
		<text>No deal, I honour my contracts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_14">
		<text>Thanks I appreciate it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_start_15">
		<text>You fool.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_0">
		<text>I brought the order to Vybegallo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_1">
		<text>And? How did he take it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_2">
		<text>Not very well, he screamed something about the tsarist gendarmerie and that you won't frighten him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_3">
		<text>I feared as much... Nevertheless thanks for your help, here your reward: it's not much but I hope it can help you out there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_4">
		<text>What will you do about Vybegallo?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_5">
		<text>I don't know, I have to council with the director... \n \nIn the meantime I'll send a global message to everyone that Vybegallo is under sanction and that whoever trades in mutant parts with him will be excluded from any business with us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_6">
		<text>Sanctioned? Does that work here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_2_7">
		<text>To be honest, no. The largest traders will maybe refrein from doing business with him, but individual Stalkers don't give a shit about sanctions. But we have to do something, and it will make at least some people think twice about working with him.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="st_sakharov_vybegallo_1_info">
		<text>Attention! Important announcement: \n \nThe scientist Amvrosiy Vybegallo is under sanction! \n \nAnyone who is caught trading with him in mutant parts will be sanctioned too!</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_3_0">
		<text>I found this in the mercenary base in Zaton. [Pseudogiant parts order]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_3_1">
		<text>What is it? \n \n...\n \nThat shit head. \n \nListen to me; what I tell you now is off the record, noone will acknowledge this: I talked to the director and he agrees with me, Vybegallo has to stopped By.All.Means! He sanctioned the liquidation of Vybegallo if he continues his dangerous experiment. Well this is it! 
		I ask you - no I insist: kill Vybegallo. He cannot continue doing his experiments. \n \nI understand that you are a Stalker and won't do it for free. I can mobilise some funds for this and let go of some highly sofisticated devices. So what do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_3_2">
		<text>Amvrosiy Vybegallo will sleep with the snorks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_3_3">
		<text>No way, I am not an assassin.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_3_4">
		<text>Thank you. Remember, we never had this conversation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_3_5">
		<text>I understand. Remember, we never had this conversation.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_4_0">
		<text>Vybegallo is no more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_vybegallo_4_1">
		<text>I don't know what you're talking about.</text>
	</string>	

<string id="st_vybegallo_help_satisfied_man_info">
		<text>Vybegallo: Mon cher, we might have a problem on our hands... Can you come urgently?</text>
	</string>	
	
	
	
---- Sidorovich----
<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_0">
		<text>I need some money Sidorovich, do you have a better paying job to offer?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_1">
		<text>You’re in luck, I’m indeed hiring some guns at the moment… I’m putting together a team to take back the railway bridge crossing. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_2">
		<text>What happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_3">
		<text>The bandits recently reinforced that crossing and are asking for quite a high bribe to let people pass – very bad for business. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_4">
		<text>An assault? What’s the plan?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_5">
		<text>We will effectuate a pincer movement. Cold send a squad over to help out, under the leadership of a certain “Castor”, they should arrive soon at the northern farm. 
		My team will gather at the mill under the leadership of Pollux. \n\nYou will take on the role of messenger – you’ll first need to bypass the railway bridge to make contact with Castor and check if they are ready for the assault. 
		If they are ready, you return to the Mill where Castor will wait. If everyone is in place, tell Castor that the assault can begin. \n\nAny questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_6">
		<text>Why do I need to make contact in person. Can’t we use the PDA messenger to communicate with the Clear Sky squad?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_7">
		<text>Are you aware that to render PDA communication secure is a complicated procedure? You would have to exchange encryption and decryption keys manually - a huge hazzle. 
		Surprise is primordial in this assault – the PDA stays silent until the very moment the assault begins. \n\nAny other questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_8">
		<text>How do I bypass the railway bridge unseen?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_9">
		<text>You really are a rookie… well there is a small underway to the west of the bridge and the mill. It’s small, badly lit and a little dangerous but will suit our needs perfectly. \n\nAny other questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_10">
		<text>How much are you willing to pay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_11">
		<text>Considering that you are a rookie, you get a rookies pay. \n\nAny other question?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_12">
		<text>About the plan.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_13">
		<text>Yes, do you have any questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_14">
		<text>Can you tell me the plan again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_15">
		<text>What about the vehicle park to the east of the bridge? Won’t the bandits come in reinforcement?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_16">
		<text>That is very possible, and the reason why the assault has to be over as quick as possible. If the bandits send reinforcement, you beat them off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_17">
		<text>Can we not make a diversionary attack on the vehicle park?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_18">
		<text>I like that idea, but we don’t have enough manpower to make such an attack. The plan stays, we overwhelm the bridge defences and dig in our heels if they send reinforcement.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_19">
		<text>What if I take on the vehicle park by myself?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_20">
		<text>Damn dude, did you watch too many movies? This is not Rambo! But if you really want to prove yourself, be my guest. \n\nAny other questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_21">
		<text>No other questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_22">
		<text>Alright, so what do you say? Are you in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_23">
		<text>I’m in!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_24">
		<text>I need some time to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_25">
		<text>I have some more questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_26">
		<text>Alright, better now than later. Ask away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_27">
		<text>Alright! Gear up, and come see me if you’re ready!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_1_28">
		<text>Alright. Think about it, but hurry, Clear Sky is on their way.</text>
	</string>

<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_0">
		<text>About the Railway Bridge assault.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_1">
		<text>Yes, tell me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_2">
		<text>I am ready. Tell me what to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_3">
		<text>I am ready. I'll take part in the main assault.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_4">
		<text>I am ready. I'll make the diversionary attack on the vehicle park.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_5">
		<text>I need more time. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_6">
		<text>Alright. Let me remind you of your task so you don't fuck it up. You are to bypass the bandit forces and establish contact with Castor, the leader of the Clear Sky forces, in the northern village.
			If he's there, you're to return back to the mill and report to Pollux, my guy. If everything is in place, you're to take part in the assault. \n \nEverything clear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_7">
		<text>Alright. Let me remind you of your task so you don't fuck it up. You are to bypass the bandit forces and establish contact with Castor, the leader of the Clear Sky forces, in the northern village.
			If he's there, you're to return back to the mill and report to Pollux, my guy. If everything is in place, you're to take part in the assault. \n \nEverything clear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_8">
		<text>Are you sure? If that's how you want it, be my guest. It certainly will help the assault. I'll tell Pollux to send someone else to establish contact with Clear Sky. Is everything else clear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_9">
		<text>Alright, but get moving, we don't have much time left! Remember, suprise is of essence!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_10">
		<text>Everything clear. I'm on my way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_11">
		<text>Wait! I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_12">
		<text>Better now than later. What is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_14">
		<text>About the plan.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_2_15">
		<text>What is it?</text>
	</string>

<string id="sidorovich_railway_3_0">
		<text>The assault has been a success, the railway is ours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_3_1">
		<text>Good job! That checkpoint is of tremendous importance for our safety and our local economy. You deserve your reward Stalker! Here! 
			I recommend you to spend it here, to support your local business. I got tremendous deals for you, have a look!</text>
	</string>
<string id="sidorovich_railway_4_0">
		<text>The assault has been a success, the railway is ours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidorovich_railway_4_1">
		<text>Good job! Your diversionary attack was indeed of great help! Now that the checkpoint is ours, our safety and that of our local economy is guarded. You deserve your reward Stalker! Here! 
			I recommend you to spend it here, to support your local business. I got tremendous deals for you, have a look!</text>
	</string>



<string id="st_assault_railway_info_1">
		<text>Let's fuck those bandits up! URRRAAAAAAAA!!!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_assault_railway_info_2">
		<text>URRRAAAAAAAA!!!!!</text>
	</string>


<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Get lost Stalker, we're occupied.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Are you the guys Cold send in order to assault the railway bridge?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Yes we are - and you're the messenger? As you can see we're ready, I hope you guys too. So tell me, can we begin, can we get this over with?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_start_dialog_3">
		<text>Yeah, I'll join up with the guys on the other side and we'll give the sign.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_start_dialog_4">
		<text>Alright, we'll be waiting.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_1_0">
		<text>What a fight, I'm glad you made it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_1_1">
		<text>Yeah, that was quite tough. Thanks for the help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_1_2">
		<text>What are you going to do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_csky_leader_esc_5_7_1_3">
		<text>I have orders to guard this checkpoint.</text>
	</string>

<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_1">
		<text>I am the guy Sidorovich sent as a messenger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Good. Is the Clear Sky squad in place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_3">
		<text>They are. When does the rest of our guys arrive?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_4">
		<text>This is all there is. Sidorovich tends to be “frugal” in his hiring.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_5">
		<text>Fuck. At least the guys from Clear Sky came prepared…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Yeah those guys are reliable. Let us hope we will catch these banditfuckers with their pants down. The plan is easy; we approach – throw our grenades and assault. Are you ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_7">
		<text>Yes I’m ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_8">
		<text>Grenades? I don’t have any…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_9">
		<text>Shit mate, who comes to an assault without grenades? Here take this one – pay me a drink when we survived this bullshit. \n\nWell, enough chatting, we have to earn our pay now. Ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_start_dialog_10">
		<text>Let’s go!</text>
	</string>

<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_1_0">
		<text>What a fight! We made it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_1_1">
		<text>Yeah mate, that was crazy! I'm glad to see you made it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_1_2">
		<text>Yeah man, I'm glad to see you to! What will you do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_1_3">
		<text>I'll stay here and guard the passage.</text>
	</string>

<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_0">
		<text>Hey mate, I wanted to thank you for the grenade you gave me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_1">
		<text>No problem, I'm sure the bandits would disagree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_2">
		<text>[Zone Vodka] Here, this is for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_3">
		<text>[Nemiroff] Here, this is for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_4">
		<text>[Putinka] Here, this is for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_8">
		<text>[Stolichnaya] Here, this is for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_5">
		<text>Wait, I'll get a drink to thank you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_6">
		<text>That's mighty cool of you to remember, I will remember this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_stalker_leader_esc_5_9_2_7">
		<text>No problem mate.</text>
	</string>
---- What a Night ----

<string id="sasha_tolstoy_1_0">
		<text>Hey man, how you're doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_1_1">
		<text>Horrible, my head is splitting itself.</text>
	</string>
	
	
<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_0">
		<text>Hey man, how you're doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_1">
		<text>I'm doing formidable my friend, do you want a shot?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_2">
		<text>You seem to be in high spirit, what happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_3">
		<text>God smiled upon me my friend, my financial worries are no more!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_4">
		<text>Congrats!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_5">
		<text>Here have a drink with me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_6">
		<text>Sure let it flow!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_7">
		<text>Nah, I'm fine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_8">
		<text>Aaaah... \n \n C'mon, between the first and the second, the break is short!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_9">
		<text>You don't want, as you want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_10">
		<text>I can only agree with you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_11">
		<text>Thanks, but I don't want to become drunk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_12">
		<text>Here have some meat to chase the burn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_13">
		<text>Thanks. So tell me, what happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_14">
		<text>You won't believe it! Yesterday I was drinking with the boys and we played some cards. My luck turned bad and I lost all my money to Andrey.
	So, this morning I set out in order to make my money back - I figured if I managed to hunt some Flesh or Boars, I could sell their parts for some good money. I set off a bit later in the morning, but
	the sun was heavy, so I decided to take a short rest in the shadow of the old Church: I had a few bites and some sips of Vodka - to fight my headache, you understand?
	Suddenly I heard some guys talking behind the wall,  what a foul language, you can't imagine! Fuck, I thought, tongues like this only grow on these Renegade Gopniks,
	so I took my feet into my hands and ran away to the north. Luckily they didn't see me, so my skin was safe... might have forgotten my bottle though now that I think of it.
	Fuck it! I bypassed the cemetery and made my way to the pond -
	I figured that maybe I might catch some of these pigs watering. Aah, my friend, my intuition was right, there were two pigs taking a rest on the shore. 
	I snuck up and BAM - shot and missed. My hands were probably still shaky from yesterday evening... doesn't matter! The two pigs squeal up, taking off in the direction of the burned farmstead. 
	I lunch myself in pursuit, but I gave those two such a fright that one run straight into the flame anomaly! The pillar engulfed him immediately, roasting him on the spot.
	I cursed the heavens, impossible to make money of that pile of ashes now I thought. But then I noticed it... the pig probably kicked a Flame while running through the anomaly,
	and the artifact landed outside, ripe for the taking! Can you imagine it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_15">
		<text>Incredible! What luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_16">
		<text>Indeed, indeed! Let's have a drink to that!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_17">
		<text>Let's drink!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_18">
		<text>Ah my friend, I quite enjoy drinking with you! Let's have another one, to friendship!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_19">
		<text>I like drinking with you too! To friendship!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_20">
		<text>Here my friend, have a bite.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_21">
		<text>Alright, my turn to propose a toast!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_22">
		<text>Let it hear!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_23">
		<text>Our will shall not break, we drank, drink and will drink again!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_24">
		<text>To you, to us, to xcvb!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_2_25">
		<text>God is not stupid, he loves fives!</text>
	</string>

<string id="sasha_tolstoy_3_0">
		<text>Dude, what the fuck, what happened last night? I woke up in Khuyevo Kukuyevo!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_3_1">
		<text>Yeah man, you were fucking blasted, hahaha! We caroused quite hard, hahaha. I went back to the camp to get some more booze, but on my return you were gone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_3_2">
		<text>So what happened yesterday?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_3_3">
		<text>Ah, that my friend only the Author knows. You'll have to wait until he remembers...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sasha_tolstoy_3_4">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_shout_0">
		<text>Librarian: Oi mate, there you are. Come here for a second.</text>
	</string>
<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_shout_1">
		<text>Forgot about me and your debt? I see how it is asshole, I will remember.</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_0_0">
		<text>You wanted to talk?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_0_1">
		<text>Yes mate, indeed I wanted to talk. I see you're happy to have found your belongings untouched after a night of carousing, yes? 
		\n \nWell, your stuff didn't protect itself, I had to watch it the whole night so that noone gets too curious. I believe my care should be rewarded, don't you mate?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_0_2">
		<text>[500 roubles] Sure sure, thank you very much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_0_3">
		<text>You're kidding me right? You got all your stuff back and this is all you give me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_0_4">
		<text>[2.000 roubles] Sure sure, thank you very much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_0_5">
		<text>Hmm, you have trouble parting from your money don't you? Well can't blame you, although I would imagine that your stuff is worth much more to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_0_6">
		<text>[5.000 roubles] Sure sure, thank you very much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_0_7">
		<text>My man, no trouble at all! I see you're an upstanding lad, here, have a drink to counter this evil headache that must plague you. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_0_8">
		<text>I'm sorry mate, I don't have much in my pockets... I'll pay you when I have made some money...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_0_9">
		<text>Eh, you have money to carouse, but no money to pay me for savekeeping your belongings? \n \nTell you what mate, pay me tomorrow and I will consider you as a man of honour.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_0_10">
		<text>What do you mean? That is more than enough for sitting behind your bar and turning thumbs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_0_11">
		<text>[2.000 roubles] You're right, sorry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_0_12">
		<text>Fuck off then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_0_13">
		<text>Alright mate, no trouble, you're not the first Stalker whose arms are not long enough to reach far into his pockets.</text>
	</string>


<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_1_0">
		<text>I wanted to pay my debt to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_1_1">
		<text>Sure mate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_1_2">
		<text>[500 roubles] Here, and thank you very much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_1_3">
		<text>You're kidding me right? You got all your stuff back and this is all you give me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_1_4">
		<text>[2.000 roubles] Here, and thank you very much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_1_5">
		<text>Hmm, you have trouble parting from your money don't you? Well can't blame you, although I would imagine that your stuff is worth much more to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_1_6">
		<text>[5.000 roubles] Here, and thank you very much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_1_7">
		<text>My man, no trouble at all! I see you're an upstanding lad, here, have a drink to counter this evil headache that must plague you. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_1_8">
		<text>I'm sorry mate, I don't have much in my pockets... I'll pay you when I have made some money...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_1_9">
		<text>I'm not waiting much longer mate, get to it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_1_10">
		<text>What do you mean? That is more than enough for sitting behind your bar and turning thumbs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_1_11">
		<text>[2.000] You're right, sorry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_1_12">
		<text>Fuck off then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_what_night_barkeeper_1_13">
		<text>Alright mate, no trouble, you're not the first Stalker to be a bit stingy with his money.</text>
	</string>

<string id="barman_sektor_gaza_0_0">
		<text>Here is your CD.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_sektor_gaza_0_1">
		<text>My man!</text>
	</string>



---- Rush to the North and Brainscorcher reactions ------


	
<string id="fanatic_north_0_0">
		<text>Hey Fanatic, how are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_1">
		<text>To be honest, I'm overwhelmed with all these new rookies. Ever since you disabled the Brain Scorcher, more and more people are flocking to the Zone.
			That's not meant as a reproach, you did well to turn that off. Sidorovich is of course esctatic about all the new business opportunities and cheap labour, but I still have to try and train them. 
			There only are so many of them, and they rapidly loose patience and don't want to wait until I have time for them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_2">
		<text>I can help if you want to?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_3">
		<text>You can? That would be great! You know the drill, right? Go shoot some boars, and then show them how to find artifacts! And, ehm, would it trouble you to provide the supplies for them too?
			It's not a lot, some 20 buckshots, an Echo detector, a Empty Container and a bottle Nemiroff?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_4">
		<text>Sure Fanatic, the same you provided me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_5">
		<text>Thank you very much! Your apprentice will be Iliaz, he's quartering in the brick house on the other side of the street.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_6">
		<text>What? I'm not a charity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_7">
		<text>Ehm, okay... well don't bother then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_8">
		<text>Damn, good luck with that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fanatic_north_0_9">
		<text>Well, thanks...</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="nr_iliaz_0_0">
		<text>Hey Ilyaz, Fanatic send me to show you some basic skills to survive here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_0_1">
		<text>That's very kind of you Stalker! Where do we start?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_0_2">
		<text>First some hunting would be in order. There are some boars east of here, we'll hunt them together.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_0_3">
		<text>Alright, I'll be right behind you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_0_4">
		<text>Wait here, I still need to make some preparations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_0_5">
		<text>No problem, I'll wait here.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_iliaz_1_0">
		<text>You see, the boars charge you and you have to dodge them and get some shots in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_1_1">
		<text>I see. What's next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_1_2">
		<text>Next we'll go artifact hunting. There is an anomaly not far from here, a bit north west from the village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_1_3">
		<text>Alright, I'm behind you.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_iliaz_2_0">
		<text>We arrived. Here is a detector which shows you the presence of an artifact. The faster the beeping, the closer you are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_2_1">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_2_2">
		<text>You have bolts right? You throw them to see if there is an anomaly in front of you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_2_3">
		<text>Yeah, I have some.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_2_4">
		<text>Here is some Vodka. Anomalies are often radiated, or even worse. When you're back to my position, you finish this bottle. It helps.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_2_5">
		<text>Understood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_2_6">
		<text>Finally, here is a container. If you find an artifact, you'll put it inside this. This will nullify the radiation of the artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_2_7">
		<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_2_8">
		<text>Now go and try your luck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_2_9">
		<text>Ay ay Stalker.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_iliaz_3_0">
		<text>Why didn't you go all the way in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_3_1">
		<text>I saw this glimmering under the metal structure over there! Isn't that an Artifact?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_3_2">
		<text>What? That's a Stoneflower! You lucky bastard! You can either sell it to Sidorovich for some fast cash, or hang onto it and sell it to the Ecologists, they will pay much better.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_3_3">
		<text>Understood! Thanks for the tip!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_3_4">
		<text>[Lie] Ah, no luck. That artifact is worthless. But as you're new, I'll take it off your hands for 1000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_3_5">
		<text>Alright... I guess that's better than nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_3_6">
		<text>We should go back to the village now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_3_7">
		<text>Alright, I'll follow you.</text>
	</string>

<string id="nr_iliaz_4_0">
		<text>We are back at the village. I hope I helped you a bit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nr_iliaz_4_1">
		<text>Very much so! Thank you!</text>
	</string>


---- Shlitzer

<string id="bh_shlitzer_greeting">
		<text>And Stalker, are you happy with your pay?</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_shlitzer_start_0">
		<text>Did the man in the bunker scam you Stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_start_1">
		<text>He send me on an assault for only 2.000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_start_2">
		<text>No, he payed me well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_start_3">
		<text>Ha! Of course he did. Sidorovich taking advantage of rookies like you, a story as old as the Zone itself. But you know, not everyone here pays that miserably. 
		I might have a proposition for you if you're interested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_start_4">
		<text>That would be the first time he would pay anyone well. Maybe you don't know the worth of your labour yet... 
			If you want to find out, I might have a proposition for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_start_5">
		<text>I'm always interested in some work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_start_6">
		<text>I don't know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_start_7">
		<text>Good, good. But let's not talk here. Follow me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_start_8">
		<text>If you come to a decision, find me in the there to my left.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_start_9">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bh_shlitzer_0_0">
		<text>What kind of work do you propose?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_0_1">
		<text>That of the sensitive kind - discretion will be necessary and no moral qualms. But I also pay accordingly. Can you be discrete?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_0_2">
		<text>Depends. What is it you want me to do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_0_3">
		<text>You need to pick up a client from the Southern Checkpoint - a rich tourist looking for some excitement here. You are to pick him up and escort him to the Northern Farm. 
		Some people are waiting there, and when the client is finished, you're to bring him back to the Southern Checkpoint. Sounds easy right? You'll be payed good money to have a stroll with him - and of course to keep your mouth shut. Understood?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_0_4">
		<text>When would the pickup be?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_0_5">
		<text>During the night, around 22h to midnight. I already provided him a PDA, here is the contact. You're to wait for him at the jeep wreckage on the road to the Checkpoint. The soldiers are paid not to shoot him - that doesn't apply to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_0_6">
		<text>What will he be doing in the Northern Farm?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_0_7">
		<text>That doesn't concern you, and you're getting paid to not ask such questions. You're the escort, the Zone taxi. You pick him up and drop him off. Easy enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_0_8">
		<text>I have to think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_0_9">
		<text>Alright, but don't take too much time, or I will find someone else to do the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_0_10">
		<text>Alright, I'll do it. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_0_11">
		<text>Great! Remember, after 22h at the jeep wreckage! And don't let the guy die!</text>
	</string>

<string id="st_bh_shlitzer_pervert_tourist_lie_1">
		<text>YOU FUCKING MORON! THE CLIENT NEVER MADE IT BACK TO THE CHECKPOINT!!! WHAT HAPPENED???</text>
	</string>
<string id="st_bh_shlitzer_pervert_tourist_lie_2">
		<text>YOU FUCKING LIAR! THE CLIENT NEVER MADE IT BACK TO THE CHECKPOINT!!! WHAT HAPPENED???</text>
	</string>
<string id="st_bh_shlitzer_pervert_tourist_lie_3">
		<text>YOU FUCKED UP AND YOU ARE A DEAD MAN!!! DO YOU UNDERSTAND??? A FUCKING DEAD MAN!!!</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_01">
		<text>The client is back in safety.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_02">
		<text>[Lie] The client is back in safety.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_1">
		<text>Excellent. I hope everything was to his liking?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_2">
		<text>Yes, he was very... excited.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_3">
		<text>Perfect, perfect, a happy client is a returning client. \n \nHere is the money. 
		\n \nAnd how does it feel? Have you ever held that much between your hands? Feels nice no? If you want more, come see me, I have another job lined up for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_4">
		<text>To his liking yes, but not to mine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_5">
		<text>What do you mean?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_6">
		<text>Nothing, forget it. Give me the money and let's part ways.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_7">
		<text>He fucking shot a guy for excitement. Do you think that's normal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_8">
		<text>Why so bitchy? \n \nHere, take the money, this should bring you back to reality.
			\n \nAnd how does it feel? Have you ever held that much between your hands? Feels nice no? If you want more, come see me, I have another job lined up for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_9">
		<text>Why the fuck should you care? There is nothing normal about this place! The Zone is the jungle! Such is life around here - if people want to pay for something you don't ask twice, you provide! 
			\n \nListen, you came here for a reason right? The reason being money right? But did you think you will get it by being nice? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_10">
		<text>Hmm you might be right.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_11">
		<text>What the fuck are you talking about? The Zone is a though place yes, but catering to pervert tourists? Shooting innocent people? What's next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_12">
		<text>I understand my friend, you're still new around here. You come here expecting that the Zone plays according to the rules of the outer world, but fuck no, that will get you killed here. 
			\n \nThis here is a new world, a world where it's either to kill or to be killed. Shed every moral notion that you had, and maybe, only maybe you will survive here. \n \nHere, take the money, this should bring you back to reality.
			\n \nAnd how does it feel? Have you ever held that much between your hands? Feels nice no? If you want more, come see me, I have another job lined up for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_13">
		<text>What the fuck, are you some fucking altar boy? Do you know that your priest is driving a Mercedes and has three bastards running around? I've been to Perchesk Lavra - I only saw Rangerovers hahaha.
			\n \nWhat I mean is don't be holier than the pope. Now, take the money, this should bring you back to reality. I mean, what is done is done right? The world continues to turn, the birds continue to chirp, and the priests continue to drive their nice cars.
			\n \nAnd how does it feel? Have you ever held that much between your hands? Feels nice no? If you want more, come see me, I have another job lined up for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_14">
		<text>Whatever.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_15">
		<text>[Throw the money into his face] Fuck you and fuck the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_2_16">
		<text>No - fuck you!!! You will think of this moment when you're covering in a ditch and praying to your mother!!!</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_0">
		<text>The client is... dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_1">
		<text>What? What the fuck??? What happened???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_2">
		<text>I fucking shot him, that's what happened! You didn't tell me that he was some sadistic pervert! Did you know about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_3">
		<text>The Zone got him... wasn't anything I could do about it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_4">
		<text>Oh my fucking god, you fucking dimwit! Did you think you get payed top money for fucking sightseeing??? 
		If you're a fucking saint, what the fuck are you doing here? \n \nFuck fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck...
		\n \nDo you have any idea who you killed? That was not some random looser - that guy was not only a fucking lawyer but also a fucking politician! He was fucking connected! PEOPLE WILL COME LOOKING FOR HIM!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_5">
		<text>Not my problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_6">
		<text>Not your problem? NOT YOUR PROBLEM? Do you think when the fucking SBU comes knocking, I won't be your fucking problem???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_7">
		<text>Ah shit. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_8">
		<text>Yes "ah shit", a big fucking shit! \n \nAnd a shit you will clean up... we have to make it look like an accident... something that will put the blame on someone else, far away from us... 
			\n \nYes of course! I'm a fucking genius! We're going to frame the gopniks!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_9">
		<text>You know what? I don't care. Fuck him, fuck you and fuck everyone coming after me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_10">
		<text>You fucking moron, you're a dead man, and you're too stupid to see it yet!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_11">
		<text>Frame the bandits? How are we going to do that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_12">
		<text>You mean, how are you going to do that? You fucking got us into this mess, you're the person to get us out of it! 
		\n \nListen, and listen carefully: you're going to sneak the clients corpse into the bandit base! 
		Dump it somewhere none of them will notice, somwhere in the back. Then, when the fucking OMON or whoever the fuck will come looking, we will point them to the bandits! 
		They will storm their base, and voila - they will find poor Stepan abducted and killed by our local scum! Nothing we could do about it - the dangers of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_121">
		<text>And how am I supposed to sneak the body into the Vehicle Station?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_122">
		<text>Use your brain dammit! Ah, I nearly forgot that you show sure signs of missing one... \n \nYou obviously have two options: you can either sneak in from the back during the night, or you disguise yourself as a bandit!
			Don't look at me like that, it's either the cover of the night or you're going to put on fucking gopnik clothes and you will sneak the fucking corpse into their base! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_13">
		<text>That sounds super risky...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_14">
		<text>It's your only way out of this mess! Now get going, we don't have much time until we will get their visit! Two days, if we are lucky three days until the day of judgment! Go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_15">
		<text>Alright, alright... I will clean up the mess...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_16">
		<text>Ah and one last thing: Most people wouldn't need to be told this, but with your fuckwit and problems to follow instructions, I need to remind you not to fucking kill the bandits! 
		Someone needs to be left in order to put the blame on! You understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_17">
		<text>The bandits have to live - understood...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_18">
		<text>Oh my god, you fucking moron! You had one job - ONE JOB - and you were not able to do it? This is a disaster! You fucked us man, you really fucked us! I should have never trusted such a rookie! FUUUUUCCCCCKKK!!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_19">
		<text>Calm down, this is not such a big deal...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_20">
		<text>Not a big deal? NOT A BIG DEAL? IT'S A HUGE FUCKING BIG DEAL! \n \nFuck fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck...
		\n \nDo you have any idea who you killed? That was not some random looser - that guy was not only a fucking lawyer but also a fucking politician! He was fucking connected! PEOPLE WILL COME LOOKING FOR HIM!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_21">
		<text>I mean it was a fucking accident! Shit happens around here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_22">
		<text>Shit happens around here? YOU WERE FUCKING HIRED TO PREVENT SHIT HAPPENING! \n \nI have to think... we need to give them a fucking scapegoat, someone not connected to me... \n \nYes of course! I'm a fucking genius! We're going to frame the gopniks!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_23">
		<text>Frame the gopniks? And how are we going to do that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_24">
		<text>You mean, how are you going to do that? You fucking got us into this mess, you're the person to get us out of it! 
		\n \nListen, and listen carefully: you're going to sneak the clients corpse into the bandit base! 
		Dump it somewhere none of them will notice, somwhere in the back. Then, when the fucking OMON or whoever the fuck will come looking, we will point them to the bandits! 
		They will storm their base, and voila - they will find poor Stepan abducted and killed by our local scum! Nothing we could do about it - the dangers of the Zone, and they will have their fucking scapegoat!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_25">
		<text>That sounds super risky...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_26">
		<text>It's your only way out of this mess! Now get going, we don't have much time until we will get their visit! Two days, if we are lucky three days until the day of judgment! Go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_27">
		<text>Alright, alright... I will clean up the mess...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_28">
		<text>Ah and one last thing: Most people wouldn't need to be told this, but with your fuckwit and problems to follow instructions, I need to remind you not to fucking kill the bandits! 
		Someone needs to be left in order to put the blame on! You understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_3_29">
		<text>The bandits have to live - understood...</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_hiding_1_info">
		<text>This seems like a good spot to hide the corpse.</text>
	</string>	

<string id="bh_shlitzer_4_0">
		<text>The body is hidden...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_4_1">
		<text>At least that you were capable off. Good, good, now we have to wait for our visit. Don't run off! They will want to speak to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_4_2">
		<text>I have been thinking...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_4_3">
		<text>My god, preseve us from your thinking!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_4_4">
		<text>I've been thinking how we could explain the body turning up with bandits, although I was the guide...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_4_5">
		<text>You're lucky that you have me! I already cooked up an explanation! Listen: after shooting the... after having experienced the Zone, the client wanted more. 
			You as a diligent escort of course insisted that you should stick to the plan. \n \nAh, but what is to be done with a guy used to power who wants more and is not used to someone telling him no? 
			While you were discussing - you of course were INSISTING that he should return home - some people of ill repute came about. The client, god bless his soul, swooned by the promises of these gopniks dismissed you and followed them to - in the end - his death. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_4_6">
		<text>But if I knew that they were bandits, why didn't I kill them to save the client?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_4_7">
		<text>But obviously you wanted to! But the client, dismissing the knowledge of someone EXPERIENCED (don't forget to mention that - I always hire the best) insisted of going with them! 
			And you, seeing him already in the hands of these potential troublemakers and OUTNUMBERED decided that a gun fight was impossible and you prefered to run back and alert your fellow Stalker, who, of course, didn't care. Then I called for help, but alas, help came too late, and now we have a dead body on our hands!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_4_8">
		<text>It sounds crazy but it might work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_4_9">
		<text>This story will never work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_4_10">
		<text>It HAS to work. Now stay close, I will tell you when the fucking hooligans will arrive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_4_11">
		<text>This story will have to work, or you are dead. Now stay close, I will tell you when the fucking hooligans will arrive.</text>
	</string>
	
	

<string id="bh_shlitzer_5_0">
		<text>You mentionned another job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_5_1">
		<text>Ah I like that you're hungry for money. Indeed, some acquaintances of mine are looking for a guy like you. 
		They need an extra gun in order to guard their... let's say workers. You know the drill, you get paid to do the job and keep your mouth shut.
		\n \nThe money is good, excellent even for what it really is. Are you in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_5_2">
		<text>Sure, sounds good. Where can I meet these guys?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_5_3">
		<text>Can you tell me more about these guys?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_5_4">
		<text>Excellent. You will find them near the Vehicle Graveyard in Garbage during the morning and early afternoon. Pavel Prikazov will be leading them. Prepare for a long day outside, and food is not provided hahaha.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_5_5">
		<text>Why all these questions? I thought you knew by now that you're getting paid to shut up and simply do your job. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_5_6">
		<text>Alright, don't get so worked up! I'll go meet your friends. Tell me where and when.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_5_7">
		<text>I really don't know...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_5_8">
		<text>Pff! Come see me when your stomach has brought you back to reason!</text>
	</string>	

<string id="bh_shlitzer_6_0">
		<text>I completed the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_6_1">
		<text>Good, very good. Apparently it was a bit hectic, usually it's not that way. But you did well!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_6_2">
		<text>About the money?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_6_3">
		<text>Yes, they told me you wanted the money immediately. But listen - there is a natural order to things, right? 
		First the artifacts have to be sold, and then you will get paid from that money. But don't worry, it won't take long! A bit of patience my friend! Come back tomorrow and you will get your money!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_6_4">
		<text>I understand. I'll be back tomorrow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_6_5">
		<text>I don't care, I want my money now!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_6_6">
		<text>Very sensible. See you tomorrow!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_6_7">
		<text>Or what? Or you're going to take it from me? I don't have the fucking money either! I tell you - everyone will get paid ONCE THE FUCKING ARTIFACTS ARE SOLD!!! \n \nNow fuck off, and wait your turn like everybody else!</text>
	</string>
	

<string id="st_bh_badger_start_0">
		<text>You're a friend of Shlitz? Here - catch the bag!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_badger_start_1">
		<text>Remind him to pay me fast - I have some palms to grease here, they already become impatient.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_badger_start_2">
		<text>And now go - quickly!</text>
	</string>
	


<string id="bh_ironchain_start_0">
		<text>You're Shlitzer's guy? Do you have the bag?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_1">
		<text>Yeah. Do you have the case?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_2">
		<text>Of course. So what are we waiting for? Are we doing it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_3">
		<text>Sure. Let's do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_4">
		<text>I don't think so.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_5">
		<text>You see! That was quite easy hahaha. No reason to be so tense. \n \nOne moment Stalker, you seem to be familiar. Aren't you one of the Stalkers which took back the railway bridge?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_6">
		<text>Don't be stupid. We won't hesitate gunning you down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_7">
		<text>No, you are confusing me with someone else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_8">
		<text>What about it? Got a problem with that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_9">
		<text>Are you sure? ... Don't worry about it - now goodbye Stalker, maybe until next time!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_10">
		<text>Relax Stalker hahaha. You did me a big favour - you eliminated my competition! Here, a sign of my appreciation! Now goodbye Stalker, maybe until next time!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_11">
		<text>I was only kidding. Here, catch the bag. Now give me the case!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_12">
		<text>Fuck you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_13">
		<text>You have a strange sense of humour Stalker...\n \nOne moment, you seem to be familiar. Aren't you one of the Stalkers which took back the railway bridge?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_14">
		<text>But... you guys are bandits!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_15">
		<text>And what of it? Don't tell me you're shitting your pants hahaha! Now, let's do it, we don't have all day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_16">
		<text>What will you do with the weapons?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_ironchain_start_17">
		<text>What a stupid question. Don't abuse my patience Stalker, are we doing the deal or not?</text>
	</string>

<string id="st_bh_ironchain_deal_gone_wrong">
		<text>Where the fuck you think you're going? Kill him!</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_shlitzer_4_0">
		<text>I got your </text>
	</string>

<string id="st_bh_shlitzer_stalker_0">
		<text>What??? What the fuck??? Who is the moron who did this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_shlitzer_stalker_1">
		<text>Damn! No brains but a lot of balls...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_shlitzer_stalker_2">
		<text>Fuck! Are we now stuck here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_shlitzer_stalker_3">
		<text>Looks like it... better to lay low for a while...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_shlitzer_stalker_4">
		<text>Shit! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_shlitzer_stalker_5">
		<text>What??? What the fuck??? Who is the moron who did this?</text>
	</string>
	
	
<string id="st_bh_shlitzer_sidorovich_0">
		<text>Sidorovich: %s !!!! Into my office!!! NOW!!!!!</text>
	</string>	
	


--- Like Rats in a Trap 

<string id="st_bh_like_rats_in_trap_0">
		<text>Careful Stalker! There a bandits trapped down there!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_like_rats_in_trap_1">
		<text>Go see our leader Naruchnik if you want to know more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_like_rats_in_trap_2">
		<text>We want to parley Stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_like_rats_in_trap_3">
		<text>Holster your weapon or we will shoot!</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_0_0">
		<text>Your men say there are bandits holed up in the underground?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_0_1">
		<text>Aye. These bastards killed one of my men, and we tracked them down to this part of the Zone. But instead of confronting us, these cowards are hiding themselves in the underground and refuse to come out.
Now they are like rats in a trap. The problem is, their position is easily defendable and it will be difficult to smoke them out. 
At the moment the plan is to starve them out, but I cannot lose too much time here babysitting the exits... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_0_2">
		<text>If the pay is good enough, I can do it for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_0_3">
		<text>If you think you're able to do it! I'm willing to pay good money for them rotting in hell.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_0_4">
		<text>Seems like a tough nut to crack. Good luck with it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_0_5">
		<text>Thanks mate, I hope the problem will be resolved soon.</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_start_0">
		<text>Wait, you are not a member of their group, are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_start_1">
		<text>Of whose group?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_start_2">
		<text>Some Stalkers pursued us to this place because we punished one of theirs. We took refuge here, but they are garding most exits, and the rest of this place is crowding with mutants. Now we find ourselves trapped...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_start_3">
		<text>No I am not, but they send me to take care of you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_start_4">
		<text>You alone? You're either very confident or foolish...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_start_5">
		<text>Why did you kill one of them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_start_6">
		<text>The guy took a loan from me, but didn't pay up - so he had to pay with his life. Logical no? I had no choice, or I would have lost all respect.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_start_7">
		<text>You said you were ready to parley?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_start_8">
		<text>Yes we are. This situation is a stalemate you see - they cannot come in without heavy losses and an uncertain victory, and we cannot get out without suffering the same fate.
		I am not ready to die in this place, but I believe that our pursuers might not be ready to die either - so I propose that they look the other direction and we slip away. 
		Or else we both are stuck here for a long and lost time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_start_9">
		<text>To be honest, that sounds a bit meager as proposal. I can check with them, but I don't think it will satisfy them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_start_10">
		<text>Convince him! If you do, I'll be sure to reward your skills to do so... If that doesn't work, I might have a second proposition for you. But first we'll try it the diplomatic route.</text>
	</string>
	

<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_0_0">
		<text>About your situation...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_0_1">
		<text>Did you manage to convince them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_0_2">
		<text>I did! You're free to leave during the night.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_0_3">
		<text>Well fucking done! Here my friend - for your troubles. Now let's wait until the night comes to see if you're speaking the truth.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_0_4">
		<text>No they were not to be convinced. He wants you to make a much better offer or there will be no deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_0_5">
		<text>Fuck! \n \nFuck that, no deal then, Horseshoe Anton doesn't pay for save passage! But I have one last proposition for you - you seem to be a ressourceful Stalker. 
		If you manage to get us out here through another exit, I will pay you a shitton of money. All you need to do is to fray a path from here to an unguarded exit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_0_6">
		<text>[Intimidate] No, fuck that! Either you cough up more money for the deal or your bodies will rot here and become food for maggots.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_0_71">
		<text>[Success] Alright, alright... calm yourself, we'll pay for our lives. You can tell your friend that he has a deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_0_72">
		<text>[Fail] Who the fuck do you think you are? Did you forget that you're surrounded? You fucking fool, you'll pay for this!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_0_8">
		<text>Alright, I can do that...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_0_9">
		<text>No way, I'm not helping gopniks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_0_10">
		<text>Perfect! We will be waiting!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_0_11">
		<text>You fucking moron! Well then you have outlived your usefulness...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_0_12">
		<text>[...]</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_1_0">
		<text>I found an exit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_1_1">
		<text>Well done! Show it to us and you're a rich man. But I don't want to see your weapon, or else you're dead - understood? \n \nNow lead the way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_1_2">
		<text>Alright - follow me.</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_2_0">
		<text>We arrived.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_2_1">
		<text>Fuck yes! That Naruchnik can suck it! \n \nYou're quite the man Stalker! I won't forget it! Here is your reward - you see, there is also honour among thieves. Now goodbye Stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_trap_leader_2_2">
		<text>[...]</text>
	</string>

<string id="st_bh_rat_trap_army">
		<text>What the fuck? Where did these bandits come from?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_rat_trap_army_2">
		<text>Fucking morons. Dump the bodies in the ditch.</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_1_0">
		<text>I found some bandits in the Underground, they said they wanted to parley with you... They believe that either side trying to assault will be costly, and thus propose that you and your men look the other way and let them escape.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_1_1">
		<text>And why would we do that? They are obviously desperate!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_1_2">
		<text>I agree with you! They tried to bribe me in order to convince you, they have nothing up their sleeve!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_1_3">
		<text>[Lie] The siege will be very protracted and they are well supplied. I saw their stockpiles - they will hold out for a long time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_1_4">
		<text>[Lie] In my experience, this smells fishy. I think they only want to parley in order to gain time and wait for reinforcement. I would advise you to take the deal...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_1_5">
		<text>Now to be honest, I'm not interested in a siege myself... My men and I have other jobs to attend. I would of course prefer to see this scum dead... 
		Hmm... Alright... If he makes us a better offer, we will consider this problem resolved.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_1_61">
		<text>[Success] Ah shit, is that so? Fuck... I'm not interested in a siege myself... My men and I have other jobs to attend... and if this takes as long as you say, we will lose a lot of money... 
		Fuck alright. Tell them that they can come out during the night.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_1_62">
		<text>[Fail] Why would I belive you? That's fucking bullshit and you know it. Are you lying? Did he promise you something? Fuck off, you're worthless.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_1_71">
		<text>[Success] Ah shit, that makes sense! Shit... If their friends come this will turn to a massacer... Fuck alright - better not to tempt fate. Tell them that they can come out during the night.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_1_72">
		<text>[Fail] Since when are you the Zone Sun Tsu? You're a fucking rookie! Forget about it, the job is above your paygrade.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_1_8">
		<text>If you want them dead, I might be of assistance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_1_9">
		<text>If you think you're able to do it! I'm willing to pay good money for them rotting in hell.</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_2_0">
		<text>I found the bandits holed up, and they said they wanted to parley with you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_2_1">
		<text>Is that so? And what do they propose?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_2_2">
		<text>They believe that either side trying to assault will be costly, and thus propose that you and your men look the other way and let them escape.</text>
	</string>


<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_3_0">
		<text>The bandits are dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_3_1">
		<text>Well done Stalker, well done. Here is your promised reward!</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_4_0">
		<text>I found some bandits down there, do you know how they ended up there?  They are not very talkative anymore.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_4_1">
		<text>You killed the bandits? These bastards killed one of my men, and we tracked them down to this part of the Zone. But instead of confronting us, these cowards are hiding themselves in the underground and refuse to come out.
			\n \nBut now you solved the problem for us. My thanks Stalker! Here, get yourself something nice to drink and eat. </text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_5_0">
		<text>The bandits are ready to pay for their lifes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_5_1">
		<text>Well done Stalker, well done. Although you didn't kill them, I'll give you a part of the ransom after they left. Wait here until this is over.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_5_2">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>


<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_6_0">
		<text>It seems my work is done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_6_1">
		<text>It indeed is. You seemed to made an impression with them, they really seemed to be frightened by you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_6_2">
		<text>Well they knew not to fuck around with me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_6_3">
		<text>It seems so. Here is your part as promised. Thanks for your help, and might the Zone be smiling upon you my friend.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_7_0">
		<text>The bandits seem to have escaped.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_rat_guards_naruchnik_7_1">
		<text>What? How is that possible... ah these fuckers... well, seems that there is no more deal on the table then. We will get moving, we have other things to do.</text>
	</string>
	
--- Hunter Orion
	
<string id="hunter_orion_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Are you the new guy?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_orion_start_dialog_1">
		<text>I am. Butcher send...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_orion_start_dialog_2">
		<text>I'm sorry, but we don't have time, the zombies are coming! We can exchange greetings later. Get your gun ready and pray we survive this night.</text>
	</string>	
		
<string id="st_hunter_orion_remarks_0">
		<text>If you ask me, what is dead should remain dead.</text>
	</string>
<string id="st_hunter_orion_remarks_1">
		<text>I fucking hate the undead.</text>
	</string>
<string id="st_hunter_orion_remarks_2">
		<text>You fucked with the wrong guy .</text>
	</string>	


--- Fanatic
<string id="bh_fanatic_zone_0_0">
		<text>What are the reason most people come here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_fanatic_zone_0_1">
		<text>There is a silent agreement not to talk about the reasons why other Stalkers are here - most of the time you wouldn't like the answer.
Most people come here for the money, out of greed but more often out of necessity, hoping to make a fortune quickly. 
Stalkers in order to find Artifacts and sell them, or working for the authorities for an increased payroll.
\n \nThen there are the one's hiding here from the law - you will find a lot of bastards who slaughtered or worse, and now hide here. And don't make the mistake to think to find these kind only among bandits.
\n \nVery few come for an adventure - mostly fools in my opinion. Most of them change their mind when it's too late. 
\n \nIn the end, it's only misery driving them here, and no one likes to talk about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_fanatic_zone_0_2">
		<text>Why are you here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_fanatic_zone_0_3">
		<text>Sometimes I wonder too...</text>
	</string>


--- Pervert Tourist

<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_message_0">
		<text>I am waiting at the jeep wreckage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_message_1">
		<text>Alright, I will be with you soon.</text>
	</string>	
	
<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_0">
		<text>Are you my guide?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_1">
		<text>I am.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_2">
		<text>Have you been here for long?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_3">
		<text>For quite some time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_4">
		<text>Not very much, but I know my way around Cordon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_5">
		<text>Have you already killed a man here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_6">
		<text>No one that didn't shoot at me first.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_7">
		<text>Yeah happens.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_8">
		<text>And? How is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_9">
		<text>What do you mean?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_10">
		<text>How does if feel... well to kill a person?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_11">
		<text>Not very good, but then again, it's either them or me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_12">
		<text>I don't know, I don't feel much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_13">
		<text>Quite thrilling actually!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_14">
		<text>Hmm, I see... well I have never killed anyone... I wonder how it is... Shall we go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_start_15">
		<text>Yes? I have never killed anyone, but I'm yearning to know how it feels! That's why I came here - my friends told me that for money everything is possible in this place... Shall we go?</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_0_0">
		<text>Why did you come here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_0_1">
		<text>You don't know? Hmm... well I have a friend who sometimes comes here for a weekend to have... let's call it uncommon experiences. He told me that for money, everything is possible in this place! 
		So I decided to come and see for myself!</text>
	</string>


<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_guard_0">
		<text>Are you the tourist? Please go inside through the other door.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_guard_1">
		<text>Wait outside Stalker.</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_1_0">
		<text>Are you done?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_1_1">
		<text>Wow! What an experience! I feel so alive! Misha told me all about it, but I never thought it would feel that good!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_1_2">
		<text>Can we go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_1_3">
		<text>Damn, I feel so alive! Quick Stalker, bring me back to the checkpoint! I need to find a sauna!</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_2_0">
		<text>What did you do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_2_1">
		<text>Wow! What an experience! I feel so alive! Misha told me all about it, but I never thought it would feel that good!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_2_2">
		<text>What did you do inside the house?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_2_3">
		<text>I shot that damn dog straight between his eyes! Damn, I feel so alive! Quick Stalker, bring me back to the checkpoint! I need to find a sauna!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_2_4">
		<text>Fuck... whatever, let's get going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_2_5">
		<text>You shot a guy??? You came here to shoot a guy, and now you want to go to a fucking sauna? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_2_6">
		<text>What? Do I have to remind you that you're the fucking errand boy? Keep your mouth shut and bring me back to the checkpoint!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_2_7">
		<text>How about I put a bullet between your eyes you fucking pervert?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_2_8">
		<text>You're right. Let's get back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_2_9">
		<text>Do you know who I am? Obviously not... Shut up and get me back to the Checkpoint, and I'm ready to ignore this outburst of... passion!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_2_10">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_3_0">
		<text>We arrived.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_pervert_tourist_3_1">
		<text>Thanks Stalker! I had an awesome time, I hope that I will be back soon!</text>
	</string>

---Nussknacker

<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_0">
	<text>Ah %s, we have been waiting for you. So you're the guy who last saw Stepan... Tell me, what happened?</text>
</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_1">
		<text>Well... Shlitzer hired me to...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_2">
		<text>I know and I don't care. Cut the intro and jump straight to the facts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_3">
		<text>After shooting the hostage we made our way back to the Checkpoint. On our way we met four Stalkers - most likely bandits...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_4">
		<text>How did you know that they were bandits?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_5">
		<text>At first I didn't, but I started to suspect it during the conversation. 
			You see, Stepan was very excited about... the events, so he got eagerly into a conversation with them and quite quickly it turned to... 
			murdering people... and they talked so casualy about it that I...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_6">
		<text>Why didn't you try to stop the conversation?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_7">
		<text>I tried multiple times, but Stepan didn't want to listen and he mentionned that he was paying me to escort him and not to interrupt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_8">
		<text>It was your job to keep him safe, especially if you noticed that they were bandits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_9">
		<text>By that time it was too late. The bandits noticed that the guy was loaded and had their hands close to their guns. 
			It was impossible for me to fight them and keep the client safe. So...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_10">
		<text>So you decided to flee and leave him with some bandits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_11">
		<text>So I decided to come back and get some help. Besides, the client wanted to go with them - they promised to show him the dark side of the Zone...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_12">
		<text>We asked around - no one here remembers you asking for help...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_13">
		<text>You're a quite imposing sight - do you think they will admit that they refused help to a person of interest to you? Besides - you're also help - why did it take so long for you to come?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_14">
		<text>Be careful lad - it is you who fucked up. If I would have been around, the problem would not have existed in the first place. 
			\n \nAnother thing is also stange: there has been no ransom demands...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_15">
		<text>I think you already know the answer to that: you will not find Stepan but his corpse... they probably tortured him for money and it turned wrong...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_16">
		<text>Hmm... we will have to see. You're coming with us - and don't try to do something weird like running away. Let's check your story out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_start_17">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_shlitzer_omon_arrived_0">
	<text>The inquisition arrived!!! They are waiting in the Rookie Village, move your ass over here as fast as possible!!!</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_shlitzer_omon_arrived_1">
	<text>You fucking useless piece of shit!!! The inquisition arrived and you failed to even clean up after your mess!!! You're a dead man!!!</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_waiting_0">
	<text>%s, we have to talk about the incident with Stepan Detronov. I will be waiting in the Rookie Village.</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_waiting_1">
	<text>%s, we are waiting for you. Come to the Rookie Village.</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_waiting_2">
	<text>Mate, what is going on? There are some serious people waiting for you here.</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_waiting_3">
	<text>Last chance %s. Come see us in the Rookie Village in the next 24h, or you will regret it.</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_waiting_4">
	<text>This is serious %s. These people are not fucking around.</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_assault_0">
	<text>Nussknacker: You can start boys. Fuck them up.</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_assault_1">
	<text>Nussknacker: You wait here with us Stalker.</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_assault_2">
	<text>Nussknacker: I'm warning you Stalker - don't move too far from us.</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_clear_0">
	<text>Clear</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_clear_1">
	<text>Alright boys, let's start looking for the target.</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_clear_2">
	<text>Nussknacker: Come with us Stalker, let's check your story out.</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_found_0">
	<text>I found him boss. He's dead - in the garage on the eastern side.</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_found_1">
	<text>I found him boss. He's dead - in the collapsed building on the eastern side.</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_found_2">
	<text>I found him boss. He's dead - behind the building on the eastern side.</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_found_3">
	<text>Nussknacker: Well fuck me... that's him</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_0_0">
	<text>Seems that we are too late...</text>
</string>
	<string id="bh_nussknacker_0_1">
	<text>Seems that way, yes... well my job is done, and your story checks out... what a shame... you're free to go Stalker...</text>
</string>


<string id="bh_nussknacker_ambush_0">
	<text>Nussknacker: There he is boys - fuck him up</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_ambush_1">
	<text>Nussknacker: Run for now, we will catch you</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_nussknacker_ambush_2">
	<text>Nussknacker: Ah fuck this shit, that slippery weasel is not worth that much trouble</text>
</string>


--- Shlitzer 2 Gulag guard

--Guard

<string id="bh_prikazov_start_0">
		  <text>Are you Shlitzer's guy?</text>
	  </string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_start_1">
		  <text>That would be me. What do you want me to do?</text>
	  </string>
  <string id="bh_prikazov_start_2">
		  <text>That would be me. What do you want me to do?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bh_prikazov_start_3">
		  <text>We need you to guard the western hole in the fence, on the opposite side of here. If anyone or anything approaches it, shoot it. If any of these hobos tries to flee through it - shoot him. Simple enough. If everything goes well you get paid - 10.000 roubles. 
      Sounds nice and easy, doesn't it?</text>
	  </string>
   <string id="bh_prikazov_start_4">
		  <text>Sounds easy enough. Let's get this over with.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="bh_prikazov_start_5">
		  <text>Who are the workers? They don't seem to be volunteers.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="bh_prikazov_start_6">
		  <text>Indeed they are not hahaha. These assholes thought they could borrow a shit ton of money and not pay it back. But we found them, and now they have to work for it, one Artifact at a time. Serves them right, fucking freeloaders.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bh_prikazov_start_7">
		  <text>For real? You mean you enslaved these people?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="bh_prikazov_start_8">
		  <text>Whatever, let's get this over with.</text>
	</string>
  <string id="bh_prikazov_start_9">
		  <text>What do you mean enslaved? No one forced these guys to take a loan. They were free to take the money, and more than welcome to pay it back. 
      They took knowingly an engagement, and now they have to live with the consequences. No slavery here mate, this is the Zone. \n \nDoes that make sense to you, or are you some kind of fucking saint?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="bh_prikazov_start_10">
		  <text>If you present it like that, it does make sense... I guess such is life here. Shall we get going and get this over with?</text>
	</string>
  <string id="bh_prikazov_start_11">
		  <text>Sound like indentured servitude... slavery with extra steps...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_start_12">
		  <text>And what about it? What do you want to do about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_start_13">
		  <text>I'm fucking leaving, but not without telling you this: fuck you and fuck all of this!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_start_14">
		  <text>How about by putting a bullet between your eyes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_start_15">
		  <text>Ah fuck it, I have my own problems. Let's get this over with, I don't want to spend more time than necessary with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_start_16">
		  <text>Fuck off boy and go back to your priest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_start_17">
		  <text>How about we put a bullet in yours?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_start_18">
		  <text>Good boy, now get to your post!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_start_19">
		  <text>[...]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_start_20">
		  <text>Yeah, let's get this business moving! And you, go to your guarding post on the western side of the fence! Take care not to walk into an anomaly, hahahaha.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_start_21">
		  <text>[...]</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_prikazov_0_0">
		<text>What's the problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_0_1">
		<text>What's the problem? WHATS THE PROBLEM? A prisoner runs away under your nose, and you ask what's the fucking problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_0_2">
		<text>I didn't notice him until it was too late!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_0_3">
		<text>It was your fucking job to notice! \n \nYou know what? Fuck off! I don't want to see your fucking face again! Where the fuck did Shlitzer find such a moron?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_0_4">
		<text>And my money?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_0_5">
		<text>Your money? Your money for what? Your job was to guard the prisoners! And where is he now? You fucking failed at your job! There is no money for failure! \n \nFuck off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_0_6">
		<text>Fuck you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_0_7">
		<text>Fuck me? No, fuck you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_0_8">
		<text>Whatever! Fucking asshole...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_0_9">
		<text>Fuck off you moron!</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bh_prikazov_1_0">
		<text>Are we done here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_1_1">
		<text>You are, yes. We still need to bring back our remaining worker here and sell the artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_1_2">
		<text>And my money?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_1_3">
		<text>You will get your money after we have sold the harvest. Talk to Shlitzer to get your due.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_1_4">
		<text>That wasn't part of the agreement! I want my money now!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_1_5">
		<text>What do you mean? Everybody gets paid after the stuff is sold - that's how it's always done. Or do you think you will get paid in advance? \n \nListen, I don't know what Shlitzer told you, but you certainly won't get any money from me here! Talk to him if you have a problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_1_6">
		<text>Alright, I'll talk to Shlitzer.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="bh_prikazov_2_0">
		<text>What's the problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_2_1">
		<text>What the fuck are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_2_2">
		<text>What do you mean?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_2_3">
		<text>What do I mean? You're fucking paid to guard a fucking hole in a fence, not to wander off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_2_4">
		<text>I only went a bit further?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_2_5">
		<text>I don't fucking care, your job was to guard the fucking spot no matter what! \n \nYou know what? Fuck off! I don't want to see your fucking face again! Where the fuck did Shlitzer find such a moron?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_2_6">
		<text>And my money?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_2_7">
		<text>Your money? Your money for what? Your job was to be a guard! A GUARD! You fucking failed at your job! There is no money for failure! \n \nFuck off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_2_8">
		<text>Fuck you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_2_9">
		<text>Fuck me? No, fuck you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_2_10">
		<text>Whatever! Fucking asshole...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_prikazov_2_11">
		<text>Fuck off you moron!</text>
	</string>
	
	
<string id="st_bh_gulag_prikazov_shout_1">
		<text>On your feet maggots! Get to your fucking work!</text>
	</string>
-- 

<string id="st_bh_gulag_guard_spot_0">
		<text>This seems like my spot to guard</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_gulag_guard_spot_1">
		<text>If I go any further, Prikazov will think I abandoned my post!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_gulag_guard_spot_2">
		<text>Where the fuck have you run off to?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_bh_gulag_guard_spot_3">
		<text>Oi %s, the prisoner is running away! Shoot him!!!!</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_bh_gulag_guard_spot_4">
		<text>What the fuck are you doing? You fucking moron, why didn't you shoot him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_gulag_guard_spot_5">
		<text>Nice shot %s! Let's continue and get this over with.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_gulag_guard_spot_6">
		<text>Fuck he got away! Well fuck it, we will get him later. Let's continue.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_gulag_guard_spot_7">
		<text>What the %s !!!! Come see me!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bh_gulag_guard_spot_8">
		<text>Okay boys, let's wrap it up! Come back to us %s.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_bh_gulag_guard_spot_9">
		<text>Abort everything! Bring back everyone, and you, %s, come see me!!! </text>
	</string>
-- Prisoner

<string id="bh_gulag_worker_shout_0">
		<text>Please... do you have water?</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_0">
		<text>Please... do you have water?... my throath... so dry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_1">
		<text>[Water] Sure sure, here have some.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_2">
		<text>[Tea or Soft Drink] I don't have water, but take this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_3">
		<text>[Alcohol] I don't have water, but take this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_4">
		<text>Shut up maggot and get back to work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_5">
		<text>Thanks... my benefactor. I knew that you're not a bad person... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_6">
		<text>Don't mention it. Why are you here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_7">
		<text>Now get back to work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_8">
		<text>These guys fucked me! I've met their boss, this Shlitzer guy, when I was in a difficult situation! 
		I needed some money in order to bail out my friend who was held hostage by bandits, money which I didn't have! So I found a guy willing to lend it to me, Shlitzer, cursed be his name... when I went back to the bandits, they told me they found someone else who would pay more money for my friend...
		What did they do to him? Sold him into slavery? Fuck, I don't know... You wouldn't have met a Stalker named Yulianov Klad, would you? \n \nAh fuck, it doesnt matter, I'm also in deep shit now... Well, I tried to give Shlitzer his money back, but he wanted interests! And what interests! 
		I did every shitjob you can find here in order to pay off my debt, I even risked my life in this fucking arena! But my debt grew faster than I could work. 
		Fuck my life... \n \nSo the day came when I wasn't able to pay one of the due dates... well here I am! But the fucking didn't stop, no! These fuckers "bill" me the food I eat, the water I drink! I will never be free again!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_9">
		<text>Shit... sounds like these guys fucked you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_10">
		<text>Sucks to be you... now get back to work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_11">
		<text>They did kind Stalker, they did! \n \n... \n \nYou have to help me! Please! Let me run away! Please, I beg you!!! Look the other way! Or pretend to be shooting at me! They will be angry, yes, but they won't harm you! This, here, it will be my end if you don't take pitty on me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_12">
		<text>No wait Stalker! I beg you, you alone can help me! Please, let me go! Don't you see, I'm a slave, condemned to die being a slave!\n \nStalker, I implore you! Look the other way! Or pretend to be shooting at me! They will be angry, yes, but they won't harm you! This, here, it will be my end if you don't take pitty on me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_13">
		<text>Ah fuck it... run, when I'm looking the other way, but be quick about it! I'll fire some shots in the air to make them think I tried to stop you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_worker_0_14">
		<text>What the fuck? Fuck you, and go back to work!</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_gulag_ecol_shout_0">
		<text>You: Halt there guys. No entry today.</text>
	</string>

<string id="bh_gulag_ecol_start_dialog_0">
		<text>What is going on Stalker? We would like to do some research here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_ecol_start_dialog_1">
		<text>I'm sorry guys, but that is not possible today. Private event.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_ecol_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Fuck off, we were here first.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_ecol_start_dialog_3">
		<text>What do you mean? This is not some private property you can close!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_ecol_start_dialog_4">
		<text>What?? What the fuck is your problem? Get out of our way!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_ecol_start_dialog_5">
		<text>That's where you are wrong, but if you want to be sure you can pull your gun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_ecol_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Listen guys, this is not my choice, but orders from my employer. I cannot let you enter, and if you try, I have to shoot you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_ecol_start_dialog_7">
		<text>Come on punk, make my day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_ecol_start_dialog_8">
		<text>We will see about this! You made a big mistake Stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_gulag_ecol_start_dialog_9">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>

--- Gulag ecolog return

<string id="st_bh_gulag_visitor_shout_0">
	<text>Oi Stalker! Who is laughing now?</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bh_gulag_visitor_shout_1">
	<text>Either you fuck off, or my friends will fuck you up! Your choice!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bh_gulag_visitor_shout_2">
	<text>Where do you think you guys are going? Come back!!!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bh_gulag_visitor_shout_3">
	<text>... FUCK!</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_0_0">
	<text>What is the meaning of this?</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_0_1">
	<text>I told you this was not over. Two choices now for you: either you fuck off, or my friends will fuck you up!</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_0_2">
	<text>Your friends? These guys are mercenaries. </text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_0_3">
	<text>Friend or mercenary - does it matter as long as they have guns?</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_0_4">
	<text>You know I cannot allow you to enter...</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_0_5">
	<text>I told you to fuck off! I'm not scared, neither by you nor your "friends"!</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_0_6">
	<text>Well then it seems we came to the end of the discussion!</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_0_7">
	<text>Spoken like a true moron.</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_0_8">
	<text>You know what? This shit ain't worth it. Fine, the field is yours.</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_0_9">
	<text>That... surprises me. I would have expected more resistance from you... maybe you're not that stupid after all. Fine, walk away and take your life with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_0_10">
	<text>...</text>
</string>

<string id="st_bh_gulag_visitor_merc_shout_0">
	<text>Roland the Headless: Don't be stupid Stalker. Choose life.</text>
</string>


<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_0">
	<text>Don't do anything rash Stalker. Simply walk away, and you will be able to enjoy another sunset. Choose life.</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_1">
	<text>You know I cannot do that.</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_2">
	<text>[Intimidate] Go ahead punk, make my day.</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_3">
	<text>[Money] How about instead of fighting, we discuss an agreement? How much does this guy pay you?</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_4">
	<text>Indeed, this job ain't worth my blood. The yard is yours.</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_5">
	<text>So you chose violence...</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_6_1">
	<text>... \n \nYou know what, this shit ain't worth the meager payment. We go men!</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_6_2">
	<text>So you chose violence.</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_7">
	<text>... \n \nHow much are you willing to pay?</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_8">
	<text>Let's say 5.000?</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_9">
	<text>Let's say 7.500?</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_10">
	<text>Let's say 10.000?</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_11">
	<text>Fuck it, I prefer taking your money.</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_12">
	<text>5.000? That won't cut it mate.</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_13_1">
	<text>Hmm... That's not a lot, but then again we don't need to gamble our lifes on this job... Alright, we accept. 7.500 it is. \n \nLet's go men, this isn't our problem anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_13_2">
	<text>Make an effort mate, remember it is you who doesn't want this fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_14">
	<text>Deal! 10.000 it is! \n \nLet's go men, this isn't our problem anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_15">
	<text>A reasonable choice Stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_visitor_merc_start_16">
	<text>...</text>
</string>

<string id="bh_gulag_shlitzer_remark_0">
	<text>What the fuck man? What is going on? I'm told you went crazy and started shooting? Tell me you didn't kill them!</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_shlitzer_remark_1">
	<text>Don't ever show your fucking face again!</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_shlitzer_remark_2">
	<text>What the fuck man? What is going on? I'm told you simply abandoned your fucking post? If that's true, don't ever show your fucking face again!</text>
</string>
<string id="bh_gulag_shlitzer_remark_3">
	<text>What the fuck man? What is going on? I'm told you let a prisoner run away! If that's true, don't ever show your fucking face again!</text>
</string>

<string id="st_bh_shlitzer_kroshka_0">
		<text>My friend we have a problem. Come see my as soon as possible!</text>
	</string>


<string id="bh_shlitzer_kroshka_0_0">
		<text>What's the problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_kroshka_0_1">
		<text>The artifacts are gone! My associates have been stuck up by a Stalker, and he took the artifacts... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_kroshka_0_2">
		<text>And my money?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_kroshka_0_3">
		<text>And YOUR money? Have you been listening? THE ARTIFACTS ARE GONE! THERE IS NO FUCKING MONEY!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_kroshka_0_4">
		<text>What? What happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bh_shlitzer_kroshka_0_5">
		<text>What? What happened?</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>
