<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_text">
    <text>I don't lend money!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_text">
    <text>Hey, Shroud.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_logoped_start_dialog_text">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_tick_start_dialog_text">
    <text>So, what's up with you?</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_0">
    <text>Halt, don't move! Who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_1">
    <text>We're contract scientists...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_2">
    <text>Don't you know anything about orders? Documents for inspection! Slowly. If you try anything I'll shoot without warning!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_3">
    <text>Here you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_4">
    <text>Alright, let's see... The permit and pass are not expired. Stamp and signatures are in place. Everything seems to be in order... But why are you on foot? Where is your escort?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_5">
    <text>The car broke down, he stayed with it. It's not far from here, a couple of kilometers. We decided to walk since we can't go any further by car anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_6">
    <text>When will they replace those pieces of junk? What are they thinking, those staff rats? They should spend a day here... Anyway, here's your papers. You may pass.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_7">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_8">
    <text>Hold it! Did you smear ink on your hand? Stop! Don't hide the pass. Yeah, this stamp is smudged, it's a forgery! Well, start praying scum!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_army_shmatco_dialog_kpp_9">
    <text>Wait, don't shoot!!!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_about_zone_0">
    <text>Tell me about the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_barman_patogen_about_zone_1">
    <text>I know! It's better to ask the eggheads about it: they can examine it under a microscope and stick it in an x-ray machine. I know a little about the Zone... It allows me to earn enough money so that in two years I can buy my own plot with a vineyard by the sea - and that's that.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_fee_dialog_1">
    <text>Thanks, bro! You saved me, I'll never forget it! Sorry, I don't have any money right now. But I'll pay you back later! Let me give you the coordinates of the stash for now. I left some extra gear there from my last trip, whatever you find there is yours. You saved my life Shroud, I'm in your debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_fee_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, anyone would do the same in my place.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_fee_dialog_3">
    <text>Not everyone would risk their life for someone they barely know, belive me. In the Zone, it's every man for himself. Anyway, I'm heading to the vehicle station, I have some matters to attend to there, I'll contact you later. Take care and stay healthy!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_fee_dialog_4">
    <text>You too!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_0">
    <text>There you are. We've searched the entire camp. So, alive, intact and kicking?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah. Just got acquainted with our new friends here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_2">
    <text>Are you talking about Cold by any chance? Well, we've known each other for a long time, but haven't seen each other in a few years. Nice reunion. So, shall we go to the village and discuss things? I found something in Logopedist's notes that I think you'll find interesting. By the way, here are your things - I can't carry them forever.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_3">
    <text>Let's move quickly, I'm starving and I have no strength left.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_0">
    <text>Thank God everything turned out fine. Those bandits could've easily finished you off, but let's not dwell on that stuff. I've learned a lot about our thing.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_1">
    <text>So, what did you discover?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_10">
    <text>There's an old man here, obsessed with clocks. They say he's been living in this village since the beginning, even before the first disaster in '86, can you imagine? And he survived the second disaster too.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_11">
    <text>And how can he help us?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_12">
    <text>Well, there were some drawings of old access points in Logopedist's notebook: Pipes, tunnels, ventilation shafts. I did some calculations and it turns out that one of these tunnels pass right under Watchmaker's house.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_13">
    <text>What are you suggesting? Break into the old man's house and search it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_14">
    <text>Are you crazy? Why break in? We'll ask the old man politely. Maybe he needs something and we can bring it to him. So, will you go and talk to Watchmaker?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_15">
    <text>Why me? I haven't been getting along well with old folks lately...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_16">
    <text>I need to visit Shaman and give him Logopedist's notebook. It contains a lot of useful information for Stalkers. Don't worry, I deleted all the information about the catacombs from the notebook. So now no one else knows about these underground passages beside us.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_17">
    <text>Alright, I'll go and talk to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_2">
    <text>A lot of interesting stuff... I've found out where the Freedom member was captured. The bandits caught him right near the village!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_3">
    <text>Right here?!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_4">
    <text>Almost. There's a shack on the hill, that's where they got him. Can you believe it? The bandits have never come this far into Stalker territory before. Seems like they were tracking the Freedom member for a long time.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_5">
    <text>What's the shack for?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_6">
    <text>Just a regular shack, who knows why they put it there. Maybe it's for ventilation or something? It's impossible to find out though, the door is welded shut.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_7">
    <text>So, what should we do?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_8">
    <text>Well, this is where it gets interesting. Do you know Watchmaker?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_complite_9">
    <text>No, who's that?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_0">
    <text>There you are. So, did you find out about the catacombs from Watchmaker?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_1">
    <text>Yep. Not only that, but I also got the key to the room that has the underground entrance.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_2">
    <text>Excellent. I didn't expect it to be so easy to gain access to the catacombs.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, do you feel like exploring?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_4">
    <text>Absolutely. Let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_5">
    <text>Let's move.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_0">
    <text>Shroud, are you alive?! Man, you're something else! How did you manage to fall?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh... I'm alive, just about... I twisted my leg though.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_2">
    <text>The clumsy mountaineer, heh! Wait! I heard something...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_3">
    <text>What?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_4">
    <text>Quiet! Follow me. Don't make any noise.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_5">
    <text>Go ahead, I'll follow you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_0">
    <text>So that's how it all happened. What do you think, can we handle it? Can we find the artifact? We can make history Shroud.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_1">
    <text>I don't know. It all seems too serious and I don't like Sidorovich, he's clearly hiding something.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, come on Shroud. Aren't you excited? We've already overcome so many hardships and now you want to stop? Let's do it!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_3">
    <text>Well... maybe you're right. If this artifact is really as valuable as Sidorovich says, then I'll be able to return home right away.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, it's a motivation alright. We all gotta eat right? I get what you're saying.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_5">
    <text>Agreed then, let's continue further into the catacombs. But I won't go to Sidorovich for the key. Wait here, I'll ask Watchmaker for his key, he must have it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_3_dialog_0">
    <text>Look at you, dressed up all nicely. Sidorovich didn't skimp. He gave me some nice gear too.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_3_dialog_1">
    <text>Guess what, someone broke into Watchmaker's house and stole his access card. That means we won't be alone down there. One of those three who disturbed Sidorovich definitely went down to the lab.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_3_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, look's like we're all set then. Follow me and don't fall behind.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_quest_line_research_underground_part_3_dialog_3">
    <text>Let's go...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_0">
    <text>Here we are, in Cordon. Don't you dare try to be a hero, the soldiers at the checkpoint don't appreciate jokes. Approach calmly, show them your documents and move along. You remember the story right?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_1">
    <text>Want me to repeat it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_10">
    <text>Hold on, let me check your documents. Crap, the ink hasn't dried yet. If it smears during the inspection, we're screwed. Well, let's try to be careful. Ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_11">
    <text>Ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_2">
    <text>No, it's fine. Remember, if something goes wrong with these fake passes, we'll end up straight in hell instead of the Zone... Although, I'm not sure which is worse.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_3">
    <text>Do you think they'll notice?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_4">
    <text>They shouldn't, but anything is possible. The fact that the soldiers didn't open fire immediately is a good sign. But if they get suspicious they might, and then claim it was justified. It's not uncommon here, even those with legal passes get killed sometimes.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_5">
    <text>But there's still hope, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_6">
    <text>There's always hope, but the odds are slim, as they say. Don't forget that you can't rush in the Zone. Every wrong step can be your last, sometimes a calculated step too. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_7">
    <text>Are there any other options?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_8">
    <text>Of course. If the soldiers aren't completely deranged by the Zone they might demand money, which we don't have. So, keep a straight face and don't let your eyes wander. Look ahead, but don't stare. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_borland_start_dialog_start_game_9">
    <text>Got it. Well, shall we get going?</text>
</string>





<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_0">
    <text>What are you looking at freak? Thought you were the smartest? I've sent a dozen like you to their graves this morning.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_1">
    <text>Don't shoot. Let me explain!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_2">
    <text>What can you possibly say? That you tried to infiltrate the guarded perimeter?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_3">
    <text>I just wanted to earn some money. Let's make a deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_4">
    <text>A deal, you say? Well, show me the money and then we'll talk deals.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_5">
    <text>How much do you need?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_6">
    <text>How much is your partner's life worth to you? How about 30,000? Fifteen for each of you, that's a generous offer right? He can be our guest in the meantime. But if you dare double-cross me, I'll cut off his head and send it back to the one who sold him out, got it?!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_7">
    <text>I'll try to get the money, how much time do I have?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_8">
    <text>Maybe you will, you better get your hands dirty though. If you don't mess up, I think you can earn even more than what I asked for in two days. Just don't bring any junk here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_prisoner_actor_dialog_9">
    <text>I'll find the money.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_0">
    <text>I have the money.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_1">
    <text>Ah, here comes our provider. We've been waiting for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_10">
    <text>Well, then so be it. That means your partner will stay with us. We'll have to squeeze every last penny out of him.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_11">
    <text>Wait, please! Don't touch Borland! Maybe there are other ways to solve this?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_12">
    <text>Hmm. There are a couple of options! Either you give up your equipment as a donation to the military or you complete a couple of tasks "and we're even" as Sidorovich says. Which one will you choose?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_13">
    <text>Alright, take my equipment. I hope we never see each other again.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_30">
    <text>I'll do your tasks, where do I start?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_31">
    <text>Alright then, we have a missing sergeant and valuable documents on a PDA. The internal investigation showed that he was last seen near the northwest tower during a chimera attack at the checkpoint. We've been tracking that agile beast near the swamp for several days, but we can't catch it. Maybe it has a lair nearby. It's possible that the chimera took the sergeant with it. So, your task is to retrieve the documents and kill the chimera.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_32">
    <text>Damn, so you've decided to send me to certain death?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_33">
    <text>You're a stalker! You came to the Zone for certain death! So let's skip the chit-chat, or have you forgotten who you're dealing with?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_34">
    <text>I remember, I remember... Alright, I'm going.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_2">
    <text>As agreed, here's 30.000.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_22">
    <text>I changed my mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_3">
    <text>Nice job bringing the cash, but the price went up while you were away. Your buddy tried to leave without saying goodbye. He broke the sergeant's nose and tried to steal his rifle, unsuccessfully. So now it's not 30.000, but 40.000 instead.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_40">
    <text>Nice job bringing the cash, but the price went up while you were away. So now it's not 30.000, but 50.000 instead.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_4">
    <text>Ah, you... Alright, here's another ten. Are you satisfied now?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_41">
    <text>Ah, you... Alright, here's another twenty. Are you satisfied now?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_5">
    <text>I am! It's nice to deal with a smart stalker for a change. You are welcome here now, feel free to stay.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_6">
    <text>No, thank you, I've had enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_7">
    <text>Suit yourself. By the way, don't forget your gear - it's in the box on the first floor. Also, if you're ever near our base, you can drop by. You won't forget where to find us, I'm sure! Ha-ha-ha! I'll let my soldiers know not to touch you. So come by if sometime, we'll find some work for you to do. We really need our own stalkers in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_8">
    <text>Noted.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_fee_9">
    <text>But that's all I have! I have nothing else.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_army_chernenco_0">
    <text>Halt! Drop your weapon! Hands up!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_army_chernenco_1">
    <text>I'm here to see the colonel. I have an appointment.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_army_chernenco_2">
    <text>Stay still and don't move. Take off your backpack and drop your gun — you'll get them back on the way out. The colonel is waiting for you in his office. Remember, no funny business!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_army_chernenco_3">
    <text>Don't put my stuff too far away.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_army_chernenco_4">
    <text>Don't you dare tell me what to do! Or do you want me to educate you?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_army_chernenco_5">
    <text>That's enough, calm down!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_0">
    <text>Why are you so scared? What happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_1">
    <text>Man, help me out! I need money fast! Can you lend me 30,000? I'll pay it back, I swear!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_10">
    <text>Ha! Of course. You're running around like you're on fire. Alright, enough talking. Let's start earning instead, shall we?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_11">
    <text>Yeah let's! What do I need to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_12">
    <text>We have a hotshot here called Blockhead. He's a promising guy, but as impulsive as diarrhea. He wants to do everything faster than anyone else. He's in the front lines when it comes to fighting mutants, you can't go anywhere without him when searching for artifacts and so on. He hasn't been seen here for a week now, and has already visited Garbage. Thinks he's experienced, but he's still green.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_13">
    <text>Well, I just arrived from the mainland myself. Where is this Garbage anyway? Isn't it too early for me to go there?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_14">
    <text>Calm down, no one's sending you to Garbage. The stalker is already here, he sent me a message a couple of hours ago, saying he's returning to the camp. He said he found something interesting at Garbage and wants to bring it to Sidorovich, the local trader. But there's still no news from him, even though it takes about twenty minutes to get here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_15">
    <text>What do you need from me then? To find him?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_16">
    <text>Yes. Preferably alive and unharmed. But if something happened to him at least bring his backpack or any other belongings.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_17">
    <text>Where should I look for him?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_18">
    <text>In his last message, he mentioned wanting to take a shortcut through the "electric train" our local attraction. Start your search from there.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_19">
    <text>How do I get there?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_2">
    <text>Calm down! Tell me what happened.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_20">
    <text>First, you need to cross the embankment. Since you're new here, it's better for you to go through the tunnel west of the elevator. Just be cautious, there are some guys there who collect a fee from everyone passing through.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_21">
    <text>How much do they charge?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_22">
    <text>It depends on who's passing by. Right now, they have nothing to take from you, so let's try to negotiate differently. Here's a bottle, no - two bottles of vodka, just to be sure. I think they'll let you pass without any issue if you offer it to them. You can return through the "electric train" - just hop on a wagon and jump to the other side.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_23">
    <text>Are there any other options? I'd rather not meet those guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_24">
    <text>Of course, there's another way - under the bridge. But even experienced stalkers hesitate to go there, let alone someone like you. It's so hot there that one wrong step can be your last. And even if you don't touch the fire, you'll still turn into a crisp the more you wait around. So it's better to go through the tunnel - you'll be safer.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_25">
    <text>Will the bandits definitely leave me alone?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_26">
    <text>Don't worry, they won't touch you. Are they complete idiots to kill the goose that lays golden eggs? We, stalkers, are their only source of income. Bandits don't search for artifacts, but take it from stalkers instead. These are the rules here - it's easier for stalkers to pay for passage than to get into conflicts.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_27">
    <text>Yeah, it's a grim situation. Well, I'm off.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_28">
    <text>Wait! Where are you going without gear? This isn't an amusement park. Here, take this novice kit, it should be enough for now. You can get better equipment on your own later.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_29">
    <text>Oh, right. Thanks for your help. I'll go search for your lost comrade.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_3">
    <text>We're in trouble! Me and my buddy got caught at the checkpoint - our documents were fake and the ink smudged while the soldiers were checking them. Now they're demanding money. Or they'll kill my partner. And then probably me too...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_4">
    <text>How much are they asking for?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_5">
    <text>I told you - 30,000, 15,000 each. So, will you lend it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_6">
    <text>I won't lend it to you, but give you the opportunity to earn it yourself instead. When did they say to bring the money?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_7">
    <text>I have to bring it within 48 hours, otherwise... I don't even want to think about what will happen.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_8">
    <text>Stay calm, everything will be fine! But still, you shouldn't delay, who knows what they'll do to your comrade. By the way, is this your first time in the Zone?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_9">
    <text>Yeah, it is. Is it that obvious?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_0">
    <text>What did you find?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_1">
    <text>I found the backpack. Couldn't find the stalker. Honestly, I didn't have much time to search - the boars were raging there. So, sorry, it seems the boars got the better of Blockhead.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_10">
    <text>Goodbye.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_2">
    <text>Blockhead is alive! He arrived ten minutes ago. His eyes are dripping like faucets - can't say anything coherent. We sent him to the basement to recover. By the way you did great! Take this bonus as a personal reward from me. Also, I talked to a local trader while you were away. He's got some work for you. The pay is not much, but it's steady. So, if you haven't already, go see him. His name is Sidorovich and he lives in a bunker behind the village. If you have any more questions, feel free to ask.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_3">
    <text>What should I do with the items?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_4">
    <text>Just give them to Blockhead. Though to be honest, we shouldn't give him back anything and teach him a lesson. Well, never mind, he already punished himself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_5">
    <text>Thanks for your help, Wolf. See you!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_6">
    <text>There's no one there. I found a torn backpack near the campfire. But it's empty. Looks like the boars took all the items. I didn't see the stalker either. Most likely the boars got to him too.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_7">
    <text>That's a shame. But don't worry about Blockhead - he came back recently. He's all scared and mumbling something. Well, it's his own fault. That'll teach him not to show off for no reason in the future.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_8">
    <text>That's for sure. So, I've completed the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_9">
    <text>Oh, right. Take this as a reward for your efforts.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dialog_wolf_the_first_penny_complite_x">
    <text>Hey, Wolf. I've been to the "electric train."</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dybolom_habar_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey hero! I brought your stuff. You left it in the backpack by the campfire.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dybolom_habar_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, another one. Everything would have been fine if I hadn't been caught off guard by a charging boar while I doing my business in the bushes. I didn't care about the backpack then. I don't even remember how I ended up on that train car, the animals were going crazy. Here's the thing, while I was walking from Garbage every bush had monsters popping out of them, I could barely run. I decided to take a break by the "electric train" and then these boars showed up. Wolf told me about you. Thanks for going on the search, I appreciate it. You can keep my things, I don't need that junk anymore. I'll buy myself some really good gear - you'll all be jealous then!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dybolom_habar_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm glad you're okay. Thanks for the gear.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dybolom_habar_dialog_3">
    <text>No problem. Wait, take out your PDA. Here are the coordinates of my stash - I hid a spare rifle there. Take it, as a reward for your honesty!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dybolom_habar_dialog_4">
    <text>Wow, thanks! Good luck!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_0">
    <text>Well buddy, did the explosion get to you? Sorry, my boys went a bit overboard. But hey, they freed you and got us some new digs.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_1">
    <text>Oof, my head... What a day. Thanks for not killing me, at least.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_10">
    <text>We were responding to Shaman's call for help and were tired of the swamps anyway, had enough of sitting in puddles, it's time to venture out into the world! So, we decided to move to your area, to Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_11">
    <text>Well, welcome then!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_2">
    <text>So you're joking around? That means you're alive. What's your name?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_3">
    <text>They call me Shroud. What about you?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_4">
    <text>Everyone calls me Cold.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_5">
    <text>Who are you guys?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, not many have heard about our group and its heyday, and now no one knows at all. Some call us the "Swampers" but in general, we're all that's left of the "Clear Sky" faction. It used to be a scientific research group. Used to... but it fell apart.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_7">
    <text>What happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_8">
    <text>Even I don't really know the answer to that. We still can't figure it out.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_holod_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_9">
    <text>And what brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_">
    <text>?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_1">
    <text>Sidorovich, I heard you sell information. Is that true?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_10">
    <text>Alright, forget it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_11">
    <text>What can you tell me about Shaman?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_12">
    <text>500 rubles, and I'll tell you everything I know.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_13">
    <text>Alright, here you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_14">
    <text>Shaman is a righteous guy, a former special forces or something like that. He may not be on par with Wolf, but he's been trudging through the Zone for years and can easily outperform many stalkers. He's a true leader, and stalkers stand behind him like a stone wall - he won't abandon them in trouble and will share his last piece of bread. He's an honest, straightforward guy with a sound head on his shoulders - a real tactical genius. You'd be amazed by the operations he carries out! In short, he's a reliable guy, a true stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_15">
    <text>Do you know anything interesting about Mark?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_16">
    <text>I know everything if you got the money. Give me 500 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_19">
    <text>Do you know Borland well? I'd like to know more about him.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_2">
    <text>That's an exaggeration, I know some things. What did you want to know?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_20">
    <text>For that kind of information, my rate is always 500 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_21">
    <text>Can you break up a thousand?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_22">
    <text>Contrary to the rumors circulating in the Zone, Borland wasn't a military man, although he did serve in the army like others. He wasn't a scientist either. Borland was a thirty-two-year-old professional race car driver. Deprived of the opportunity to pursue his favorite activity due to the chaos in the country, which also affected sports, Borland began searching for a new place in life. And soon he realized that he could only find it in the Zone. All his talents found the widest application here: precision of eyes and hands, perfect physical condition, a cool head, and a passionate heart. Borland can assess the situation on the fly. He has an impeccable sense of time and distance. He didn't find anything fundamentally new for himself in the Zone though - it was the same as beyond the barrier, only more dangerous. If the cards are ever stacked against him and he needs to get out of here, he will find a way to do it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_23">
    <text>I heard something about a guy named Fang. What can you say about him?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_24">
    <text>Oh, Shroud, now you're asking about the right guy. Give me 500 rubles and listen.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_25">
    <text>All ears.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_26">
    <text>Fang is a super stalker, a member of Strelok's group, he was a fighter responsible for fire support. He was a skilled shooter and smart too. He modified and reinforced his exoskeleton so much that he could go to the Monolith alone. He disappeared somewhere a couple of years ago. Some said he was dead, others said he left the Zone. I don't know for sure myself, and I won't lie to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_27">
    <text>Can you tell me anything about Strelok's group? About Ghost, for example.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_28">
    <text>Give me 500 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_29">
    <text>Here you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_3">
    <text>Tell me about Wolf. Who is he, where is he from?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_30">
    <text>Ghost was a natural-born scout - he could stealthily infiltrate anywhere. It's no wonder he was given such a nickname. Unfortunately, he died. He went into the laboratory beneath Yantar and never came back. Ah, what a loss - he was a skilled stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_4">
    <text>Information comes at a price Shroud. Give me 500 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_5">
    <text>Ah, well, of course. Here you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_6">
    <text>Wow, isn't that too much for a simple conversation? I don't have that kind of money.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_7">
    <text>Sergey Ekimov (Wolf) and his family were always unlucky. His wife left him when he lost his job. He drank heavily for a while. But one day, when his younger brother, Pyotr Ekimov, got involved with a bad crowd and was severely beaten, with his nose and arms broken, Sergey lost control. He took his father's old shotgun, found his brother's abuser, and shot him. After some reflection, the brothers ventured into the Zone. At first, Sergey didn't have a nickname, he was constantly referred to as "Gray" until one of the experienced stalkers made a joke and recited the rhyme "Gray Wolf". The name stuck and that's how Sergey became Wolf. Over time, he got more experienced and famous. So he became the local veteran in the rookie village, traversing the Zone inside out and was considered a legend of the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_8">
    <text>Do you know anything else?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_9">
    <text>I see. Well, thank you for the information.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_klin_quest_trimming_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, stalker. Ready to go on a safari with us?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_klin_quest_trimming_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_klin_quest_trimming_dialog_2">
    <text>Then don't fall behind and cover the rest of the guys. Ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_klin_quest_trimming_dialog_3">
    <text>Let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_0">
    <text>Can I join your clan? I think I've helped enough to be considered one of you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_1">
    <text>Of course! I liked you from the start and after what you've done, I'm ready to accept you into our clan. What do you say?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_2">
    <text>Yes, of course. What could be better than the life of a free stalker?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_3">
    <text>Cold beer and hot sand on the beach? Never mind... I hope I don't have to explain the stalker's code to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_4">
    <text>Better tell me, so there won't be any questions later.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_5">
    <text>Actually, it's quite simple. To be a stalker means to be human. To help a comrade in a tough moment, not to be sneaky, not to commit treachery, to share a medkit or a piece of bread, to cover each other's backs in battle, to share a campfire. Also, our main enemy is the Bandit scum, who only parasitize on our stalker brethren. Our goal is to cleanse the Zone of these degenerates once and for all.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_6">
    <text>I understand.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_7">
    <text>Then I won't bother you anymore. Everyone present, congratulate out new comrade's arrival to our friendly community! May you be free from claws and anomalies, stalker!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_8">
    <text>Alright, I'll go about my stalker business then...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_complite_9">
    <text>I'll think about it some more.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_failure_0">
    <text>How can I join your clan?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_failure_1">
    <text>Easy! If I see that you're a good person and can be trusted, I'll call you one of us. You know, they say a friend is known in times of trouble. Well, we have plenty of troubles right now! If you help us, consider it a test passed.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_leader_shaman_joining_a_clan_failure_2">
    <text>Got it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_0">
    <text>Got a minute?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_1">
    <text>What do you want? Make it quick, time is money.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_2">
    <text>I heard your guys recently caught some Freedomer. Is that true?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_3">
    <text>Kid, do you even know where you've come, who you're standing in front of, and what nonsense you're spouting here?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_4">
    <text>Sorry, I must have mistaken. I'll leave now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_0">
    <text>I'm here, did you want something?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, it's you. I have an offer for you. Will you join our brigade? We're in desperate need of people. As a newcomer in the Zone, you can either join us or the Stalkers. Everything else is chaos: everyone kills whoever they want. But we live by principles and teach others the same, for which we take our rightful share. Garbage is under control for now, and now it's time for Cordon. We've already reclaimed about half of it. We just need to clear out the stalkers in the vehicle station and show who's the boss around here, then we would completely dominate the area. As for the rookie village, it's filled with nothing but fools. So, it's advantageous for you to join us. Well, have you made your decision?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_10">
    <text>I've sent the coordinates to your PDA. You have a gun, so there won't be any problems.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_11">
    <text>Alright, I'm on it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_12">
    <text>I'm a loner so I won't join your group. I wouldn't mind working for you though.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_13">
    <text>That's a shame, but I won't force you. I always have work if you're interested.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_14">
    <text>I'm listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_15">
    <text>We need to take down a stalker. He's currently returning from Dark Valley with valuable loot. If you kill him, you can keep the loot for yourself. Plus, I'll pay you extra. Are you in?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_16">
    <text>No problem, I'm in.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_17">
    <text>I've sent the coordinates to your PDA. You have a gun, so there won't be any problems. I'll be waiting for your good news.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_18">
    <text>I'll handle it quickly, wait for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_2">
    <text>No, sorry, I prefer to be on my own.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_3">
    <text>Too bad, kid. Well, up to you. Get out of here while I'm still feeling generous.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_5">
    <text>Actually, I've always dreamed of being one of the tough guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_6">
    <text>Great, then you'll have to pass a little test, a real one involving blood. I happen to have a job like that.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_7">
    <text>I'm all ears.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_8">
    <text>We need to take down a stalker. He's currently returning from Dark Valley with valuable loot. If you kill him, you can keep the loot for yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_dialog_9">
    <text>No problem, I'm in.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_gotovo_dialog_0">
    <text>I killed the stalker and kept the loot for myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_gotovo_dialog_1">
    <text>Job done, you can celebrate! Here's a small cash reward for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_gotovo_dialog_2">
    <text>If you need anything else, feel free to ask.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_soglasn_dialog_0">
    <text>I killed the stalker and took his loot for myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_soglasn_dialog_1">
    <text>You did the job well, no questions there. But everything went a bit too smoothly... It seems suspicious to me. So, you hang around the Zone while I gather some information. If everything checks out, I'll contact you on your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_gopstop_soglasn_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_0">
    <text>I need medical help.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_1">
    <text>Alright, let me take a look...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_11">
    <text>[continue...]</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_111">
    <text>There you go, all good now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_2">
    <text>Let’s have a look... Well, your liver is bigger than I'd expect, but that's an occupational hazard, right? Apart from that, you’re as healthy as a burer.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_moskit_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, dead man! Empty your pockets and hand over your loot.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_moskit_dialog_1">
    <text>I don't understand! What's with the hostility?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_moskit_dialog_2">
    <text>There's nothing to understand, give me your loot or you'll die!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_moskit_dialog_3">
    <text>Alright, here you go. I only have this artifact and 1300 rubles. You won't get away with this though.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_moskit_dialog_4">
    <text>Get lost while you're still alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_merc_dialog_0">
    <text>Hold on and don't move. Who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_merc_dialog_1">
    <text>I'm from Sidorovich, I brought the payment.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_merc_dialog_2">
    <text>Got it. Proceed.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_merc_dialog_3">
    <text>Here, take the bag. The seal is intact, just as we agreed. You can count it if you want.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_merc_dialog_4">
    <text>Great. Let me check the number... All good. I won't bother counting it - Sidorovich always keeps his word. So, are you coming with us or will you wait here?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_merc_dialog_5">
    <text>You go ahead, we'll see how it goes. Don't worry, I won't get in your way.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_0">
    <text>How's it going with Shmyga?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_1">
    <text>You arrived just in time - the mercenaries are already on their way. Did you rest up?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_10">
    <text>I'll manage. So, can I go now?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_11">
    <text>Hold on. If everything goes smoothly, you'll receive a whopping 10,000 rubles from me. It's worth it for such a job. Alright, now go.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_12">
    <text>Well, Sidorovich, that's quite generous of you. I'm on my way.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_2">
    <text>We'll all sleep in the afterlife!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_3">
    <text>Great! So, here's the situation: Some mercs will be waiting for you near the camp of that scum Shmyga and his gang. I'm paying them good money for this job. Here, take the money bag. Give it to the squad leader. And let me remind you, no funny business! There's a seal on the bag and I've already sent the number to the mercenaries. If something's wrong with it, they'll shoot you on the spot. So be careful around them.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_4">
    <text>Would they really kill me?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_5">
    <text>Absolutely, Shroud. The Mercenaries are serious professionals. If they take on a job, they'll complete it in the best way possible. Otherwise, no one would hire them again. But if you come across them in the Zone, it's best to steer clear. They won't hesitate to shoot you if you get in their way. Understood?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_6">
    <text>Got it. But if the Mercenaries are like that, why didn't you ask Stalkers? They're closer and won't ask for as much money.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_7">
    <text>Everything has to go perfectly, and only professionals can be trusted with that. Stalkers are a friendly bunch, but they can't keep their mouths shut. Alright, enough talk. The mercenaries will be waiting for you near the rocks not far from Shmyga's camp. Just give them the cash, you don't have to join the fight. The main thing is to find Shmyga and take my case from him.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_8">
    <text>Are you sure there will be a case there? What if Shmyga has already opened it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_9">
    <text>He hasn't opened it, I'm certain. It has a tricky lock that can only be cracked by one master in the Zone. But I've already informed him about the theft, so Shmyga won't go near him. The most he can do is hiding the case somewhere, but it will be nearby, always within reach. So if you don't find the case with Shmyga, look for it in the camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_complite_0">
    <text>Be happy Sidorovich! I took care of Shmyga.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_complite_1">
    <text>The case, where's the case?!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_complite_2">
    <text>Here it is, here! Take your case, Scrooge McDuck. Hehe!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_complite_3">
    <text>Oh! Praise the Black Stalker! Well done, Shroud! Here's your well deserved reward. Ah, now we can live it up!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_sidor_dialog_complite_4">
    <text>Well, don't let me interrupt your joy.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_complite_dialog_0">
    <text>About the bandits...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_complite_dialog_1">
    <text>So, how did it go?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_complite_dialog_2">
    <text>I took care of them.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_complite_dialog_3">
    <text>Nothing yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_complite_dialog_4">
    <text>You're not dragging your feet, alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_complite_dialog_5">
    <text>Thanks a lot! Here's your reward!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_dialog_0">
    <text>Shaman sent me, do you need help?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_dialog_1">
    <text>Help? Yes, I do. You see, we've just set up our base and haven't had time to clear the area yet. The bandits are all over the place, robbing stalkers who bring me goods. At this rate I won't have anything to trade. Just yesterday, another Bandit squad showed up. Bold of them - they settled right in front of our base! Could you teach them a lesson?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_dialog_2">
    <text>No problem! They'll remember my lesson for a long time.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_kusto_dialog_3">
    <text>You know, maybe another time.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_shaman_dialog_0">
    <text>Can I help with anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_shaman_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, we have a little problem. Ask our trader, he'll tell you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_fighting_for_territory_shaman_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_apparatyra_dialog_0">
    <text>Phew, I brought your equipment. It's heavy.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_apparatyra_dialog_1">
    <text>That's great, Shroud. We'll set it up now. The important thing is for it to work.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_apparatyra_dialog_2">
    <text>Can I help with anything else?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_apparatyra_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, Shroud, but later. For now, you can go about your business. Just don't go too far, your help will be needed tomorrow if not today. Everyone's help will be needed.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_apparatyra_dialog_4">
    <text>Got it. I'll be around.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_0">
    <text>What's the matter?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_1">
    <text>Sit down, it's a serious matter. Pathogenych told me about our contact. I don't know if Logopedist or Sleeper arranged all this, but it's become tiresome. It's time to put an end to these scumbags. Are you in?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_2">
    <text>Of course. What do you need from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_3">
    <text>Actually, almost nothing. We have plenty of weapons, enough ammunition and armor for everyone. But we're really short on people. As you can see, we don't have the numbers here in the vehicle station. I don't count the rookies from the village - they're all inexperienced. To deal with the Bandits once and for all, we need allies. The military won't help us, they're too proud. Duty couldn't care less about our problems, they're fighting with mutants. Freedom doesn't even know what's happening around here and they have some sort of neutrality with Bandits. So, it turns out that we're completely alone against this gang of thieves.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_4">
    <text>What should we do then?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_5">
    <text>I think I know someone who can help us. Can you go to Sidorovich for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_6">
    <text>No problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_7">
    <text>Great. I'll contact him now, he'll give you what you need when you meet. That's it, you can run along now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_shaman_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_sidor_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey Sidorovich, Shaman sent me. I need to pick something up?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_sidor_dialog_1">
    <text>Ah, yes. Here's your cargo. So, are you trying to make friends with the "Swampers"?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_sidor_dialog_2">
    <text>What? I don't know anything about that. Who are the "Swampers"? </text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_sidor_dialog_3">
    <text>Oh, well, if you don't know then I won't spoil the surprise for you. You'll find out when the time comes, heh. Also, be careful not to drop the equipment, there's valuable parts inside!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_help_nebo_sidor_dialog_4">
    <text>I'll do my best. Alright, I'm off.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_atp_dialog_0">
    <text>Thank you so much, Shroud. I'll tell our people how you helped me. Go see Shaman, he'll reward you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_atp_dialog_1">
    <text>Alright, how about you? How are you doing?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_atp_dialog_2">
    <text>Not too hot but I'll make it. The medkit did its job and I'm feeling okay. I might need to visit the medic to patch up some holes, though.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_atp_dialog_3">
    <text>See you later.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey. I was starting to think you wouldn't show up. Did Wolf send you?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes. So, you must be the best hunter around here?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_dialog_2">
    <text>Correction - the only hunter. They call me Leshiy. Wolf has already filled me in about you. Listen carefully - everything I say is to be followed without question: if I say stand, you stand; if I say lie down, you lie down; if I say kiss a boar, you kiss that boar.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_dialog_3">
    <text>Are you serious man?!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_dialog_4">
    <text>Just kidding! Don't get all worked up. Try not to make any noise and follow me closely. We're going to hunt down a boar. There's one here with the strength of a bear. It's injured several people already. We need to calm it down. Ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_dialog_5">
    <text>It's still just a boar right? Show me the way.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_hanter_dialog_0">
    <text>We last saw the boar not far from the train tracks. There's a small hollow there - it's always damp even on a sunny day. The boar will most likely be there. When we get closer, you go around the hill on the right, and I'll go on the left. Once you spot the boar, drive it towards me - I'll take it down with buckshot. Stay alert, there might be other mutants around.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_hanter_dialog_1">
    <text>Let's go quietly.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_wounded_dialog_0">
    <text>Damn, damn, damn! That damn thing! It gutted me! It hurts like hell! Do you have a medkit?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_wounded_dialog_1">
    <text>Here, take this.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_wounded_dialog_2">
    <text>No, sorry.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_wounded_dialog_3">
    <text>Thank you, Shroud. Listen, I can make it back to the camp on my own, but I'm no use as a shooter right now. Can you take me to the vehicle station? Who knows what other creatures are lurking in these bushes.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_npc_wood_goblin_wounded_dialog_4">
    <text>No problem. Hang in there, Leshiy, we're almost at the camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_shaman_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, if it isn't Shroud.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_shaman_dialog_1">
    <text>Do we know each other?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_shaman_dialog_2">
    <text>Not personally, but I've heard about you. I'm Shaman. I'm sort of the leader around here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_shaman_dialog_3">
    <text>Nice to meet you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_shaman_dialog_4">
    <text>Wolf speaks highly of you. Now I see for myself that you're a skilled guy, despite being a rookie. Well, since you're truly experienced beyond your years and willing to help a comrade in a difficult time, you can consider yourself one of us. From this moment on, you're officially recognized as a licensed stalker. We'll make you an ID later so you can roam the Zone whenever you want. But don't mess with the military, they can put you against a wall with or without an ID. Well, congratulations, Shroud! Here's a reward for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_hunting_shaman_dialog_5">
    <text>Thank you, chief! I'm happy to help!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_0">
    <text>Borland! Glad to see you alive and well! How did you manage to escape from the soldiers?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_1">
    <text>There are good people in this world. Stalkers from the vehicle station helped me out. I knew right away that there was no way you could gather that much money in two days. And Kolyazin isn't a fool, by the second day, when the deadline was approaching, he came up to me and started asking who else could pay the ransom for me. They can always put you against a wall, but there is no money to be earned that way. So, I sent a message to Shaman. He sent a messenger with the ransom. Kolyazin is very angry at you, so don't cross paths with the soldiers anymore. Also be careful, you never know what might happen.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright, I'll see you later!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, what a mess. I almost had the money too, just a little short. Kolyazin kept sending me threats on my PDA, he even wrote that they fed you to the mutants, and now it's my turn. Well, I panicked.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_3">
    <text>Yeah, it's an unpleasant situation. The colonel is determined to get you now, he's stubborn like that. But don't worry, we'll come up with something.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_4">
    <text>True, let's not dwell on these things. How are you doing?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_5">
    <text>I'm alright, just a few bruises. Nothing serious, I've had worse. So, I called you here to ask: is it possible for you to become my partner? I've been in the Zone for quite some time, you won't get lost with me. True, I was on the mainland for the past few months but you know what they say, experience doesn't fade away! My last partner decided to quit the Zone and went somewhere far away, maybe to the States or somewhere else. He got tired, basically. I was planning to go with him, but changed my mind the last second. I can't live without the adrenaline! So, I decided to come back to the Zone and find a new partner around here. Then I saw you, this idiot who's crawling through a hole in the fence, right near the minefield. Well, I thought, that's it! Both this idiot and I are done for. That's when I decided to save you. Now I see that you're not such a fool, you catch on quickly. I can teach you a few tricks, and you could become a great stalker. So, what do you say, are you in?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_6">
    <text>You seem like an honest guy, so why not? But what are we going to do? I've already seen enough of Cordon - there isn't much to find here. I don't dare to go further alone, so maybe we should go together? Somewhere towards the center of the Zone, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_7">
    <text>Hold on, you want to go to the center with our ragtag gear? We should get some proper equipment and better weapons first.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_8">
    <text>Any ideas about that?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_9">
    <text>I'm always filled with ideas. So, here's the plan: I'll go talk to Sidorovich. He asked for some kind of favor, either to go somewhere or do something else. I can't refuse or he'll get upset. I'll try to negotiate some gear at a lower price for the favor. So, I might be gone for a day or two. While I do that, don't sit here twiddling your thumbs, go and see Pathogenych. They've got something going on with Shaman and apparently it's not going well for them. They might need some help. Perhaps you can earn a little something there.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_borland_meet_dialog_frend_0">
    <text>Hey, buddy, how's life? How are you doing?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_0">
    <text>Where have you been? I've been looking for you everywhere.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_1">
    <text>You won't believe what happened while you were away!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_10">
    <text>Let me see. So... hmm... wow... Is that all? Very interesting... What kind of an artifact does the Monolith have? I've also never heard of a laboratory under Cordon. There are some service tunnels below, but nobody knows where they lead. Also, an undercover Monolith agent posing as a Freedom member? It's hard to believe!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_11">
    <text>Do you think the info on the PDA is true? I mean, about the artifact and the laboratory?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_12">
    <text>I think it's a waste of time. If there was an artifact, someone most likely found it and handed it over to Sidorovich or someone else. But I wouldn't mind checking out the laboratory. Imagine if no other stalkers have been there yet, we can gather so much stuff! It would be better than finding a mountain of artifacts!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_13">
    <text>So, what's the plan?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_14">
    <text>I'll try to get some information about the underground from Sidorovich. He's been sitting in his basement for a long time, he's practically one of the first stalkers, he must know something. As for you brother, go and see Logopedist. Try to get some information from him about the captured Freedom member. The bandits still don't know they had a Monolith guy captive. Try to find out where they caught him, maybe there's an entrance to the catacombs nearby. Just be careful, you don't want to mess with those guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_15">
    <text>Okay, I'll do my best.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, what could have happened here? Mutants gave you a hard time? Or was it a Bandit robbery?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_3">
    <text>Neither! Someone almost cracked my skull in the elevator, can you imagine?! Someone sneaked up from behind and hit me right on the head. It still hurts.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_4">
    <text>What the hell were you doing in the elevator?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_5">
    <text>I was looking for Van there, he was supposed to unlock the Freedom member's PDA for me. I found it but it was too late - Van was killed.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_6">
    <text>Wow! Who killed Van then? Was it all because of that PDA? Rumors about the suicidal Freedom member have been spreading all over Cordon, and now there's his PDA too. What's the story behind all this?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_7">
    <text>Well, I freed that crazy Freedom guy from captivity and instead of saying thank you, he put a bullet in his own temple. He had nothing on him except the locked PDA. So I took it to Van to unlock it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_8">
    <text>What's on the PDA? Anything interesting?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_important_meet_borland_dialog_9">
    <text>Not everything is clear, maybe you can figure it out.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_0">
    <text>I heard you might have some work?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_1">
    <text>And I've heard they milk cows in Limansk! Ha-ha! Well, I have a few problems. Can you help me sort them out? I'll pay well.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright, I'll do it. I'll come to you as soon as I find out something.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_2">
    <text>Tell me, what's the problem?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_3">
    <text>Me and Shaman decided that we've had enough of losing people to Bandits, even Stalkers are tired of all these fighting. Not everyone can pass through the "Bakery" so we decided to make a deal with the gangsters. They agreed to let our guys through the tunnel without any trouble, and we agreed to pay them once a week, Logopedist was satisfied. Well, we sent our mediator with the money to the gang yesterday, but he never reached Logopedist. I have no idea where he could have gone - it's like he disappeared into thin air. The bandits say he didn't pass through the tunnel and didn't show up in their camp. It's just a stone's throw away and yet he vanished. We don't want to suspect the bandits yet, especially since there's no reason for them to kill him. Everyone would benefit from the deal. But yeah, our mediator is gone.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_4">
    <text>Why did you send him alone?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, the thing is we didn't expect any problems. I've known Logopedist for a long time, we crossed paths a few years ago. Despite being a Bandit, he keeps his word. Although he doesn't get along with Shaman - they had a big falling out a couple of years ago. That's why I handle all the negotiations with Logopedist, he's clearly not involved in this.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_6">
    <text>Someone's disappeared regardless. Maybe Logopedist has enemies who wanted to set him up?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_7">
    <text>Yes, that thought crossed my mind too. Maybe someone doesn't approve of our arrangement with the bandits, and I can guess who that someone might be.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_8">
    <text>Who is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_9">
    <text>There's this scumbag in their camp called Sleeper. He was always in favor of killing all of our guys, but Logopedist kept him on a short leash. It's possible that Sleeper pulled off something like this behind his boss's back. Here's the deal: Our technician Van has golden hands. He hacked into the PDAs of the entire gang's top brass a long time ago. They don't have their own technician, so they call Van whenever something breaks. And Van is no fool, he's already cracked their frequencies, meaning we can monitor their movements at any time. Take this PDA, I'll send you Sleeper's frequency. Keep an eye on him, what he's up to, where he goes and so on.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_one_0">
    <text>I tracked Sleeper down. He's an unpleasant guy.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_one_1">
    <text>Did you find out anything about our contact?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_one_2">
    <text>I do, but it's bad news. The contact is dead, the bandits got him, but I don't think it's as simple as it seems.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_one_3">
    <text>That's what I feared. Did Sleeper decide to set up Logopedist, or did Logopedist know everything from the start? But then why did they kill our guy? So many questions, no answers. Here, take this as payment for your work.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_one_4">
    <text>That's not all. Besides your contact and the bandits, there was another stalker there. Judging by the patch, he was from the Freedom faction. But he was completely nuts - I killed the bandits and this Freedom guy picked up a pistol from the ground and shot himself. Can you imagine?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_one_5">
    <text>No way! You're kidding, right? He shot himself! We haven't seen anyone from Freedom around here for a long time. What business do they have here? And I won't believe for a second that he shot himself in the head. Maybe they like to smoke some weed or some other hallucinogenic stuff, but to commit suicide? You're quite the storyteller. Well, here's 500 rubles for your interesting tale. Go buy yourself something nice. As for me, I'll continue dealing with more serious matters - the bandits won't get away with killing our contact.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_one_6">
    <text>You're not believing me Pathogenych, but that's how it happened. Well, suit yourself, goodbye.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_0">
    <text>I tracked Sleeper down. He's an unpleasant guy.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_1">
    <text>Did you find out anything about our contact?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_2">
    <text>I'm not a hundred percent sure, but he's most likely dead. I didn't dare to get too close, but I saw a dead stalker there. I assume that's your contact.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_3">
    <text>What if it's not him? Well, who am I kidding, it's probably him, poor guy. The bandits won't get away with this, whether Logopedist knew about it or not, these scumbags need to be punished. Here's your payment - thanks for tracking him.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_4">
    <text>Hold on Pathogenych, that's not all. Sleeper and the bandits have a stalker captive in that house. I can't say for sure, but I think the patch on his armor said "Freedom".</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_5">
    <text>That's interesting! Why would a Freedom member wander so far from his base? We've never seen them around here before... Are you interested in finding out? I'll pay for any information.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_6">
    <text>I'm curious myself, plus we can't just leave the man captive with those scumbags.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_7">
    <text>Then hurry and rescue him before they shoot him. Once he's free, bring him to us.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_patogen_meet_dialog_complite_two_8">
    <text>On it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_salvation_freedom_dialog_0">
    <text>Pathogenych, I don't know how to say this... The Freedom member shot himself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_salvation_freedom_dialog_1">
    <text>What? What do you mean he shot himself?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_salvation_freedom_dialog_2">
    <text>Exactly how it sounds! I took care of the bandits, approached the Freedom guy, and he picked up a pistol from the ground and shot himself in the head. I didn't even have time to react.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_salvation_freedom_dialog_3">
    <text>Well... We didn't really need Freedom in Cordon anyway, still, why did he surrender to the bandits? Aren't they supposed to be neutral? And why did he shoot himself, was he high or something? Well, it's quite a story. If you find out anything new, come back.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_salvation_freedom_dialog_4">
    <text>Will do.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_fyrgon_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, master of hammer and screwdriver! I have something for you - can you unlock this PDA?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_fyrgon_dialog_1">
    <text>You forgot about the soldering iron. Hi, give me your PDA and I'll see what I can do. Why is it locked? Did you steal it or took it from a corpse?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_fyrgon_dialog_2">
    <text>No way! I didn't kill anyone, he was already dead, the owner I mean. Can you imagine, I saved him from the bandits and then he just took a gun and shot himself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_fyrgon_dialog_3">
    <text>Wow. Well, never mind, it's not my business. I can unlock the PDA, but it will take some time. Come back in a couple of hours.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_fyrgon_dialog_4">
    <text>Great, I'll be back soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_fyrgon_dialog_5">
    <text>Wait, you should talk to Shaman, he has an urgent task for you. I'll unlock your PDA for free while you're at it, deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_fyrgon_dialog_6">
    <text>Deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_patogen_dialog_0">
    <text>Have you seen Van? I asked him for a favor, but he disappeared somewhere. Strange.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_patogen_dialog_1">
    <text>I have no idea where he could have gone, he doesn't report to me. Wait a minute... Sergey just came back from a walk like five minutes ago and he mentioned something about Van. It seems Van was running towards the grain elevator and nearly knocked Sergey down near the bus stop. Check there.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_line_secret_freedom_patogen_dialog_2">
    <text>Thanks, I'll go take a look.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d1_dialog_0">
    <text>Have you seen a stalker named Shmyga around here recently? Someone who looks like him? Or anyone suspicious for that matter?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d1_dialog_1">
    <text>Suspicious, you say? Let me think. I haven't seen him myself, but the guys by the campfire were talking about some strange guys at the abandoned elevator. Maybe your Shmyga is hanging out there?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d1_dialog_2">
    <text>Could be. I'll go ask elsewhere. Maybe someone knows something about this Shmyga.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d1_dialog_3">
    <text>Ask Gut, he sticks his nose in everything around here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d1_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, I'll go ask. Thanks, Wolf.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d2_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, have you seen any suspicious characters around Cordon recently?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d2_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, every face here looks suspicious. Be more specific - who are you looking for?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d2_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm looking for Shmyga. Do you know him?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d2_dialog_3">
    <text>I vaguely remember that stalker. It was a couple of days ago. We were sitting by the campfire, and this Shmyga was bragging to everyone that he's going to get rich and leave the Zone soon. Then he disappeared somewhere. We thought he left. But yesterday, Roman saw him near the abandoned house across from the farm with somebody. They were arguing loudly so Roman decided not to get involved and walked away. You should go and talk to Sketcher at the vehicle station. That guy knows all the rumors: who, what, where and why. He's like a one-man grapevine. If he doesn't know, then no one does.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d2_dialog_4">
    <text>Thank you for the lead.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d3_dialog_0">
    <text>I heard you might have some rumors to share. Do you know anything about a stalker named Shmyga?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d3_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, people say all sorts of things. I know your Shmyga - not a pleasant guy. But if you're looking for him, you've come to the wrong person - he doesn't report to me, so I don't know where he hangs out. But if he's in Cordon, there are only a few decent hiding spots here: the grain elevator, the house by the farm, and the checkpoint up north. Check those places, maybe you'll find him.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d3_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay then, thanks anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d3_dialog_3">
    <text>Thanks won't butter my bread.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d3_dialog_4">
    <text>Here's a sandwich with red caviar for you. Good luck!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_d3_dialog_5">
    <text>Don't worry, you won't starve.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_0">
    <text>What do you want, scum?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_1">
    <text>Guys, I don't want any trouble. I'm just looking for someone here. Do you happen to know Shmyga?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_2">
    <text>Who are you and what do you want from him?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_3">
    <text>I just need to deliver a message to him, just a couple of words. So do you know him?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_4">
    <text>Listen, messenger, you better get out of here before we rearrange your bones.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_5">
    <text>I'll leave, just tell me if Shmyga is here or not.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_6">
    <text>Are you not getting it?! I'll open another hole in your head if you mention our boss again!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_7">
    <text>So Shmyga is your boss?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_8">
    <text>That's it, punk, you're in for it now! Get him, boys!!!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_npc_pate_dialog_9">
    <text>Damn!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_0">
    <text>Stalker Shroud reporting for duty!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, you're quick! Well done! Here's a treat for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_10">
    <text>Don't worry, Sidorovich, I'll take care of everything.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_2">
    <text>Happy to help! Okay, enough jokes. What's the matter?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_3">
    <text>Well Shroud, I'm not in the mood for jokes either. So here's the deal: There's a stalker here named Shmyga. Silly name, I won't argue. But that's not the point. Anyway, this Shmyga owes me a hefty sum of money. He volunteered to be the middleman between me and some very serious people who dwell closer to the center of the Zone. It doesn't matter who they are, but I needed their connections badly. Well, I ran a couple of checks on this Shmyga and he seemed like a decent guy. He did everything smoothly and without a hitch. So I trusted him - asked him to deliver the payment to those people for the goods. In the end, I got the goods, but the money never reached the clients. Well, luckily I always keep a backup stash and managed to settle with the suppliers somehow.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_4">
    <text>What happened to Shmyga? Did he die or run away?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, I thought he died too at first. But damn it, he's alive and kicking. They don't call him Shmyga anymore though. I don't know his new name. But I know for sure that he's lurking somewhere in Cordon - the local guys saw a guy resembling him recently. So, I have a very important task for you: find this stalker, but don't kill him, he might not have any money on him. Your task is just to locate him. The rest is my concern. So, are you up for the search?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_6">
    <text>What's the pay?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_7">
    <text>I'll give you ten thousand. Plus, a discount on my goods. Shroud, this is really important, agree to it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright, I'll find your debtor.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_9">
    <text>Remember, under no circumstances should you kill Shmyga or his buddies. If he dies, my money will go to the grave with him. And if he escapes to the north of the Zone, we'll never find him again.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_complite_0">
    <text>I haven't seen Shmyga himself, but I know where his camp is. He and his gang have settled at the northern checkpoint. His friends are really aggressive - they almost put a bullet in my head.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_complite_1">
    <text>Well done, Shroud! You did everything right. As for Shmyga and his gang, don't worry, professionals will take care of them. Rest up while I have a talk with someone. Come back in an hour and I'll have a special task for you. Just remember, you may need to shoot, so stock up on ammo and medkits, you never know how things will turn out.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_complite_2">
    <text>Great, can't wait to teach those bastards a lesson.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_fail_0">
    <text>I took care of those bastards, Shmyga's guys. But he wasn't there. Looks like he managed to slip away. I'm sorry, Sidorovich, but they started it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_fail_1">
    <text>"They started it"? Are you a little kid making up excuses? Oh Shroud, you've ruined everything! Who asked you to play the hero? I clearly told you - don't kill anyone! And what did you do?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_fail_2">
    <text>I told you what I did! They shot at me first! What did you expect me to do, stand there and get shot? I taught those monsters a lesson, next time your Shmyga won't mess with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_fail_3">
    <text>There won't be a next time! Now Shmyga will go to the center of the Zone and good luck finding him there. That's it, my money is gone. Oh, Shroud, Shroud... I had such high hopes for you. Goodbye.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_serious_business_sidor_dialog_fail_4">
    <text>Uh... I... I didn't do it on purpose, Sidorovich...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_complite_dialog_0">
    <text>I tracked down Sawyer and discovered the stash location. Here are the coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_complite_dialog_1">
    <text>Excellent, Shroud. Here's your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_complite_dialog_2">
    <text>What will you do with him?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_complite_dialog_3">
    <text>We'll make him pay! Just kidding. Though, our clan has rules and he broke them, so we'll have to punish him. We'll take him somewhere in the woods, give him a pistol and a single bullet. It'll be a lesson for him, if he manages to get out, that is.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_complite_dialog_4">
    <text>Harsh.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_complite_dialog_5">
    <text>Rules are meaningless without consequences. I can't let it slide, that's why I'm the leader.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_complite_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, good luck to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_dialog_0">
    <text>Is there any work?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_dialog_1">
    <text>Ah, Shroud, come in. I have a job just for someone like you. You see, there's a rat on the ship. The guys' belongings have started to disappear. Suspicion falls on Sawyer, but they haven't caught him red-handed, and no one can prove that it's him. I need you to follow him, but quietly. Just observe where he keeps going, and then show us that place. But act stealthily and don't take matters into your own hands, we'll take care of him ourselves.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_dialog_2">
    <text>We should just deal with him and be done with it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_dialog_3">
    <text>We'll have plenty of time for that. But the stolen items won't be returned to us that way. This Sawyer is a stubborn guy. I'm sending you the coordinates of his PDA. See where he's heading again. Just don't make yourself visible.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_shaman_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, I'll do it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_0">
    <text>Phew! Man, you scared me. Why are you sneaking up on people like that?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_1">
    <text>So, this is where you're hiding the stolen stuff.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_2">
    <text>Hey man, calm down! These are mine! Who are you anyway?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_3">
    <text>Shaman sent me to track down the rat who's taking his supplies.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_4">
    <text>Damn! Please man, don't hand me to Shaman! He won't have any evidence without these items. Don't turn me in! I'll give you money. How much are they paying you? Two thousand? Five? I'll give you ten if you keep quiet. Just give Shaman fake coordinates, it's the stash of Vasya February. I'll throw a couple of stolen items there so everyone will think it's him. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright, deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_6">
    <text>Here's the money. Get your PDA out, I'll send you the coordinates of Vasya's stash. That's it, we're done.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_shadowing_soer_dialog_7">
    <text>Take care.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_npc_garlic_dialog_0">
    <text>Are you Sidor's courier? Did you bring it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_npc_garlic_dialog_1">
    <text>Of course, here's your crate with everything intact. It was damn heavy.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_npc_garlic_dialog_2">
    <text>Thank you, you've done us a favor. We were planning to go on a raid with the guys so we ordered various things, but there was no one to go and pick them up and the time was running out. Take this bonus from me personally for the speedy delivery.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_npc_garlic_dialog_3">
    <text>Wow, thank you! If you need anything else, just ask for Shroud. I'm at your service.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_0">
    <text>What's the matter?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_1">
    <text>Finally, you showed up. I was starting to think you disappeared. Heh-heh.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_10">
    <text>That's more like it. Enough chit-chat. Hand over the package.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_2">
    <text>I don't get the joke. Why did you call me?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_3">
    <text>Do you need more work?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_4">
    <text>Obviously, I came here for a reason, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_5">
    <text>Well who knows, maybe you came to visit an old sick man, brought some oranges or some other treats? You guys never give us traders the respect we deserve. Do you think our life is a bed of roses? The color might be the same, but the taste is completely different. I might just pack up and leave for the mainland. Maybe I'll go to Crimea for a vacation. Then you'll remember who Sidorovich was and what he did for all of you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_6">
    <text>Got that off your chest? Can we talk about the job now?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_7">
    <text>Oh, forget it. I don't want to deal with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_8">
    <text>Then why the hell did you call me, you old goat? If there's work, let's hear it. If not, I'm out of here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_9">
    <text>Hold on, Shroud, I'm sorry. I got carried away... I do have something for you. It won't require much effort - you just need to deliver a package to a stalker at the vehicle station. He will be waiting for you at the entrance. I'll pay you 3.000 rubles for the job. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_complite_0">
    <text>Everything went fine. I delivered it in perfect condition. That stalker even gave me a speed bonus.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_complite_1">
    <text>Well, since he did, I won't pay you anything.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_complite_2">
    <text>What the hell, you prick!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_complite_3">
    <text>Just kidding! Have a sense of humor like me! Ah young ones, immediately spewing insults... you don't understand anything in life, especially here in the Zone. Here's your money - I always keep my word.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_complite_4">
    <text>You're quite the joker. Petrosyan would be jealous.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_complite_5">
    <text>Of course! We can't do without a little humor here! Heh-heh-heh!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_complite_6">
    <text>Well, well, we have a comedian in the basement. Alright, call me if there's more work.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_fail_0">
    <text>What the hell Sidorovich?! Why didn't you warn me that there are thugs roaming around here? They took your package! Damn it! I barely escaped with my life, they almost shot me. Give me compensation for the risk!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_fail_1">
    <text>Get out of here, you bastard! Did you think you could scam me like that? You think I would just believe your word like a little child?! That stalker you shared the contents of the package with, he works for me!!! You're a damn fool!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_fail_2">
    <text>Sidorovich, I... </text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_fail_3">
    <text>Get the hell out of here before I feed you to the dogs!!! You dare try to trick me, you scum?! I never want to see your sorry face again!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sidor_dialog_fail_4">
    <text>Well, I... Don't be mad, chief...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey there, wanderer. I have something to discuss, let's talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_1">
    <text>What's the matter?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_10">
    <text>Come on, open the lock already. There's no time to waste!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_11">
    <text>Now we're talking! Just a moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_12">
    <text>Well, what's in there?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_13">
    <text>Wow, there's a lot of good stuff here! Hold on, let's divide everything fairly. Say, which one do you want: an AK or a helmet?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_14">
    <text>Give me the helmet. People keep shooting each other around here, at least I'll protect my head.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_15">
    <text>Give me the AK, you can't go anywhere without a gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_16">
    <text>Here you go. Now, let's see. Which one do you choose: a Soviet underbarrel grenade launcher or a foreign scope?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_17">
    <text>Give me the scope, I'll find a good spot for it. I was the most accurate shooter in my squad, you know.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_18">
    <text>Give me the grenade launcher, love those things - one shot and everything goes boom.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_19">
    <text>Alright, take it. Oh, there are more guns here! Which one do you want: an Italian shotgun or a British rifle?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_2">
    <text>I heard you're delivering a package to the vehicle station. How much did Sidorovich promise you for it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_20">
    <text>Give me the rifle, not a fan of shotguns.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_21">
    <text>Definitely the shotgun - it packs a punch!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_22">
    <text>Alright, there are a couple of artifacts here too. I think I'll keep those for myself, I've earned it. But you can have this suit - "Wind of Freedom". It's a good piece, I tell you. Freedom fighters know their way around light armor.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_23">
    <text>Works for me. Is that all?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_24">
    <text>Yep. So are you satisfied? You got way more than you would ever buy for 3.000, that's for sure. As for Sidorovich, you'll figure things out with him somehow.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_25">
    <text>Yeah. See you later.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_3">
    <text>What's it to you? Go on your way and don't stick your nose into other people's affairs.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_4">
    <text>Calm down! Watch what you say or you might catch a bullet for those words. I want to help you, and you're cursing at me? If you don't want to take my deal, just say so.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_5">
    <text>What kind of help? I didn't ask for your help.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_6">
    <text>Do you know what's inside the package, huh? I can see that you don't, but I do. There's thirty grand worth of merchandise in there! And Sidor is only giving you what, three? So here's my offer: let's split the contents of the package in half, and you can tell the trader that Bandits took the package from you. I can even cut you for authenticity. So, what do you say? Say yes! It's worth it for such a prize!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_7">
    <text>Why don't you go away!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_8">
    <text>Oh well! If you don't want to, then you don't. It's my job to offer and it's your job to refuse. Just keep in mind that without special equipment, you won't be able to open the lock on the crate. And as luck would have it, I happen to have that equipment. If you change your mind, I'll be waiting here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_trifling_matter_sour_dialog_9">
    <text>Sure, you go find some other fool!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello grandfather, where can I find the trader? Sidorovich or something?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_1">
    <text>Ha-ha-ha! Grandfather?! Ha-ha! I can't believe it! Ha-ha-ha! Oh, I can't stop laughing!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_10">
    <text>Come on, man. I get it, I'm not a fool. I'll find that... what's it called? Artifact-smartifact. Anyway, I'll bring you your miracle crap. Just don't get all hot-headed. Wait for me, I'll be back soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_2">
    <text>What's so funny? Are you Sidorovich? I got your message, what's the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_3">
    <text>Hold on, ha-ha-ha! Oh, the youth calling me grandfather! Oh... What did you say you wanted?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_4">
    <text>I'm looking for work, like I said.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_5">
    <text>What's your name? Your face looks unfamiliar.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_6">
    <text>I'm new here, they call me Shroud.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_7">
    <text>Here's the deal, Shroud. Before I give you a proper job, I need to make sure you're capable. First, let's start with the standard procedure - bring me an artifact. Preferably something from the "Bakery," my lower back has been bothering me lately - I want to warm it up. For such a service I'll give you... one thousand rubles. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_8">
    <text>Are you joking or something grandfather? Because it's not funny. I need to find 30,000 in two days and you're offering me a thousand? You can't be serious. Let's do it differently: you lend me 30,000 rubles now, I pay off the soldiers and free my partner, and then I come back to you and work off the debt. So, what do you say?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_9">
    <text>You don't get it do you, kid? Either you agree to my generous offer and find me some fiery artifact, or you get out of here and I'll make sure you won't earn a penny in the Zone. Make your choice.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_0">
    <text>About the artifact...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_1">
    <text>Did you bring it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_10">
    <text>I found an interesting thing here. Look.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_11">
    <text>Excellent, Shroud. Here's your well-deserved reward, just as promised. This is a good start, but you're not ready for serious business yet. Take a walk, explore the surroundings, talk to people. If I need anything, I'll send you a message. Good luck, stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_12">
    <text>Take care, Sidorovich.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_2">
    <text>No, I haven't found it yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_3">
    <text>Then why did you bother coming here?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_4">
    <text>Just dropped by to see what's going on.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_5">
    <text>Sidorovich, it's like hell in there! I tried to approach from the side and almost burned my pants off. I can't get close. And I still don't know what kind of artifact you want - what does it look like? Anyway, I came back empty-handed. Give me another, easier task.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_6">
    <text>Oh, you fool... Sorry, but I don't have any more tasks for you. If a job suitable for a scatterbrain like you comes up, I'll give you a call, don't worry.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_7">
    <text>Alright then, goodbye.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_8">
    <text>I found something, here. It's a weird thing, looks like a cave crystal but glowing. Is it okay?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_work_for_beginner_sidor_dialog_complite_9">
    <text>Listen, I'm not sure if it's the right one, but here, take this ball, it's warm. There was nothing else there.</text>
</string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_0">
        <text>I'm here to collect my order.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_111">
        <text>Here's your Steppe Eagle. It turned out trickier than I thought. Some kind of pistol buff showed a lot of interest, but I barely snatched it in time. See for yourself - a hand-crafted gun, components are all adjusted with unmatched precision. Ever wonder what a perfect sniper pistol would look like? Well, this is it. You owe me 2,800 extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_1111">
        <text>Okay, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_11111">
        <text>There you go. Nice doing business with you.!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_1112">
        <text>I don't have that much on me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_11121">
        <text>Okay, I'll hold the gun for you a while. I hope you find the money soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_1113">
        <text>I don't want to buy this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_11131">
        <text>If you refuse to collect the order, I won't be able to rely on you next time around. I'll have to include the risk estimate in the price and ask for a larger advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_111311">
        <text>Still, I will not be collecting this order.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_1113111">
        <text>All right, suit yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_1114">
        <text>I'll think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_11141">
        <text>Sure, that's up to you. I'll hold the gun for you a while.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_112">
        <text>Here's your ultrahigh-accuracy Steppe Eagle. You owe me 2,800 extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_121">
        <text>Behold the Alpine - a real beauty. You can rest assured this pistol is one of a kind in the whole Zone. A unique model, very limited issue commissioned for a single special unit. It wasn't easy to obtain, I even had to involve one of my overseas associates. An expanded magazine, extra hard steel barrel, receiver made of extra strong polymers. Add the remaining 2,800 and this baby's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_122">
        <text>Here's your Alpine pistol with an expanded magazine. Add the remaining 2,800 and this baby's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_131">
        <text>Lookit, this is March. The pistol belonged to a mercenary called Wolfhound. A compact high-caliber shooter with short blowback and a lightened bolt. Wolfhound was one hundred percent scum, but he knew his weapons, gotta give him that. They say his favorite trick was to blow all four of his victims' limbs off and then his head - before it hit the ground. Anyway, that'll be 2,800.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_132">
        <text>Here's your rapid-fire March pistol. You owe me 2,800 extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_211">
        <text>Here you go - Cutter, a submachine gun. Let me say it right off, don't you mind the appearance. It's a brand new model, not in serial production yet. It's a prototype, fresh from the armory. The designers aimed to make a new-generation close-range weapon: a combination of high caliber, rapid fire and accuracy. So that'll be 8,000 extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_212">
        <text>Yes, here's Cutter, a rapid-fire submachine gun. That'll be 8,000 extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_221">
        <text>Here's a fine specimen - Carabineer. A true army shotgun. Capable of automatic fire while providing good anti-recoil thanks to a balanced, shock-free system. Add 8,000 and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_222">
        <text>Here's Carabineer, an automatic shotgun. Add 8,000 and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_231">
        <text>I reckon this is just what you need. Eliminator, a latest development. The whole batch was supposed to be shipped to Central Africa, but I got a 'sample' as a special favor from friends. An automatic shotgun with a large magazine and an excellent rate of fire. Yours for only 8,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_232">
        <text>Sure. Automatic shotgun Eliminator, with an extended magazine. For 8,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_311">
        <text>Sure. Behold Storm, a submachine and grenade launcher in one. This prototype is a modified version of a conventional weapon designed for special units operating in the Zone. Technical innovation at its best from our Slavic brothers... Add 16,000 and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_312">
        <text>Sure. Here's Storm, a submachine and grenade launcher with an extended magazine, for an extra 16,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_321">
        <text>Here it is - GP37, a new-generation assault rifle. Accurate, reliable, and convenient with a built-in optical scope. It was previously owned by a UN observer. Their group was sent to the Zone to investigate. However, the situation turned for the worse... 16,000 and the rifle is yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_322">
        <text>Here it is - GP37, a new-generation assault rifle. The price is 16,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_331">
        <text>Just a sec. Here's a modular FT-200M rifle, the brainchild of Belgian gunmakers. Accurate, all-purpose, handy for both righties and lefties, comes with an optical scope and a grenade launcher. I got it from some unlucky UN observers... That'll be 16,000 extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_332">
        <text>Here's a modular FT-200M rifle. That'll be 16,000 extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_411">
        <text>Here's Tide. Based on a silent sniper rifle, it was specifically designed for military units to fight zombies. Tide yields rate of fire in favor of stopping power, allowing the sniper to pick off zombies one by one without disclosing his location. However, it then became clear that stalkers alone will be enough to stop zombies at the Barrier, so the rifle never reached mass production. This baby's yours for an extra 16,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_412">
        <text>Here's Tide, a silent sniper rifle with increased stopping power. Add an extra 16,000 and enjoy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_421">
        <text>Here. This is an SVU2-A, a short sniper rifle with an increased rate of fire. I bought it off Mac, the legendary Freedom guard. He swore there are no others like it in the whole Zone. It's an exclusive item, at least in these parts. It'll be 16,000 extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_422">
        <text>Yeah. SVU2-A, a short sniper rifle with an increased rate of fire. It'll be 16,000 extra.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_431">
        <text>Sure, just look at Lynx here.  Hand-crafted by a local expert. He's deceased now, so there won't be any copies. It looks just like any other rifle, but take it out for some target practice and you'll feel all the difference. It's got a perfect combination of accuracy and stopping power. Add the remaining 16,000 and this baby's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_432">
        <text>Yeah, Lynx - a sniper rifle with increased accuracy and power. Add 16,000 and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_511">
        <text>Look here. I managed to get everything off my list - a CS-3a with a helmet. The helmet is nothing special on its own, but it allows for installing a mobile tactical complex, which includes a high-quality night vision system and an active infrared sensor. Now, the CS-3a armor is a real beauty. Excellent protection from bullets and anomalies is a rare feature indeed in a suit as light and mobile as this one. The whole thing will cost you 32,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_512">
        <text>Yeah. A set of CS-3a armor with a tactical helmet. 32,000 in all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_611">
        <text>Specially for you, a SEVA suit. Everything just like you ordered - a closed-cycle respiratory module, thermal resistant, protective electrical circuit, and outer-surface anticorrosion materials. Plus several built-in artifact containers as a bonus. A must-have suit for any stalker. Toss in 24,000 like we agreed and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_612">
        <text>Here. A SEVA suit. The price is 24,000, like we agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_711">
        <text>There it is, a combat exoskeleton as large as life. The best protection you can get in the Zone from bullets, claws or grenade fragments, with the exception of armored vehicles. But it also takes after armored vehicles in that it relieves your weight burden - within reason, of course. 48,000 and it's yours, warts and all... err... by that I mean batteries and servomotors.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_get_order_712">
        <text>There it is, a combat exoskeleton as large as life. 48,000 and it's yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_0">
        <text>I want to place an order.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_1">
        <text>No problem. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_11">
        <text>A pistol.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_111">
        <text>Of course. It'll be 3,500, of which I will require an advance payment of 700.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_1111">
        <text>Okay, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_11111">
        <text>I'll get in touch with you as soon as the order is ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_1112">
        <text>I don't have the money on me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_11121">
        <text>Well, please come back when you've got the cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_1113">
        <text>You know, I've changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_11131">
        <text>Fine. If you finally decide to make an order, I'm always here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_112">
        <text>You're not a very reliable customer, so the pistol will cost you 4,200. And I will require an advance payment of 1,400.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_113">
        <text>I'm afraid the best pistols have already sold out. If you want the regular stuff, Owl's the man to see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_12">
        <text>A close-range weapon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_121">
        <text>Sure thing. The price is 10,000, and I'll need 2,000 of that in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_122">
        <text>You refused to pick up your last order... So this one will cost you 12,000, and I'll need 4,000 of that in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_123">
        <text>Hrm... You know, I probably can't help you there. The demand is too high.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_13">
        <text>An assault weapon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_131">
        <text>Something high-caliber and with rapid fire capability, okay... The regular price is 20,000, with a 4,000 advance payment. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_132">
        <text>You're a tough customer. I'll have to charge you 24,000 and I need 8,000 paid in advance. Deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_133">
        <text>Right now is a bad time... the military are making things hot at the Cordon. Someone attacked their outpost the other day, which made them even more difficult to deal with.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_14">
        <text>A sniper weapon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_141">
        <text>For you I can get the best for only 20,000, but you'll have to pay me 4,000 in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_142">
        <text>Working with you entails a certain amount of risk... I can try to arrange your order for 24,000, but you'll need to make a 8,000 down payment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_143">
        <text>Sorry, this type of weapon is hard to come by right now. My contact for sniper stuff is... let's say he's indisposed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_15">
        <text>An armored suit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_151">
        <text>Yeah, I can think of something... suitable. It'll cost you 40,000, but you'll have to pay me 8,000 in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_152">
        <text>Yeah, I can think of something... suitable. You refused to collect your last order, so the price will be 48,000 and you'll have to pay me 16,000 in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_153">
        <text>I won't be able to do any better than the last suit I got for you. That one was both unique and top of the line.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_16">
        <text>A suit with a closed-cycle respiratory module.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_161">
        <text>That's a tall order... Won't be easy to obtain, not by a long shot. I can try to get one of these babies for 30,000, but I have to ask for a down payment of 6,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_162">
        <text>You let me down on the last order, so I have to think twice this time. I can try to get one of these babies for 36,000, but I have to ask for a down payment of 12,000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_163">
        <text>I bent over backwards to get the last one. Don't think I'll be able to repeat that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_17">
        <text>An exoskeleton.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_171">
        <text>You must have given this choice a lot of thought. I can get my hands on a combat version, but it'll cost you 60,000. Expensive, I know, but well worth it. Keep in mind I'll need 12,000 of that paid right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_172">
        <text>You didn't treat me very nicely on the last order, so this one'll set you back 72,000. Keep in mind I'll need 24,000 of that paid right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_173">
        <text>No way. Since they closed the manufacturing plant, vacant exoskeletons are typically found only on corpses... That's just not my method.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_18">
        <text>Nothing right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_risovalshik_place_order_2">
        <text>Sorry, my shop is closed at the moment. Temporary difficulties with order shipments...</text>
    </string>
<string id="esc_risovalshik_start_11">
    <text>Hello, I'm Sketcher. People usually come to me for unique weapons. Rare models, prototypes, personalized guns, and elite gear - as well as the latest developments in protective and combat suits... Each item is personally inspected by me, so quality is guaranteed! I also buy weapons in any condition at a low price, trade information, and can purchase useful intel.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_risovalshik_start_12">
    <text>Hello. Do you want to place an order or sell something?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_risovalshik_start_13">
    <text>Hello.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_risovalshik_start_14">
    <text>Your order will be completed soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_risovalshik_start_15">
    <text>Your order is complete. You can pick it up.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_0">
    <text>Can you answer a couple of questions?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_1">
    <text>Go ahead and ask.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_2">
    <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_22">
    <text>Tell me about the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_221">
    <text>Ask away, I'll share what I know.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_222">
    <text>Well, from the first day here, one question has been on my mind: is it true that the Zone is constantly expanding?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223001">
    <text>What do you think? Of course, it's true. The Zone used to be much smaller. When it first appeared, its border was north of the current Bar area. I can't tell you exactly where, and no one can, but judging by the presence of anomalies, the Zone started around abandoned army warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223002">
    <text>And how fast is it expanding? There are quite a lot of anomalies here now, so was it less before?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223003">
    <text>Believe it or not, just a year ago there were far fewer anomalies here. And five years ago, there wasn't a single anomaly in this area. The military used to maintain a defensive perimeter around the current northern checkpoint at Garbage. But then the Zone started expanding. I don't know why, you should ask some scientists, maybe they know something about it. The expansion happened in spurts, without any apparent reason. This expansion was usually accompanied by emissions. They used to happen very rarely, once every few months. But with each passing year, the expansion slowed down, and the emissions weakened but became more frequent. Now there's a loud bang every week, but so far, anomalies haven't been seen beyond Cordon. Nevertheless, the military started building a new barrier, now about ten kilometers away from the current one.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223004">
    <text>What will happen with the current barrier? I assume this isn't the first perimeter?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223005">
    <text>You're right Shroud, this isn't the first barrier. Let me think... This checkpoint, the one with the wall to the south of Cordon, is already the third in line. They started building it when the Zone first expanded. Back then, many people lost their lives on the perimeter, some were caught in the emissions, but most were torn apart by mutants. No one had ever seen so many of those creatures; there were thousands of them! They sounded the alarm, and nearby units rushed in. Oh, the carnage that took place here! Artillery, aviation, tanks—everything was firing at once. They even made bombing requests over the radio, but by that time, everything had already calmed down. After that incident, the Zone was taken seriously. They decided not to rebuild the old barrier and hastily constructed minefields and fortified strongpoints to the south of Garbage. But they didn't stop there. They decided to build a second line of defense in case the first one couldn't handle it. The current checkpoint to the south is the former second line. Now it's on the front lines.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223006">
    <text>Why does the checkpoint look so strange? I mean, it doesn't resemble a fortified defensive position. And that wall, why is it built in a way that some structures ended up inside the perimeter?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223007">
    <text>It's strange to you? Well, it's not actually a checkpoint. There were no military constructions here before. Before the accident in '86, there was a service station. They even used it afterward to refuel and repair the equipment used at CNPP. And after the appearance of the Zone, the military settled in. There was no wall planned at that time. They started building it after the first breach when this checkpoint was designated as the second defensive line of the Exclusion Zone. However, the engineers messed up something in a hurry, or for some other reason, and they started building the wall south of the checkpoint. After the construction was completed, all the structures ended up inside the Zone. Some people got a good scolding for their mistake, and they decided to turn the wall around to at least cover part of the buildings. That's how it ended up like this.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223008">
    <text>And where are the gates? I didn't see them there.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_223009">
    <text>Well, they're gone. They were demolished a couple of months ago when mutants made an unexpected charge. Interestingly, there was no emission that day, and it wasn't expected either. Suddenly, hordes of dogs, boars, and flesh appeared out of nowhere from the center, knocked down the gates, trampled a few soldiers, and moved further into the Great Swamp. When the helicopters arrived and started pounding the mutants, something really strange happened - all the creatures suddenly turned around and rushed back toward the center of the Zone. Nobody understood what it was, it was something never seen before. The gates at the checkpoint were not rebuilt since they will soon complete the second line, and then the soldiers will be evacuated from here. By the way, did you come from the south? Have you seen the second line? It's beautiful, isn't it? Everything according to fortification rules: flamethrowers, mortars, fortified trenches, and redoubts. The minefield is quite something; no rat can get through. They poured billions into it. Europe doesn't spare expenses on security, top-level sponsorship.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_2231">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_224">
    <text>Question 2</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_225">
    <text>Answer 2</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_2251">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_226">
    <text>Question 3</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_227">
    <text>Answer 3</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_2271">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_228">
    <text>Question 4</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_229">
    <text>Answer 4</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_2291">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_230">
    <text>Question 5</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_231">
    <text>Answer 5</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_2311">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3">
    <text>Is there something specific you're interested in?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_33">
    <text>Tell me something interesting.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_331">
    <text>Have you heard the story about American spies?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_332">
    <text>No, what's the story?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_333">
    <text>Well, last year, Sidorovich received an offer to organize a tourist trip to the Zone for three foreigners. The money was good, so the trader agreed. But he's a cunning guy, he checks everything. He dug up information about these foreigners through his channels and found out that they were not tourists at all, but CIA agents. Sidorovich didn't want to lose the money, but he didn't want to expose the stalkers either.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330001">
    <text>And what did he do?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330002">
    <text>He came to me, explained everything as it was. We had a heart-to-heart talk, and we found a solution - to send Ilyusha Muromets as a guide with the spies. You know, the nickname suits him well. He's over two meters tall, with the strength of a bear. Once, he twisted the neck of a full-grown boar with his bare hands, just to see if he could. So, he can take care of himself if anything happens.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330003">
    <text>What happened next?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330004">
    <text>At the appointed time, Ilya met with the "tourists" and took them to the notorious places in the border locations. The "tourists" wanted to observe mutants from a distance, take photos of them, and if lucky, even shoot one. But Ilya didn't speak English well and understood only a tenth of what his companions were saying. All he understood from his limited knowledge was that the guests wanted to fight mutants, so Ilya decided to give them that.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330005">
    <text>I think I can guess what happened next.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330006">
    <text>Listen, that's just the beginning! Ilya dragged those poor Americans around for three days. They went everywhere and saw all sorts of things during that time. In the underground tunnels of Agroprom, they were attacked by a bloodsucker, and one of the "tourists" almost got killed. In Yantar, Ilya "accidentally" forgot to warn the foreigners about the zombies, and when a half-decomposed corpse started getting up just a meter away from the spy who was relieving himself, he almost relieved himself from the back too. Not to mention the encounters with several wild boar packs, blind dogs, and controllers that Ilya "accidentally" led the group to. And on the third day, on the way back, Ilya suggested spending the night in an unfinished complex in the northern Dark Valley. Of course, he didn't mention burers. I don't even know who was more terrified that night, the American spies who saw those smelly and dirty dwarves in tattered robes up close, or the burers who encountered screaming "tourists" on their ultrasonic frequencies. When Ilya was telling all this, we almost burst our guts laughing. But that's not all. The next morning, the "tourists," full of fear, returned to Sidorovich at the Cordon to be escorted through the checkpoint. The checkpoint was lively that day - some big shots had arrived from across the border. Kolyazin asked Sidorovich to arrange special conditions for the newly arrived. The foreigners turned out to be three CIA agents officially sent to the Zone for a special preparatory program. Sidorovich was puzzled why the CIA first sent their agents disguised as "tourists" and then officially sent three more agents. He shared his thoughts with the "tourists," who, with horror in their eyes and broken Russian, barely managed to speak. We learned that they were not spies at all but ordinary tourists who came to see the Zone and paid a considerable amount of money for their tours. They had no connection to the CIA!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330007">
    <text>No way! So, this Ilya Muromets of yours dragged around genuine tourists in the Zone and scared them in every possible way, thinking they were spies? Well, you guys really messed up! Ha-ha-ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330008">
    <text>Yes, that's the story. We almost ruined people's lives. By the way, we also sent the official spies with Ilya, following the same route. The burers in Dark Valley were delighted. Heh!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3330009">
    <text>Thank you, you've made my day.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3331">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_334">
    <text>Question 2</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_335">
    <text>Answer 2</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3351">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_336">
    <text>Question 3</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_337">
    <text>Answer 3</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3371">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_338">
    <text>Question 4</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_339">
    <text>Answer 4</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3391">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_340">
    <text>Question 5</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_341">
    <text>Answer 5</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_3411">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_4">
    <text>Where are you from?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_44">
    <text>I was born in the glorious city of Okha, located on Sakhalin Island. I hope you know where that is? Nowadays, young people aren't interested in anything, especially their own country.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_44001">
    <text>About Sakhalin? Of course, I know. It's an island in the Far East, not far from Japan. Well, well, how did you end up there? And what were you doing there?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_44002">
    <text>It's a working town, mainly sustained by oil and gas industries. And there are traditional professions as well, like logging and fishing. So, there was always plenty of work. But since I was a child, I was drawn to adventures, I couldn't stay in one place. I explored all the mountains and forests around. But it wasn't enough for me. So, as soon as I turned eighteen, I happily went to the military enlistment office. In my case, it was the only way to leave the island and see the world.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_441">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_5">
    <text>How did you end up in the Zone?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_55001">
    <text>To be honest, I still don't know whether it was a chain of coincidences or if the Zone itself brought me here. In the army, I proved myself well. I've been into sports since I was a kid, so even two years in special forces weren't too challenging for me. Although, by the end of the Afghan War, I managed to get lucky and barely participated in combat. Then, based on recommendations from headquarters, I was sent for specialized military training. During my studies, I started a family. We didn't have any children, which turned out to be for the best. After my training, I was stationed in different garrisons, and there was no time for children. And then, I was sent to Chechnya. It was there that I lost my Marishka... Why, what a fool I was to bring her along. They warned us that the base was dangerous, that there could be attacks by Chechen militants. I was an idiot... I couldn't protect her.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_55002">
    <text>I'm sorry, I didn't mean to remind you... I didn't know...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_55003">
    <text>Forget it, it's my fault, my past, my burden. I have to live with it until the end. Maybe that's why the Zone brought me here? After the first Chechen War, other things have happened, long story. But I remember the emergence of the Zone as if it were yesterday. The chaos was unforgettable. No one understood what had happened in the first few hours: whether it was a reactor explosion or a meteorite impact, or maybe even the start of a war. Moscow was just as alarmed as Kiev. That's when our troops were sent to the Zone as agreed upon. I'll never forget that day, the Zone did its best. I lost almost my entire squad because of those rats from headquarters. They wanted to find out how anomalies affect people. Bastards. And no one even asked us. I can't imagine how Seryoga, Dima, and I managed to get out of there. It was as if the Zone itself guided us between the anomalies. As soon as I entered the headquarters, I punched that general right in the face. I was about to draw my gun, but they apprehended me. I would have been sitting in confinement for a long time if it weren't for my friends. They helped me escape from the prison cell. When I left the camp, I didn't have much choice: either try to survive in the Zone or struggle to exist outside world. So, I chose my path - I'd rather live a short time in the Zone than spend the rest of my life in prisons.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_55004">
    <text>What a story... But don't you ever feel the need to go home, to the homeland?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_55005">
    <text>You know, I didn't feel the urge at all at first, it wasn't on my mind. Nowadays, the Zone is somewhat inhabited, wherever you go, you'll definitely come across someone. But back then, there was no one here at all. Even though I'm a combat officer and I've seen horrors during my service, when you witness all the known laws of physics being violated right before your eyes and you see a loyal comrade disappear in inhuman agony, right in the air, there's no room for self-control. Fear replaces all senses. But you can't drink away your skill, somehow I managed to survive. Then, with time, as I gained more experience in the Zone, thoughts of the future started to come. Now, I really want to go back home. See my parents, if they're still alive, visit at familiar places. Believe me, I'm even willing to face a tribunal if they gave me just one day to spend in my homeland. Eh...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_551">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_6">
    <text>Question 3</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_66">
    <text>Answer 3</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_661">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_7">
    <text>Question 4</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_77">
    <text>Answer 4</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_771">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_777">
    <text>I've already told you everything I know.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_8">
    <text>Question 5</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_88">
    <text>Answer 5</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_881">
    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_999">
    <text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shaman_about_info_dialog_9990">
    <text>text in default</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_0">
    <text>Rise and shine stalker!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_1">
    <text>What is going on?! Why does everyone keep hitting me on the head?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_2">
    <text>Be grateful they left you alive. Looks like Logopedist has special plans for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_3">
    <text>Damn! My head hurts, I have no strength. Listen, buddy, maybe we can make a deal? I can pay.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_4">
    <text>What will you pay with? You have nothing! And I don't want to deal with Logopedist later.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_5">
    <text>How much do you want? My partner has money, he'll pay! His name is Borland.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_6">
    <text>Borland, you say? I've heard of him. Yeah, he might pay. Alright, you sit here for now, I'll have a chat with your friend.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shoroh_quest_away_from_the_bandits_dialog_7">
    <text>Where else would I go?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_0">
    <text>Damn it! You scared me, you wretched scoundrels! What the hell are you doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_1">
    <text>Sidorovich?! What are you doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_10">
    <text>Shroud, let's be straight with each other. I can see right through you, you can't hide anything from me.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_11">
    <text>Well, we... um...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_12">
    <text>Spit it out, don't drag it out.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_13">
    <text>Okay, okay. Have you heard about the deal with the Freedom stalker?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_14">
    <text>About the suicide? Of course. Whole Cordon is on edge, people are afraid that the Freedom guys will come here to investigate. No one can prove to them that he shot himself in the head after all, you're the only witness. So, what's the deal with that stalker?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_15">
    <text>He's not from Freedom. He was a secret Monolith agent.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_16">
    <text>Are you serious?! That can't be! What was he doing here? Their group has long since fallen apart, the puppeteers have all been killed.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_17">
    <text>What are you talking about?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_18">
    <text>I'll tell you another time. We don't have to be so secretive now though, so I'll share some information with you. But tell me about this agent first, you didn't bring him up for no reason, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_19">
    <text>Well, you see, this Monolith guy had a PDA on him but it was locked. I asked Van to unlock it, that was when I came to you for some work. When I left your bunker and went to see the technician I found out that he had disappeared without a trace. I went to look for him... and found him too. I wish I hadn't...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_2">
    <text>None of your damn business! So, it was you guys, I can't believe it! The alarm was triggered three times this week! Which entrance were you using?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_20">
    <text>Well, go on, what happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_21">
    <text>Van was killed.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_22">
    <text>So that's where he disappeared. The whole camp has been searching for him for a day now. Why didn't you say anything earlier?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_23">
    <text>Hold on, Sidorovich, let me finish. When I found Van, someone hit me on the head hard. I was unconscious for several hours in the elevator. When I woke up Van was gone, as if he was never there. Who would believe that I didn't touch him when there's no body?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_24">
    <text>Well, that's true. Wait a minute, where did you say you found Van, in the elevator?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_25">
    <text>Yeah, yesterday. So what? Do you have any ideas who knocked me out?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_26">
    <text>I do, but I can't tell you. Let's just say I arranged a meeting for some very serious people in the elevator yesterday, and the meeting got disrupted. Probably because of you and Van. But who could have killed the technician remains a mystery to me. Although...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_27">
    <text>What? Sidorovich, don't beat around the bush. Van's dead, this is no time for secrets.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_28">
    <text>Alright, fine, it's a serious matter. I sent a stalker to the elevator. He found an interesting container at Garbage recently, which my clients from the center of the Zone have been searching for a long time. The one called Shmyga stole their money you know.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_29">
    <text>What container? What's inside? And who is that stalker?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_3">
    <text>Sidor, what alarm? Three times this week? This is our first time here, I swear.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_30">
    <text>Well, who knows what's inside the container. I didn't open it, just looked at the numbers on the lid and immediately realized it was the exact container my clients were looking for. The stalker is called Blockhead. He was thrilled when I told him about the deal. I didn't dare to buy the container from him, so I arranged the meeting. But now I don't know what happened - the clients didn't get the container, the stalker disappeared, and you and Van are involved. My clients wouldn't attack Van - it's not their style, and I doubt the stalker would do something like that either. Although I can't vouch for him. There must be someone else involved. Maybe Bandits?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_31">
    <text>Blockhead? Well, well! I know him. Wolf asked me to find that stalker when we first met. He seemed strange to me back then, didn't care about his reputation. And look what he was planning. Maybe he killed Van and then hit me on the head before he was seen?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_32">
    <text>Could be, although the guy seemed normal, no strange behavior or anything. Why would he kill Van? It's truly a strange story. And now we don't even know where to find Blockhead.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_33">
    <text>Yeah... So, where was I? Oh yeah. I found the unlocked Monolith PDA on Van. There were only a few messages left. In short, it talked about a group of stalkers who stole an artifact from Monolith and were being pursued by them. The artifact has devastating effects on people, something about the psyche was mentioned, too complex for me. That's why it was put in a container, and the stalkers took off with it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_34">
    <text>A container, you say? Could it be the same container I was telling you about?..</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_35">
    <text>Maybe. Anyway, listen. During the pursuit several of the stalkers were killed, but the remaining ones managed to lose their pursuers. That's why Monolith brought in their undercover agents to track down the thieves. I don't know how many agents there were, but one of them, posing as a Freedom member, made it here to Cordon. He traced one of the thieves to the rookie village, but he himself was captured by bandits. I don't know how.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_36">
    <text>I don't get it. Are you saying Blockhead is one of those stalkers? It can't be. He's only been in the Zone for a couple of weeks and just recently made it to Garbage. He spent only a day there and came back. It was on that same day he brought me that container. I already told you what happened afterwards.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_37">
    <text>So, Blockhead found the container in Garbage. The way I see it, those stalkers who stole the artifact hid it in Garbage and Blockhead stumbled upon it by chance. He couldn't have killed them. Or could he? Someone killed Van. And then there's the artifact. What do you think, Sidorovich, what kind of artifact is in the container?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_38">
    <text>Well, who knows! New artifacts appear every day. But if I were to guess, there's one artifact that comes to mind with a similar effect, it's called "Pendulum". It's an extremely rare artifact however, only two of them have ever been found. They're worth a fortune.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_39">
    <text>And why is it so highly valued?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_4">
    <text>Stop messing with me! Who else could've triggered the alarm? It's designed for humans, not rats or dogs, and mutants don't roam around here. So, only a human could have triggered it. If it wasn't you, then who?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_40">
    <text>This artifact is two-sided. It has two opposing properties: its one side absorbs all psi-radiation, but the other side emits it with incredible power. The absorption and emission poles switch over a certain period of time, about an hour or so. That's why you need to constantly flip it when carrying it on your belt.\nBroker's group was the first to find this artifact. But at that time they didn't know the effects of the Pendulum. Because of this, only Corkscrew managed to reach the scientists' camp in Yantar alive. He could barely stand on his feet. The eggheads flew him to mainland on a helicopter, and of course, they kept the artifact for research. Several of their own lab technicians nearly died until they assembled a suitable protective container. I learned about this later from a copy of the report. Sakharov was involved. Since then, nothing is known about the artifact. It's probably still being studied in some secret research institute.\n</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_41">
    <text>And what about the second one?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_42">
    <text>Oh, the story of the second artifact is even more interesting. Have you heard of Strelok?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_43">
    <text>No, who is Strelok?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_44">
    <text>Not just an ordinary stalker, but a legend! I don't know when he appeared in the Zone, but he knew his business inside out - the artifacts he'd bring, man, you'd be amazed. No one knew where he found them either. One time, he was lucky enough to find this very Pendulum, being the clever guy he is, he immediately realized that the artifact had a negative influence. I don't know how many days he studied this artifact, but he found out almost everything about it that the scientists have in their labs. And all in field conditions, can you imagine?! After that, he started carrying this artifact everywhere. And thanks to him, he led his group through the Brain Scorcher. They brought so much stuff that you could have bought a small island in the Pacific. Traders from all over the Zone lined up for his artifacts. But he was stubborn, he sold a few and kept the rest for himself, who knows where he put them. Ah, he was a good man.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_45">
    <text>Why "was"? What happened to him?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_46">
    <text>Strelok suddenly disappeared a couple of years ago. We thought he died because of the massive emission. I've never seen anything like that emission before and believe me, I've seen a lot. Anyway, to our surprise, they found him alive in one of the death trucks a few months later. How he ended up there is unknown. He didn't even remember anything, not even his own name. I didn't recognize him right away - it was scary to look at him: thin, covered in bruises, weathered face, mysterious scars all over his body. And that mark on his arm, as if he was branded by beasts - the S.T.A.L.K.E.R. tattoo. But the strangest thing was that there was only one entry in his PDA: "Kill Strelok." That's right, himself, can you imagine?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_47">
    <text>What did he do then?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_48">
    <text>I won't lie, we called him Marked One because of his tattoo and used him. He needed to find Strelok, which meant he could find his stashes as well. But the most interesting thing for us was the path to the north of the Zone, where the motherlode of artifacts is located. So, me and the other traders decided to keep him in the dark for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_49">
    <text>I'm not surprised.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_5">
    <text>Sidorovich, I swear we didn't mean any harm. We made a deal with Watchmaker and he let us explore the tunnel and catacombs. We didn't plan anything bad.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_50">
    <text>Ahem. So, Strelok, I mean Marked One, set out to find himself. That is, he followed his own tracks to the north of the Zone. The scientists gave him a prototype psi-blocker to keep his brain from boiling. Unbeknownst to Marked One, he was gathering all the information about the inaccessible areas of the Zone for them while wearing it. He also disabled two emitters: one in Yantar and one in Radar - the infamous "Brain Scorcher." The path to Pripyat and the center of the Zone was opened. It shouldn't have been done, but who knew how it would all turn out?\nEveryone in the Zone went crazy. Even the laziest ones rushed to the center. Everyone wanted to be the first to reach the "Wish Granter." I was happy at the time, thinking that since the path to Pripyat and CNPP was now open, the artifacts would flow to me like a river. But things didn't go as planned - no one came back. Most fell in Pripyat, the whole city was teeming with Monolith fighters. All factions started warring again - no one wanted to retreat, everyone was pushing forward. Later, the military also joined in. In short, it was chaos. And to top it off, an emission happened. The number of casualties was uncountable.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_51">
    <text>And Strelok? Did he make it out?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_52">
    <text>I don't know. No one has seen him here since that incident, we couldn't even find the psi-blocker. It had a GPS module but it seems the emission damaged it. The last coordinates pointed to the entrance of the Sarcophagus though, which means Strelok reached it a couple of minutes before the emission. Maybe he survived, we'll never know. It's been a year since then and many people have been to the center. They found a strange laboratory in one of the bunkers near CNPP - there were bodies in capsules, and it looked like they were shot while asleep. Stalkers found various documents there and handed everything over to the scientists. What was written there was unbelievable. But eventually, we came to the conclusion that it was all true.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_53">
    <text>What did the documents say?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_54">
    <text>It contained technical information about psi-emitters, generators, and Wish Granter. It turned out that the Monolith was an artificial construct used to brainwash fanatics. This explained why no one found said Wish Granter after the emission - there was nothing in the Sarcophagus except for the destroyed reactor. With the help of this device, certain scientists from the C-Consciousness project, as they called themselves in the documents, hypnotized stalkers who got too close to the secret of the Zone's origin. The recruited agents were given secret assignments and sent to the Zone's borders. Apparently, Strelok somehow became one of these agents and was tasked with killing himself. But then the Monolith was destroyed. The fanatics started to regain their senses after that - several dozen squads returned from the center, not remembering anything. Initially, they were almost killed, as they were former enemies of all stalkers. Not everyone has fully recovered from the hypnosis however, and judging by your story, there are still many puppets without puppeteers. They're up to something too, hence why the Pendulum artifact was placed in the container. I wonder if that's the same artifact that belonged to Strelok?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_55">
    <text>That's what Borland and I will try to find out. Thank you for the interesting story. We'll continue exploring the catacombs.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_56">
    <text>Hold on Shroud, I have a proposition. In light of recent events I suggest we make a deal: I'll provide you with top-notch equipment and weapons, and in return, if you find the Pendulum artifact you come and sell it specifically to me. I'll pay you handsomely, what do you say?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_57">
    <text>I don't know, Sidorovich. What if we don't find anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_58">
    <text>Well, in that case you can just pay me the minimum rental fee for the gear. The most important thing is for you to stay alive because searching for and stripping armor off corpses is not a pleasant task.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_59">
    <text>Well, that's reassuring. We need to think it over, consult with each other. Let's talk this later, okay? In the meantime, we'll explore this place and maybe find Blockhead.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_6">
    <text>Wait, Watchmaker let you in? So you didn't come in through the pipe?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_7">
    <text>What pipe? We used the stairs. What pipe are you talking about?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_8">
    <text>That's bad Shroud. You may act like a fool sometimes, but you can't lie to save your life. This means that three people, not counting you, have infiltrated here in the past week. So, you're saying you're here looking for something?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_9">
    <text>I'm not saying anything. We just wanted to see what's down here and how it looks. It's an interesting place, you know.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_0">
    <text>We've considered your offer. We agree.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_1">
    <text>Now we're talking! Hold on, let me grab the stuff. Here! Just as I said. It may not be the best equipment, but it's been tested on countless expeditions. You can only get something better by ordering it from the mainland. I'll send you the master code via PDA too. It'll work a hundred percent, unlike regular service codes. And finally, here's the rest of the gear, just as promised. Now, I'll let you through my passage. Are you ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_quest_line_research_underground_part_2_dialog_2">
    <text>Ready.</text>
</string>
	
	
	
<string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_0">
    <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_1">
    <text>I value independence, so I've always been on my own and worked for myself. But when I heard that the stalkers had outpaced the military and established their own base, I came here right away. You know, I've crossed paths with many people in the Zone, but as far as I'm concerned, Stalkers are the real deal. Well, how can I put it... they're normal, you know? No silly codes, rules, like in other factions. In my opinion, the Zone should belong to the stalkers alone: then there will be mutual assistance everywhere, and it will be more peaceful. So, I decided to support these guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_11">
    <text>You rarely come across technicians in the Zone. Can you tell me what you're capable of?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_111">
    <text>Well, don't expect any fancy gadgets or sophisticated stuff from me. But you don't need to doubt me either: my kettle is still boiling and I have skilled hands. I can perform work that can save your life. I repair weapons and armor most of the time, but if the necessary parts show up, I can even upgrade your gun or gear. If you want to know exactly what I do, take a look at the upgrades - I think you'll figure it out.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_1111">
    <text>I guess you've wandered around the Zone quite a bit? Have you seen anything unusual?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_11111">
    <text>Unusual? I came here through Agroprom right after the powerful emission, and I saw some wonders... In places where there used to be nothing were now patches of twisted land that has swelled up. They were emitting such radiation that you have to run past it. The guys later told me that there's no more powerful anomaly than that one: it's not just an energy fountain, but a Niagara Falls of energy! It's a dangerously unpredictable place, but the catch is that rare artifacts often appear there, unique ones. So if you come across that place, keep an eye out.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_0">
    <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_1">
    <text>I'm a trader... a rookie. As you can see I'm pretty new here, but as soon as Shaman said that anyone can become whoever they want, I decided - I'll be a trader! And why not? I have the skills and Sidorovich is a living example that it can be done... You know, back in school, I used to profit using an battery toy - remember, the one where the wolf catches chicken eggs? - well, I used to let my classmates play for ten kopecks per game. Oh, those were the golden days... I have a knack for it, you know? Now I'm settling in, learning the trade, so to speak. I'm taking goods from Sidorovich for resale, so the prices are... you know... aren't that great yet. But still! There are some interesting things to be found. The guys have started bringing me some loot little by little too.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_111">
    <text>Oh buddy, we're going to live like kings now, like we've got divine favor... or whoever's in charge of us sinners. The military won't bother us anymore, things are looking up for us Stalkers. We'll be able to relax on Cordon after raids and the equipment we need will be right there for us... We'll also get real money for our goodies, not like before, where we got scraps, and the cream went to the soldiers. We'll still mess with the military though! So what? They shouldn't relax, you know, it's not a fairy tale we're in! Long story short, we're going to live it up!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_2">
    <text>How do you think life will change in Cordon?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_3">
    <text>Oh buddy, we're going to live like kings now, like we've got divine favor... or whoever's in charge of us sinners. The military won't bother us anymore, things are looking up for us Stalkers. We'll be able to relax on Cordon after raids and the equipment we need will be right there for us... We'll also get real money for our goodies, not like before, where we got scraps, and the cream went to the soldiers. We'll still mess with the military though! So what? They shouldn't relax, you know, it's not a fairy tale we're in! Long story short, we're going to live it up!</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_student_quest_conductor_atp_dialog_0">
    <text>Thank you very much, comrade stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_student_quest_conductor_atp_dialog_1">
    <text>You're welcome "comrade." Man, where do you people even come from...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_student_quest_conductor_atp_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm from Novosibirsk. You know, Akademgorodok...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_student_quest_conductor_atp_dialog_3">
    <text>What's the matter with you?! Such a chatterbox! Well, I've done my job, others can deal with you now. Good luck!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_student_quest_conductor_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, Student. Ready to go?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_student_quest_conductor_dialog_1">
    <text>So you'll be my guide? Nice to meet you. Are you an experienced stalker? Isn't it dangerous? What if we get shot by Bandits on the way? And mutants...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_student_quest_conductor_dialog_2">
    <text>Shut up! Stop talking for a second! Oh, I have a bad feeling about this... Let's get one thing straight: if you keep talking on the road, I'll leave you behind. Then you'll have to find your own way out. Got it? Let's go.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_tech_barkas_dialog_0">
    <text>Are you the new technician?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_barkas_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, Van disappeared somewhere so now I'm taking his place.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_0">
    <text>I wanted to ask about tools.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_1">
    <text>What about them?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_2">
    <text>Well, I used to bring tools to Van...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_3">
    <text>Yeah, well, not all of them are here, so we still need more. If you find any, bring them over.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_4">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_0">
    <text>I brought you some tools.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_1">
    <text>Great! Which ones?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_11">
    <text>Tools for basic work.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_111">
    <text>Excellent! Now if only you could find tools for fine and calibration work...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_12">
    <text>Tools for fine work.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_121">
    <text>Excellent! Now if only you could find tools for basic and calibration work...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_13">
    <text>Calibration tools.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_131">
    <text>Excellent! Now if only you could find tools for basic and fine work...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_14">
    <text>Nothing for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_141">
    <text>Great! Now if I could just get some calibration tools, everything would be perfect.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_151">
    <text>Great! Now if I could just get some tools for fine work, everything would be perfect.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_161">
    <text>Great! Now if I could just get some tools for basic work, everything would be perfect.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_171">
    <text>Wow! You're capable... where did you find them all?</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_0">
    <text>If you need tools, I can get them for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_1">
    <text>That would be great! I feel like I'm working in the Stone Age. The only modern tool I have is a soldering iron, but even that's like a shamans wand... With the right tools, I can do top-notch tuning, and you'll get your fair share too.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_11">
    <text>Alright then. I'll look for them.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_12">
    <text>I changed my mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_3">
    <text>Great! I'll do the tuning, you'll make some profits.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_tex_instryments_1">
    <text>Hi. Do you need tools?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tex_instryments_2">
    <text>Do you even have to ask?! Of course I need them. Show me what you have.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tex_instryments_3">
    <text>Tools for basic work.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tex_instryments_4">
    <text>Great! Now I can modify your weapons and armor to a higher level.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tex_instryments_5">
    <text>Tools for fine work.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tex_instryments_6">
    <text>Excellent! Now our local scientific and technological progress will take a leap forward.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tex_instryments_7">
    <text>Calibration tools.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tex_instryments_8">
    <text>Great! Now I'll be able to make you such a powerful rifle that even Sidorovich would give his soul for it, hehe.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tex_instryments_9">
    <text>Nothing for now.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_0">
    <text>Welcome to our humble corner of happiness, dear traveler. Would you like to see the menu?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_1">
    <text>What?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_2">
    <text>Show me the money, that's what!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_3">
    <text>Um, I don't have any money.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_4">
    <text>Heheh, you're funny! And where do you think you're going without money, you fool? No money means no gear, no gear means no artifacts, and no artifacts means... Hmm, what comes next? Oh right! No artifacts means no money! That's what we call a vicious circle, see? Heheh! So why don't you get lost while you're still in one piece! You can thank me later. You damn superhero you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_5">
    <text>Guys, I need to pass, it's really important. Maybe we can work something out?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_6">
    <text>Hehe! He needs it! Maybe I "need" to sober up, but you don't see me bothering you with my problems.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_7">
    <text>Well, how about some vodka? I have some.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_71">
    <text>Guys, it's my first day in the Zone. Maybe you can let me pass, just this once?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_72">
    <text>Hehe! Look at you, "let me pass, just this once." Just like that huh!? Either pay up or get lost - there's no third option!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_73">
    <text>Damn all of you!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_8">
    <text>Heheh, you're a decent guy. Alright, give me your vodka. I still won't let you pass though. Haha!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_9">
    <text>I have another bottle - here you go!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_10">
    <text>Oh, look at you! You're a real magician, I respect that. Alright, you can pass through the tunnel. We'll take care of business with the gang in the meantime. Now get lost!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_trepach_dialog_robbery_11">
    <text>Already gone.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_0">
    <text>Thank you son. Mutants have been going crazy lately, not allowing anyone through.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_1">
    <text>No problem grandfather. You're Watchmaker, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, yes. Who might you be?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_3">
    <text>They call me Shroud. I've been looking for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_4">
    <text>Me? Well, how can I help you?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_5">
    <text>Tell me about the tunnel under the village.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_6">
    <text>You're straight to the point, aren't you son? I respect such people. I'll tell you everything I know, but don't mention it to anyone, got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_7">
    <text>Got it!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_8">
    <text>After the Great Patriotic War, Soviet leadership was extremely concerned about the security measures and escape routes for high-ranking officials. Therefore, it was decided to create a secret underground communication network. Primarily, this network was intended to provide emergency evacuation from besieged cities such as Kiev, Minsk, and Moscow. One of the underground railway branches of this network is located here, beneath the Zone, it's the Kiev-Minsk route. Along with this branch, underground communications were built to serve the rolling stock and deliver materials to other important facilities that were abundant at that time. I was assigned to guard this secret passage. That's why I'm still here, keeping watch.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_9">
    <text>So, the tunnel beneath the village leads to a railway? That can't be true!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_10">
    <text>Oh, you didn't live during the Soviet times. They did even more incredible things back then - they could make rivers flow backward! That's right! Digging holes in the ground was a piece of cake for them!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_11">
    <text>How can I get there grandfather, to the catacombs I mean? I really want to see it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_12">
    <text>Oh, you're a smart young man, but why should I let you into the tunnel? My superiors strictly ordered me not to let anyone in without their knowledge.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_13">
    <text>What superiors grandfather? The Zone has been here for a long time - your superiors are long gone.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_14">
    <text>What do you mean, gone? Then who's making all that noise there?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_15">
    <text>Where?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_16">
    <text>In the tunnel. Every night there are noises. If it's not my superiors, then who?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_17">
    <text>Well, who knows what creatures might have settled there over the years. Do you want me to take a look?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_18">
    <text>Take a look? You thought you could deceive me son? It's alright, I suppose I owe you. Here's a spare key to my house, just don't touch anything inside!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_19">
    <text>Alright, grandfather. Thank you!</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_0">
    <text>It's you! What else do you want from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_1">
    <text>What's wrong grandfather? Why are you so angry?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_2">
    <text>And he's mocking me too! Why did you rummage through my house? What were you looking for? Money, valuables? I have nothing except broken watches!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_3">
    <text>I wasn't looking for anything in your house grandfather! It wasn't me!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_4">
    <text>Then who rummaged through my cabinets? Ghosts? Even the key is gone.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_5">
    <text>What key?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_6">
    <text>The access key. The card I mean.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_7">
    <text>Is it the keycard to the door of the underground laboratory?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_8">
    <text>How do you know that? I knew it, you took it! Give it back!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_9">
    <text>It's a coincidence, I actually wanted to ask you for that keycard. I didn't steal your key grandfather, but I think I know who might have done it. I'm going to need the help of the trader.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_10">
    <text>Son, you find that scoundrel who rummaged through my cabinets without permission and please return my key. People have no shame or conscience anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_watchmaker_quest_line_research_underground_dialog_11">
    <text>I'll take care of everything grandfather, don't worry.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_about_around_0">
    <text>What's interesting around here?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_about_around_1">
    <text>This is a rookie hangout. There's a trader named Sidorovich on the outskirts of the village. Beyond that is the military checkpoint - that's where you came from. On the other side of the checkpoint is the road going deep into of the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_about_around_11">
    <text>Tell me about the rookie village.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_about_around_111">
    <text>Well, what can I tell you about the local haven? Those who are a bit more experienced stock up on the essentials from Sidorovich and head to Garbage. More valuable artifacts can be found there and it's not too dangerous, you can gain some experience. Here, we have... idiots, to put it mildly. Sometimes miracle workers shows up with just a bag and nothing but slippers. He suddenly got a romantic impulse to visit, you know! Some kind of assistant professor who never held anything more serious than a logarithmic ruler in his hands. People like that don't last long here. Sometimes, experienced stalkers come by to give Sidorovich goods after a long raid and to get some rest for a day or two in a peaceful area.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_about_around_1111">
    <text>Are the military bothering you? You seem to have settled in nicely here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_about_around_11111">
    <text>They don't really bother us. They have other things on their minds right now. They even say "Why waste ammunition on these stalkers when they'll die in anomalies anyway?" We don't provoke them either. When there are raids or inspections at the checkpoint from their headquarters, we hide in the basements. As you can see, we don't mess with each other.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_about_around_22">
    <text>Tell me about Sidorovich.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_about_around_222">
    <text>Sidorovich is the tight-fisted trader of Cordon. His main clients are rookie stalkers who have recently entered the Zone. He has many connections, including us. He has been involved in trading since childhood and used to sell soft drugs during his student years. He is both an authority and the subject of humor among stalkers. On one hand, he runs a fairly honest business and gives many newcomers a chance to survive in the Zone. On the other hand, he is criticized for his greed, selfishness, alcoholism, and mercantile nature. Long story short, everyone in the Zone knows him! He's the most influential trader around here. If Sidorovich can't get you something, no one can.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_about_you_0">
    <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_about_you_1">
    <text>I'm sort of the leader around here. I teach the rookies and softies so that they don't get bumped off on their very first foray... Let me tell you, it's not an easy job! As for me, I've already trampled all over the Zone, left a chunk of my life here. I've been thinking of leaving, but it feels like forever since I arrived Cordon. There's some wicked witch casting spells I swear - I just can't seem to get out: either the military comes with a raid, or there's some damn emission. And honestly, money is a good incentive to stay too... Sometimes people offer very profitable jobs, so why not take them? You know how it is: you think, just one more expedition and that's it, I'm out - but it keeps happening over and over again.</text>
</string>
	
	
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_0">
        <text>Tell me about this place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_0">
        <text>Tell me about this place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_0">
        <text>Tell me about this place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_1">
        <text>We're in Cordon. Beyond the military checkpoint is the outside world, and further on is the Zone. There's not much here that reminds you of the Zone: few anomalies, almost no artifacts, and you rarely encounter mutants. There's also not much noise here because the military tries to keep things in check. It's a rather quiet place, compared to the rest of the Zone of course.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_1">
        <text>We're in Cordon. Beyond the military checkpoint is the outside world, and further on is the Zone. There's not much here that reminds you of the Zone: few anomalies, almost no artifacts, and you rarely encounter mutants. There's also not much noise here because the military tries to keep things in check. It's a rather quiet place, compared to the rest of the Zone of course.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_1">
        <text>We're in Cordon. Beyond the military checkpoint is the outside world, and further on is the Zone. There's not much here that reminds you of the Zone: few anomalies, almost no artifacts, and you rarely encounter mutants. There's also not much noise here because the military tries to keep things in check. It's a rather quiet place, compared to the rest of the Zone of course.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_111">
        <text>This is the rookie village. There's a trader named Sidorovich on the outskirts of the village. Beyond that is the military checkpoint - that's where you came from. On the other side of the checkpoint is the road going deep into of the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_111">
        <text>This is the rookie village. There's a trader named Sidorovich on the outskirts of the village. Beyond that is the military checkpoint - that's where you came from. On the other side of the checkpoint is the road going deep into of the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_111">
        <text>This is the rookie village. There's a trader named Sidorovich on the outskirts of the village. Beyond that is the military checkpoint - that's where you came from. On the other side of the checkpoint is the road going deep into of the Zone.</text>
    </string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_art_medusa_dialog_0">
    <text>Wolf, I've thought about your offer and decided to sell you that artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_art_medusa_dialog_1">
    <text>You made the right decision. Sidorovich would have given you half as much for it. I know that miser well.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_art_medusa_dialog_2">
    <text>Yeah, I've already seen it for myself.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_0">
    <text>What's the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_1">
    <text>It's not a hard one, you just need to escort a guy to the stalker camp at the vehicle station. The client is new to the Zone but loaded, he's paying ten thousand. Half now - half when the job is done. Are you in?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_2">
    <text>Deal. Where's the client?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_3">
    <text>There he is, they call him Student. Once you get him to the base, come back, I'll give you the second half. Student will let me know when you reach the vehicle station.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, I'm off.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_5">
    <text>No Wolf, sorry, I don't have time. Maybe someone else will take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, suit yourself. That kind of money doesn't grow on trees, I can always find someone willing to do it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_dialog_7">
    <text>Good luck.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_repeat_dialog_0">
    <text>I have some free time now... I can escort that rookie.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_repeat_dialog_1">
    <text>I'm not surprised. Alright, he's standing over there, goes by the name Student. Once you get him to the vehicle station, come back to me, I'll give you the second half of the money. Student will inform me when he reaches the vehicle station.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_repeat_dialog_2">
    <text>Don't worry Wolf, I'll handle everything. The place isn't far away.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_repeat_dialog_3">
    <text>Too late, Shroud, too late. The rookie is already gone. You took too long to decide and missed an easy job.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_repeat_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, it wasn't something I really wanted anyway.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_reward_dialog_0">
    <text>Job's done - Student is at the vehicle station.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_reward_dialog_1">
    <text>So, everything went well? Nothing happened on the way?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_reward_dialog_2">
    <text>Student happened... Man, he's quite the chatterbox. Now I understand why the payment for this job was so high.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_reward_dialog_3">
    <text>Yeah, he loves to talk. What can you expect from an egghead? Speaking of the payment, here's the second part as promised.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_conductor_reward_dialog_4">
    <text>Thanks Wolf. If anything else comes up, let me know.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_hunting_dialog_0">
    <text>I received your message. Is there anything interesting?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_hunting_dialog_1">
    <text>Of course there is! Give me your PDA, I'll send you the location of a stalker. His name is Leshiy, an experienced hunter. He eats bloodsuckers for breakfast you know? That's right!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_hunting_dialog_2">
    <text>What do I have to do? I'm not interested in bloodsuckers.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_hunting_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, you never know what you'll encounter in the Zone, Leshiy can teach you how to kill mutants more effectively. Don't refuse, not every rookie gets such a chance. So, are you willing to go hunting with Leshiy?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_hunting_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, why not! Send me the coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_hunting_dialog_5">
    <text>Now we're talking! I've sent it. Leshiy will be waiting for you down the road, not far from the vehicle station.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_hunting_dialog_6">
    <text>Thanks, Wolf.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_0">
    <text>I got your message. What do you need?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_1">
    <text>Good, you're here. I could handle this myself, but it'll be more fun with you. Plus, you can learn something.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_2">
    <text>How can I help?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_3">
    <text>I got myself a new detector and I want to test it. Let's go search for artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_4">
    <text>Artifacts? Those strange things that are highly valued on the mainland? Where can we find them?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_5">
    <text>Anomalies. More precisely, in anomalous fields. So, do you want me to teach you how to find artifacts?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_6">
    <text>Of course!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_7">
    <text>Alright then, follow me. It's not far from here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_8">
    <text>Lead the way.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_complite_1">
    <text>Which artifact did you manage to fish out? Let's see it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_complite_2">
    <text>Here, this is what I found!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_complite_3">
    <text>You got lucky. Artifacts like this aren't often found around here. Well done - you're a capable student! If you want, I can buy this artifact from you at its full value. Traders will never give you the full price, but I happen to need this particular artifact. If you agree, I can also buy other artifacts from you, but only the rare ones. Think about it and if you decide to agree, come see me. Alright, let's head back to the camp. I bet you can't wait to tell everyone about your find, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_complite_4">
    <text>Of course. Let's go to the village, we'll talk about it there.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_gg_0">
    <text>Alright, I found a path in the center of the field. Judging by the readings on my new detector, there's an artifact here, maybe even more than one. Now it's your turn. Here, take my old detector - it's an upgraded "Bear" model. With its help, you can not only determine the distance to the artifact but also the direction of the search. Throw bolts and bypass anomalies. When you see a signal on the screen, go in that direction. Just be careful! You won't immediately see the artifact. You'll need to get pretty close to it and then it will pop out. Good luck!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_gg_1">
    <text>Thank you!</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_strahovka_0">
    <text>Here we are. See that pit behind me? That's the anomalous field. You need to be extremely careful here - one wrong step and you're done for. So, here's the plan: I'll investigate the anomaly, find a passage, and test the detector at the same time. Meanwhile, you watch me carefully, but don't forget to look around also - mutants might show up. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_strahovka_1">
    <text>Got it.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Wolf. I wanted to ask you something. Do you happen to know where I can find Watchmaker? He's not at home, but I have a question for him.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_1">
    <text>He's left two days ago.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_2">
    <text>Where did he go?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_3">
    <text>To the Swamp, he's gathering some herbs there for his tinctures. Perfect for colds, I must say, helps with other ailments too.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, that's disappointing. When will he be back?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_5">
    <text>He'll be back today. How much time has passed anyway?... Hmm, he should have arrived by now. It's strange, he never runs late. There's a reason he's called Watchmaker. Maybe something happened to him? Listen Shroud, I have an important task for you: make your way to the tunnel not far from the barrier, Watchmaker was supposed to return through it. Who knows what might have happened there? He's a tough and experienced man, spent his whole life in the Zone, but age catches up with everyone, you know? I've sent you the coordinates. Now hurry.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_line_dungeon_dialog_6">
    <text>I'm gone.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_0">
    <text>Do you have any work available?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_1">
    <text>I always have something interesting for you. Would you like to go on a safari?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_2">
    <text>I don't know, never been on one.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_3">
    <text>Would you like to? We don't have savannas here, no lions either, sorry. But we have boars that could give any lion a run for its money. It's those boars we need to calm down. A hunting group has just left a few minutes ago - they want to shoot mutants in the vicinity of the village. Would you like to join them?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_4">
    <text>Why not. There really are a lot of animals here, I still can't forget those boars near the "electric train" station.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_5">
    <text>Nice going my friend. It's good for the camp and some extra money won't hurt you. By the way, the pay for this job is 6,000 rubles. Not bad huh? So what do you say, will you go?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_6">
    <text>Do you even have to ask? Of course, I'll go! Give me the coordinates?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_7">
    <text>I've sent it to your PDA. Like I said, the guys just left, so there will be plenty for you to shoot at.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright, I'll go catch up.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_complite_0">
    <text>Job's done, we shot those mutants good!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_complite_1">
    <text>Already back? How was our local safari?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_complite_2">
    <text>Great. I should do it again sometime.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_complite_3">
    <text>Good, there are always plenty of creatures around here. I can't fathom where they all come from. Anyway, enough chit-chat - here's your reward. If there's any more work, I'll send you a message. Good luck!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_trimming_dialog_complite_4">
    <text>Thank you, Wolf! Take care!</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_0">
    <text>You don't have any customers right now, want to chat?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_1">
    <text>Sure thing. What's up?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_11">
    <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_111">
    <text>Well, brother, back in the Union days I was involved in commerce! I was one of those... "cursed speculators." Got burned in a serious deal and paid the price. Served my time, made some acquaintances among the criminal folk. When I got out, the Soviet Union had already collapsed. Things didn't work out for me with the new order, so I had to do odd jobs for a while, ended up completely broke, and then bam - the Zone appeared. I came here and it's been a blast: almost everything is like in the old days! With my experience, trading here is just perfect.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_1111">
    <text>Got it. Can you tell me something else?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_1112">
    <text>Understood. Well, enough chit-chat.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_12">
    <text>What do you think about Logopedist?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_121">
    <text>I'll tell you this, Logopedist won't be around for much longer. I have a gut feeling that Koba will undercut him and take him down once and for all. The boss has been acting all high and mighty, thinking he's untouchable. He's cozying up to the snake, but doesn't realize that most of the guys can see through it. I'm not telling you this so you start blabbering left and right. I'm trusting you so you can trust me, right?. So, if you come across anything interesting, bring it to me. And remember: whoever comes out on top, Logopedist or Koba, I'll always be in my place regardless.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_13">
    <text>Tell me about Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_131">
    <text>No one used to go there before: trash, radiation... But then a couple of stalkers got lucky and dug up some valuable items, and that was it - people from all over the Zone rushed here like diseases to an old whore. Chaos ensued, but our guys restored order. The important thing is to have a strong hand and keep the scum in check and our guys did just that. Some sacrifices have to be made for order though, so the guys want their share and get a cut of everything. Ah, even though I'm doing pretty well here, I still want to reach places that are even more lucrative...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_14">
    <text>What's the latest news in the Zone?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_141">
    <text>There was an incident the other day... This stalker dropped by, pale as a ghost, hands trembling... He started confessing for some reason. Here's the story: He and his friend were escaping from poltergeists when suddenly a pack of snorks jump on them. Well, the guy freaked out, some crazy reflexes or something kick in and he sprayed his friend with bullets. Of course, he immediately realized what he had done and got the hell out of there. Meanwhile the snorks were already on the dead body. Why bother running after meat when there's already some on the ground, right? After that and the second bottle of vodka, his conscience kicks in, he starts howling all over Garbage: "Igor, you gave me your last medkit and I killed you, like a scum, killed you!.." Long story short, he howled and howled, and at night he hanged himself with a belt. It happens sometimes...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_15">
    <text>Oh, nothing, probably.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_151">
    <text>Whatever you say, it's up to you.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_0">
    <text>Can I help you with something?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_1">
    <text>No Shroud, thanks, but we handle things ourselves. There's something, but I doubt you'll accept...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_2">
    <text>What's the matter, Pathogenych? Come on, spill the beans or I won't stop bothering you. I'll decide whether I accept or not.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, not much to tell. There's a mutant that settled nearby, a pseudodog. It's a cunning bastard, comes to the camp and starts howling at night. It's worn out our nerves. We tried to find its lair a couple of times, but found nothing - no tracks, no sign of the creature, as if there was no one there. But it keeps howling at night.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_4">
    <text>You should deal with it at night, when it comes to the camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_5">
    <text>Ha, easier said than done. I'm telling you, these pseudodogs are smart bastards, and this one is particularly elusive. To go after a mutant during the night, you either have to be a complete idiot or Chuck Norris, and even then there's no guarantee you'll survive. Do you think you can handle it yourself? I'll give you a helmet with night vision. Heck, if you successfully kill it, you can keep the helmet for good, and I'll even throw in some extra cash. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright! I've been wanting to get myself some night vision goggles for a while now. Give me your helmet. I'll return it once I'm done.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_7">
    <text>No, thanks. I don't want to deal with pseudodogs.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_8">
    <text>Well, I said you wouldn't accept, didn't I? You can't handle it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_9">
    <text>Whatever.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_complete_dialog_0">
    <text>I took care of your mutt, Pathogenych. You were right, it's a cunning creature, hard to hit. But hey, I'm no pushover either. You won't hear howls at night anymore, I guarantee it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_complete_dialog_1">
    <text>That's fantastic, well done! Here's something extra from me, you've earned it. We'll finally get some decent sleep tonight thanks to you. Remember, you're always welcome here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_complete_dialog_2">
    <text>No problem, Pathogenych. If any other creature bothers you, you know who to call.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Do you have a job for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, I have a job just for you. We need to find a technician who can fix weapons and gear for the boys. We'll pay him threefold for each repair and the boys will treat him with respect of course. You'll also get your share for the work. Are you up for it?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_2">
    <text>No problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Alright, just be quick about it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_4">
    <text>I'm already on it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_11">
    <text>I don't think so...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_12">
    <text>What nonsense... Get lost then.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_start_dialog_13">
    <text>Gone.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_end_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey boss, I found a technician for the crew, nice guy, and skilled too.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_end_dialog_1">
    <text>That's great. Now things will finally go back to normal around here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_mechanic_search_end_dialog_2">
    <text>Yeah, I'll see you later.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_dybolom_quest_mechanic_search_dialog_0">
    <text>Listen Blockhead, would you be interested in repairing gear for the brothers?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dybolom_quest_mechanic_search_dialog_1">
    <text>I sure would. Besides, I'm not very good at expeditions as you know, but I can tinker in a way that would even make Van jealous. But hold on, Logopedist is offering jobs to Stalkers now?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dybolom_quest_mechanic_search_dialog_2">
    <text>Logopedist doesn't care if you're a Stalker. He promises payment for your work and the respect of the crew either way.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dybolom_quest_mechanic_search_dialog_3">
    <text>Then I agree.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dybolom_quest_mechanic_search_dialog_4">
    <text>Got it, I'll let Logopedist know.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_0">
    <text>The chimera is dead, here's the PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_1">
    <text>Excellent, now, here's your new assignment: One of our servicemen, Private Nikita Sergeevich Nefedov, has deserted. It seems he fled into the Zone. Find out where he's hiding or confirm his death.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_2">
    <text>Alright, it should be easier than dealing with chimeras.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_0">
    <text>I found the deserter.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_1">
    <text>Where is he hiding?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_2">
    <text>Unfortunately he's dead. Here are the dog tags from the body.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_3">
    <text>Well, that's his fate. You and your partner are free to go now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_4">
    <text>Goodbye, I hope to never see you again.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_10">
    <text>He's at the Bandit base, goes by the name Scar now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_11">
    <text>So that's how it is. Alright, I'll send a squad to arrest him. You and your partner are free to go. Don't get caught again!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_colonel_kolyazin_quest_contract_end_12">
    <text>We'll do our best.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_0">
    <text>Listen Wolf, you're an experienced hunter. Can you give me some advice on dealing with a chimera?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_1">
    <text>You're not a bad hunter yourself. You took care of business with Leshiy and helped a lot with clearing the area of mutants. So, I'll tell you an unconventional method, a trick from one hunter to another.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_2">
    <text>Unconventional? What do you mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_3">
    <text>Do you know Trapper? Well, he made a repellent using the urine of a male chimera. If you cover yourself with it, the chimera should smell the scent of a rival and retreat. But it's not that simple...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_4">
    <text>As expected, what's the side effects?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_5">
    <text>The thing is, the urine affects each individual differently. Female chimeras will prefer to flee, a weak male will also run away, but if you encounter a strong male, the scent of a rival will drive him into a frenzy, and as you can imagine, an enraged male chimera will tear you apart.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright, do you have the repellent?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_7">
    <text>Here, take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_8">
    <text>Thanks.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_army_contract_dialog_10">
    <text>I'd rather manage without it.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_dezertir_dialog_0">
    <text>Wolf, have you seen a soldier named Nikita Nefedov around the village?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_dezertir_dialog_1">
    <text>Soldiers don't come around here. We have tense relations with them.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_dezertir_dialog_2">
    <text>Have there been any newcomers named Nikita recently?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_dezertir_dialog_3">
    <text>There was a rookie named Nikita a while back. He had a strange nickname... something like "Porridge". I don't know why, but he moved to the vehicle station a while ago.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_quest_dezertir_dialog_4">
    <text>Thank you for the information.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Pathogenych, I have a question for you. Have you come across a stalker named Porridge or Nikita? Supposed to be a former soldier?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_1">
    <text>No, I haven't met anyone named Porridge or Nikita. Besides, it's not common for stalkers to use their real names.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, maybe you've met a soldier recently?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_3">
    <text>How would you know whether someone was a soldier or not? Pick the one who jumps up the fastest when you yell "attention"?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_4">
    <text>Pathogenych, you're an experienced and observant stalker, can't you recognize someone who's served?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, there was one stalker called Epaulet, he had a scar on his face. He definitely looked like a former soldier, not just because of his nickname but also by how he looked at other stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_6">
    <text>Where is he now?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_7">
    <text>Black Stalker knows, he may have died or joined the Bandits.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_patogen_quest_dezertir_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright, thanks for the information.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_dezertir_dialog_0">
    <text>Logopedist, do you know someone called Epaulet?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_dezertir_dialog_1">
    <text>Epaulet? Isn't he one of the rookies?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_dezertir_dialog_2">
    <text>Not exactly. He has a scar on his face and may have come here recently.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_dezertir_dialog_3">
    <text>We had a guy with a scar on his face show up recently. Well, we just call him Scar.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_dezertir_dialog_4">
    <text>Is he at the base now?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_dezertir_dialog_5">
    <text>Yeah, look around if you need him.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_logoped_quest_dezertir_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_dezertir_quest_dezertir_dialog_0">
    <text>Good day, I have something to discuss with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dezertir_quest_dezertir_dialog_1">
    <text>What business could you have with me?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dezertir_quest_dezertir_dialog_2">
    <text>Nikita, I've been given a hard task, I can't handle it alone. I need a partner, can you help me out?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dezertir_quest_dezertir_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, if the business promises to be profitable... Wait, what did you call me?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dezertir_quest_dezertir_dialog_4">
    <text>I called you Nikita Nefedov, a former private in the Ukrainian army, now a deserter on the run. Kolyazin has gone crazy trying to find you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dezertir_quest_dezertir_dialog_5">
    <text>Damn, my past won't let me go... Listen, I can't go back and Kolyazin won't rest until he finds me, help me out. Here are my dog tags, give them to him and tell him you found them on my dead body.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_dezertir_quest_dezertir_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright, I'll do it.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_sidor_about_price_dialog_0">
    <text>Sidorovich, what's with the prices these days?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_about_price_dialog_1">
    <text>Some smartass stalker pissed off the soldiers, so Kolyazin raised the toll of delivering goods through the checkpoint. If I find out who that stalker was, I'll rip his head off.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_about_price_dialog_2">
    <text>Now what?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_about_price_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, tough times for all stalkers, what else? Now food, gear, ammunition, weapons, basically everything, has gone up in price. It's no longer profitable for me to trade here in Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_about_price_dialog_4">
    <text>Something needs to be done.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_about_price_dialog_5">
    <text>I don't know what the stalkers would do, but me, I'll be moving to the Dytiatky checkpoint if things don't change.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_about_price_dialog_6">
    <text>Got it.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_patogen_about_price_dialog_0">
    <text>Pathogenych, what's with the prices these days?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_patogen_about_price_dialog_1">
    <text>Kolyazin has gone mad, he raised the price for transporting goods through the checkpoint. That means increased prices of course.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_patogen_about_price_dialog_2">
    <text>Got it.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_antibiotic_about_price_dialog_0">
    <text>Antibiotic, what's with the prices these days?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_antibiotic_about_price_dialog_1">
    <text>Kolyazin snapped, he raised the price for transporting medical supplies through the checkpoint. That means increased prices of course.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_antibiotic_about_price_dialog_2">
    <text>Got it.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_tick_about_price_dialog_0">
    <text>Tick, what's with the prices these days?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tick_about_price_dialog_1">
    <text>Kolyazin is a damn scumbag, he's demanding a fortune for transporting supplies through the checkpoint. I can't afford to be at a loss.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tick_about_price_dialog_2">
    <text>Got it.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_kusto_about_price_dialog_0">
    <text>Cousteau, what's with the prices these days?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kusto_about_price_dialog_1">
    <text>Kolyazin has completely lost it, he raised the price for transporting goods through the checkpoint. Now it's tough with supplies and that means a price increase.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kusto_about_price_dialog_2">
    <text>Got it.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_dialog_0">
    <text>What do you need?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_dialog_1">
    <text>I heard about Shmyga and how he pulled off a profitable deal. The problem is, he doesn't want to play fair. He only pays a tenth of the loot to the common fund.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_dialog_2">
    <text>Are you suggesting that I should get a share from Shmyga?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_dialog_3">
    <text>Very perceptive, but it's not just about getting a share, it's also about punishing him for his arrogance and unwillingness to play fair.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_dialog_4">
    <text>How should I punish him?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_dialog_5">
    <text>In a proper gangster way, draw some blood with a knife so that he thinks twice before crossing the line in the future. Tell him that if he wants to stay alive, he better cough up his share.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright, I'll do it.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hand over Sidorovich's case, you snake.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_first_dialog_1">
    <text>What, don't you want the keys to my apartment as well? Back off while you still can.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Don't mess with me. It's not your case and you won't be able to open it anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Don't worry, I'll find a way.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_first_dialog_4">
    <text>I'll shoot you right now, you bastard...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Are you sure talking tough at our base is wise? You have no chance of raising your gun to a real gangster.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_first_dialog_6">
    <text>We'll meet again.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Your boss sent me, you scum. You didn't play fair, didn't share the loot, the gang won't help you now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_second_dialog_1">
    <text>The gang? Screw 'em, I'll have my own gang soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_second_dialog_2">
    <text>No, you won't. Logopedist ordered me to carve that smug smile right off your face.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_second_dialog_3">
    <text>What? We'll see who carves who, you sucker.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Go ahead and try.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_last_dialog_0">
    <text>Don't kill me! I'll give my share...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_last_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, maybe you should've started with that huh? I'll let Logopedist know.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_last_dialog_2">
    <text>Will you let me go?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_last_dialog_3">
    <text>You can live for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_last_dialog_10">
    <text>Not so fast, bastard. You owe Sidorovich, not Logopedist.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_last_dialog_11">
    <text>But you said it was my share for the common fund.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_shmiga_last_dialog_12">
    <text>I lied! Now I'll not only take what you owe to Sidorovich, but your life too. Dead men don't talk after all...</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_0">
    <text>I dealt with Shmyga.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_1">
    <text>Great, now no one will dare not to contribute to the common fund. Here's your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_2">
    <text>Not bad, not bad.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_10">
    <text>Who do you think you are? I told you to cut him, not to kill him!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_11">
    <text>Yeah, I went too far, but it was hard to resist.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_12">
    <text>Do as you're told next time! What about the cash?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_13">
    <text>Not sure, Shmyga didn't have anything on him.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_14">
    <text>You really messed up this time. Get out of my sight before I order someone to get rid of you.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_quest_dangerous_business_logoped_end_dialog_15">
    <text>I'm already gone.</text>
</string>
		
	
	<string id="esc_army_stepan_dialog_0">
        <text>--------</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_army_stepan_dialog_1">
        <text>--------</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_army_stepan_dialog_2">
        <text>--------</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_army_stepan_dialog_3">
        <text>--------</text>
    </string>
	
</string_table>
