<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="zat_b22_medic_pda_desc">
		<text>Entry #12: The research is almost over... People in the camp are starting to suspect something. Grouse made a deal with Danila to go after the bloodsuckers... I wonder when they will figure it out?... Need to sort the blood vials: find out which ones are infected and hide the rest... Someone is coming!..
Entry #13... possibly the last one. Everything is falling apart! First that curious idiot-hunter, and now Grouse. It's naive to think I can get away with it. They will come after me. But really... what difference does it make? Hemoglobin dependency will consume me soon. It's better to be shot - that's better than dying from the illness...</text>
	</string>

	
	<string id="st_gar_main_quest_lekarstvo_all_name">
    <text>Antidote</text>
</string>
<string id="st_gar_main_quest_lekarstvo_all_descr">
    <text>A powerful experimental antidote capable of combating poisoning from highly aggressive chemical compounds.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_gar_b47_digger_pda_name">
    <text>Digger's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_gar_b47_digger_pda_descr">
    <text>PDA of a deceased digger. The information stored in it can be quite valuable.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_labx5_b10_cfo_codekey">
    <text>Door key</text>
</string>
<string id="st_labx5_b10_cfo_codekey_descr">
    <text>The key to the storage room that has the stashes of the Monolith group.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_b10_cfo_oszillograf_name">
    <text>Oscilloscope C1-65A</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_b10_cfo_oszillograf_descr">
    <text>The universal oscilloscope C1-65A is designed for studying the shape of electrical signals through visual observation and measurement of their amplitude and time parameters in workshop, laboratory, and field conditions. The oscilloscope complies with GOST 22261-76 and 9810-69 standards. In terms of accuracy of signal reproduction, measurement of time intervals, and amplitudes, the oscilloscope C1-65A belongs to the II class of GOST 9810-69.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_labx5_quest_document_1">
    <text>Documents with notes</text>
</string>
<string id="st_labx5_quest_document_1_descr">
    <text>Some of the military documents that mention their classified project that was being developed in the laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_labx5_quest_document_2">
    <text>Documents with notes</text>
</string>
<string id="st_labx5_quest_document_2_descr">
    <text>Some of the military documents that mention their classified project that was being developed in the laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_labx5_quest_document_3">
    <text>Documents with notes</text>
</string>
<string id="st_labx5_quest_document_3_descr">
    <text>Some of the military documents that mention their classified project that was being developed in the laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_labx5_b10_cfo_codegrabber_name">
    <text>Code grabber</text>
</string>
<string id="st_labx5_b10_cfo_codegrabber_descr">
    <text>A special electronic device designed for intercepting, recognizing, and decoding radio signals. It is used for hacking various types of electronic locks.</text>
</string>



<string id="esc_gruz_safe_name">
    <text>Container</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_gruz_safe_desc">
    <text>A sealed container.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_esc_quest_serious_business_pda_name">
    <text>Beater's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_esc_quest_serious_business_pda_desc">
    <text>The last message on the PDA:\n "These bastards have decided to make their own rules on our territory. They've settled in the house right in front of our base, fearless bastards! Go there and have a heart-to-heart with them. If they don't get it the first time, you can give them a lead shower. And do it quickly, before their leader escapes to Garbage!"</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_habar_name">
    <text>Sidorovich's money case</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_habar_desc">
    <text>The case that holds Sidorovich's money.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_money_merc_name">
    <text>Money bag</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_money_merc_desc">
    <text>A bag of money to pay the mercenaries.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="esc_sidor_habar_key">
    <text>Key</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sidor_habar_key_descr">
    <text>The key to the box where Sidorovich's stash is hidden.</text>
</string>



<string id="st_esc_quest_freedom_pda_name">
    <text>Yablonsky's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_esc_quest_freedom_pda_desc">
    <text>"PDA BLOCKED"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_esc_quest_freedom_pda_upd_name">
    <text>Yablonsky's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_esc_quest_freedom_pda_upd_desc">
    <text>Message 64:\n "The target group didn't appear at the specified time. Our informant reported the absence of any traces. Stop the attempt to move the sacred Monolith piece outside the perimeter by any means necessary."\n Message 65:\n "In addition to us, the Spectrum group has started hunting for the artifact. Their goals and objectives are unclear, but anyone involved in the theft must be eliminated and the artifact must be returned to the sarcophagus."\n Message 66:\n "The artifact is extremely dangerous, with off-the-charts psi emissions. Monolith fighters experience intense mental stress upon contact, if an ordinary person opens the container, it will lead to instant death."\n Message 67:\n "Recently, coordinates of one of the stalkers who stole a part of our sacred stone were obtained. We must make our way to the underground laboratory in the area and deliver the enemies of the Monolith to their death."</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="st_esc_quest_shvabroid_pda_name">
    <text>Sleeper's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_esc_quest_shvabroid_pda_desc">
    <text>Incoming message:\n "Finish off this Freedom guy and wrap up the matter. Just make sure everything is clean, we don't need any problems with Freedom later."</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_help_nebo_radio_name">
    <text>T-169-7KDNЕ radio station</text>
</string>
<string id="st_quest_help_nebo_radio_desc">
    <text>The T-169-7KDNЕ radio station provides open and crypto-protected radio communication in the HF/UHF frequency ranges of tactical command and control networks under harsh operating conditions, including the use of PPRCH. Manufactured at the Yaroslavl Radio Plant.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="st_esc_watchmaker_key_door">
    <text>Key</text>
</string>
<string id="st_esc_watchmaker_key_door_descr">
    <text>The key to Watchmaker's house.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_esc_quest_army_doc_name">
    <text>Sergeant's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_esc_quest_army_doc_desc">
    <text>Sergeant's PDA containing valuable information for Kolyazin, for which he is willing to send people to their death.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_esc_quest_chimera_repilent_name">
    <text>Chimera repellent</text>
</string>
<string id="st_esc_quest_chimera_repilent_desc">
    <text>Repellent for chimeras. Made from male chimera urine. Repels females but angers males.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_esc_quest_army_brelok_name">
    <text>Deserter's keychain</text>
</string>
<string id="st_esc_quest_army_brelok_desc">
    <text>The deserter's keychain - a proof of death.</text>
</string>



<string id="st_bar_a2_juk_component_1_name">
    <text>Component #1</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_a2_juk_component_1_desc">
    <text>A special microchip needed to create a listening device.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_a2_juk_component_2_name">
    <text>Component #2</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_a2_juk_component_2_desc">
    <text>A specifically marked capacitors needed to create a listening device.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_a2_juk_component_3_name">
    <text>Component #3</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_a2_juk_component_3_desc">
    <text>Inductance coils with specific markings needed to create a listening device.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_a2_spec_juk_item_1_name">
    <text>Listening device</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_a2_spec_juk_item_1_desc">
    <text>A homemade bug for covert room surveillance. It has the ability to record and transmit gathered information to a special storage device. The working range is uncertain.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_a2_spec_juk_item_2_name">
    <text>Listening device</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_a2_spec_juk_item_2_desc">
    <text>A homemade bug for covert room surveillance. It has the ability to record and transmit gathered information to a special storage device. The working range is uncertain.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_a2_spec_juk_device_title">
    <text>Lukey-853D soldering station</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_a2_spec_juk_device_descr">
    <text>Advantages of Lukey-853D: modern design, compact size, anti-static execution to protect the PCB from static electricity. The built-in microprocessor provides temperature display and control, rapid temperature rise, and precise temperature setting. These advantages enable lead-free dismantling and soldering, allowing for the dismantling and soldering of temperature-sensitive components housed in SOIC, PLCC, QFP, BGA packages. Included: tips, assembly and disassembly clamp for tips, stand, user manual, soldering iron, soldering iron holder, power cord, testing pen.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_b10_cfo_spec_razia_name">
    <text>R-250M2 Kit-M2 radio receiver</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_b10_cfo_spec_razia_descr">
    <text>"R-250/M/M2" ("R-670/M") - Beloved by many radio enthusiasts. It's a legendary shortwave, vacuum tube, mainline, tabletop military radio receiver. Produced from 1948 to 1981 in several modifications: "R-250/M/M2" ("Kit/M/M2") - for ground forces; "R-670/M" ("Rusalka/M") - for naval forces. The receiver features a precise mirror optical tuning scale, a thermostatically controlled quartz frequency heterodyne stabilizer. It has 12 sub-bands, each 2 MHz wide. The range switch is mechanical, drum-type.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_key_door">
    <text>Key</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bar_key_door_descr">
    <text>The key to the door leading to Lab X-14.</text>
</string>


<string id="labx14_access_card">
    <text>Old magnetic access card</text>
</string>
<string id="labx14_access_card_descr">
    <text>A magnetic access card for entry to the sealed underground railway station, code "0519".</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="city_safe_container_name">
    <text>Container</text>
</string>
<string id="city_safe_container_desc">
    <text>Container with radio components</text>
</string>
<string id="city_bomb_c4_name">
    <text>C-4 explosive</text>
</string>
<string id="city_bomb_c4_desc">
    <text>A plastic explosive of military purpose. Used for various destruction tasks, also widely used as a weapon to engage personnel and equipment.</text>
</string>
<string id="city_money_sp_name">
    <text>Money case</text>
</string>
<string id="city_money_sp_desc">
    <text>A case that holds a very large amount of money.</text>
</string>


<string id="st_labx14_csky_pda_name">
    <text>Hoarse's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_labx14_csky_pda_descr">
    <text>Last message: ...silent here, an eerie silence. Not even the wind can be heard. Feels like I'm moving silently in one second, and like someone is walking nearby the next. The sound strangely echoes off these tiled walls.
I don't know when, or if, I'll get out of here. There is still hope...
Today I went in circles again, been walking the same route for three days now: staircase, tunnel, staircase, tunnel, staircase... How do I get out of here? Who am I asking? No answer. Clever... I didn't even mention where I was heading to anyone. How funny it is to think about such secrets now, only the Zone finds it amusing. They don't even know where to look for me.
I'll eat some canned food and have a little vodka to fall asleep. In this darkness and silence, they taste completely different to me.
Today I stumbled on some cages and it seems like the floor was smeared with something. Piles of polished white bones are on the ground. I don't want to think they're human, but if not, then what? And who neatly stacked them like a little shack?
I can't see them but I keep tripping over them, they scatter loudly across the floor.
The flashlight died two days ago. 
I can see well in the darkness now, or so it seems to me. Sometimes I see colored flashes and hear voices. I go towards them... but there's nothing there. Fog... just thick fog. I have to follow my path through the fog and reach the light of God. I forgive and ask for forgiveness.</text>
</string>


<string id="st_labx14_doc_1_info_name">
    <text>Report No.1542 on Experiment No.21</text>
</string>
<string id="st_labx14_doc_1_info_descr">
    <text>After daily intracavitary injections of broad-spectrum antibiotics, the test subjects did not show any positive dynamics. Tissue decomposition continues evenly throughout the body. The speech center of the subjects remains suppressed, they can only utter one or two phrases. Training and conditioning have not yielded visible results - the subjects still cannot associate food delivery with pedal pressing. Motor functions remain unchanged, aggressiveness increases if infected subjects are not fed for a long time, then they start attacking each other, but cannibalism has not been observed.
Conclusion: the infection (if any) does not respond to antibiotics, infected subjects behave as before, retaining all known basic functions they acquired after overcoming the "transformation" stage.
\n April 26, 20##</text>
</string>


<string id="labx14_doc_2_info_name">
    <text>Report No.1556 on Experiment No.05</text>
</string>
<string id="labx14_doc_2_info_descr">
    <text>For two weeks, feeding of the infected subjects was carried out according to the approved reduced schedule in order to determine the onset period of critical depletion of the affected organism and attempt to establish a connection between body build and the time when depletion reaches a critical and fatal level. After a few days into the experiment, the infected individuals began exhibiting aggressive behavior. Attempts to break the restraining bars intensified. Interestingly, even without regular feeding, the physical strength of the infected subjects did not diminish. It seemed to have even increased, as they managed to loosen several bars of the bars. After feeding, the individuals noticeably calmed down. The longer the individuals starved, the more desperate they became to escape beyond its limits. A request has been sent to the relevant department regarding the reinforcement of the isolation facility. Please refer to the attached document for the interim report and conclusions. Observations are ongoing. \n May 25, 20##</text>
</string>
</string_table>
