<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>	
<string id="st_af_bat_name">
    <text>Bat</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_bat_descr">
    <text>Anomalous formation with magnetic properties similar to highly dense metals. However, it has a relatively low specific mass. It creates a powerful protective field capable of altering the trajectories of bullets and projectiles. It is considered rare due to its difficult detection. Radioactive. \n %c[default]Properties:\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Increased bullet resistance %c[255,238,15,26](%c[255,1,128,54]+7%c[255,238,15,26])\n%c[default]</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_fire_loop_name">
    <text>Fire Loop</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_fire_loop_descr">
    <text>An extremely rare artifact. It is generated by the influence and close proximity to the Burner anomaly. Its ability to significantly lower the temperature within a 0.5m radius, combined with high thermal radiation absorption, makes it an indispensable thermal protection aid. It has weak healing properties.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_fountain_name">
    <text>Fountain</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_fountain_descr">
    <text>Despite the absence of any gravitational effects, Fountain significantly reduces the weight of carried objects. According to one theory among scientists stalkers, this is due to the low density of the artifact's substance (significantly lower than the density of air masses). As a result, it has the effect of an air balloon. The fact that it remains grounded and cannot overcome gravity on its own remains unexplained.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_generator_name">
    <text>Generator</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_generator_descr">
    <text>This artifact not only heals wounds and other injuries, but also greatly improves tissue regeneration and accelerates healing. This is achieved through a temporary immune restructuring within the body and does not require additional therapy. Radioactive.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_eye_dragon_name">
    <text>Dragon's Eye</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_eye_dragon_descr">
    <text>A powerful reparant of muscle tissues. In combination with the stabilizing effect on the respiratory system, it enhances RNA biosynthesis, functional and enzymatic cellular components, including those constituting cell membranes, and stimulates DNA replication and cell division. The source of such an effect is not fully understood. Radioactive.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_peas_name">
    <text>Peas</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_peas_descr">
    <text>A stable chemical compound, it's capable of removing almost one hundred percent of radionuclides from the body, regardless of the source of contamination, be it food, water, or air. The artifact's action is based on its high ability to capture and eliminate actinides, the most dangerous radioactive elements, from the body. Research by stalker scientists has confirmed the complete non-toxicity of this artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_cell_name">
    <text>Cell</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_cell_descr">
    <text>The main drawback of this anomalous formation is its high gravitational field value. This effect increases the weight of carried objects and attracts metallic items relatively strongly. However, the vector of the magnetic influence is directed towards the ground, significantly reducing the accuracy of bullet trajectories due to their deviation. Radioactive. \n %c[default]Properties:\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Increased bullet resistance %c[255,238,15,26](%c[255,1,128,54]+10%c[255,238,15,26])\n%c[default]</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_cocoon_name">
    <text>Cocoon</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_cocoon_descr">
    <text>The properties of this artifact can be described as immobilizing. It has two oppositely charged poles that, when interacting, create heterogeneity in local atmospheric formations while maintaining an optically unchanged spatial structure. The relative hardness of this "dome" is provided by stable nano-compounds that absorb the energy of all external impacts. Radioactive. \n %c[default]Properties:\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Increased bullet resistance %c[255,238,15,26](%c[255,1,128,54]+12%c[255,238,15,26])\n%c[default]</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_lighthouse_name">
    <text>Lighthouse</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_lighthouse_descr">
    <text>A super-dense cluster of substance. When exposed to an aggressive environment, it releases a cloud of colorless gas with strong alkaline properties. Acting as a neutralizer, it reduces the danger and consequences of chemical burns and contamination. The energy released during chemical reactions is used to absorb radiation.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_medallion_name">
    <text>Medallion</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_medallion_descr">
    <text>It consists of a small-diameter hoop with four attached parts of streamlined triangular shape. These parts have two pairs of opposite charges that change their position within the structure arbitrarily. Concentrating on the central "pearl" of the formation, they create a unique healing, regenerative, and radioprotective effect on the human body. Due to its high value, it is a sought-after item among stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_tapeworm_name">
    <text>Tapeworm</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_tapeworm_descr">
    <text>Essentially, it is pure silicon dioxide, considering solely the atomic mass of the substance. However, it differs from natural crystal not only in its saturated vitriol shade but also in its extremely strong mechanical characteristics. Formed in clusters of anomalies like Electro, this quartz fragment has a complex system of internal currents with external dielectric properties. Radioactive.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_black_angel_name">
    <text>Black Angel</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_black_angel_descr">
    <text>A root turned into an artifact. Its impact is difficult to overestimate in conditions of powerful psi-field influence. The anti-psi radiation of the Black Angel consists of blocking the neurodegradation of monoamines in the body (serotonin, dopamine, etc.). By stabilizing the concentration of these neurotransmitters in the blood, it completely removes the antidepressant threshold below which psi-resistance is absent. Consequently, control over psi-state remains constant, almost regardless of the level of threat, while maintaining overall physical activity.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_signet_name">
    <text>Signet</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_signet_descr">
    <text>Stalkers also call this artifact Amulet. Its pronounced protective properties lie in its ability to alter the means of armor protection at the interatomic level of the element. Virtually all metals within a one-meter radius can undergo transformation. In a set of three, it can reduce the wear of the used weapon. \n %c[default]Properties:\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Increased bullet resistance %c[255,238,15,26](%c[255,1,128,54]+3%c[255,238,15,26])\n%c[default]</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_star_phantom_name">
    <text>Star Phantom</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_star_phantom_descr">
    <text>An anomalous formation, it consists of plasma substance within a transparent pulsating shell. The main feature is its active absorption of oxygen, which acts as a protective factor in local fire suppression by blocking access to the air necessary for temperature increase. It has a healing effect. Radioactive.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_gimlet_name">
    <text>Gimlet</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_gimlet_descr">
    <text>It has a plant-based nature. The cup-shaped petals of the artifact are sources of the emission of a powerful gaseous stimulant. The result of its influence is a change in the hormonal background and, as a result, a significant increase in the level of norepinephrine in the blood. The intensive production of this hormone enhances aggression, rage, and the desire to overcome obstacles. However, along with its positive properties, the consequences of prolonged artifact use include enlarged myocardium and decreased adrenal activity. Radioactive.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_sandstone_name">
    <text>Sandstone</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_sandstone_descr">
    <text>A thermal insulator capable of imparting its properties to contacting objects. There have been cases of no thermal burns after placing the palm with the artifact held tightly into flames with a temperature of 300°C. The resistance to thermal damage is accompanied by a weak healing effect. It is a semi-open sphere with a moving loose substance held from decay by a field of unknown origin.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_serofim_name">
    <text>Seraphim</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_serofim_descr">
    <text>A rare artifact of organic nature. It represents a concentrated mixture of vitamins and amino acids that penetrate the body by an unstudied method. It improves overall health condition as well as cellular and tissue metabolism. By stimulating the metabolism of various chemical groups, it acts as a dual-action metabolic corrector, promoting rapid body recovery. It accelerates muscle mass growth.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_skull_miser_name">
    <text>Miser's Skull</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_skull_miser_descr">
    <text>An interesting artifact of spherical shape containing a large amount of magnesium hydrosilicate. Its properties are capable of significantly slowing down, and in some cases, halting chemical reactions. According to observations by experienced stalkers, it is completely non-radioactive, which makes it attractive to both stalkers and clients outside the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_spaika_name">
    <text>Commissure</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_spaika_descr">
    <text>Externally resembling a fossil formation, it has a pronounced radiation background. Therefore, it is not very popular among stalkers but is of interest to scientists. The uniqueness of its effect lies in the fact that the emitted psi-field neuro-programs the body to improve the efficiency of muscle processes. As a result, the maximum weight that can be carried is increased up to 25 kg. Radioactive.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_kislushka_name">
    <text>Sorrel</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_kislushka_descr">
    <text>One of the most frequently ordered and beautiful artifacts in the Zone. It is a hollow spherical formation resembling transparent parchment. It has a faint emerald inner glow. Due to its regenerative properties, it is also popular among stalkers. Radioactive.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_grapes_name">
    <text>Grapes</text>
</string>
<string id="st_af_grapes_descr">
    <text>A melted piece of greenish wood resin. As a result of various anomalous influences and emissions, it has acquired powerful radio-absorbing properties. Its uniqueness lies not so much in being a "black hole" for radionuclides but in its ability to accelerate the half-life of any isotopes multiple times. In simple terms, it is a true radiation eliminator.</text>
</string>
</string_table>
