<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="bowie_text_1">
		<text>Date: So ... the headquarters sends it to the zone again, damn ... How I do not want to return there.</text>		      
	</string>
	<string id="bowie_text_2">
		<text>Date: That's the perimeter, now, as usual, they will arrange a medical examination worse than that of astronauts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bowie_text_3">
		<text>Date: Not lucky, health allows - eh, to be a military man. Okay, in the zone ... with God.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bowie_text_4">
		<text>Date: It seems that the landing should go through the vicinity of the dome. Well ... I have never been there yet.</text>		      
	</string>
	<string id="bowie_text_5">
		<text>Date: We will get to the place soon, it's so strange - when flying in the sky, so many anomalies sparkled next to us!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bowie_text_6">
		<text>Date: Here is a landing, damn ... That's it, I turn off the C-livaries. It's time to fight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bowie_text_7">
		<text>Date: Something our client is delayed. Everything seems to be under the pretext - transactions with mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bowie_text_8">
		<text>Date: The deal is disrupted. I hide the case, go to the place of evacuation. The task is completed. Lucky ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_exit">
		<text>Exit (ESC)</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_menu_rukzak_close">
		<text>Close</text>
	</string>	
	
	<string id="st_condition_wpn_complite">
		<text>Weapon repair is completed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_condition_wpn_none">
		<text>Repair is impossible: place the weapon in the second slot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_condition_wpn_bad">
		<text>Repair is impossible: the weapon is too badly damaged.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_condition_wpn_full">
		<text>Repair is impossible: weapons are in excellent condition.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_condition_hlem_complite">
		<text>The repair of the helmet is completed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_condition_hlem_none">
		<text>Repair is impossible: put on the helmet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_condition_hlem_bad">
		<text>Repair is impossible: the helmet is too badly damaged.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_condition_hlem_full">
		<text>Repair is impossible: a helmet in excellent condition.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_condition_outfit_complite">
		<text>Costume repair is completed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_condition_outfit_none">
		<text>Repair is impossible: put on a suit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_condition_outfit_bad">
		<text>Repair is impossible: the costume is too badly damaged.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_condition_outfit_full">
		<text>Repair is impossible: a suit in excellent condition.</text>
	</string>		
	
	<string id="st_actor_repair">
		<text>Repair</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_gui_menu_rukzak_close">
		<text>Close</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_gui_actor_cooking">
		<text>Prepare</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="st_gui_selection_revords_info">
		<text>Back</text>
	</string>	
	
</string_table>
