<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

    <string id="ws_tech_task_got_item_0">
        <text>I have details, what do you need? Look.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ws_tech_task_got_item_1">
        <text>For pistol spare parts, electronic spare parts and rifle spare parts - I will pay you. So if you find something from this, bring them to me. We will deal with the award.</text>
    </string>

    <string id="atr_ecolog_stalker_m15_dialog_0_txt">
        <text>Hey stalker! I understand, Glock? Good day ...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="atr_ecolog_stalker_m15_dialog_1_txt">
        <text>Yes, hello.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="atr_ecolog_stalker_m15_dialog_2_txt">
        <text>So ... I hope the professor told you everything and you are ready to help?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="atr_ecolog_stalker_m15_dialog_3_txt">
        <text>Yes. What is your plan? Didn't you find a thief? Check the entire tunnel?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="atr_ecolog_stalker_m15_dialog_4_txt">
        <text>Not everything is so simple ... At the end of the tunnel there is a dead end, but there is a response, apparently there is also a subscription collector is located ... So, to get there, you need to open the door hatch, and for this you need to find an access card ... Horseradish knows where to look for it, we sorted everything here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="atr_ecolog_stalker_m15_dialog_5_txt">
        <text>Damn, but this is a problem ...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="atr_ecolog_stalker_m15_dialog_6_txt">
        <text>So what am I talking about? ... Listen, for some reason it seems to me that a thief - there is no one at all, but you know why? Because this very hatch was closed on this side ... And more, the ways to that collector, there is no. What do you think about this?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="atr_ecolog_stalker_m15_dialog_7_txt">
        <text>I think we would not have interfered with the "Decoder" now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="atr_ecolog_stalker_m15_dialog_8_txt">
        <text>Hmm, I do not think that scientists have this in stock. This should be addressed to the fur coat, now I will contact him by walkie -talkie.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="atr_ecolog_stalker_m15_dialog_9_txt">
        <text>Fine.</text>
    </string>
	
    <string id="atr_ecolog_quest_arts_outfit_zaebis_dialog_1_txt">
        <text>Of course! Hmm ... you have a good equipment ... Let me tell you a little about what we need. The fact is that recently our group brought two very rare types of artifacts. The heart of the oasis and compass. But the day did not pass even as someone stole them! Right from under our nose! Can you imagine? According to our tip, the thief fled with them to the old M-15 complex, which is not far from here. We have already sent the group to search for it, but they still did not find anything, maybe ... Maybe you could help us with this? In the complex: a large variable psi field, which is still subject to research, and urgently ... Perhaps you have already been sure of the relative security of this enterprise? We just need your help in obtaining these samples. Do you agree to help science?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="atr_ecolog_quest_arts_outfit_huinia_dialog_1_txt">
        <text>Hmm ... I ask you to forgive me for the refusal, but understand - with your equipment you are not ready to go to a variable psi field. This threatens you with nothing more than a sudden and painful death. And such a load of my soul is useless ...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="atr_ecolog_quest_arts_outfit_dialog_0_txt">
        <text>Do you need help, professor?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="atr_ecolog_quest_arts_outfit_dialog_227_txt">
        <text>Yes, I am ready to help science.</text>
    </string>	
    <string id="atr_ecolog_quest_arts_outfit_dialog_228_txt">
        <text>No, I'm not ready yet.</text>
    </string>	
    <string id="atr_ecolog_quest_arts_outfit_dialog_229_txt">
        <text>It's clear.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="atr_ecolog_quest_arts_outfit_dialog_8542_txt">
        <text>Great! Then, here, keep the coordinates of our group. They will wait for you in the complex. Ah, and yes ... here, it's for you - a couple of tablets from psi radiation, they will not be superfluous, good luck! I hope you succeed!</text>
    </string>	
	
    <string id="sad_sich_quest_posilka_atr_dialog_1_0">
        <text>Professor, you are a package from Shcherban. He said you will be in the know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sich_quest_posilka_atr_dialog_1_1">
        <text>Yes. Thank you very much, young man. Here is your reward! Oh yes! Due to the fact that you have removed the indicators from the scanners - we can track the presence of artifacts in these anomalies. Here, I registered your PDA tracking. Now you will know in which anomaly, and what artifacts are there. For this, special thanks to you, personally from me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sich_quest_posilka_atr_dialog_1_2">
        <text>Great. Another thing is done.</text>
    </string>
	
    <string id="sad_sich_quest_posilka_atr_dialog_2_0">
        <text>Is there any work?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sich_quest_posilka_atr_dialog_2_1">
        <text>Yes, there is something. I need someone to bring this envelope to the scientist to the "VNZ", and that the extra eyes do not look into it ... do you take it? The package is not urgent, there are some reports on anomalies ... But, it is better to deliver - as soon as possible.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sich_quest_posilka_atr_dialog_2_2">
        <text>Fine. I will transfer the parcel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_sich_quest_posilka_atr_dialog_2_3">
        <text>That's great. Keep an advance, you will get the second half from the professor. I will inform him about you now, he will wait for the parcel.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="az_radar_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_0">
        <text>Maybe something else needs to be helped?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="az_radar_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_1">
        <text>No, brother, thanks, we can cope. Although ... there is one business here. Yes, I only doubt that you will take him</text>
    </string>
	<string id="az_radar_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_2">
        <text>What is the matter? Come on, forge, I won't leave you. Tell everything as it is, but I will already decide whether to take on my work or not.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="az_radar_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_3">
        <text>Yes, there is nothing special to tell. The creature here alone settled nearby. Pseudo -sail ... cunning, bastard. As it gets dark, he comes to the camp and begins to howl. Already all the nerves exhausted us. A couple of times ours wanted to find his hole, but they did not find anything, no traces, nor the creature itself did not even see, as if there was no one. But he continues to howl at night.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="az_radar_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_4">
        <text>So you would have figured it out in the evening when he comes to the camp!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="az_radar_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_5">
        <text>Ha, it's easy to say. Well, I say, pseudo -baches of the creatures are cunning, and this freak is so elusive. Yes, and in order to go to the mutant at night, you need to be either the last idiot or Chuck Norris, and even then it is not a fact that he is lucky. What do you think yourself, are you mastering?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="az_radar_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_6">
        <text>Come on! As I finish, I'll be back. Prepare a reward.</text>
    </string>	
	<string id="az_radar_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_7">
        <text>No, thanks ... This is definitely not for me.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="az_radar_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_8">
        <text>Well, I said that you won't take it, you won't be able to.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="az_radar_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_dialog_9">
        <text>To him ...</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="az_radar_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_complete_dialog_0">
        <text>I flooded your dog, spirit. You turned out to be right, oh and a cunning creature ... But nothing, I myself did not do it with my finger. I won't be more at night, I guarantee it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="az_radar_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_complete_dialog_1">
        <text>This is well done, I respect! Keep me a reward, deserved. Today, at least we get enough sleep. Thank you, mercenary. Remember, you are always happy here.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="az_radar_quest_night_hunting_barman_patogen_complete_dialog_2">
        <text>Yes, there is nothing, spirit. If there will be any other creature, you know who to call.</text>
    </string>
	
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_complete_quest_1_0">
        <text>The work is completed. I brought your box.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_complete_quest_1_1">
        <text>Thank you, let him go here as soon as possible. Wow! All things are in place. Comrades will be glad that you brought them. Well, Stalker? You worked well. Waiting for a reward? It is understandable - you deserve it in full. I can give it artifacts, money or a set of medicines. Which is closer in spirit - then choose.</text>
    </string>
	
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_complete_quest_1_2">
        <text>Come on money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_complete_quest_1_21">
        <text>As you say! Keep a worthy payment! Thanks again for the help!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_complete_quest_1_3">
        <text>Come on artifacts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_complete_quest_1_31">
        <text>Out! Here they are - Major ... Hold on! I pass it in good hands. These artifacts are not radioactive, so you can safely wear outside the container, here. Thanks for the help!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_complete_quest_1_4">
        <text>Come on a set of medicines.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_complete_quest_1_41">
        <text>Here! Hold on! They will definitely come in handy in the area of вЂ‹вЂ‹the zone. Thank you for your help!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_complete_quest_1_5">
        <text>I just wanted to help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_complete_quest_1_51">
        <text>I did not expect ... thanks for the kindness. It is a pity that now it is now becoming smaller and less each time. Okay, this is all the lyrics. Keep this trunk and a little money, from me personally. All the same, in the zone will come in handy. Happily!</text>
    </string>
	
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_complete_quest_1_6">
        <text>Wow! Probably he steamed you with such a weight!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_complete_quest_1_7">
        <text>Of course, the heavy box, but I hope it is worth it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_complete_quest_1_8">
        <text>No, not steamed. I think it was worth it.</text>
    </string>
	
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_start_dialog_0">
        <text>Is there any work for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_start_dialog_1">
        <text>There is, but small. It is difficult to call work as it were ... It will rather a minor assignment. You need to run away by one box. And it is natural to bring not to anyone, but to me personally. Interested in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Yes. Can I more about the box?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_start_dialog_3">
        <text>No. Another time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_start_dialog_4">
        <text>So, I will briefly tell the essence of history. During reconnaissance with my detachment, I came across one box. Then it was too late and dark. They decided to throw him in a secluded place so that no one would open it to our return. It was dangerous to take excess cargo with you, and there was a code castle on the box. We put the password just in case before leaving. Well, what am I going to. The task is simple - bring this box here. I will pay and will definitely give part of what is inside.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_start_dialog_5">
        <text>I'll be back soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Keep the coordinates of the box. And on now ... at the expense of the "establishment", drink - otherwise there is absolutely no face on you. Hehe.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="zat_a2_venic_start_dialog_7">
        <text>Work? ... Everything is this, probox. Wozmyosya?</text>
    </string>

    <string id="sad_b2_tech_util_1_0">
        <text>Do you, by chance, do you need damaged trunks for spare parts?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_util_1_1">
        <text>Need. See the box to the left of me? Tear off unnecessary iron there. I rest on my leisure and take what I will need. I won't give a lot of money, but you will get rid of the trash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_util_2_0">
        <text>Well, I chose any of the glands that I left?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sad_b2_tech_util_2_1">
        <text>Yes. Here, keep your money.</text>
    </string>

	<string id="kupol_a2_sich_trade_info_lager_0_text">
		<text>I wanted to ask something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_sich_trade_info_lager_1_text">
		<text>What are you interested in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_sich_trade_info_lager_2_text">
		<text>What are your relations between the military?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_sich_trade_info_lager_3_text">
		<text>At the moment - normal. They do not pull us. And we try not to create problems for them. In addition, I have one familiar among bosses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_sich_trade_info_lager_22_text">
		<text>Why in the area of вЂ‹вЂ‹the last couple of months was not a single sectarian from the Monolith group?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_sich_trade_info_lager_33_text">
		<text>Hmm, I don't know ... It's necessary for your scientists or duty to go to the VNode. They know for sure something interesting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_sich_trade_info_lager_222_text">
		<text>In the territories of the dome, many underground utilities?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_sich_trade_info_lager_333_text">
		<text>Yes, even a lot! Here is the truth to many of them the paths are already forever closed. After the last waves of the вЂњoverвЂќ mutants, the debts decided to undermine many holes and dungeons. However, occasionally, these super creatures come out from somewhere ... Damn it knows what kind of experts they spent before the second explosion.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_sich_trade_info_lager_2222_text">
		<text>Do you know anything about a certain mercenary "gloomy"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_sich_trade_info_lager_3333_text">
		<text>Yes ... have already heard ... They say this blue zone has already put on his knees. I collected some kind of group and is now looking for something ... Okay, I'm sorry. But there are many rumors on this subject now and can tell you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_sich_trade_info_lager_22222_text">
		<text>Do you know anything about the "chrome"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_sich_trade_info_lager_33333_text">
		<text>I don't have a concept about who you are talking about ...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="kupol_a2_sich_trade_info_lager_1488_text">
		<text>Clearly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_sich_trade_info_lager_1489_text">
		<text>Nothing, forget it.</text>
	</string>	
	
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_0_text">
		<text>I need to buy something from you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_1_text">
		<text>No problems. Here, all I can offer.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_2_text">
		<text>I need: a rem.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_22_text">
		<text>I need: oil and solvent.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_222_text">
		<text>I need: an advanced sewing set.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_2222_text">
		<text>I need: a professional set for repair.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_3_text">
		<text>Rem. A set for weapons - costs: 14,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_33_text">
		<text>Oil and solvent - costs: 7000 rubles.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_333_text">
		<text>An advanced sewing set is: 7200 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_3333_text">
		<text>Professional recruitment - costs: 15,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_4_text">
		<text>Let's. Here is the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_6_text">
		<text>Hold yet to your place. I'll be back later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_7_text">
		<text>Great.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_8_text">
		<text>I changed my mind. Nothing is needed so far.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="kupol_a2_texnik_trade_mex_items_5_text">
		<text>Keep your goods.</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>
