<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<string id="zat_a2_linker_b29_actor_get_adv_task_111">
<text>I look forward to. Mind you, the order is urgent, it must perform two days.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b106_stalker_gonta_info_about_soroka_gone_0">
<text>I found forty. He was at the station 'Midsummer', under the name Flint. He's already figured out.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b106_stalker_gonta_info_about_soroka_gone_1">
<text>Sorted out? Oh, sorry. Even in the throat is not used ... Well, no, it is still good news. Here you go, as promised.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b106_stalker_gonta_info_about_soroka_gone_11">
<text>Thank you.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b18_noah_plateau_way_112">
<text>Through the burned-out farmhouse. Hmm ... And you do what?</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b215_stalker_guide_about_surge_1">
<text>To tell the truth, to tell - a bit. It is extremely dangerous, and is almost always fatal. He rolled slowly - the easiest to catch him coming to change the weather - but the peak of his passes quickly enough ... At the first signs of its approach to find shelter - a cave or something made of concrete, brick and steel ... I, like some others, I feel it coming - back ache. But the nature of emissions can not say anything - I do not know ...</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b215_stalker_guide_leave_zone_0">
<text>I want to get out of the zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b215_stalker_guide_leave_zone_1">
<text>You sure? This is a one-way road.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b215_stalker_guide_leave_zone_11">
<text>Sure. Come on.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b215_stalker_guide_leave_zone_12">
<text>Although, all right ... While staying.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b22_barmen_about_vampire_actor3_0">
<text>Capercaillie dead. It looks like he was killed by Tremor ... Once he's dead, too.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b22_stalker_medic_dialog_start_1141111">
<text>[More ...]</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b22_stalker_medic_need_health_care_11">
<text>[More ...]</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b22_stalker_medic_need_health_care_2">
<text>Now let's see ... With such health? Well, when I apparently need a ticket to the morgue ...</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b30_owl_stalker_trader_buy_info_15311">
<text>This place is also called the 'Iron wood'. The helicopter crashed right on the power poles. From the military there were no survivors ... Even if he survived - would not have chosen. Poltergeists, for sure, RE would be herded. You know, these creatures react to any movement.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b30_owl_stalker_trader_buy_info_15411">
<text>Listen ... How to helicopter crashed, the military saw there - just five people. It seems to be out of swamps, they successfully got. No, it is not difficult to get there, the main thing - not to go into the water, and jumping over bumps. And protection from chemicals needed. So you, if you want there to climb, buy from a medical antidotes.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b30_owl_stalker_trader_choose_task_111213">
<text>I have something extracted from there.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b30_owl_stalker_trader_choose_task_1112131">
<text>But why then are you silent? .. Well, found something for me?</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b30_owl_stalker_trader_choose_task_116">
<text>You need to get information in the camp of mercenaries. Not as difficult as it seems.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b30_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_26">
<text>Prototypes of detectors. You do not want to buy them back?</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b30_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_27">
<text>Found secret documents on the bridge at the convoy. Want to see?</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b30_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_28">
<text>PDA envoy of Sultan.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b30_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_281">
<text>Not so interesting. I will give him 500.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b30_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_2811">
<text>Agreed.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b30_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_31">
<text>A strange artifact. Found on the dredger.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b30_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_32">
<text>A strange artifact. Found near the station 'Midsummer'.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b30_owl_stalker_trader_sell_items_33">
<text>Artifact 'Heart of the Oasis.'</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b30_owl_stalker_trader_start_dialog_11">
<text>Need the goods? Information? .. Or maybe you want to sell the information to me?</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b3_stalker_tech_start_1311">
<text>Oh, sorry you did not find the Joker from the barge, my comrades ... Good to have sat ... Well were like brothers to each other out - Mount ... How so we could get? ... I am here, and they're ... it is not clear where the ...</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b3_tech_buddies_about_0">
<text>Tell me about the Joker and Barge.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b3_tech_buddies_pda_11">
<text>PDA Barges. I found his body in a cave under the burned village.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b3_tech_buddies_pda_12">
<text>I found it near the skeleton not far from the 'Sosnoduba.' This PDA Joker.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b3_tech_buddies_pda_121">
<text>Joker? ... It can not be! ... What is this? ... It turns out that the Joker is dead ... Ah, the Joker does not laugh us more ... Rest in peace ... I hope that the barge's all right ...</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b3_tech_buddies_pda_122">
<text>Joker? ... It can not be! ... What is this? ... Does that mean that the Joker is dead ... Ah, the Joker does not laugh us more ... Rest in peace ... And Barge ... How did it happen ...</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b3_tech_buddies_pda_13">
<text>Barges and the Joker. One found a short distance from the 'Sosnoduba', the skeleton, the other - on the dead body in the caves under the burned village.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b51_stalker_nimble_b52_about_gun_questions_11111">
<text>Well, then clear. I know him, he was still a rascal and insolent, I look much lately. Stalkers thinks plant ... We ought to put him in his place.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b52_robbery_port_bandits_1_1111">
<text>Yeah I do not care who does what dobazarilsya. Goni all here!</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b52_robbery_port_bandits_1_11111">
<text>Hey, take it easy ... Here you go.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b52_robbery_port_bandits_1_1111212">
<text>Okay, hold on.</text>
</string>
	
<string id="zat_b52_robbery_port_bandits_1_21">
<text>Do not know? ... We already do not care. Goni all here, simpleton!</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b5_stalker_commander_dialog_31">
<text>Yes, help from you - as with goat milk ... Okay ... You know, you can not reward shine - nothing to give.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b5_stalker_commander_dialog_311">
<text>It happens.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_b30_compass_give_actor_dialog_1">
<text>Hammer! It now remains sympathetic terpily dodavit. I tipped off that beard gave his stalkers cool detectors to rare artifacts often nasharivat. It is necessary to enroll in these stalkers and make the detectors you have fallen on the pocket. Caught?</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_b30_start_actor_dialog_2">
<text>Figure there. There is no way to influence it. I wanted to pinch his supply chain, so that bearded bastard still got this 'Compass'. Consider it all with velvet ... yet.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_b7_give_task_dialog_0">
<text>What kind of job can you offer?</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_b7_give_task_dialog_1">
<text>Profitable. What you clicked? You - a new man, while here - no contacts. And could quickly rise ... Interested in what I have to say about this?</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_b7_give_task_dialog_11">
<text>Interested.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_b7_give_task_dialog_111">
<text>Then look here. There are a couple of stalkers Beard thought the currency to rise. Rustling was not planned ... Will you come with all the guys at night to 'Shevchenko', and as long as customers are savvy - take with them provisions. We - the benefits to you, personally - the authority ... Caught? All right. Here is Knuckles, peretresh with him the details.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_b7_give_task_dialog_12">
<text>Not really.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_b7_give_task_dialog_121">
<text>That's for good reason. Do you still think ... As you will understand, that's good for you - let's talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_bandit_boss_sultan_b7_give_task_dialog_2">
<text>Useful to you if you want to climb ... Interested in what I have to say about this?</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_raiders_actor_choose_dialog_0">
<text>Sultan said - you want to stalkers shake. I am with you.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_raiders_actor_choose_dialog_2">
<text>Excellent. To heap up 'Shevchenko' midnight - we'll be waiting for you. Current until the morning do not wait.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_raiders_actor_teleport_dialog_0">
<text>Better I'll stay with you. Let's wait for midnight - show me the way to the 'Shevchenko'.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_raiders_actor_teleport_dialog_1">
<text>No question, you stay. To reduce the barge - no problem.</text>
</string>
	
<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_raiders_actor_teleport_dialog_12">
<text>Although there is not. I'll do as long as their business.</text>
</string>
	
<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_raiders_dialog_13">
<text>And, bro ... Well, what with the Sultan to dobazarilis?</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_raiders_dialog_14">
<text>Mr. Th ... Heap up to the barge after midnight until dawn is not the beginning - we'll wait for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_raiders_dialog_151">
<text>Come on.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_raiders_dialog_152">
<text>Wait a minute.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_raiders_dialog_191">
<text>Well, take the money. We will not quarrel.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_raiders_dialog_1911">
<text>What? ... All lend the fuck! And get out of here! Quickly!</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_raiders_dialog_19111">
<text>I'm leaving.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_raiders_dialog_192">
<text>It will not work!</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_raiders_dialog_21">
<text>And we cool them voltanuli! Only you, simpleton, aside hesitated because fuck you and do not share. Okay, do not ssy. If you still cares naklyunetsya we mayaknem.</text>
</string>

<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_victims_actor_start_dialog_0">
<text>You are going to rob a group of stalkers. I advise you to be alert.</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_victims_actor_start_dialog_1">
<text>Scum! Do not worry, we will prepare them a warm reception ... Listen, if possible, rub them in confidence. Find out how and what, but help us to fight back ... we will not stay in debt!</text>
</string>
<string id="zat_b7_stalkers_victims_actor_start_dialog_2">
<text>Scum! Do not worry, we will prepare them a warm reception ... Look, if there is such a possibility, we fight back. We will not stay in debt!</text>
</string>

</string_table>
