<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>

<string_table>
	<!-- Freedom trader -->
	<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_1_name">
		<text>Destroy the Mutant Lair</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_1_text">
		<text>I've agreed with Sava to destroy a mutant lair.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_1_about">
		<text>Yeah, there's a small issue that needs sorting out. A new mutant lair has sprung up not too far from here. It needs to be cleared before it gets too large. So, what do you say? Will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_1_finish">
		<text>Great work. Thanks to you, we will have more room to breathe without being thrown into the deep end. Here's your payment - they all contributed a little to it. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_name">
		<text>Find the %s Artefact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_text">
		<text>I've agreed to find Sava a %s for his experiments.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_about">
		<text>I'm interested in artefacts, if you can bring it to me. Of course, you'll also get a reward. Sound good?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>I need an artefact for some of my experiments. Anyways, we're looking for an artefact called %s.  Are you in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Well done, stalker. Here is your reward.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_name">
		<text>Capture Encrypted Documents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_text">
		<text>Sava will pay me to ensure some coded papers end up safely in his hands.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_about">
		<text>So, recently, a stalker slipped some stash info that apparently leads to some rather interesting documents. I will give you the coordinates and, in exchange for delivering the papers, you'll be well paid. Anything else you find in there is for you to keep.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_finish">
		<text>Great job, stalker.</text>
	</string>


	<!-- Bandit trader -->
	<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_1_name">
		<text>Eliminate Mutant Threat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_1_text">
		<text>Burhan has sent me to do some housecleaning. I should return to him for payment once I've cleared the mutants off the marked area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_1_about">
		<text>Yeah, stalkers aren't moving in as often anymore. Why? Because they see the mutants, shit themselves, then leave. If this keeps happening, we won't be able to collect rent, borrow goods... you get the picture? It's time to give this village a spring clean.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_1_finish">
		<text>Fantastic! Here is your payment. I'll make sure to put a good word in for you with the boss.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_name">
		<text>Hit Man</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_text">
		<text>Burhan has contracted me to run a hit on some poor sucker, then return for payment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_about">
		<text>I've got a list of people who've rubbed me the wrong way. I want you to rub one of them out. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_2_finish">
		<text>Good, you got rid of that asshole! Here is what I promised.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_name">
		<text>Procure %s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_text">
		<text>Field dress freshly dead mutants to collect meat. Then deliver %s to Burhan in the Town's camp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_about">
		<text>If you are good with a gun and not afraid of a few mutants, then I have a job for you. Are you interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>Rations are running low, and I need to keep everyone in camp's bellies full. Some of the guys bring me back a kill or two every now and again. But it's been slow lately... So, I need %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_poselok_ug_trader_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Great! I have payment for you.</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
