<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>

<string_table>

	<!-- ---------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- //////////////////////// Task 1 //////////////////////// -->
	<!-- ---------------------------------------- -->
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_1">
		<text>Have you heard about the newly opened places?</text>		<!-- asking about new places -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_2">
		<text>Yes, yes, we have already started studying one of them. A few days ago, we sent one of my proteges with a guard to the area known to you as the Promzone, but something went wrong with him, now he refuses to do his job and does not respond. We already have a shortage of people, and allocating them for unexplored territory is simply irrational.\n
		\nMaybe you would agree to help us? The job shouldn't be particularly difficult, you probably deal with it every day, and my graduate student will reward you generously. We just need you to accompany our worker in the so-called Promzone while he takes some measurements.</text>		<!-- Sakharov responds and gives a job to protect the scientist in the Industrial Zone -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_3">
		<text>Generous, you say? Well, if the work is truly not difficult, then why not.</text>		<!-- ok -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_4">
		<text>Maybe next time.</text>		<!-- no -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_5">
		<text>Great, thank you in advance. I will write to him that I am sending another person to help, let's hope he will read it. I will arrange a meeting at the exit of the railway tunnel next to the train, good luck!</text>		<!-- Sakharov responds -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_6">
		<text>Goodbye.</text>		<!-- okay -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_1_eco_1">
		<text>Hello, are you the stalker sent by Sakharov? He's been bothering me with his messages.</text>		<!-- scientist greeting -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_eco_2">
		<text>Yes, it's me.</text>		<!-- okay -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_eco_3">
		<text>Alright, I hope you won't act like the previous one. Sakharov said that there weren't enough people and started hiring anyone for lower priority tasks. One of the "escorts" ended up with me, a stalker just like you, no offense. We went out a few days ago and everything seemed fine, we reached the Freedom base without any incidents and spent the night there. When I woke up in the morning, he was gone, along with almost all of my belongings! I asked around, but no one saw anything or knows anything, as usual around here. The only things he didn't touch were the measurement device and the pistol, so thanks for that. I wrote to Sakharov, and he started assuring me that I can handle it on my own. I got angry and stopped responding to him. I had some money in my pockets to stay at the base for a while.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_eco_4">
		<text>Sakharov promised that when we finish, you will give a "generous" reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_eco_5">
		<text>I have nothing left except for small change, but I'm sure that when you return to Sakharov, he will easily pay you. He's a man of means, but money is not the most important thing for him.</text>		<!-- response about the reward -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_eco_6">
		<text>Oh well, tell me what needs to be done.</text>		<!-- question about the task -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_eco_7">
		<text>Nothing special, I need to take measurements at three points around the factory area, you just cover me.</text>		<!-- task response -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_eco_8">
		<text>Sounds really easy, alright, let's go.</text>		<!-- okay -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_1_eco_9">
		<text>Have you finished your measurements?</text>		<!-- question about measurements -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_eco_10">
		<text>Yes, I have finished. I will now send everything to Sakharov, inform him about your help, and ask for payment. You can return to him, I still have something to do here nearby.</text>		<!-- answer about measurements -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_eco_11">
		<text>Okay, bye for now.</text>		<!-- okay bye -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_7">
		<text>Did you receive your measurements from the Promzone?</text>		<!-- I'm back -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_8">
		<text>Yes, I received a message from my assistant and I understand that everything went well? Well, that's good. While you were on your way, the measurements were almost processed. It seems that I was mistaken about their insignificance...</text>		<!-- Sakharov's response -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_9">
		<text>I'm very glad, so what about my reward?</text>		<!-- question about the reward -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_10">
		<text>What reward? Ah, yes, one moment. Here, I think this will be enough.\n
		\nWhile you were here, you showed yourself in a good light, my graduate student praised you very much in his message, although it seemed to me that he was just glad to finish this experiment, anyway, it doesn't matter, maybe you agree to help us in future research of the new area?</text>		<!-- answer about the reward and question about a new task-->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_11">
		<text>Do you need to measure something else at the Promzone?</text>		<!-- more work? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_12">
		<text>Not quite, scientific work requires a more careful approach, new research, data comparisons, and much more. After obtaining the initial measurements and realizing the importance of this work, I am now ready to allocate more of my people to it. From you, however, it will be required to perform a slightly different type of work, more, so to speak, closer to you. I promise to provide equally good compensation in the future. Besides, haven't you also become interested?</text>		<!-- question about a new task -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_13_1">
		<text>Not really, but "good compensation" sounds tempting, tell me more.</text>		<!-- answer about a new task 1 -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_13_2">
		<text>No, thank you, but I will think about it.</text>		<!-- answer about a new task 2 -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_14">
		<text>Everyone has their own motives, I understand. Well, I'll try to explain in a few words what we got from the results of the Promzone and what we need from you. As far as I know, your colleagues, that is, stalkers, have already been to almost every corner of this location. Therefore, there are no "brain scorchers" as you call them, or at least they are not active. But our measurements say otherwise, which means that either our data is incorrect, which is unlikely, or there is a ray emission, but of a completely different nature. I have long believed that ray emission can be diverse, but we have had no examples to confirm my hypothesis. If I am right, then we have just come across this very example!\n
		\nIt's too early to talk about anything yet, we don't have enough data on it for comparison and further analysis. But I think I know where to look. As you know, stalkers come to us from time to time for part-time work, one of them was familiar with our cook even outside the perimeter of the Zone and after a few glasses for the meeting, he told about another stalker who celebrated his birthday in the Bar. He, in a state of alcoholic intoxication, began to complain to everyone about how he found secret documents in one of the basements of the Promzone and how he risked his life for this, but not a single merchant wanted to buy them for the amount he needed. I don't understand why he didn't come to us, although then most likely we wouldn't have considered these documents something important... In general, this is not much and may be just rumors, but at the moment this is the only clue that can bring us closer to understanding this radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_15">
		<text>Are you indebted to vodka for all your research?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_16">
		<text>In what sense? Oh, no. Although, to be honest, it applies to a significant portion of them. Let's get back to business. If you want to verify the information, it's best to start with Bar itself. Please try to find out if these documents exist and, if so, locate them. Even if there's a small chance that they contain the information I need, we must try. It could be a milestone in the history of science!</text>		<!-- proceed to the next task -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_1_sakharov_17">
		<text>Alright, I understand. I'll try to find out something. Goodbye.</text>		<!-- leave -->
	</string>


	<!-- ---------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- //////////////////////// Task 2 //////////////////////// -->
	<!-- ---------------------------------------- -->
	<string id="st_redemption_2_barman_1">
		<text>Did anyone here recently celebrate their birthday by any chance?</text>		<!-- the actor asks about the stalker -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_barman_2">
		<text>There was one, I think his name was Hare. Why do you ask?</text>		<!-- the bartender responds -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_barman_3">
		<text>Well, I'm his friend. We used to wander around the Zone together for a while. He received some important news from the other side, but they can't reach him and asked me to find him. The stalkers said they last saw him here.</text>		<!-- boldly lies -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_barman_4">
		<text>Well, I won't be able to help you much with that anyway. He came in seeming cheerful, treated many people, and told me he found some important documents. I skimmed through them a bit while everyone was drinking, compared them to my orders, and told him that his papers were not needed by anyone, but added that I was willing to buy them for a small amount. He started yelling about how difficult it was for him to obtain these documents and that someone was trying to rip him off, so my security guard had to throw him out along with his scribbles.\n
		\nRumor has it that he left towards the Garbage the next morning. We haven't seen him here since. He probably went to try and sell them to someone else.</text>		<!-- the bartender tells what he knows -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_barman_5">
		<text>Understood, thank you and that's it.</text>		<!-- okay, bye -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_barman_6">
		<text>Wait, are you planning to search for him throughout the Zone? It's like looking for a needle in a haystack. How about you do something for me instead, while I ask around my acquaintances? Let's consider it payment for their concern, I promise we'll find your friend, and the task is not difficult.</text>		<!-- oh no, wait -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_barman_7">
		<text>Not difficult you say? Alright, tell me what needs to be done.</text>		<!-- question about the task -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_barman_8">
		<text>Just without unnecessary questions, okay? We're running low on alcohol, and the next delivery won't be for another week. I managed to arrange with someone to sell me a crate, but these people can't come to the Bar. Everything has already been paid for, you just need to meet them at the Truck Cemetery, pick up the goods, and bring them to me. I'll tell you upfront, the crate is heavy.</text>		<!-- answer about the task -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_barman_9">
		<text>Sounds a bit shady, but alright.</text>		<!-- okay, I'll do it -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_2_bandit_1">
		<text>Come for a box of vodka?</text>		<!-- The bandit asks if it's us -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_bandit_2">
		<text>Yes.</text>		<!-- Yes -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_bandit_3">
		<text>And where is the money?</text>		<!-- And where is the money? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_bandit_4">
		<text>What money?</text>		<!-- What money? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_bandit_5">
		<text>What do you mean "what money"? Did you mistake me for a sucker or are you expecting some charity here?</text>		<!-- expressing indignation -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_bandit_6">
		<text>The bartender said it's already paid for. Maybe you should check with your people?</text>		<!-- the bartender said it's already paid for -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_bandit_7">
		<text>Hold on, just stay put and don't move, or I'll get nervous, got it?\n
		\n Hmm, yeah, the boss said it's all covered. Alright, here's the box, you can leave while I'm feeling generous.</text>		<!-- giving the box -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_bandit_8">
		<text>[Leave]</text>		<!-- leave -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_2_barman_10">
		<text>Here's your crate of drinks, heavy.</text>		<!-- brought vodka -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_barman_11">
		<text>Didn't strain yourself? Thanks. Take one bottle, drink with a friend, we just found him. I asked around and people say they saw your Hare in the Cordon, he's sitting in the rookie village.</text>		<!-- thanks here's your stalker -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_barman_12">
		<text>Alright, thanks.</text>		<!-- bye -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_1">
		<text>Hey, is that you, Hare?</text>		<!-- hey hare -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_1_1">
		<text>What about the documents?</text>		<!-- what about the documents? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_2">
		<text>Suppose I am, who are you?</text>		<!-- who are you -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_3">
		<text>I'm here about the documents you're trying to get everyone to submit.</text>		<!-- I'm here about the documents -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_4">
		<text>And why do you need them? You don't look like a trader or an egghead. Well, okay, give me a million and they're yours.</text>		<!-- give me a million -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_5">
		<text>Did you drink too much? Didn't the Bartender tell you how much they're really worth?</text>		<!-- did you drink too much? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_6">
		<text>You can't even imagine where I've been and what I've been through to get them. I lost a friend there and barely made it out myself!</text>		<!-- talking nonsense -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_7">
		<text>I guess Sidorovich didn't need your documents either? If these two didn't want to take them, then the rest won't need them either.</text>		<!-- trying to convince -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_8">
		<text>How would you know? The Clear Sky guys will take it, they sometimes deal with scientific nonsense and communicate with scientists. As a last resort, I'll go to Sakharov, he'll definitely pay whatever I say.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_9">
		<text>I just came from Yantar, exactly on Sakharov's order, and believe me, new territories are "of the lowest priority" for them right now. Or do you think they hire random stalkers for important missions? You can, of course, go around half of the Zone with mutants and anomalies if you want, but it won't bring you any more benefits. I suggest you solve everything right here and not go anywhere, just name a reasonable price.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_10">
		<text>Hmm, let me think for a second.\n
		\nLet's say 15... no, 20 thousand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_11">
		<text>Even Sakharov wouldn't give 20 thousand for this. Let's do 15, I'll have to pay extra from my own anyway, and also go back.</text>		<!-- let's do 15 -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_12">
		<text>Alright, 15 thousand.</text>		<!-- okay -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_13_1">
		<text>Here's your money.</text>		<!-- pay -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_13_2">
		<text>I'll be back soon with the money.</text>		<!-- I'll be back soon -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_14">
		<text>I only have copies of a few pages from there with me as an example for the traders. The actual documents are hidden at the Garbage right behind the hangar. There will be a van there, and the documents are under the passenger seat. You still going back that way. There are many ears here, you know, and many people are itching to get their hands on them.\n
		\nI... I guess I lied a little about where I found them, and also about my friend who I lost, heh. Well, I did find them on the outskirts of the Promzone, at a gas station. We were sitting in a bar and one of our buddies from the group shared with us how to get to the Promzone. So in the morning, I decided to explore a bit, you know, new places are interesting, and maybe I'll find something along the way. I passed by the Truck Cemetery, where there's hardly ever any living creatures around. Eventually, I arrived at the gas station in the Promzone, checked out a few cars, rummaged through the glove compartment of one sedan, and found these documents. Then I heard a barking nearby and decided it was time to head back.\n
		\nBut I can feel that there is some important information in these documents and they were worth my money.</text>		<!-- He is asking where the documents are. -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_hare_15">
		<text>Not very convincing, but I hope it's true for your own good, I hope the documents will be at the Garbage exactly where you said.</text>		<!-- we're leaving -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_2_sakharov_1">
		<text>I brought your documents from the Promzone, professor.</text>		<!-- brought the documents -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_sakharov_2">
		<text>Wonderful! I never doubted your talents for a second. And how did it go?</text>		<!-- and how did it go -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_sakharov_3">
		<text>I had to run around, carry some boxes, but overall everything went as usual. Here are the documents... By the way, I had to buy them back from that stalker for my own 20,000.</text>		<!-- handing over the documents -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_sakharov_4">
		<text>Ah, I understood you perfectly, just a second. Where did I have them... Here, it's 20000 for the documents and some on top of that for your brilliant work, thank you again for your help.\n
		\nLet's take a look at these documents... Hmm... Interesting... Most of the damaged pages are probably lost forever, but I think some can still be restored. Give me a couple of hours to study these materials, and maybe I'll find more work for you. You can take a break here for now.</text>		<!-- give awards -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_2_sakharov_5">
		<text>Okay.</text>		<!-- okay for now -->
	</string>


	<!-- ---------------------------------------- -->
	<!-- //////////////////////// Task 3 //////////////////////// -->
	<!-- ---------------------------------------- -->
	<string id="st_redemption_3_sakharov_1">
		<text>So how are the documents? Did you find out anything about this ray emission of yours?</text>		<!-- So how are the documents? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_sakharov_2">
		<text>To be honest, we didn't learn much about it. Most of the pages are damaged, and the remaining ones cannot be put together into a coherent picture. It seems to be a diary of a radio technician intern, full of physics problem solutions for undergraduates, many of which are incorrect, as well as road maps: routes, hotels, and so on.</text>		<!-- It's nonsense, not documents -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_sakharov_3">
		<text>So, was all of this in vain?</text>		<!-- All in vain? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_sakharov_4">
		<text>Not entirely, there is a small connection. He often mentions people who, in his opinion, were from the special services. They would constantly come to his workplace for checks and meticulously inspect the lower premises, which seemed quite strange to him. I suspect he is referring to the radar station at Promzone.\n
		\nWhile you were looking for this document, we were not sitting idle either. I sent several groups with advanced devices to make more accurate measurements at all the key points in this area. Almost all the groups were able to place the devices in the designated points and return safely, except for one. We don't know what happened to them and we can't establish contact with them.</text> <!-- A story about groups -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_sakharov_5">
		<text>And what does this have to do with a student's diary?</text>		<!-- How is this related? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_sakharov_6">
		<text>The task of this group was precisely to install devices at the radar station. I believed that the greatest surge of this emission would come from the factory, but it turned out that the data obtained from these coordinates say the opposite. I suppose that the station itself is the epicenter, but we need to make sure of this first.\n
		\nNot much time has passed since our research groups returned, and I still need their help in analyzing the data. Perhaps the last group simply encountered some difficulties and will arrive a little later, this happens sometimes. But I would like to know for sure that the device is installed... Yes, that my employees are safe and unharmed too, of course.\n
		\nBy finding the documents, you once again proved yourself to be a talented specialist... In a certain field, of course. That's why I would really not like to end our cooperation.</text>		<!-- story about group 2 -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_sakharov_7">
		<text>So what is required of me? Just go and see if your device is worth it and look for scientists nearby?</text>		<!-- What is required of me? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_sakharov_8">
		<text>Some basic scientific knowledge is required for this job, but thanks to the data already obtained from other devices, I will now be able to easily adjust the most basic parameters on site, and adjust the rest remotely after installation.\n
		\nI will give you a new device and all you will need to do is install it in the radio room at the very top. Just don't press anything on it, except for this big button when you install it.\n
		\nThe device is expensive and I can only trust it to you personally, so please, to avoid any incidents, perform this task alone.</text>		<!-- tells about the task -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_sakharov_9">
		<text>Okay, give me your device.</text>		<!-- agree -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_sakharov_10">
		<text>Here you go. And also, if the device is already there, just come back and I'll still pay you. But if it's not, besides installing yours, try to find the old one and return it to me, I'll pay you extra for that, as well as for my missing employees. And if they show up before you reach the station, I'll contact you.</text>		<!-- gives a task -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_sakharov_11">
		<text>Good.</text>		<!-- leaving -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_3_ecos_1">
		<text>Professor, I found the bodies of your scientists at the station.</text>		<!-- found ecologists -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_ecos_2">
		<text>Impo... ... ...tall the devi... ...</text>		<!-- install the device -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_ecos_3">
		<text>Professor...?</text>		<!-- ... -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_3_news_1">
		<text>Can you hear me? I've installed the device, check it.</text>		<!-- installed the device -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_news_2">
		<text>Inte... ... ...rfer... ... ...exit the territory of the sta... ...</text>		<!-- interference -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_3_hare_1">
		<text>Oh, great to see you again. What are you doing here?</text>		<!-- oh great, you're here too? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_hare_2">
		<text>I'm still running errands for the scientists, and you?</text>		<!-- on their orders, and you? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_hare_3">
		<text>I thought this time I would go a little further, maybe I'll find some more documents while the area is not fully explored. Hey, do the scientists have any more work by any chance? Yours doesn't seem too dusty, that's just what I like.</text>		<!-- decided to look for documents, is there any work? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_hare_4">
		<text>No idea, go to Yantar and ask yourself, maybe there will be something.</text>		<!-- idk, maybe -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_hare_5">
		<text>Alright, after I search here for a b... Wait, who is this?</text>		<!-- and who is this -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_hare_6">
		<text>Where?</text>		<!-- where... -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_3_monolith_news_1">
		<text>Brother Vakhar, it's not him again.</text>		<!-- he's not here -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_monolith_news_2">
		<text>Finish off the infidels and let's keep searching.</text>		<!-- finish them off -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_news_1">
		<text>Are you awake? Don't get up yet.</text>		<!-- are you awake? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_news_2">
		<text>You.. who..?</text>		<!-- who are you? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_news_3">
		<text>According to the token, my name is Illeon.</text>		<!-- my name is Illeon -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_news_4">
		<text>T... token...?</text>		<!-- token? -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_1">
		<text>How are you feeling?</text>		<!-- How are you? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_2">
		<text>My whole body hurts...</text>		<!-- Everything hurts -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_3">
		<text>No wonder it hurts, you looked like a sieve when I dragged you here.</text>		<!-- No wonder -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_4">
		<text>Where is here? And why are you wearing their uniform? Who are you anyway?</text>		<!-- Who are you? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_5">
		<text>We're in a collapsed tunnel, in the east. You've been lying here for almost two days. My name is Illeon... At least, I think so. As for the uniform, I have no idea.</text>		<!-- Illeon -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_6">
		<text>Seems like? Don't know?</text>		<!-- seems like? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_7">
		<text>You don't look very good, although you were very lucky. Everything heals quickly here and I had some good medicine with me, but it's still better for you to rest some more.</text>		<!-- rest some more -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_8">
		<text>I'm fine, just tell me what the hell was that and who are you?</text>		<!-- I'm fine, who are you? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_9">
		<text>Most likely they were following you, just like they were following those scientists. And as for who I am... The thing is, I don't remember.</text>		<!-- I don't remember -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_10">
		<text>What do you mean you don't remember?</text>		<!-- what do you mean -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_11">
		<text>The last thing I remember is walking along the road, somewhere in the middle of this area. And then... it's like I woke up... And everything before that just disappeared from my memory.\n
		\nIt was about a week ago, before that no memories, just fragments that I can't connect together.</text>		<!-- talking about what he remembers -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_12">
		<text>But you remember how to shoot?</text>		<!-- do you remember how to shoot? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_13">
		<text>Yes, some skills and general abilities remained. My hands seem to remember what to do on their own. The same goes for speech.</text>		<!-- skills remained -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_14">
		<text>Do you know where exactly you are or at least what year it is now?</text>		<!-- what year -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_15">
		<text>Approximately... When I see or hear something familiar, I can sometimes remember it. The mutants around, for example, helped me remember where I am almost immediately, otherwise I would have ended up in some anomaly.\n
		\nBut I don't remember the whole area, only a few locations, and even those not exactly.</text>		<!-- approximately -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_16">
		<text>And looking at your form, does nothing come to mind?</text>		<!-- and form -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_17">
		<text>Just now, it's the uniform of the "Monolith" group, who apparently are looking for me. Nothing more from this. The first time I met them was a few days after... well, waking up.\n
		\nAt first, I was sitting in the basement of the station where they attacked you. I had supplies with me, so I didn't have to go out much. I thought maybe something would become clear during this time, so I only went out a couple of times to look around.</text>		<!-- monolith -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_18">
		<text>[continue...]</text>		<!-- continued -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_19">
		<text>Then I heard people outside, but I decided not to show myself to them and instead follow them when they leave. I could hear a lot from below through a hole in the floor. They started inspecting the station and kept complaining about some professor, and a few minutes later I heard gunshots and screams.\n
		\nAfter that, I heard one of the attackers asking the wounded person about how to turn something off. His voice seemed familiar to me, but I couldn't remember. The wounded person just screamed in pain and said he didn't know anything, that he was just a guard. They shot him almost immediately. Then the attackers mentioned a couple of phrases, mentioned the name Illeon, and I realized that besides everything else, they are also looking for me.</text>		<!-- story about scientists -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_20">
		<text>What happened next?</text>		<!-- And what happened next? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_21">
		<text>Nothing... The group that killed those people left. I decided that they couldn't have appeared a few minutes after the arrival of the first ones and most likely were following them or lying in ambush. So I waited until night and decided to look for a more inconspicuous place. This one turned out to be just right.</text>		<!-- I left -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_22">
		<text>Then why did you go back there when you saved me? By the way, thanks for that, I never got a chance to thank you.</text>		<!-- How did you end up there again? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_23">
		<text>I was following the stalker, but not to rob or kill him, I'm not a thief or a maniac like those from the station. I wanted to observe... I don't know, what kind of person he is, if he can be trusted. It's just a pity that I didn't have time to save him, everything happened too quickly...</text>		<!-- I was following -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_24">
		<text>And why do you need some stalker?</text>		<!-- Why do you need a stalker? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_25">
		<text>Do you know why I'm still here? I have no idea who can be trusted and who can't. Where to go and how to go. I don't even remember all these factions of yours, so you approach someone and when you realize who it is, it's already too late. I need a guide.</text>		<!-- I need a guide -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_26">
		<text>A guide? Where exactly?</text>		<!-- Where -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_27">
		<text>Seeing the body of one of those people, I vaguely remembered that there are scientists here somewhere. If anyone can help me, I think it's only them.</text>		<!-- to the scientists -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_28">
		<text>And that's why you saved me?</text>		<!-- And that's why? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_29">
		<text>Not only because of that... So, will you help?</text>		<!-- No, will you help? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_30">
		<text>I think taking you to Yantar is the least I can do in exchange for saving your life.</text>		<!-- yes -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_31">
		<text>Thank you. After seeing what those people did to you and those scientists, I thought it would be best not to wear their group's uniform. That's why I took the suit off your acquaintance. I wouldn't normally rob dead people, but I didn't have any other choice.</text>		<!-- suit -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_32">
		<text>It's normal here. A dead person won't need it anymore, and in your uniform, we won't be able to walk past other stalkers for even a hundred meters.</text>		<!-- yes, let's go -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_33">
		<text>I'll change clothes, bring your things, and we can go.</text>		<!-- I'll change clothes -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_34">
		<text>Okay.</text>		<!-- ok -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_stalker_1">
		<text>Here are your things. By the way, did those Monolith guys say anything?</text>		<!-- here are the things -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_stalker_2">
		<text>I don't think so... Although, they called their leader Vakhar.</text>		<!-- vakhar -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_stalker_3">
		<text>Vakhar...\n
		\nRemembering the voice I heard at the station, along with his name, something starts to come up in my memory. The "Monolith" has intelligence, sometimes they send small groups deep into the Zone, Vakhar is the head of their intelligence.\n
		\nThe mindset of high-ranking soldiers in the faction is slightly different from regular foot soldiers. They don't blindly run into bullets, they calculate their chances and know when to retreat. At first, I wanted to catch up with him and end it all, but then I saw that you were still alive. Besides, others will come to take his place anyway...</text>		<!-- remembering -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_stalker_4">
		<text>It's quite strange to know such details about these fanatics. I would say that you are one of them, but you seem rational, and there are definitely no rational ones among them. I still don't understand anything.</text>		<!-- strange -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_stalker_5">
		<text>Just like me, that's why we need to reach your scientists.</text>		<!-- just like me -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_illeon_stalker_6">
		<text>Alright, let's go.</text>		<!-- let's go -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_1">
		<text>There is someone here who wants to talk to you.</text>		<!-- brought a person -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_2">
		<text>Ah, there you are. I was starting to find it strange that you haven't been in touch for so long and haven't returned for payment. Judging by your appearance, it seems like you've encountered some difficulties?</text>		<!-- where were you -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_3">
		<text>Difficulties? They almost killed me there! I barely had time to leave the station and got caught in a hail of gunfire from the Monolith who appeared from around the corner. It seems like they also wiped out your scientists before that. I don't feel like going back there anymore.</text>		<!-- ambush -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_4">
		<text>That's really unfortunate to hear...\n
		\nHmm, you say it was the "Monolith" group? It's curious what their interests could be in this area. As far as I know, the northern passage is completely blocked by anomalous fields, which means they must have passed through the Red Forest and the Army Warehouses.\n
		\nThank you for the information. From now on, I'll send combined groups of the most experienced hired workers there... Wait, so they just wounded you and left?</text>		<!-- how did you get out -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_5">
		<text>No, I was saved by this stalker here. He took out most of their squad and then I woke up with patched up wounds in a nearby tunnel. He says he needs to see you because he doesn't remember anything.</text>		<!-- here's the person -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_6">
		<text>But we're physicists, not neurologists, and we already have plenty of work as it is. It's better to consult someone else for cases of amnesia.</text>		<!-- we're physicists -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_7">
		<text>When he met me, he was wearing a Monolith suit. And on the way, he remembered details that an ordinary stalker wouldn't know. Just talk to him.</text>		<!-- insisting -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_8">
		<text>Alright, as a sign of your merits to the scientific community, I'll make an exception this time.</text>		<!-- alright -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_9">
		<text>Thank you.</text>		<!-- thanks -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_10">
		<text>By the way, if you're interested, the device you installed is working properly. Now we're receiving data on ray emission from all points. The radar, as expected, shows the highest spikes of emission. We just need to carefully study the data and maybe do a more thorough check of the station, but this time my most experienced employees will take care of that.</text>		<!-- station story -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_11">
		<text>I don't want to know anything more about this station.</text>		<!-- not interested -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_12">
		<text>I understand, well then, here's your reward for installing the device. As promised, with an additional payment for my employees who were found, even though they died, but now we know what happened to them. And I assume you didn't find their device? Well, never mind... I'll also compensate you for the damage you suffered during the mission.\n
		\nI'll finish up with something quickly and then examine your comrade. It wouldn't hurt for you to rest as well. If you're interested in the results, come see me in a day.</text>		<!-- reward -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_13">
		<text>Alright.</text>		<!-- leaving -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_1_1">
		<text>I have installed your device.</text>		<!-- installed the device -->
	</string>
	<!-- st_redemption_3_yantar_2 -->
	<!-- st_redemption_3_yantar_3 -->
	<!-- st_redemption_3_yantar_4 -->
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_5_1">
		<text>No, I was saved by a stalker. He shot most of their squad, and then I woke up with patched wounds in a nearby tunnel. He said he needed to meet with you, but he was killed on the way.</text>		<!-- the person died -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_6_1">
		<text>Also killed? Too bad, maybe he could shed some light on the situation...\n
		\nBy the way, if you're interested, the device you installed is working fine. Now we are receiving data on radiation from all points. The radar, as expected, shows the highest radiation spikes. We just need to carefully study the data and possibly thoroughly check the station itself, but this time my most experienced employees will take care of it.</text>		<!-- too bad, story about the station -->
	</string>
	<!-- st_redemption_3_yantar_11 -->
	<string id="st_redemption_3_yantar_12_1">
		<text>I understand, well then here is your reward for installing the device. As promised, with an additional payment for my lost employees, even though they died, but now we know what happened to them. And I assume you didn't find their device? Well, never mind... I will also compensate you for the damage you suffered during the mission.\n
		\nI think our cooperation has come to an end, thank you once again for your help.</text>		<!-- reward -->
	</string>
	<!-- st_redemption_3_yantar_13 -->

	<string id="st_redemption_4_sakharov_1">
		<text>How is that stalker doing? Has he regained his memory?</text>		<!-- checked the person? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sakharov_2">
		<text>Partially, we took some tests, conducted a small examination, and did a few tests. It turned out to be a truly unique case. This person couldn't remember a single detail about life beyond the Zone perimeter, but when we mentioned almost all artifacts, he was able to list all their known properties!\n
		\nWe found it quite strange that he was able to remember the specifics not only of most of the factions surrounding us, but also of the "Monolith" faction in particular, as you mentioned. I believe his information will also help us in our current research.\n
		\nIt's still too early to draw any conclusions, a series of additional tests is needed, and I have just ordered the necessary equipment for them.</text>		<!-- yes -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sakharov_3">
		<text>So should I come back later?</text>		<!-- come back later? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sakharov_4">
		<text>I thought you said you had enough of it last time?</text>		<!-- not enough for you? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sakharov_5">
		<text>Well, I'm definitely not going to run around the Promzone with your devices while there are crazy fanatics roaming around. Honestly, I'm just curious about what all this means.</text>		<!-- just curious -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sakharov_6">
		<text>Scientific curiosity? That's good, but unfortunately, finding answers to these questions will take some time. I don't know exactly how long, it depends on the delivery dates of the equipment, which can vary from time to time.\n
		\nIf you're interested, I have sent some data to my superiors and managed to secure a grant for researching this radiation. Our employees are excellent specialists in their field, but when it comes to completing tasks that are closer to regular stalkers, the results are not always successful. That's why I often have to hire other people, and with the help of this grant, I was able to hire someone known to you as Barman, to search for any information related to our research.\n
		\nSo, if you're interested, you can join the search. I have no doubt that your help will expedite the whole process. The payment will come from us, so you can expect a corresponding reward.</text>		<!-- go to Barman -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sakharov_7_1">
		<text>Okay, I'll go to him.</text>		<!-- taking the task -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sakharov_7_2">
		<text>No, for now that's enough for me, but I'll think about it.</text>		<!-- maybe later -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_1">
		<text>Sakharov said you have a job?</text>		<!-- I heard from Sakharov -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_2">
		<text>Yes, I do. By the way, did you find your friend?</text>		<!-- found a friend? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_3">
		<text>Found him, his fanatics killed him at the Promzone.</text>		<!-- killed him -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_4">
		<text>Yeah... That's life in the Zone, it feels like we just saw each other recently, and a week later the person is gone. I've been hearing rumors that monolithians have been seen more often in this area too.</text>		<!-- that's life -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_5">
		<text>So, what about the job?</text>		<!-- what about the job -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_6">
		<text>You don't seem too upset. Well, life goes on.\n
		\nSakharov ordered me to gather information about any mention of research or radiation related to the Promzone. He allocated quite a bit of money, so I've already assigned several groups of stalkers. I can find something similar for you too.</text>		<!-- yes -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_7">
		<text>Tell me.</text>		<!-- let's hear it -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_8">
		<text>So, from what I know, many people have already been to the Promzone, some just to look around, some to search for something in the far corners. I think everything that was lying around has already been taken, because Sakharov said that his people couldn't find much. I hear rumors about some findings, and we are checking them. The remaining places to check are not pleasant.\n
		\nYou will need to go to the Dark Valley. A source told me that some of the records from the Promzone are located at the bandits' base.</text>		<!-- story about the task -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_9">
		<text>And I just knock and say, "hello, I'm here for the documents"?</text>		<!-- and how -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_10">
		<text>Something like that, yes. But I have already made a deal with their leader, just don't spread the word about it. I will let them know what you look like and they will let you in. Then Sultan will simply give you the documents and that's it.\n
		\nBut there are two conditions. First - you will be alone. And second - you must arrive at the Dark Valley without any weapons, leave knives and grenades as well. If they notice a weapon in your hands or sticking out of your backpack, they will shoot.</text>		<!-- they will let you in -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_11">
		<text>How am I supposed to get there without any weapons?</text>		<!-- and how -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_12">
		<text>However you want, use your wits. If you don't have any wits, just run.\n
		\nAnd one more thing, my contact informed me that for a sum of 4000, he is willing to tell us some details that might interest us. Sultan seems unpredictable to me, you can expect anything from him, so it would be good to have a backup plan. But I won't pay myself, it's up to you to decide.</text>		<!-- offer to pay -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_13_1">
		<text>Alright, here's the money.</text>		<!-- 1 we pay -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_14_1">
		<text>I'll send it to him now, wait a minute...\n
		\nOkay, he received it. He says that the documents are in Sultan's room on the table, but he is always there. On the first floor of the unfinished building, there is a pile of dry firewood that can be set on fire. The building won't burn down, but there will be a lot of smoke and commotion for some time.\n
		\nThat's it, you can get ready.</text>		<!-- 1 we paid, listen -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_13_2">
		<text>I'll manage without the help of your informants.</text>		<!-- 2 I'll manage on my own -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_14_2">
		<text>It's your choice, be careful there.</text>		<!-- 2 as you wish -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_13_3">
		<text>I don't have the money yet, I'll be back later.</text>		<!-- 3 no money -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_15">
		<text>I'm leaving then.</text>		<!-- we're leaving -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_1">
		<text>I'm here for the documents for the Barman.</text>		<!-- I'm here for the documents -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_2">
		<text>Who do we have here? No hello, no please, just "give me the documents". Did you get something wrong?</text>		<!-- what -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_3">
		<text>Barman said that he already arranged everything with you and that I should just come and pick them up.</text>		<!-- we agreed -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_4">
		<text>Just come? Well, let him come here and pick them up himself. Who are you anyway?</text>		<!-- who are you -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_5">
		<text>...</text>		<!-- ... -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_6">
		<text>Oh, come on, don't be scared, I'm just joking. It's boring here. If you only saw your face right now.\n
		\nI have your papers here on my desk, yeah, we took them from a couple of suckers recently. Well, listen, there are mutants running wild in the west, you'll have to kill them, then come back and get your documents... If I'm in a good mood.</text>		<!-- go kill mutants -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_7">
		<text>More jokes? Do I have to go and beat them up with my bare hands?</text>		<!-- more jokes? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_8">
		<text>Do I look like I'm joking? Alright, I'll give you some knife. We agreed that we'll let you pass through, and will talk about your scientific stuff, so here we are talking, while we have mutants multiplying and bothering us.</text>		<!-- I'm not joking -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_9">
		<text>Didn't the Barman pay you enough? Think about what's more profitable, betraying him now or milking him constantly?</text>		<!-- think -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_10">
		<text>Well, he did give me a good discount... Alright, let's see how it goes.\n
		\nBut I'm dying of boredom here anyway. Let's make it simpler, have you seen the movie Gladiator? We have a couple of cameras in the basement and we caught some zombies, we'll take your stuff for a while, lock up the basement, give you a knife, and you'll fight against them, hehe. And then we'll watch this movie with popcorn with the whole gang. Once you kill them, I'll give you your stuff and that folder too, my promise as a man.</text>		<!-- let's fight -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_11_1">
		<text>... Alright, I agree to fight. Let's just get this over with.</text>		<!-- alright -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_12_1">
		<text>That's a talk. Too bad we don't have that gladiator armor, that would be a spectacle.</text>		<!-- different story -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_13_1">
		<text>Lead your zombies already.</text>		<!-- Russell Crowe begins -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_11_2">
		<text>Am I a clown in a circus or something? I didn't come here to entertain you.</text>		<!-- clown or something -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_12_2">
		<text>Hey, don't talk back to me, got it? If you don't want to, then just leave while I'm still in a good mood.</text>		<!-- just leave -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_13_2">
		<text>[Leave]</text>		<!-- leave -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_zombies_1">
		<text>I've killed your zombies.</text>		<!-- killed zombies -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_zombies_2">
		<text>That was a great show, haha! I bet it turned out a hundred times better than those cops at the Bar. Well done, you entertained everyone, the guys even fell off their chairs.\n
		\nHere are your documents on the table, you've earned them. Take them and you can leave.</text>		<!-- gives documents -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_zombies_3">
		<text>[Leave]</text>		<!-- leave -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_news_1">
		<text>What's with the smoke? Hey, you, stand at the entrance and don't let anyone in, I'll deal with these idiots.</text>		<!-- stand here and don't let anyone in -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_news_2">
		<text>What's going on here, you idiots, fell asleep with a cigarette again?</text>		<!-- what's going on here -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_news_3">
		<text>Sultan, the room is on fire!</text>		<!-- the room is on fire -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_news_4">
		<text>Put it out! Make sure it doesn't spread to the storeroom.</text>		<!-- put it out -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_news_5">
		<text>This stalker was just here.</text>		<!-- a stalker was here -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_sultan_news_6">
		<text>Find that rat! Tell everyone to chase him away.</text>		<!-- find the rat -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_1">
		<text>Brought Sakharov's documents.</text>		<!-- brought the docs -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_2">
		<text>Knew you would handle it. Did everything go smoothly?</text>		<!-- how did it go -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_3">
		<text>Not very smoothly, but it could have been worse. Sultan doesn't seem like a reliable business partner to me, I must say.</text>		<!-- meh -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_4">
		<text>The benefits of such relationships sometimes outweigh the risks.\n
		\nGive me your folder, I'll give you the payment. Let's see... Yes, it seems to be what Sakharov asked for, here's your reward for the job. I'll send it to them, let them study it there.</text>		<!-- here's the reward -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_5">
		<text>Any news from Yantar?</text>		<!-- any news -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_6">
		<text>No, it's still too early for news. He asked to first retrieve all possible records. By the way, two more groups of stalkers that I sent on a search mission have returned before you. One of them brought documents similar to yours, but only one person returned from the second group, and with bad news.\n
		\nAlthough there were newcomers in the second group, the job didn't seem to be particularly difficult. They just needed to meet a Clear Sky member at Agroprom, who would hand them the documents. They were supposed to meet on a hill near the entrance to the Garbage, where there aren't many mutants. So, the member handed them the documents, but as they were descending the hill, a bloodsucker attacked them in broad daylight.</text>		<!-- bloodsucker -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_7">
		<text>[continue...]</text>		<!-- continued -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_8">
		<text>The returning stalker said that the bloodsucker threw him first, and he rolled down the hill. The second friend froze in fear. The third one was less lucky, the creature tore his chest apart with one strike, then knocked him down and dragged him across the road like a sack.\n
		\nThe stalker said that it took him another two minutes to understand what had happened. When he came to his senses, he panicked and ran away. What happened to the second person is still unknown. In short, the one who was dragged away by the bloodsucker had the documents. I'm ready to bet my bar that he settled in the nearby tunnel and is hunting our young ones who pass by.</text>		<!-- bloodsucker 2 -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_9">
		<text>[continue...]</text>		<!-- continued -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_10">
		<text>It's better to avoid bloodsuckers, who knows how many of them are there. I was planning to organize a more serious squad later, but it will take time. If you want, I can give you this task and Sakharov will get his documents faster. I'll even pay you extra from my own pocket for the deceased guy, the main thing is to kill that creature. So, are you in?</text>		<!-- bloodsucker 3 -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_11_1">
		<text>Alright, I'm in.</text>		<!-- continue the mission -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_12_1">
		<text>I'll be waiting.</text>		<!-- okay -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_11_2">
		<text>I'd rather wait, health is more important. There might be a whole nest of these beasts there.</text>		<!-- end the mission -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_12_2">
		<text>I understand, then you'll have to wait for about three days, including the time Sakharov will spend studying them. You can go straight to Yantar, I'll send everything there.</text>		<!-- wait -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_docs_13">
		<text>[Leave]</text>		<!-- leave -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_agro_docs_1">
		<text>Here are the documents from Agroprom.</text>		<!-- brought the docs from agro -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_agro_docs_2">
		<text>Great, Sakharov will be glad that we found everything we could. That newbie asked if you saw his partner there, who stayed behind?</text>		<!-- saw the partner? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_agro_docs_3">
		<text>I saw, both are dead.</text>		<!-- both are dead -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_agro_docs_4">
		<text>That's it... The search turned out to be not as easy as I expected.\n
		\nGive me your folder, I'll give you a reward. I think Sakharov will be satisfied for now, but if anything else comes up - I'll send it too. By the way, he asked you to come in.</text>		<!-- too bad -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_4_barman_agro_docs_5">
		<text>Going back to Yantar then.</text>		<!-- for now -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_1">
		<text>Have you studied your documents?</text>		<!-- studied the documents? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_2_1">
		<text>Yes, I managed to study them in general terms. Did the bartender say that you greatly contributed to obtaining them? Thank you for your efforts.</text>		<!-- yes -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_2_2">
		<text>My colleagues will need one more day or less.</text>		<!-- 1 day -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_2_3">
		<text>In the process of studying, come back in a couple of days.</text>		<!-- 2 days -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_2_4">
		<text>Sorry, I'm very busy at the moment. Not all the documents have arrived yet, come back in three days.</text>		<!-- 3 days -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_3">
		<text>So what did you find out?</text>		<!-- and what's there -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_4">
		<text>We found out that the radar is an emitter, but it is controlled from another location, it is still unknown from where exactly. The station itself, apparently, served only as a cover, because we didn't find anything inside that could be somehow related to what was described in the documents. And in the documents themselves, it is mentioned only indirectly, just like the research itself.\n
		\nThanks to the person you brought, we assume that the purpose of this emitter was to suppress the mind control effect. It won't save people who have fallen under the so-called "brain scorcher", the destruction of neural networks is definitely irreversible. But it is quite capable of suppressing implanted programs in an undamaged brain. The neural connections in such a brain are reformatted, but still intact. It seems that the emitter was developed in case the controlled people regain consciousness.</text>		<!-- story about the emitter -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_5">
		<text>So that stalker after all...</text>		<!-- you're hinting -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_6">
		<text>Yes, now I am completely sure - the person you brought was one of the soldiers of the "Monolith" group. Everything indicates that, including numerous tests with new equipment. His identity is gradually being restored, feelings and emotions from the time before being zombified are returning. But remembering is much more difficult, now he can only recall moments after the zombification effect, everything before that is permanently erased from his logical memory. But his mechanical memory is practically untouched.</text>		<!-- I'm not hinting -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_7">
		<text>I think we both knew that, but it was hard for me to make myself believe it. So, what if he remembers how fun it was to shoot stalkers and kills us all here?</text>		<!-- joking again -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_8">
		<text>Don't worry and trust in science, young man. That won't happen, the emitter was developed by top-class specialists and... Well, mathematically, there is always a small chance.</text>		<!-- Sakharov is joking -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_9">
		<text>I don't even know how to take this, as good news or bad...</text>		<!-- what's next -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_10">
		<text>I suppose the northern passage of the factory leads to the Radar and the "Monolith" group managed to find a way through the anomalous fields. But they didn't take into account the emitter directed at this sector... Or your acquaintance was just the first test subject.\n
		\nIn any case, for our common good, we need to prevent this group from finding a way to turn off the emitter.</text>		<!-- don't let Monolith -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_11">
		<text>And how do we do that? Setting up a second barrier there only if, but as you can see, the first one doesn't really help.</text>		<!-- and how -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_12">
		<text>The documents describe various modes of the system, one of them is dispersing the beam's energy over a larger radius. Currently, everything seems to be set in focusing mode, directed only to the north. Measurements have shown that the beam's energy is too high for its current task. If we distribute the energy around the perimeter, there should still be enough to prevent anyone from "Monolith" from trying to enter the Promzone territory.</text>		<!-- distribute -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_13">
		<text>And the documents don't say where exactly the center of this system is?</text>		<!-- where is the center -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_14">
		<text>We need more time to thoroughly study all the documents, maybe there will be an answer there, but I doubt it, the project was strictly classified. Under one of the buildings in the Promzone territory, my employees found an iron door similar to those leading to the laboratories, but they couldn't figure out how to open it. Although there is a whole network of underground communications there, and it is still unknown where this door leads.\n
		\nWe could search for the entrance, but from what I've heard, the area of the factory has already been occupied by numerous "Monolith" squads.</text>		<!-- idk -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_15">
		<text>So what do we do next?</text>		<!-- what's next -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_16">
		<text>We will need help. The bartender said that Duty has been increasingly encountering the Monolith group near their territory as well. It will be in their own interest, I will talk to the bartender and let him know that you will come, and you will try to convince Duty to help us with his help. I apologize for making you go back and forth, but the topic is quite serious and I wouldn't want anyone else to hear about it.\n
		\nBy the way, I have conducted all possible tests on the stalker you brought. It seems to me that the more memories of him return from the time when he was a part of the Monolith group, the more guilt he feels, which has returned to him from an even earlier life.\n
		\nI doubt that I will be able to learn any more useful information from him, and he himself asked to help us. If you want, you can take him with you, he should be by the campfire outside. I also gave him one of our new suits.</text>		<!-- go to Duty -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_17_1">
		<text>Okay, I'll try to talk to Voronin.</text>		<!-- alright -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_sakharov_17_2">
		<text>[Leave]</text>		<!-- leave -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_5_1_illeon_1">
		<text>How are you feeling?</text>		<!-- how are you -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_1_illeon_2">
		<text>Fine, I guess. Talk to Sakharov first, he will explain everything.</text>		<!-- talk to Sakharov -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_1_illeon_3">
		<text>Alright.</text>		<!-- alright -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_5_2_illeon_1">
		<text>How are you feeling?</text>		<!-- how are you -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_2_illeon_2">
		<text>Fine, I guess. Did the professor tell you everything?</text>		<!-- alright -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_2_illeon_3">
		<text>Did you remember anything?</text>		<!-- what did you remember -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_2_illeon_4">
		<text>With the professor's help, a lot... And now I wish I didn't remember it. I understand if you don't want my help, but I still want to join. I feel like I have a lot to fix and a lot to answer for.</text>		<!-- a lot of things -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_2_illeon_5_1">
		<text>Alright, we can go together.</text>		<!-- yes -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_2_illeon_5_2">
		<text>I'm sorry, but I don't think I can trust you right now.</text>		<!-- no -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_1">
		<text>Professor Sakharov asked for your help.</text>		<!-- hello -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_2">
		<text>Barman has already told me everything. How can we help? We don't have enough people, and with each passing day, there are even fewer of them. Almost every patrol sent to the north or east encounters squads of Monolith soldiers. Several squads have settled in the Promzone, and they constantly patrol the area. I definitely don't have enough people for that, and I won't send them there to certain death.</text>		<!-- no people -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_3">
		<text>But this is the only opportunity. If we don't act now, there will be even more of them in the future.</text>		<!-- need to act now -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_4">
		<text>What makes you think that some installation can stop their attacks? According to what Barman told me, all the scientists have are assumptions. They don't even know where this thing is located.</text>		<!-- who knows -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_5">
		<text>We have already seen how it affects them, and so far, all of Sakharov's assumptions have been correct. For now, the Monolith fighters are infiltrating the Promzone in small squads, but if they manage to disable the emitter and open the northern passage, there will be a whole army instead of just a few squads.</text>		<!-- convincing -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_6">
		<text>Even if we decided to do it, as I said, I don't have enough people.</text>		<!-- I told you -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_7">
		<text>We can ask the Freedom faction for help. They need it even more than you do.</text>		<!-- Freedom -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_8">
		<text>Let the fanatics kill them all, I'll be happy about it.</text>		<!-- never -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_9">
		<text>After they kill them, who do you think will be next? You can't even leave the Bar peacefully right now. I suggest only a temporary truce.</text>		<!-- well, let's do it -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_10">
		<text>We... Let me think...\n
		\nThey recently attacked our reconnaissance squad at the Warehouses. They killed one of our men, wounded another, and the last one managed to escape to report it. The wounded one is probably taken captive. I'm willing to negotiate with them, but only if they give me back the captured soldier. If you want, you can try to talk with them about it.</text>		<!-- captive -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_11">
		<text>Looks like I'll have to.</text>		<!-- I'll talk -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_1">
		<text>Have you heard about the Promzone?</text>		<!-- promzone -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_2">
		<text>What exactly? We don't need to hear anything, we can see it all ourselves. Fanatics are rushing there from every crack, shooting at everyone who moves. They used to go through the Red Forest, but those were mostly small reconnaissance groups attacking the Barrier. There are too many mutants and anomalies there. It's much more convenient for them to go in large squads from the Radar. Now they still come in small groups from the forests, but much more often. We simply don't have enough people to constantly control the entire territory, and I still have more wounded every day. I don't know how many of them are already in the Promzone, but I think there are many.</text>		<!-- heard yes -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_3">
		<text>Sakharov thinks that there is a emitter in the Promzone that prevents them from going there directly from the Radar, although there is a passage known only to the Monolithians. The emitter only affects zombified people, it doesn't seem to have any effect on regular stalkers. If they disable this device, they will be able to move freely to the south in large groups.</text>		<!-- convince -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_4">
		<text>An emitter against the fanatics? Like a reverse brain scorcher? That's a useful thing. We just found the plan of the entire factory, including the underground tunnels, when the location was not yet full of these psychos.</text>		<!-- found plan -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_5">
		<text>Does it say where the entrance is?</text>		<!-- where entrance -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_6">
		<text>It's all here. Entrances and exits, there are a couple of entrances to the bunker, but there is no plan of the bunker itself. It's unclear what's inside. Did you want to suggest something?</text>		<!-- wanted to suggest -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_7">
		<text>Yes, someone needs to infiltrate this bunker and reconfigure the emitter so that it covers the entire territory of the Promzone.</text>		<!-- infiltrate -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_8">
		<text>And you and your eggheads know how to do that? Well, thanks for sharing the plans, good luck to you there.</text>		<!-- good luck -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_9">
		<text>Soon everyone will be too busy to joke if no one does it. I asked the Duty guys, they don't have enough people for that. But they are willing to agree to a temporary truce if you agree to help... And return their captive.</text>		<!-- need people -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_10">
		<text>Oh, you're a joker too, I see. Why should we take risks, especially for these idealists? To us, those fanatics are no different from them.</text>		<!-- joker -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_11">
		<text>At least you can talk to them. If the monolithians start passing through the Radar in large crowds, do you think they will just go south and forget about you? You will be surrounded, and it will be impossible to negotiate with them anymore, and I guess you don't have enough people for a couple more new barriers.</text>		<!-- convince -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_12">
		<text>Damn, I don't know... Well, maybe for a while, but we still won't be able to help until we have a good supply of weapons. The mutants have now blocked the road from the Mercs, and all my people are already busy with patrols.\n
		\nIf you can wipe out the mutant lair in the Grimwood near the pond, which constantly attacks our people and prevents them from meeting with the hires, then we can talk.</text>		<!-- mission -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_13">
		<text>Alright, I'll do it.</text>		<!-- leaving -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_14">
		<text>Shot the mutants in Grimwood.</text>		<!-- killed mutants -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_15">
		<text>Oh, finally some good news for a change. Well, tell me what you wanted.</text>		<!-- speak -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_16">
		<text>You will give the Duty their man, then we will meet and discuss how to eliminate the fanatics. After that, we will reconfigure the emitter and everything will go back to normal.</text>		<!-- telling -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_17">
		<text>It sounds simple, but I don't know if we can trust them. We don't even know how many crazies have settled in the Promzone, we didn't count the ones running by. But let's meet them anyway and see what happens.\n
		\nTell them to come to the farmstead, I will send one of my most experienced people to talk to them. We will clear the area so that we don't shoot each other at the slightest noise. I will bring their servant now and you can go.</text>		<!-- okay, let's meet -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_lukash_18">
		<text>Okay, I will pass on the message.</text>		<!-- okay -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_12">
		<text>Brought your soldier.</text>		<!-- brought soldier -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_13">
		<text>Didn't think he was still alive, thanks. What did they say?</text>		<!-- what did they say -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_14">
		<text>They said they are ready to meet and discuss the situation at the farmstead.</text>		<!-- meeting -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_15">
		<text>Next to their base, so it's easier for us to wipe them out? Fine, my captain is currently patrolling the Wild Territory, I will tell him to go to the Warehouses, but only if you're going to be there too. If anything happens to him, you will be held responsible.</text>		<!-- sending captain -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_voronin_16">
		<text>Understood.</text>		<!-- understood -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_5_freedom_cap_1">
		<text>So, finally you're here.\n
		\nSo listen, I've come up with a couple of ideas. Judging by the factory building plan, the entrance to the laboratory is located in the eastern part of it. The fanatics are scattered around the perimeter, but especially in the eastern part. We'll split into two groups, the first one will attack from the main entrance and lure as many Monolith members as possible from the eastern part. The second group will break through the hole in the fence from the east.</text>		<!-- So, finally you're here -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_freedom_cap_2">
		<text>Sakharov said that the door cannot be opened, how will we get in there?</text>		<!-- how -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_freedom_cap_3">
		<text>This door can only be opened from the inside, but there is another entrance through the bunker at the very bottom, which is located above the laboratory. At the end of the lower corridor, there is a ventilation shaft, the entrance to the bunker should be behind it.</text>		<!-- stairs -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_freedom_cap_4">
		<text>Doesn't sound great, but if there's nothing better...</text>		<!-- not bad -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_freedom_cap_5">
		<text>In my opinion, it's a great plan. Alright, I think that's it, let me know when you're ready.</text>		<!-- that's it -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_freedom_cap_6">
		<text>Alright, we'll write it down.</text>		<!-- ok -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_5_duty_cap_1">
		<text>It might work, I'll pass everything to Voronin. Go to the Barman when you're ready, he'll contact Sakharov.</text>		<!-- go to the barman -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_duty_cap_2">
		<text>Understood.</text>		<!-- ok -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_5_barman_1">
		<text>Pass on to Sakharov that Duty and Freedom have agreed to help.</text>		<!-- transfer -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_barman_2">
		<text>Already contacted, he asked you to pass a small instruction on setting up the emitter.</text>		<!-- already -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_barman_3">
		<text>Wait, me? And what about his scientists?</text>		<!-- me? -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_barman_4">
		<text>He mostly has hired guards capable of scaring off bandits and shooting at small mutants. As far as I know, it will be quite hot there, they haven't prepared for assaults on the fortifications. And the scientists themselves either won't go under fire with you, or will run away at the first opportunity.\n
		\nSakharov said that you are already familiar with the principle of the emitter's operation in general terms. He also asked to convey that it's not difficult there, you just need to pull a couple of levers.</text>		<!-- scientists -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_barman_5">
		<text>Oh... Alright, tell me what needs to be done.</text>		<!-- okey -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_barman_6">
		<text>So, listen. When you find yourself inside and find the emitter itself, there should be two cabins, they are located higher than everything else. First, you will need to pull the lever in both of them. After that, go to the control center, which should be nearby, and on one of the panels there should be the last lever. That's all you need to change the mode. Seems not difficult.\n
		\nSakharov added that according to their calculations, all the Monolith members in the area should drop dead or have their minds blown by a sudden surge of something. So when you figure out the emitter, you can safely get out.\n
		\nThere's one more thing. They also asked to search the laboratory for anything related to the emitter. If you manage to find anything, bring it to Sakharov, he's willing to pay for each item.</text>		<!-- listen -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_barman_7">
		<text>If we can even get there at all.</text>		<!-- Understood -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_barman_8">
		<text>Let me know when you're ready, I'll write to everyone to move out.</text>		<!-- tell me when -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_barman_9_1">
		<text>Ready to go now, write to everyone.</text>		<!-- ready -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_5_barman_9_2">
		<text>I'll let you know when I'm ready.</text>		<!-- not ready -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_6_freedom_1">
		<text>What's going on there?</text>		<!-- What's going on there -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_6_freedom_2">
		<text>We just arrived ourselves. We looked around a bit, it seems like they're starting to fortify the area. We'll signal the Duty to attack. As soon as we hear shots, some of the fanatics should run towards them, and that's when we'll start too.\n
		\nAlright, one more time. As soon as we reach the building around the corner, immediately go down the hatch. The main entrance is already barricaded, we'll stay behind to cover. Then go down the corridor to the main staircase, then go to the lowest level and to the ventilation. Once you deal with the emitter, exit through the main door, no need to crawl back into the bunker.\n
		\nI bet the Monolith are wandering around the location, and as soon as they find out about our attack, they'll start converging from all directions. We'll try to hold them off for as long as possible.</text>		<!-- Let's start -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_6_freedom_3">
		<text>Understood.</text>		<!-- Okay -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_6_stalker_1">
		<text>Oh, did you kill the bloodsuckers at Agroprom?</text>		<!-- you killed the bloodsuckers -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_6_stalker_2">
		<text>Yes, and you...</text>		<!-- yes -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_6_stalker_3">
		<text>I'm a stalker who was in that group. Barman told me that you found their bodies...\n
		\nAfter that, I went on a bender. Then I heard conversations in the Bar about how everyone is screwed because of the Monolithians. I asked Barman, he explained briefly, and I begged to join. Maybe now I can do something useful for everyone, Barman even found me an old suit.</text>		<!-- stalker -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_6_stalker_4">
		<text>It will be dangerous for newcomers here, but any help will be useful.</text>		<!-- for now -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_6_freedom_news">
		<text>We're here, that hatch to the right of the building. Go, we'll cover as much as we can.</text>		<!-- we'll cover -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_6_vakhar_1">
		<text>Kill everyone you see.</text>		<!-- kill everyone -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_6_vakhar_2">
		<text>The traitor is here too! Kill him first!</text>		<!-- traitor -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_6_duty_freedom_news">
		<text>Stalker, you did it! Look, the fanatics are all dead or gone crazy.</text>		<!-- you did it -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_6_sakharov_1">
		<text>Seems like we reconfigured the Promzone emitter.</text>		<!-- reconfigured -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_6_sakharov_2">
		<text>Did you manage to do it after all? That's great news!\n
		\nYou've done a great service to all people and to us in particular. Here, take this, you've earned it. The bartender told me that if you haven't visited the leaders of the Duty and Freedom factions yet, they are also ready to reward you materially.</text>		<!-- reward -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_6_sakharov_3">
		<text>Thank you, what's next?</text>		<!-- what's next -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_6_sakharov_4">
		<text>Now we'll have time to study the documents and the emitter itself more carefully, maybe we'll find something interesting related to all this. That's all for now.</text>		<!-- that's all -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_6_sakharov_5">
		<text>Understood. Well then, goodbye.</text>		<!-- leave -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_finish_voronin_1">
		<text>I was told that you wanted to discuss something about the Promzone?</text>		<!-- What did you want -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_finish_voronin_2">
		<text>I heard the fight was tough, I don't even know what you had to deal with inside those bunkers. But I'm glad you made it... Now I hope everything will be as it was before.\n
		\nI asked Petrenko to pick something up for you, take this.</text>		<!-- reward -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_finish_voronin_3">
		<text>Thank you.</text>		<!-- thanks -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_finish_lukash_1">
		<text>I heard you wanted to talk about the Promzone?</text>		<!-- What did you want -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_finish_lukash_2">
		<text>Dude, we did it! Now the fanatics will keep rushing our fortifications, where we can at least hold them back.\n
		\nHere, we prepared something for you.</text>		<!-- reward -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_finish_lukash_3">
		<text>Thank you.</text>		<!-- thanks -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_finish_sakharov_1">
		<text>I found some things in the Promzone laboratory.</text>		<!-- found items -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_finish_sakharov_2">
		<text>Alright, let's see... Ah... Oh, this is interesting.\n
		\nWe can use this, thank you. And here's your money.</text>		<!-- reward -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_finish_sakharov_3">
		<text>Thank you.</text>		<!-- thanks -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_finish_sakharov_41">
		<text>You managed to gather enough information.\n
		\nHere's a special reward for your efforts.</text>		<!-- gathered everything -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_finish_sakharov_42">
		<text>We will need more items with information, bring us everything you could find.</text>		<!-- gathered not everything -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_finish_sakharov_51">
		<text>This will be useful, thanks again.</text>		<!-- thanks -->
	</string>
	<string id="st_redemption_finish_sakharov_52">
		<text>Alright, bye.</text>		<!-- bye -->
	</string>

	<string id="st_redemption_end_illeon_join">
		<text>Come with me.</text>		<!-- let's go -->
	</string>

</string_table>
