<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
----Stories from the Zone----

--- Atomic Crusader ---
<string id="ac_charon_0_0">
		<text>You wanted to speak to me, Father?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_charon_0_1">
		<text>Yes young Brother, I decided to assign you to Blue Winter's chapter. Report to your Brother upstairs, he will fill you in about the details.
		And remember, the Monolith is always watching.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_charon_0_2">
		<text>Alright Father.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_charon_0_3">
		<text>For the Monolith.</text>
	</string>

<string id="ac_blue_winter_0_0">
		<text>Father Charon sends me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_blue_winter_0_1">
		<text>Good, welcome Brother! I am Blue Winter, and our chapter is a reconnaissance unit. You will meet the other Brothers of our chapter shortly, but first I want to brief you on our mission.
		\nFather Charon wants to take back the Kindergarten in the Outskirts in order to use it as a forward base. Our chapter has been assigned this task, and our Brothers Melchior and Caspar are already there scouting out the building.
		Accodring to them, the building is a mutant den at the moment, so prepare for such an encounter. We will do it during the night, in order to take the enemies of the Monolith by surprise - they shall only know our intentions when we already have a foothold there. 
		\n \nI got the authorisation to allow you an advance in order to supply yourself. Prepare for the mission, we will set out at nightfall.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_blue_winter_0_2">
		<text>Understood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_blue_winter_0_3">
		<text>Very well Brother. Prepare and find me, we will wait together for nightfall. In the meantime you can already get acquainted with our Borther Balthazar here, the pillar of our chapter. 
		He fills out the position of fire support.</text>
	</string>

<string id="ac_blue_winter_1_0">
		<text>About our mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_blue_winter_1_1">
		<text>Yes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_blue_winter_1_2">
		<text>I am ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_blue_winter_1_3">
		<text>Very well, let's wait together for the night. Then, when the sun is down, we set out. You will lead the way, Brother.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_blue_winter_1_4">
		<text>I am ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_blue_winter_1_5">
		<text>The night already set in, let's move out. Lead the way, Brother.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_blue_winter_1_6">
		<text>For the Monolith.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_blue_winter_1_7">
		<text>I still need to do some preparations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_blue_winter_1_8">
		<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>

<string id="st_ac_task_1_0">
		<text>Blue Winter: What is your report?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_1_1">
		<text>Melchior: A couple of snorks and a Poltergeist. No enemy activity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_1_2">
		<text>Blue Winter: Alright, that should be manageable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_1_3">
		<text>Blue Winter: Melchior and Caspar, you stay outside and guard the entrance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_1_4">
		<text>Blue Winter: Balthazar and %s, you come with me. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_1_5">
		<text>Blue Winter: Brother %s, you take point.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_1_6">
		<text>Blue Winter: For the Monolith!</text>
	</string>

<string id="ac_blue_winter_2_0">
		<text>How do we reach our Brothers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_blue_winter_2_1">
		<text>When we are at the Outskirts we approach the Kindergaten from the north. We'll have to bypass the Vulcano anomaly and then our Borthers should wait for us close to our target.</text>
	</string>

<string id="ac_blue_winter_3_0">
		<text>That seems to have been all of them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_blue_winter_3_1">
		<text>Indeed. Excellent work Brother! You did great on our first mission. I want you to have the honour to report this victory to Father Charon, he will send further troops to fortify our position here.
		Use the opportunity to stock up on supplies, and when you are ready, come see me and I will give you your next mission briefing.</text>
	</string>

<string id="ac_charon_1_0">
		<text>Father, our chapter has succesfully claimed the Kindergarten for the Monolith.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ac_charon_1_1">
		<text>Excellent work Brother! I will immediatly give the order to send more troops there. Here some money to stock up on supplies. \n \nNow go and spread the glory of the Monolith!</text>
	</string>




<string id="st_ac_task_3_0">
		<text>I see four Stalkers leaving their base. They look like serious guys, armed to the teeth.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_3_1">
		<text>Good job Brother! Keep an eye on them and keep me informed about their intentions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_3_2">
		<text>They passed the apartment complex and seem to turn south.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_3_3">
		<text>Good! So no need to alarm the troops.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_3_4">
		<text>I'll soon loose sight of them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_3_5">
		<text>Brother Melchior is already on the job. Keep your position and wait for instructions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_3_6">
		<text>I just saw them entering the Department Store.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_3_7">
		<text>Excellent job Brothers! That's an excellent place to surprise them - I have a plan.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_3_8">
		<text>Brother %s, come join our squad. We will wait for you to the south of the Kindergarten, between the Grocery Store and the apartment buildings.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_3_9">
		<text>I reached the exit of the tunnel!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ac_task_3_10">
		<text>Perfect. We launch our attack, you take them from behind! For the Monolith!</text>
	</string>



































</string_table>
