<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="dm_about_story_talk">
		<text>Those who have trampled on the Zone for a long time, as far as I know, are interested in something other than bubble, booze and wish-seeker. Maybe I&apos;m wrong, but in my opinion I heard in the bar that among you went the fashion for philosophical sayings. Will you tell us some interesting parable?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_story_end">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_zonanews_end">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_1">
		<text>Well, as you say, there is such a trend among the experienced walkers. Then we&apos;ll sit down on one or the other. Listen. It is said that one day King Mahmud overtook his retinue. Rushing on his horse at full speed, along the river, he suddenly saw at the water&apos;s edge a little boy who was fishing with a seine. The child seemed very unhappy. The king sharply besieged the horse, and, approaching the boy, asked him: 
   &quot;My child, why are you looking so sad?&quot; I&apos;ve never met a man more sad than you. 
   The boy replied: 
   Your Majesty, there are seven of us brothers. Our father died, and we live with our mother in extreme need. To somehow feed, I come every day to the river and throw the net. If for a day I can not catch a single fish, I stay hungry for the night. 
   My son, &quot;said the king,&quot; if you do not mind, I will help you. &quot; The boy agreed, and King Mahmud himself threw the net, which from the touch of the king&apos;s hand returned with a rich catch. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_2">
		<text>Heh, when it&apos;s already one year balancing between life and death, then any fool will sooner or later become a philosopher. So listen. A peasant came out to sow wheat in the field. The day draws to a close, and he does not manage to finish his work ... He begged: &quot;Oh, Lord, I would have an assistant, we would have settled two times with the sowing ...&quot; 
   Look, and from the bushes the bear climbs and says to him: &quot;Come on, man, I&apos;ll help you, all together are more cheerful.&quot; 
   The man was delighted and agreed. They sowed the field on time and, parting in parting, parted ... 
   It&apos;s time for harvest ... The peasant does not have time to harvest the harvest by the time ... Look, and from the bushes the familiar bear climbs out and says: &quot;Come on, man, I&apos;ll help you, the two of us are more handy.&quot; And the work began to boil ... They gathered a harvest, yes, such as the peasant never saw before. 
   So he says to the bear: &quot;Come on, Misha, to my house. You helped me to sow and to reap ... Let&apos;s go, we&apos;ll sit at the table: we&apos;ll have a drink, we&apos;ll eat, we&apos;ll talk ...&quot; 
   The bear agreed, pleased with his generosity of the peasant. 
   They sit at the table, rejoice, and the bear keeps saying: Look, man, if it were not for me, you would not have sown the whole field ... If it was not for me, you would not have harvested such a crop ... 
   A guy and thought: &quot;Vaughan he is healthy and strong, he will take everything from me and break my bones ... No wonder he himself praises so ...&quot; 
   The man of a pitch-fork suffices, and sticks them into a bear. The bear was sick with pain ... and fled into the forest. 
   The time has passed ... and it&apos;s time to sow ... The peasant left the field to sow, but without an assistant only half the field sowed. It&apos;s time for harvest, but only half of the harvest was collected by the peasant ... 
   He goes home dull ... Look, and from the bushes the bear climbs. A peasant and says with reproach: &quot;What are you, Misha, did not come to help me sow and reap? ... I did, and I fed you, and you?&quot; 
   To which the bear, pointing to the chest, answers: &quot;But here I have a pain ...&quot; 
   A peasant approaches a bear, probes, and says: &quot;Why, it&apos;s all healed, Misha!&quot; A bear in return: &quot;The wound has healed ... SOUL IS SICK !!!&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_3">
		<text>Well - not so much we are more than cool philosophers. Just lovers to read something that really has a price. So I&apos;m telling you. One unknown king came to an unknown poet and said: 
   &quot;O King, unparalleled in the heavens!&quot; I composed a hymn in your honor, and my creation is brighter than all the poems that so far other poets have written to you, like Sirius, the brightest of all the stars in the night sky. 
   With these words he handed the king a sheet on which was written only the name of this ruler. The king looked at the sheet and became angry: 
   &quot;Where are the verses?&quot; He cried. &quot;Are you crazy?&quot; You did not sing our royal glory, did not sing our victories and good deeds. You did not even say that I created this whole kingdom with my own hands! Do you dare to joke at me? 
   But the poet did not frighten the king&apos;s wrath, and he replied with dignity: 
   - All the royal wisdom, mercy and power and all military glory fit in this name, and anyone who reads it, immediately imagine all the acts committed by the king. After all, the name is a symbol of your kingdom, and it is in itself above the thickest book of praise. So I was right before you, calling what was written by my hand, an incomparable hymn, glorifying you and your deeds! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_4">
		<text>Hmm, now I&apos;ll remember one of the last. Once upon a long time in the Middle Empire - at that time they called China - the best, most powerful fighters gathered in the tournament from around the world. The great Chinese sage judged the contest. Finally, after many thousands of fights, he chose the three greatest warriors and asked each of them to tell how he trains. 
   The first to rise was a huge fierce warrior and said: &quot;Every morning at sunrise I break down trees, stones, boards - everything that comes to my way. Around my house on the day of the journey everything is turned to dust, into the desert. 
   &quot;Fine,&quot; said the sage. - And how do you train? He asked another soldier. 
   A tall, lean man rose up, more like a monk or an ascetic. 
   &quot;Every morning at sunrise,&quot; he said, &quot;I indulge in meditation. I take my body under the control of reason and will and make it be light and fast, like a thought. 
   &quot;Fine,&quot; said the sage. - And how do you train? He asked the third warrior. 
   A very ordinary, unremarkable, outward man rose up. If he had not just won a thousand bouts yet, no one would have thought that it was a warrior, and even a great one. 
   &quot;I do not train at all,&quot; said the third. &quot;It&apos;s just that I try to be present in everything I do.&quot; </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_5">
		<text>Yes really at least someone began to understand us. Wow. So came insight in life. So listen. There was Godelo. He had a wife who constantly sawed him for the fact that his father prevented them from living, and could not Godelo calm his wife. 
  Father Godelo, listening to the cries of his wife every day, beckons his son, and says to him: 
  &quot;Son, I see that I am interfering with your presence with your family well-being, let me go to the mountains to live ...&quot; 
  - It was good to say that after listening to my father I began to refuse, but there&apos;s nothing to do ... 
  The father began to assemble, as he beckoned to his son and said to him: 
  - I have only one problem, I myself will not go to the mountains, let me put you in the basket on your shoulders, and there I&apos;m like myself. 
  &quot;Good,&quot; agreed Godelo. 
  He put his father in a basket and carried him to the mountains. Brought his father, landed, then he was afraid to leave, as his father says to him: 
  - Wait a son, do not forget to grab your basket, if your son is of little use. 
  Then Godelo became ashamed, he realized his mistake, repented, put his father back in the basket and brought back home. 
  ... And the evil wife from the house drove out. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_6">
		<text>Well, as you say, there is such a trend among the experienced walkers. Then we&apos;ll sit down on one or the other. Listen. One pilgrim walked not one thousand steps to meet the Teacher and, finally, appeared before him, asking to share the highest wisdom. 
  &quot;Then take a sip from this stream and describe to me the taste of water.&quot; The teacher told him. 
  &quot;I already heard and understand this Truth,&quot; the Seeker said, a little disappointed. 
  - Tell me, what do you understand? Asked the Teacher. 
  &quot;The taste of water can not be described in words, water must be drunk, there is no need to talk about it, so too is the truth ...&quot; 
  &quot;Now imagine - I&apos;m sitting by the brook, and a crowd such as you stand in line for me to describe to them the taste of water, although many of them have already heard this description from other Teachers. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_7">
		<text>Heh, when it&apos;s already one year balancing between life and death, then any fool will sooner or later become a philosopher. So listen. On the way there was a girl, beautiful, like a fairy. Suddenly she noticed that a man was following her. She turned and asked: 
  &quot;Tell me, why are you following me?&quot; 
  The man replied: 
  &quot;Oh, master of my heart, your charms are so irresistible that they command me to follow you.&quot; People say that I play beautifully on the lute, that I am dedicated to the secrets of the art of poetry and that I am able to awaken the torments of love in the hearts of women. And I want to explain to you in love, because you have captivated my heart! 
  The beauty silently stared at him for a while, then said: 
  &quot;How could you fall in love with me?&quot; My younger sister is much prettier and more attractive than me. She follows me, look at her. 
  The man stopped, then turned around, but saw only an ugly old woman in a patched mantle. Then he accelerated his steps to catch up with the girl. He lowered his eyes and asked in a voice expressing obedience: 
  &quot;Tell me, how could a lie get out of your mouth?&quot; 
  She smiled and replied: 
  &quot;You, my friend, did not tell me the truth either when you swore love.&quot; You know perfectly all the rules of love and pretend that your heart is blazing with love for me. How could you turn around to look at another woman?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_8">
		<text>Well - not so much we are more than cool philosophers. Just lovers to read something that really has a price. So I&apos;m telling you. One trader sent his son to learn the Secret of Happiness from the wisest of all people. The young man walked for forty days through the desert and, at last, approached the beautiful castle standing on the mountain top. There also lived the wise man whom he was looking for. However, instead of the expected meeting with the wise man, our hero got into the hall, where everything was boiling: traders came in and out, people were talking in the corner, a small orchestra was playing sweet melodies and there was a table set with the most exquisite dishes of this area. The wise man talked with different people, and the young man had to wait about two hours to wait his turn. 
  The wise man listened attentively to the explanation of the young man about the purpose of his visit, but said in reply that he did not have time to reveal the Secret of Happiness to him. And invited him to walk around the palace and come again in two hours. 
  &quot;However, I want to ask for one favor,&quot; the sage added, holding out to the young man a small spoon, into which he had drunk two drops of oil. &quot;Keep this spoon in your hand all the time, so that the oil does not pour.&quot; 
  The young man began to climb and descend the palace stairs, not taking his eyes off the spoon. Two hours later he returned to the sage. 
  &quot;Well,&quot; he asked, &quot;did you see the Persian carpets that are in my dining room?&quot; Have you seen the park that the chief gardener created for ten years? Did you notice the beautiful parchments in my library? 
  The young man in confusion had to admit that he had not seen anything. His only concern was not to shed a drop of oil, which the sage entrusted him. 
  &quot;Well, come back and get acquainted with the wonders of my universe,&quot; the sage told him. - You can not trust a person if you are not familiar with the house in which he lives. 
  Calmed down, the young man took a spoon and again went for a walk around the palace; This time, paying attention to all the works of art, hung on the walls and ceilings of the palace. He saw the gardens surrounded by mountains, the most delicate flowers, the subtlety with which each of the works of art was placed exactly where it was needed. 
  Returning to the sage, he described in detail everything he saw. 
  &quot;And where are those two drops of oil that I trusted you?&quot; Asked the Sage. 
  And the young man, looking at the spoon, found that all the oil had poured out. 
  &quot;This is the only advice I can give you: The secret of Happiness is to look at all the wonders of the world, while never forgetting two drops of oil in your spoon. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_9">
		<text>Hmm, now I&apos;ll remember one of the last. Once upon a time there was an old monarch in the Indian kingdom-state, who all his life solved for himself one purely eastern question: what is the essence of strength? And he decided, in the end, to find the strongest man in his possessions, in order to learn from him what the essence of strength is. As a reward to this hero, the Indian king appointed a horse from his stables, and at the request of the winner of the announced contest: he wants white - he will get a white horse, he wants a black horse - he will get a black horse as a gift. In order to solve this difficult task, the choice of the eternal problem, he collected the wisest people of his kingdom and sent them with the inspection of cities and towns.
  The task of the monarch was really incredibly difficult - the sages trampled not one pair of sandals, but they did not find the strongest man. They arranged competitions, gave the contenders for the victory many tasks, but the effect was zero: none of the subjects of the Indian king could claim unconditionally for the right to be called the strongest man in the Indian kingdom. 
  The sages are already quite desperate to find a man who they could give with a clear conscience to choose one of the best horses of the royal stables ... At heart these &quot;experts&quot; scraped the cat - do not take down their heads! And suddenly, passing through some small Indian village, they noticed a giant man. He was lying on a huge trestle in the middle of a large garden that surrounded his house. &quot;What a tremendous power is hidden in this man!&quot; - the sages exclaimed and decided to subject him to three tests. 
  &quot;Can you break a horseshoe with one hand?&quot; The wise men of the giant man asked. The same did not answer them, but simply took and broke his hand with a horseshoe. &quot;And can you pull out the tree?&quot; The sages again asked him. The same did not answer them, but simply wrapped a ten-meter-high tree with both hands and pulled it out of the ground with one stroke. &quot;Truly, you are strong, man! But can you block the river? &quot;The sages asked for the third time.&quot; The giant man did not answer them, but went up to the river, lifted a huge stone lying on the shore and threw it into the stream and the river stood up. &quot;Glory to the gods! Exclaimed the wise men. &quot;Truly, you are the strongest man on earth!&quot; Choose any of the royal horses: if you want - take a black, you want - white! &quot; 
  And only the giant man raised his hand over his head to scratch his head before announcing his decision, when suddenly a small, frail woman in a dark dress appeared on the threshold of his house. &quot;Husband, I warn you: choose a white - you do not like it, I can not vouch for myself!&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_10">
		<text>Yes really at least someone began to understand us. Wow. So came insight in life. So listen. There was a case when the wife of one prince approached Genghis Khan, asking her to release her relatives. 
  Genghis Khan said: 
  - Here, in front of you are your husband, your son, and your brother. I will only let one go, whom do you choose? 
  Without hesitation, she replied: 
  - Brother. 
  &quot;Explain to me why?&quot; 
  The woman said: 
  - I can find a husband, I can give birth to a son, but I can not create a brother. 
  After hearing, Genghis Khan released all three. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_11">
		<text>Well, as you say, there is such a trend among the experienced walkers. Then we&apos;ll sit down on one or the other. Listen. ... The gate of Zhundu opened, and the steppe people poured into the richest city of the Celestial, screaming and waving their weapons violently. 
  Li Kui, known in Zhundu as Nosy Li, a tramp without a clan and tribe, who came to town from the very time before the invasion, - a tiny and ruffled Lee Kui, limping, ran along the alleys of the western outskirts, hoping for luck. 
  If the great Guanyin helps him to leave unharmed, he will become a shaven-headed heshan monk in saffron cassocks, living alms and indifferent to worldly vanity - and let other fools give risky advice to the meager Son of Heaven, the dumb emperor, and let the unfortunate Celestial Empire be raped and robbed All who are not lazy, though greedy dignitaries, at least dirty Mongols, though ... 
  Before he realized that Guanyin was looking the other way today, Nosaty Lee stopped short, hissed in pain on the injured knee, and threw up a short, three-arm, staff. 
  At the end of the alley, a tall Mongol wounded joyfully in leather armor, playing with a long spear with a crossbar under the tip of the tip. 
  The disgraced commander Li Kui, who was named Nosatym Li in Zhundu, and in the capital - the Blue Tiger Hou, took a deep breath and slowly went to the smirking steppe, forcing his will to stop limping. 
  Mongol waited until the frail ragamack came closer, and lazily jabbed a spear in front of him. 
  A moment later, the weapon almost escaped his hands, and when the astonished warrior managed to jump back, clinging his spear stinging upward, a stick hollowed from inside flew to his face, in which, like a silkworm in a cocoon, a straight sword was hiding from idle eyes -Jian of the Blue Tiger Hou. 
  The city was already burning. Bitter smoke stelilsja the streets Chzhundu, uvlekshihsja ahead of plundering warriors indomitable Temudzhina Genghis Khan; smoke in a hurry, before making his way into the Western outskirts of invaders, from Gary pershilo acid in the throat and leg ache unbearably Whether kuya, and Mongol Beale skillfully and fiercely, the tip, the reverse side of the flagpole, and therefore had to move much until the Guanyin deigned not to turn his benevolent gaze on Chzhundu and on a deserted Lane, in which Lee managed to get twice-nosed blade wrist Mongol. 
  Now I could only wait. Wait and do not turn under the spear, the movements of which became increasingly uncertain and trembling. And after waiting - to put the last forces into the last jump. 
  ... He never released the spear, this unlucky warrior in light leather armor. Coughing and skosobochivshis, he sat at the wall of someone&apos;s house, his right palm clamped pierced his side, while the left continued to hold a spear lying next to him. And above them, over the wounded Mongol and the impotent spear, Li Qui, former commander of the left wing of Lee, former Blue Tiger Hou, former Nosaty Li, future rector of the monastery near the mountain of Wutai Shan, stood panting and trying not to bear weight on the injured leg, tired little human. 
  He stood and watched the Mongolian face become more and more pale, and the incised wrists bleed less and less. 
  Mongol barely lifted his head - and their glances met. 
  Lee Kui sighed, tore his cloak on the stripes, crouched next to the Mongol and began to bandage the arms of the invincible Chinggis warrior. 
  Lee did not know why he was doing it ... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_12">
		<text>Heh, when it&apos;s already one year balancing between life and death, then any fool will sooner or later become a philosopher. So listen. The royal daughter with her beauty was like the moon and enchanted all those who were awarded at least once to look at her. One day a dervish, preparing to refresh himself, brought a piece of bread to his mouth, when he suddenly saw her and froze in amazement. His fingers unclenched themselves, and the bread fell to the ground. Passing by, the princess smiled at the dervish. Delight put his body in awe, bread remained lying in the dust, and he almost lost his senses. In this state dervish stayed seven years. His house became a street, neighbors - stray dogs. The mad dervish bored the princess, and her bodyguards decided to kill him. Then she called him to her and told him: 
  &quot;No union between us is possible.&quot; You must leave the city immediately, because my servants want to kill you. 
  The unfortunate lover replied: 
  &quot;Since I saw you, life has no value for me.&quot; They will shed innocent blood. But before I die, I conjure you, grant my only desire, for you are the cause of my death. Tell me, why did you then smile at me? 
  - Fool! Said the princess. &quot;When I saw how ridiculous you put yourself, I smiled out of pity - and that&apos;s all.&quot; 
  And, having said so, the princess disappeared. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_13">
		<text>Well - not so much we are more than cool philosophers. Just lovers to read something that really has a price. So I&apos;m telling you. Between the two sages there was a conversation about love. One said: 
  - The property of love - always bring torment and misfortune, and the lover always suffers and suffers. 
  Another objected: 
  - Shut up, you apparently never experienced the sweetness of reconciliation after a quarrel and never knew the taste of the connection after separation. No one in the world is cleaner and more tender than the pure soul in love, and there is no dirtier than anyone who is far from the idea of ??love. 
  In the beauty of the man&apos;s heart is the reflection of the glow of love: 
  If the heart is ugly, beauty does not honor it! 
  Let the ignorant remember the saying of the wise: 
  Where the breed is honored breed, - the soul affinity is approved. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_14">
		<text>Hmm, now I&apos;ll remember one of the last. Once there was only one man, possessed by insane love and exhausted by love torments. The beauty of the one whom he loved was incomparable even with the beauty of the paradise virgins. About such as she, said that its beauty, it overshadowed both the Sun and the Moon. And besides, her incomparable beauty was dangerous to people not only because she threatened every deadly torment of love, but also because this beauty was smart and ruthless. 
  And once a man in love with her, thinking that he was alone, said to himself: 
  - Oh my God! Her face is more beautiful than a rose, and the mill is slimmer than a cypress tree! Her whole face is brighter than a peacock, and her gait is more graceful than that of a pheasant! 
  But it turned out that his beloved at that time was nearby and heard his words. Openly presented to him, she said: 
  &quot;You probably wanted to flatter me with your comparisons, but they only angered me, and I consider them to be shameful.&quot; Now you have compared my face to a rose, but where did you see such beautiful eyes and eyebrows as roses? You compared my camp with cypress, but does cypress have my mobility and ardor? You compared all my appearance to a peacock, but did someone burn with love, contemplating peacocks? You compared my tread to the pheasant&apos;s tread, but who of the people will take care of his soul, remembering the walking pheasant? 
  - Forgive me! Cried the lover. - I foolishly imagined that you can be described in words! 
  These words further angered the moon-faced, and in anger she said: 
  &quot;For this foolishness of yours, I&apos;ll kill you!&quot; 
  Then the lover fell at her feet with the words: 
  &quot;O unparalleled unearthly Beauty!&quot; All my awkward speeches were caused by my true and pure love for you. There is no malice, no reproach, no complaint at all in them, and if they seemed inappropriate to you, then be good and do not take me severe for this fault, consider them a sign of my ignorance and ignorance, and I myself will perish From shame and shame! 
  And so long he sought and said the words of repentance that the beautiful woman had calmed down and abandoned her intention to take revenge on this man in love with her. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_15">
		<text>Yes really at least someone began to understand us. Wow. So came insight in life. So listen. In the old days there was one thief. Once he robbed the treasure of the padishah. After the thief, the padishah sent all his detectives. The thief was seized and robbed of his loot. Here the padishah asked his chief vizier: 
  &quot;What should I do with this thief?&quot; 
  &quot;We need to assemble the whole population of the city and kill the thief with all the people,&quot; the vizier answered. 
  And the padishah had a daughter. The padishah asked her: 
  - Does the vizier speak correctly? 
  &quot;The Vizier judged in essence,&quot; the girl answered. 
  Then the padishah asked the middle vizier: 
  &quot;What should I do with this thief?&quot; 
  - We need to add more firewood, put a thief on them and set them on fire. 
  And again the padishah asked his daughter: 
  - How do you find what the Vizier said? 
  And the daughter of the padishah again answered: 
  - Your vizier judged in fact. 
  Finally the padishah asked his younger vizier: 
  &quot;What should I do with the thief?&quot; 
  - It is necessary to put the thief from head to foot, give him everything, so that his stomach is always full, and let him go. 
  The Padishah again asked his daughter: 
  - How do you find what the Vizier said? 
  &quot;Your vizier judged in essence,&quot; answered the girl. 
  Then the padishah said: 
  &quot;You talked about each of the three viziers that he judged in essence.&quot; What do you mean, explain to us. 
  And the girl answered: 
  &quot;The chief vizier, who said that the thief must be slaughtered, by origin, must be from the butchers.&quot; It seems that your average vizier is made of brick burners. And the younger vizier is inherently noble. 
  The Padishah checked, and it turned out that the girl was right. The thief was treated, as the younger vizier advised: they fed him enough to eat, they gave money to spend money and saved him from death. And the younger Vizier was made the chief vizier. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_16">
		<text>Well, as you say, there is such a trend among the experienced walkers. Then we&apos;ll sit down on one or the other. Listen. Once a gang of robbers went to rob. 
  Having ransacked many things, they began to divide them among themselves. All the shares were equal, and only the dress of the finest threads, it was considered the worst part, was given to the weakest in the gang. And he, weak, having received his share, was enraged. He began to shout that he had been circumvented. 
  When he came to the city to sell his outfit, all the eminent rich people began to offer him big money. What he got alone, was twice as much as all his companions, taken together. 
  Then he rejoiced and jumped with joy. This is similar to how laypeople, not knowing whether retribution will result in the distribution of alms or not, give out a small charity (part of their income). When they are reborn in heaven and experience immense bliss, they begin to regret - they regret that they did not give out an extensive charity (of their entire state). They are like the one who, having received a lot of money for the dress, rejoiced. With the distribution of charity the same thing: they get a lot for small businesses. 
  That is why, together with glee, they regret the incompleteness of the deed. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_17">
		<text>Heh, when it&apos;s already one year balancing between life and death, then any fool will sooner or later become a philosopher. So listen. Once upon a time there was one family: a husband, a wife and a daughter. This family was poor, pre-poor, barely made ends meet. The husband and his wife began to think how they could get rich. 
  &quot;We live in poverty now. Let&apos;s find some rich man, we&apos;ll stay with him, we&apos;ll see what he&apos;s doing, and we&apos;ll imitate him in everything. 
  So they did. They broke their hut and built a new one next to the house of the rich sethei. Sethei forced his employees to cultivate the field and garden, and then sent them to sell the crop. The poor tried to imitate the Sethei, in what they could, they worked in the field, and then a part of the crop was sold at the market. Gradually, their business went better and better, prosperity grew. 
  The husband and his wife decided to thank the Sethei, from whom they secretly learned to farm. My husband took a handful of gold and went to the rich man. 
  &quot;Why did you bring me gold?&quot; The sethei was surprised. 
  - I was poor. We decided with my wife to break our hut, settle near your house and imitate you in everything. Our business quickly went into harmony, the family became rich, and we thank you for accepting our gift. 
  &quot;Since you yourself think that you have gained all your wealth thanks to me, it means that this is my wealth.&quot; You must give me all your fortune, and I&apos;ll decide how much to allocate to you. 
  &quot;But I did not remain ungrateful and brought you gold.&quot; If I knew that you would demand all my state, then I would not bring you anything. 
  A long time the Sethei and the former poor man argued. Finally, they turned to the judge. The judge could not resolve their dispute and led both to the king. The former poor man bowed and said: 
  &quot;Your Majesty, I settled next to the Sethei&apos;s house, watched him go into the farm, send his workers to the field and trade in the bazaar.&quot; I began to imitate the Sethei, as I could, and achieved prosperity and success in business. Out of gratitude, I brought gold to the sethey, who helped me, without knowing it, but the sethey demands all my state. I ask you, Your Majesty, to understand this matter in justice. 
  The king turned to the Sethei: 
  - Correctly stated the case of this man? 
  &quot;It&apos;s all right, Your Majesty.&quot; 
  The king realized that the Sethei was not too greedy, and said: 
  &quot;Sethay, do you have children?&quot; 
  &quot;Son, Your Majesty.&quot; 
  - And you have? - the king turned to the former poor. 
  &quot;Daughter, Your Majesty.&quot; 
  &quot;In order for there to be no quarrel between you, I command both families to become related.&quot; Then you will have nothing to share. 
  Sethhey and the former poor bowed low to the king and retired to follow the wise royal decision. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_18">
		<text>Well - not so much we are more than cool philosophers. Just lovers to read something that really has a price. So I&apos;m telling you. There lived in the desert a man-recluse. Once in his homeland, he was a good carpenter. But his life, by chance, threw him into the desert. About this master learned one rich man and found him, turned to him: 
  - They say that you are a good master. So I want to order an oak table and chairs for my room. I will come for my order in a month and pay it well. 
  And left. After the appointed time the rich man again came to the master and asked: 
  &quot;Where are my tables and chairs?&quot; 
  - Yes, I&apos;m a good master. But this is not enough. In order for me to fulfill your order, I still need a tree and an instrument that I do not have ... 
  One desire is not enough: we also need opportunities ... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_19">
		<text>Hmm, now I&apos;ll remember one of the last. In the army of Shamil came a letter to some warrior with a notice that his wife had died. The letter was received by Shamil himself. He decided to check that warrior and sent for him. When he came, Shamil said: 
  &quot;You received a letter with the news that your father was dead.&quot; 
  &quot;If so, then the roof of our house has fallen off, and I need to go home,&quot; answered the warrior. 
  &quot;No, my father did not die, but your brother died.&quot; 
  &quot;Then the wall of the house collapsed, and I must go to the funeral.&quot; 
  &quot;It turns out that my brother did not die, but your mother died.&quot; 
  &quot;So the house began to fail.&quot; We must go home. 
  &quot;Not your mother, but your sister passed away.&quot; 
  - A flower fell from my heart - I have to go home. 
  &quot;I checked you.&quot; In fact, your wife died. 
  &quot;If so, then the whole house collapsed and nothing left of it.&quot; Now I do not need to go home. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_20">
		<text>Yes really at least someone began to understand us. Wow. So came insight in life. So listen. Two men went to meet each other. One hurried to the aid of his benefactor, and the other was in a hurry to celebrate. They met each other on a narrow bridge and did not want to give way to each other. They argued, argued and turned to the judge. The judge in their case could not figure it out, led both to the king. 
  The king asked: 
  - Explain to me why you did not want to give each other the way? 
  One of the disputants replied: 
  &quot;Your Majesty, I was in a hurry to celebrate, I met this person on the bridge, but he did not miss me.&quot; 
  The second disputant said: 
  &quot;A man once did me a great favor. Now he&apos;s in trouble. I hurried to his aid. That&apos;s why I did not give way. 
  The king made the following decision: 
  - Anyone who was in a hurry for the holiday should pay damages to those who hurried to help their benefactor. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_baiki_talk">
		<text>What intresnogo of life you can tell?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_baiki_end">
		<text>Quite entertaining.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_1">
		<text>The regiment in which I served had a rather large subsidiary farm. A decent sized greenhouse, a pigsty and even there was a horse named Bouquet.
And in the pigsty, the pigs were looked after by the conscript-martyr, the gypsy by nationality. One winter, a pig was drugged. Everyone was happy, the piglets were counted, entered, and at night one died ... In the morning, he comes to see the girl in childbirth, and the gypsy (I do not remember any name or surname) present him with a newcomer. What should I do? Have written down one.
And the gypsy, do not be a fool, the dead pig did not throw out, but put it in a snowdrift. In a day or two, a living pig takes it (I do not remember it for a long time, I just ate it with the sidekicks, or I sold it to the local), and presents the formerly dead, providently zanykany in the snowdrift.
Have written one more. And he again went to a snowdrift. Alas, with a second attempt to divide the authorities in the same way, the scam failed.
The commander of the regiment was very angry when he was told about it. I personally showed up at the pigsty. For some reason, he especially did not like the receiver standing in the room where this gypsy spent the night. Healthy such, the ancient radiola, in the wooden case. And he forced this soldier to drag this receiver in his arms from the pigsty to the regimental parade ground, where the entire regiment was standing. And then march along with the receiver on the parade ground. And the question asked: &quot;How long?&quot; Answered: &quot;While Nikolai Slichenko does not sing ...&quot;.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_2">
		<text>A large diesel submarine was in the sea, in combat service. According to the daily plan, the so-called emergency response measures were carried out, aimed at preventing later from actual accidents. In the central post the deputy commander of the brigade peacefully gnawed the cracker. The comrade was very violent, but that day he did not touch anyone.
And in the crew of the boat was a midshipman named Fire, a man from the breed of those who are all and always need. This time, for some reason, he suddenly needed a lockbrig. When it turned out that the midshipman was not in the regular place, they gave the command on the boat:
- Report, in which compartment is the midshipman Fire!
The team was given and in the bustle about it was immediately forgotten.
Suddenly, from the diesel compartment, through loud-speaker communication, they reported:
- Central, Fire in the fifth compartment! (But in the oral speech of the capital letters are not visible!
The reaction of the central post was instant and unambiguous. There were short calls, followed by words that made even the thickest skinners shudder:
- Emergency alarm! Fire in the fifth compartment!
It was from what the soul go into the heels. In the diesel compartment, there is even something to burn ...
The boatswain on the team shifted the horizontal rudders to the ascent, the acousticians listened to the horizon tensely (not to collide with anyone on the surface), the bilge were preparing to use a very serious fire-extinguishing system on the fifth compartment.
The central post shouted:
- Fifth! Fifth, report the situation! What is there burning in you ?!
The dieselists answered calmly and embarrassedly:
- Yes, we do not burn anything. There was a command: to report in which compartment the midshipman Fire is, here we reported.
After the cessation of the emergency alarm in the central office, the &quot;analysis of flights&quot; took place with the use of all terms from the naval lexicon. Then zamkombrig announced by loud-speaker communication:
&quot;Attention, comrades, the submariners!&quot; From now on and until the end of the autonomy, this name will be Ivanov !!!.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_3">
		<text>In the early 2000s, I actively participated in the conduct and preparation of various charitable events, where the main trump card was the opportunity not for a non-commercial basis to meet on equal terms with very serious people. Well, the children, of course, help. When organizing one of these events, held in a departmental hotel, I helped a woman from the class &quot;I can do everything, but I do not want anything for myself.&quot; In exchange for a huge amount of work to prepare and raise funds, I was promised several extremely valuable contacts among sponsors.
As a matter of fact, every charity event, especially large-scale, there are 4 main categories of people — these are real sponsors, event organizers together with various artists, etc. &quot;attendants&quot; children or other recipients of charitable aid, and actually, the category you want to stress because of it discussed further — their Majesties Haljavshhiki. Of course, not all freeloaders are full-fledged freeloaders - some of them contribute a small fraction to the fund for helping children, but understand me correctly, if they cover a banquet for sponsors for 100 bucks per person, then they do not expect 200 rubles for the purchased lottery ticket.
At the very beginning of the event, I looked around the hall and noticed each of the 4 groups of guests. There were not many freeloaders this time - they were still in control, but still they were present, because the table was full of food and drinks, and the program included performances of stars and other joys. The evening was divided into 2 parts - during the first there was a story about who is going to get money, children&apos;s performance and in prison - charity auction.
It is on him that there are full freeloaders. For they never buy anything and try not to glow before the auctioneer actively working with the hall, and often even for the time of the auction quietly shed from the audience (charity auctions differ in that they often sell the work of the children themselves, and without active work with the hall In terms of promoting the product of children&apos;s creativity, the proceeds of the auction will be scanty). It was at the auction that I was very surprised by the behavior of one of the freeloaders, who drew my attention from the first glance to the hall. It was a guy of about 30 with a tail, a completely rural look, very simply dressed (although freeloaders always try to merge with others) and with the look of a child from a small Siberian city, who was taken to the Kremlin for the first time in his life. The guy did not even buy a lottery ticket, which completely killed me.
Since the organizer work was just too much, and it all lay on my young shoulders (I was 22 years old), but the event was responsible and as it was said in the well-known film &quot;these are the children!&quot;, In general I gave all the best.
During the interval, the woman I helped fulfilled my promise and really introduced me to several very serious people from Russia and not only.
On my question, is there really someone cool, she hesitated and said that she can not answer. Actually, even the contacts received were enough for serious achievements, and I decided to score.
During the second part there were performances by artists, in whose organizations I took part. And whether the stars so agreed, or the atmosphere had - in general, the holiday was a success on URA with a capital letter - the sponsors were burning eyes, sweat was pouring from me and I had not eaten anything since morning. The freeloader I noticed rejoiced like a child, slapped and ate for both cheeks.
After the end of the event, all guests went around with a piggy bank - they threw in an amount that no one really expected, but freeloaders at best shipped there by a hundred rubles, and my village guest - nothing at all. In general, the woman - organizer was happy. And when the guests began to disperse, she said - &quot;Okay, you helped me a lot, I&apos;ll show you&quot; the hero of our time. &quot;But you will give me my word of honor that you will not tell anyone about him and you will not pester him with questions, he is extremely shy A man and never shines on part of his help.
This man financed the construction of new buildings of our orphanage for 300 children and all the surrounding infrastructure, and besides, he led a gas pipeline to them from the nearest settlement. I gave her my word.
We went out the door of the hotel together and she showed me to that very village guy who got behind the wheel of the usual second-hand Volga.
To say that I had a revolution in my head is not to say anything. The fact is that I personally saw this construction, which was just the simplicity of revolutionary speed. And even at that time I understood very well how much gas is worth pumping and what I need to be, that would be agreed upon in such a short time.
It was at that moment that the understanding of the expression &quot;a truly serious person&quot; came to me.
Since when I&apos;m looking at &quot;freeloaders&quot; at such events, I always remember these children&apos;s eyes full of love and simple joy, and I am looking for such people among them.
Happens - I find. And immediately I understand everything ..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_4">
		<text>It was a long time ago. In the early 90&apos;s. I worked as a young specialist in one famous institute that compiled OUR supercomputers. Money did not pay much and had to be tricked. 
Once we went to another salary in Perm. There, some cooperative sold it to a local plant like NefteorgSintez, to encourage its employees, a batch of Chinese shit (players, toasters, a pair of TV sets). Of course, the percentage of marriage went off over 50. Well, and so, the story:
Having been encouraged by these wonders of technology, we are sitting at the airport, the weather is bad, snowing with rain. Flight to Moscow for the second time postponed. We drink in a restaurant. After a while I understand: I can not drink more - and you can die! Give, I think, I&apos;ll go through the frost - I&apos;ll soot up a bit ... and carried me to the airfield. I look: some military transport is loaded.
- Where are we flying? - I ask.
- To Moscow.
&quot;Take it with you.&quot;
- Carry three bubbles and climb aboard.
— Gut!
I fly with bullet for vodka, a bag with a pair of panties for some reason already with me, and back. Flew very fun. In my opinion, the crew was drinking with us. (I vaguely remember the phrase that was thrown by a man in the pilot&apos;s uniform: &quot;Take off - hnya! The main thing is to sit down!&quot;) We sat down in Zhukovsky. On UAZ, under the tarpaulin, they were taken out of the territory. Then I do not remember. Four hours a night, I sleep in the soft bed of the house. The phone rings. The wife reluctantly picks up the receiver. Through a dream I hear how she tries to say something to the person at that end for about five minutes ... Finally, a phone rings to me with the words: &quot;Tell him this!&quot; &quot;Alla,&quot; I say.
- Who is it? Dimon, are you?
- Well.
Pause.
- Yep your mother! Shithead! Fucking!
Etc.
- We here put all the Perm police on their ears! Man with money is gone! Traffic policemen visiting cars are browsing. The plane left without us (this is a regular flight)! And you, you bastard, you sleep on the soft sofa at home!
In general, the next day I took a sick leave. Just in case...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_5">
		<text>It was a long time ago, when the planes were drunk, and there were no terrorists.
Flying a watch at us, one guy, well, say Vasya. A month at work thumps, the month of the house is fasting, because you will not get very clear. The last day of the watch
Noted with the peasants, and in a state of autopilot with the help of the same miserable aircraft. And picking up the bus from the territory of the base, lies his backpack,
And kind jokers, who are everywhere enough, throw a valve in the backpack.
The valve is such a thing 25 cm long, with a diameter of 8.3 cm and weight of a kilo four.
Everything, loading, flight, meeting with the beloved wife, the salary is immediately selected, Junk from the backpack to the laundry, on the floor of the piece of iron.
&quot;Vasya, why is this?&quot;
Who wants to admit that you were bred and for three thousand miles you dragged an unnecessary piece of iron.
&quot;It&apos;s for the dacha, the right thing, and you go to the store.&quot;
My wife went to the store, Vasya looks angry at the devil with a hangover, and throws him in disgust at the window. Steps of the wife in the hall, on the table, an object is placed on the table, resembling a healing potion of forty revolutions, Vasya opens his eyes.
- Vasechka, you pulled this spare part, I&apos;m going from the store, I look under the window the same is lying.
The Vasin Valve stands proudly on the table ..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_6">
		<text>He gave his duty to the Motherland as a radio-radio operator at the reserve command post &quot;Zhilny&quot; in 1978-1980. I had a habit of saluting officers without their headdress. We had a deputy major in charge, I do not remember Fio, the shit was terrible. Our commander, Filipok, Phillipov, commander from God, called me. I go into the office and as I should by the statute report, attaching my right hand to my temple. And since he was on alert, removing headphones did not put on a pilot&apos;s jacket. 
With Philip was also our deputy. He says:
- Do not put an arm against an empty head.
I would not say anything, but the devil pulled me to answer:
- There is also a head in a cap with a cockade buzzing like an empty jug.
Filipok smiled, and the deputy politician skewed. All, I think, the lip is assured.
After listening to the order and replying:
&quot;Yes, allow me to do it.&quot; I left the office.
I do not know how other officers learned about this incident, but within three hours I began to prophesy to become a general.
By the way, all the officers when meeting with us, the soldiers of urgent service after giving honor greeted the hand, one zampolit never gave his hand ..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_7">
		<text>The usual hose is a long rubber gut. &quot;To pretend to be a hose&quot; for a Soviet soldier is the same as playing in misunderstandings, passively sabotaging the orders of the commanders&apos; fathers. Sometimes at the expense of their colleagues, so &quot;planes&quot; - those who take the service seriously and by any means gain positive points in the eyes of their bosses (they are cut off) - do not really like hoses. However, there are hoses in the law, similar to the Russian spy Shtirlitsa: &quot;What to catch it, he&apos;s cunning still get out.&quot; They are treated with love.
A rare soldier-conscript does not want to return home as soon as possible. Most often they dream of it. Someone tries to bite. In our part there was a legend about a soldier who, for the first time entering the barracks, immediately went to look for the heaviest weight, and after discovering it, immediately began to swing his right hand. He was engaged in this every free moment, being in every way encouraged for such zeal by a company commander. Just a month later, the kid came to the hospital and said:
- At me, that, the left hand dries ...
Nachmed personally measured the circumference of the biceps of both hands, but only naturally recorded the difference in the results, as was required by the instruction ...
&quot;Let&apos;s check the trend, warrior,&quot; said the major, slightly surprised. After a couple of weeks of even more intensive training with weight, the difference increased, and by the end of the calendar month the comic soldier went to his native Grodno ...
Followers of it for some reason was not, apparently, even very stupid it was clear that the epidemic of desiccations would not go unnoticed ..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_8">
		<text>This story occurred at a time when my uncle served in the ranks of the Soviet army, around 80 years.
As if in their military unit, two soldiers brought sand on the dump truck of the ZIL system. In principle, a truck-dumper is very convenient thing, drove up where it should, jerked the lever, and loose material falls out into a neat pile, yielding to the laws of gravity. But as it was in the deep fall with variable rains and frost, the sand in the back of the truck was a little freezing. And to get enough sleep, as far as the slope, not really wanted. However, the driver with the partner was an example of a healthy pofigizma and judged that at the highest point of the body lifting the sand will not hold in any case and the sky will fall to the earth. Usually this is what happens, but our comrades pofigists did not take into account that they put the car under a slight bias. And not the poured sand seriously increases the center of gravity of their typewriter, as a result ZILok falls to one side (with the sand finally falling off the body), in the cabin, of course, fall on each other our soldiers.
The history, however, is quite ordinary - dump trucks are capsized quite often. The most interesting happens right after the fall, a crowd of soldiers who watched with interest the process of unloading immediately rises to the cabin of ZIL, with powerful brushes and improvised materials, knocks out almost all the glass and pulls out two of our comrades from the cabin, grabbing for anything, as a result of one torn The form of the second is scratched face.
As it turned out, the watching soldiers were frightened of the explosion and decided to heroically save our drivers ..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_9">
		<text>I do not remember who told me this story, but it was so. This story happened back in the days of the Soviet army. In one of the areas of our vast country there was a military unit, I do not remember what direction. Either infantry, or artillery, but it does not matter. So imagine, a quiet, dark summer night, the whole part of sleeping strong, bogatyrskim sleep. In one of the barracks, as are awake duty Rota (Sergeant starosluzhashhij, who left retirement just over a month) and private-Soviet (only to &quot;spirit&quot;) a young stands on the bedside table, all the forces struggling with sleep, and Sergeant hard snoozing in the so-called &quot;Leninist room&quot; at once, as this will play a role in future, on-call and have one&apos;s Messman&apos;s only weapon is a knife bayonet, which meet strict as for other weapons.
And one fine moment when the night was in full swing, the young soldier suddenly realizes that either his stomach has not yet adjusted to soldier&apos;s food, or he has caught some infection, or both. And that if he does not take urgent action, then all the contents of his intestine drain into his boots. Exhausted and full of flour in a whisper, not to wake the company, he calls the duty officer. He whispered and whispered and cursing all the &quot;spirits&quot; who do not let him calmly finish his demobilization, asks the reason for which his sweet dream was broken. Young quickly, clearly and briefly, as taught by the military regulations, sets out the cause of the alarm. The sergeant, grumbling and again cursing all the young and their tender mother&apos;s mamas, lets the orderly go to the toilet, and he gets up. It should be noted that the fruits of civilization in the form of sewerage have not yet reached this part, and for the management of natural needs there was a stand-alone wooden toilet, in the most remote place, with three points, and without any partitions. 
And now, young with an enviable speed, having overcome the distance from the barracks to the sanostroeniya, unbuttoning his ammunition, perched on one of the holes and blissfully relaxed. And then, at the very apogee of this action, the bayonet knife, issued for the defense of the Motherland, slides off the belt and falls into the hole with a deaf and mocking &quot;bully&quot;. When a soldier understands what has happened, the forces of the urge of his fifth point intensify threefold. There are scenes in his head like he will be judged for the loss of military weapons, but even worse, what the sergeant will do to him - &quot;demobilized&quot; Collecting the remnants of his will, sweating with fear, he flocks to the barracks and tells all the sergeant. 
When the sergeant understands that he will be bailed out no less, and maybe more, and that his demobil will be moved to the very end of the line, the urge in his stomach begins already with him. But the Russian soldier, as they say, is unbeatable and will find a way out of any situation. Without thinking twice, the sergeant finds, as it seems to him, the only solution at the moment. He dresses a young man in a suit OZK (combined arms protective kit, designed to protect against chemical weapons), a gas mask and sends it back. Type, go, dive, look and without a knife do not come back. Young, not hesitating, he began to execute the order. 
But now, not lucky, at this very time, the duty officer, a major of the Soviet army, was impatient. He goes to the above-mentioned institution and, with a pacified look, settles himself over the hole. 
And now imagine the reaction of the major, when from the next point, suddenly something crawls out in a gas mask, all in shit and with a dagger in his hand. As the assistant on duty later explained, the major flew into the duty room with wild eyes, with one hand supporting unfastened pants, the other hand waving the timekeeper Makarov, he was carrying shit on a verst and was yelling furiously, either about the saboteurs, or About the evil spirit. 
As a result, the part was raised by alarm. After the proceedings, both soldiers were stuck in for 15 days of guardhouse, and the major was sent to heal nerves ..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_10">
		<text>Here is how it was. In one of the military units, training jumps were conducted. The very process of a jump, as such, with the usual airborne parachute (D-5) does not seem quite complicated. 
Drop out over the side of the plane, you think to yourself: &quot;501, 502, 503&quot; - and after this, flying at least 60 meters during this time, you try to find the filled dome of your parachute over your head. Finding the dome in the proper place, you land carefully. At all, everything happened according to plan - fell out, opened the dome, landed. But the trouble is, one poor fellow was unlucky. No, the dome opened, but he did not reach the ground. A gust of wind carried it to the pines that surrounded the landing area. And here&apos;s a picture of butter: in the branches of a mighty ship pine at an altitude of about 10 meters, dangles, in the manner of puppets, a fighter. It is not possible to reach the trunk, it&apos;s possible to crawl up the slings, but there is still the same problem of descent to the ground. Usually, in such cases they open a spare parachute (it is located on the chest) and, using its slings, descend to the ground. Since the fighter is young, several advisers hurried to him at once. After enjoying the picture, everyone began to shout in chorus: &quot;Toss the spare!&quot;. Then everything happened like in a movie. Already an orderly frightened paratrooper snatched the strapping cutter ... in one fell swoop broke the lines of the main parachute and in the fall pulled the ring of the spare parachute ...
R. S. I have to admit that the record for skydiving from super low altitudes was not established at that time ..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_11">
		<text>There was a student in my group at the military department, named Yellow. Masturbation is unique, apparently from the womb yet. Well, it happened with him the usual trouble for students - during self-training caught his officer-teacher enthusiastically playing cards with another blast ... well, that is, a student. 
As punishment, the children were left after class, gave them a bucket of quick-drying paint, brushes and an order to paint all the tables and chairs that were in the classroom. The work was done, handed over to the duty officer, the brushes were cleaned ...
The next morning the cleaning lady came to wash the floors and the first thing she did was turn all the chairs over, putting them on the tables. Her second action was a trip to the teaching, where she returned from the deputy. The head of the department and demonstrated to him repeatedly repeated on the reverse unpainted side of the chairs familiar to all from childhood three letters. A couple of cheerful painters appeared on the same day before the bright eyes of the head of the department.
&quot;Well, then what are you doing, comrade students, your mother, do?&quot; The chief scolded them gently.
Yellow suddenly stretched out into the frut, clicked his heels and reported
&quot;Excuse me, Comrade Colonel, it broke out!&quot;
&quot;It&apos;s how many times you broke out,&quot; the Colonel marveled.
- But how much broke, so much and wrote - phlegmatically finished Yellow ..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_12">
		<text>I worked then at the Institute of Instrument Engineering, that in Moscow on Kutuzovsky, there still near the entrance to the monument to the pilot-hero Valentine Grizodubova, who was driving there, probably paid attention to a granite woman with an airplane helmet. During the Soviet years, systems for on-board radar systems were developed there, after the collapse of the USSR, they basically switched to commercial orders, they had to eat something for something. And then the task was coming from the Ministry of Defense to create a kind of &quot;black box&quot;, about the appointment of which, for obvious reasons, I will not tell. About the fact that in the process of setting up a few hours to sit in the technical compartment of the A-50 - it&apos;s not in the soft chair of the &quot;Boeing&quot; cognac to sip, I will not tell, the story is not about that. Colonels-generals from the ministry came to check the prototype of our product. One of the points of the act of acceptance-transfer is a test for the tightness of the shell. The case has a cunning form, but for simplicity of description let it be just a cube with an edge per meter. The test procedure for hermeticity is purely Soviet, no complex measuring instruments, the body with the help of a winch is drowned in a giant aquarium made of thick Plexiglas, the depth of three meters. If there are bubbles of air in the water - according to the test procedure, the product is rejected entirely, together with the electronics inside.
Have seen in the movies of abandoned factories? The room with the aquarium looked about the same, and the aquarium was last washed, probably in Soviet times. The poured water became rusty-unclear. The winch, which pulls the tested product underwater for a long time, was stolen, probably handed over to scrap metal. They called the worker to drown the body with his hands. Let me remind you that this is not an air ball, it is a large hermetically sealed aluminum cube. The worker could not be drowned alone. We, simple engineers, refused to help the worker, our work is to invent schemes, not to play cubes. But the warriors took the initiative of the worker, three men in uniform with a bunch of stars rolled up their sleeves, climbed onto the ramp around the aquarium and shouted &quot;one, two, three!&quot; Began to push down the stubborn corps. 
It was almost possible for them to do this. At the last moment, the cube tumbled on its side, and all but the prudent worker could not resist and found themselves in the aquarium. Those who stood side by side, bounced away and shook the dirty water from their clothes, the &quot;bulka&quot; was not sickly. The aquarium started chaos, try to imagine what is happening: the warriors are trying to climb out, someone is constantly attacking someone, sending him down (and the depth is about three meters), then falls himself, and already attack him. The picture is supplemented by a floating metal cube floating around in a circle, for which they tried to grab, as for a life ring, and he kept turning over and beating another pop-up on various parts of the body. The phrase &quot;b @ d, help the same&quot; was the most censored, the rest of the cries of warriors and the words of the watchers will not lead. 
This lasted for half a minute, and maybe more, until the worker, who had fallen on the ramp, came out of the stupor and gave his hand to the drowning man. Dirty soldiers in a drenched form completely taken somewhere, probably, treated 40-degree sedative, and the &quot;presentation&quot; of the device on this ended. We smoked, discussed what had happened, and went on to work. Contrary to expectations, no one &quot;flew in&quot;. And later it became known that our &quot;black box&quot; was admitted to armament, although a couple of tests after visiting the &quot;free pool&quot; by the host committee (we were joking) did not get the device.
PS. Before the arrival of high officials, the product was, of course, preliminarily subjected to all checks, except for bathing in the notorious aquarium, this experienced specimen can still fly on one of the &quot;Russian Avaks.&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_13">
		<text>I happened to be somehow in the hospital with the most banal radiculitis. Years by the time I was about 25, a dude, a favorite of women and that&apos;s Don Juan. To make an accurate diagnosis, they decide to take a picture of the spinal column. And for this seemingly very simple procedure, it turns out that the enema is made beforehand so that all sorts of excesses in the intestine do not interfere with the entire set of my intervertebral hernias in the picture (alas, even in such young years this happens with the back).
After taking a good roll of toilet paper, I come to where it says. Considerable size of the cabinet (whether procedural, or figs it knows-one of three). Mature aunt in a white coat. Get laid down, grit, my dear, here, on the couch, on the barrel. Lay down. Got a &quot;dose.&quot; My aunt leaves. I look - in the corner of the room a toilet. Without any hints at any partitions and booths. He simply whitens himself lonely in a corner, invitingly beckons. And he put it on such a foundation, and if you climb on it, you will necessarily look like some proud mountain bird on the rock. And the process inside me is already going on with might and main. I jump to the door, I&apos;m looking for something that does not look like a latch, the lock - no! I look out into the corridor, I estimate the distance to the known to me male institution. I understand with all my inner self that I will not make it there, and I jump to the white-tailed eagle on the white toilet bowl.
As it later turned out, on that day the hospital was full of interns from a local medical school. The picture is not for the nerve: in the &quot;red&quot; corner of the room, on the very, it is possible to say, frontal place, the young eagle is sitting proudly, holding a roll of paper claws in claws. The process of preparing the spine for the photo session is in full swing and we will not stop it practically. Every minute the door to the room opens, a pretty head of an innocent creature appears in a white coat:
&quot;Is Mari-Ivanna here?&quot; Oh!
Another minute. Another no less handsome head:
&quot;And Mar-Ivanna ... Oh!&quot;
How many of the trainees were lucky enough to observe the proud bird sitting on that accursed faience ledge, now I do not remember. There were many of them. And one another is prettier. Only I was somehow not very happy ....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_14">
		<text>It was in the Army. I studied at the Irkutsk Military Aviation School together with my brother. We are twins. Not that they are exactly alike, but you can not figure it out with a run. Once during the exams, my brother thundered into the medical unit (put him).
And how can he take the exam, if he is not released from the medical unit (army, yap her)? I refused to take the exam for both at once, but to lie down for a little while, until he passes the exam - why not? So, I passed the examination that day, ran to the medical unit, changed my clothes with the brother. And the thing is that I&apos;ve never been in a medical unit and do not know where everything is. Well, there is nothing to be done, the brother explained to me: you will go up to the second floor, you will come to such and such a room, you will find such a bed in such and such a row - it&apos;s yours! I found this bed without any problems, lay down. I lie, I enjoy life. Well, I think I&apos;ll sleep after the exam.
After about 5 minutes, the nurse comes in and says: &quot;Mrs on the injection!&quot; I was thrown from the bed, shouting: &quot;What kind of shot? I&apos;m healthy.&quot; She: &quot;I do not know anything, I&apos;m waiting in the Procedural&quot;. Well, I think everything, I&apos;m stuck, specifically! For the brother I will now be spoiled. I think, what to do? And it occurred to me a crazy idea to sit tight in the toilet.
I rested in the toilet for about 20 minutes. Well, I think it&apos;s time to go out. I creep out of the toilet with the thought of getting into the ward. I look, there is some madam in a dressing-gown. She saw me and said: &quot;Oh, Mrs, well, take these tanks to the dining room.&quot; П-ец !!! How do I know where they have a canteen here? I took the tanks and the cellar along the corridor, hoping that I was going in the right direction. Madame jamb on me presses: type what is it he brakes? I walk along the corridor, mother to myself, and read the tablets on the door. On the last door I saw the inscription &quot;Dining room&quot;.
Well, thank God! Found! I threw these tanks and jumped into the room. And only I lay down, again this nurse: &quot;Mrs, how much you can wait? But come on.&quot; And that&apos;s all! Still, I got my portion of penicillin in the ass for a bro. Then we laughed for a long time, especially I ..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_15">
		<text>This ridiculous story happened in the glorious, still Soviet army. They sent the cadets to clean the howitzer. The people are bustling about with a bath-house, everyone is running back and forth, a lot of water is sprayed with a special detergent, consisting of SEVEN alkalis!
As this happened in our country, the cadets cleaned the gun without protective suits or even gloves. And then, one of them was impatient &quot;for the little one.&quot;
He went to piss, returned to the system. He feels, somehow he becomes uncomfortable, and most importantly, every minute the discomfort is stronger and stronger! Looked, baaaaa! The member swelled up, blushed and became four times more than usual!
Since there was no one remotely familiar with the medicine at that time, the cadet just washed the damaged organ well, was wrapped in bandages (clumsily) and sent to the medical unit.
The doctor was not there. In the waiting room sat only a young girl-paramedic. Throwing a stern look at the wounded soldier, the girl asked:
&quot;Well, what&apos;s the matter with the serviceman?&quot;
- Yes, here ... look ...
A little shy, the guy points at his unbuttoned fly, from which the bandaged member of the Gordian knot stands.
- Lord! What did you do to him !? (The nurse was genuinely surprised)
- I cleaned the gun ...
To finish the speech to the cadet have not given, from wild laughter of the girl-medical assistant and in time arrived in time the doctor, the work of the medical unit was simply paralyzed !.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_16">
		<text>I served in Germany. This here in Russia could have been both a layoff and wolves, and there, even if they let go, where to go? Everywhere the Germans! Once we went to the field exit. When they were in place, according to the word of mouth, they learned that not very far there is a lake where the beach of nudists was located, that in the mid-eighties there was something unimaginable for understanding, and one thought about it could be compared with the capacity of five kilotons of Viagra. - That&apos;s great! - I told Igor, and began to think about the plan of events.
The next evening, due to the temporary absence of officers, we decided to use the chance. Of the number who previously showed courage to go, the three of us remained - Igor, Musa and I. The rest began to screw up the brain and otmazalis. In short, zassali. As real scouts, we agreed to be on the beach undetected, disguised as Germans. The lake was not big, and we decided to swim on the other side and go ashore, as if nothing had happened. And now, we are on the other side of the lake, we pull together the HB. There began to creep into doubts about the possibility of being unnoticed.
Musa was all in portals like &quot;GSVG&quot;, &quot;I love as an angel,&quot; I laugh &quot;like a demon&quot;, well, and other combinations of soldier&apos;s folklore. Nipples were everywhere, aggravated by dense black vegetation, starting from the top and to the heels. There was a feeling that there was a snowman in front of us. In short, he was not very much like a German. But being a man from the mountains, Musa had good eyesight and a hot temper. Apparently already having seen boobs in his natural binoculars, Musa immediately somehow tensed with his little brother. &quot;No, I will not take off my panties,&quot; he said. Despite the fact that our secret journey will be revealed at the first glance at Musa, we nevertheless tried to persuade him to remove these blue, washed-out HB panties, which our army is famous for, which we could not without effort.
Musa was all hoo. And here we are swimming in the middle of the lake like real Germans, the first bare fragments are already flickering, women&apos;s voices are already audible, we are already on the shore and are on the shore. Previously, with an effort of will, suppressing in oneself all natural instincts to which even cold water did not act, Igor and I went ashore, trying not to look around, and lay down on the sand, as if nothing had happened. Only after that we found out that Musa is waist-deep in water with a wide open mouth and broader eyes.
The nearby Germans smiled. From the bushes of hair on Musa&apos;s breast a parachute with the Cyrillic alphabet peeped out, but Musa still believed that he looked like a German. We began to imperceptibly give signs, they say, let&apos;s go out. Musa somehow shook his head incomprehensibly and answered in a purely German language: &quot;Nine!&quot; After standing for about fifteen minutes as dead in the cold water, Musa drew the attention of half the beach, causing smiles and encouraging phrases in German, shimmering with red shades of embarrassment under the wool. It&apos;s time to save a friend, we thought. Entering the water and coming to him from behind, we began to carefully push him to the shore.
Musa resisted, swearing for some reason in Russian, as a radio operator Kat during childbirth, revealing military secrets. Unable to withstand our pressure, Musa was at the very shore. Realizing that it was not easy for us to cope with it, he fell on his stomach. But just as the secrecy of our operation was already broken, laughing loudly and waving anything, we dragged Musa by the hands to the sand to the sonorous &quot;I your mother&quot; laughed &quot;&quot; and the applause of the spectators. Musa and lay all the time on his stomach, attracting to us local female representatives. As a result, we several times with Igor went to wolf in the nearest village to newly baked girlfriends, but already without Musa.
Z. Y. Back in the water, Musa ran very quickly).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_17">
		<text>One pilot served in our regiment, he was famous for having sat down on a jet four times forced on a jet plane with a stalled engine. The fourth time was the most fun)
And it was so. 
The airfield was on the Lena River. It took off normally, but at an altitude of 600 meters the engine stalled.
I must say that the jet aircraft without a traction engine fly like a brick, thrown out of the window. So what to do? Below him is the city, and ahead of it directly at the rate - Lena, straight as an arrow, thick ice, winter in the yard, translates
He is a plane in a dive and pushed to the river. We must add that he was flying to the test site, under the wings of the bomb, the missiles were hanging, in general, the kind of zashibis.
In short, sits on the belly and slides on the ice, glides well - the speed of something go-go. Slipped two kilometers, stopped, opens the cockpit&apos;s lantern and sees that literally five yards away from him the man catches fish, wrapped himself up
With his head in the sheepskin coat and, of course, hears nothing. Then our brave flyer unzips the oxygen mask and yells: &quot;Hey, buddy, you took my hole!&quot;
The little mover turns and when he saw what the comrade was on the fishing trip he asked such a swinger that according to the pilot&apos;s words and afterburner it would not catch up. This is the story that happened in our glorious air force,
When kerosene was in bulk ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_18">
		<text>This is a real case that happened to me in the Caucasus Mountains in the spring of the 95th shaggy year. I then studied in Krasnodar at the journal of the Moscow Economic University (Kuban branch) and regularly visited the mountains with a backpack in the company of the same amateur (and self-ambitious) tourists. Outfit - at best a few meters of rope, sometimes an ice ax. On that expedition we conquered Mount Achishkho. Who does not know is in the vicinity of the upcoming Olympics. Then, almost twenty years ago - the places are pretty wild. The ascent we started on the second day, after spending the night on some half-dead camping site. The mountain, in principle, is not difficult. The climber does nothing there, if only to practice on the rocks. For the tourist it is. Slope, although steep, but you can climb without special equipment. The main difficulty at that time was in weather conditions. End of April - beginning of May. The slope, the mountain and the plateau are covered, well, with a very thick layer of snow. A lot of deep cracks, avalanche danger, of course. Plus, a strong wind with wet snow. In that campaign at zero, about the temperature, I froze my left hand. In the right there was an ice ax, she worked and was not injured. However, this is prehistory.
At one &quot;beautiful&quot; moment, when the pass was a hundred meters to the pass, and the steepness of the slope went over 60 degrees (I can lie, but it was very cool), I decided that it would be easier to move to the left of the main group. Because they did not go in a bundle - it was decided - done. I understood my mistake in five meters. But it was too late to go down and I tried to go back to the previous course horizontally. Snowball underfoot is not too caked, rather wet and devilishly unreliable. In general, I slipped and rolled down no worse than a bobsledder. There was no fear, only the feeling that everything was not happening to me. In the beginning he tried to brake the ice ax. Then I picked up speed, I was thrown up and put my forehead against something hard. From the head flew off the cap &quot;Afghan&quot;, but the worst - with this blow I was hit by glasses. With my &quot;eagle eye&quot; -7 - this is equivalent to almost complete blindness. And so, somersaulting, I flew two hundred meters. In itself came already at some site. I lay face down and nothing I do not need. The hardest part was getting myself to get to my feet. I got up, I just shook everything, I could not feel my hands, I do not feel my legs, but it seems like nothing hurts. Mind I understand that the hike is broken, without eyes, now I have only one way - to the valley with a good guide. Ten minutes later I see our commander Gennady Ognev coming down from the fog, (unfortunately he is no longer alive, he died in the mountains).
&quot;Aim?&quot;
- Alive like ...
- Now ...
Goes down a few meters down and comes back with my cap.
&quot;You&apos;ll catch cold on your head.&quot;
With a stifling tongue, I ask if he has seen my glasses anywhere. Gennady laughs nervously and reasonably notes that I dug up the snow better than any tractor, and my cracked body cracks the cracks as well as the slalom. So, the archeologists will find the glasses in 25 thousand years. And here comes the incredible. The commander suddenly bends down and pulls out the POINT from beneath the sole of my left boot. THE WHOLE!
&quot;Well, the guy will live for a hundred years.&quot;
I would never have believed in such luck, if it had not happened to me personally.
... And after half an hour, on the pass, Svetlana from our group fed us with a hand of chocolate, her own hands did not work.
... And the next night in the premises of an abandoned weather station in the vicinity of Achishkho, I saw a real ghost. .</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_19">
		<text>Somehow celebrated the birthday of one girl. I and her several responsible partners came on time, but the rest of the guests were late. For obvious reasons, no one was waiting for them to late-the booze was in full swing. 
Those who appeared just wrote a penalty and took a friendly campaign.
When about 30% of the guests gathered, everyone was already fairly on gas. The culprit of the celebration went to the toilet. A couple of minutes we hear - from the toilet are heard the cries of a drunk girl:
- Open the door!
We, as true gentlemen simply could not leave the lady in trouble and, under friendly hooting, carefully removed the door to the toilet from the hinges. The first thing we heard from a girl sitting on a push in the pose of a proud eagle was the words:
- DOLBOBS! INLET DOOR OPEN ....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_baiki_20">
		<text>It was during the second company in the Chechen Republic (Chechen Republic). A group of heroes safely completed a business trip and got to Mazdok without any losses (who knows, he understands what they mean) was waiting for the board in the camp on the territory of the airfield. 
At that time, in the area of ??the Mozdok airfield there was a transshipment base, a large tent village (or a small tent city, as you like) with streets, lanes, headquarters (city hall), canteen, etc., etc. Attributes. To the heroes, two tents (dozens) are set aside at the edge of the village, but all fell into one (the collective is edenat), well, and having bought the last travel medicine for stress in the local pharmacy (boiler room) went to nirvana (and the board was to arrive the next morning) . Among the heroes was a cynologist Minorozychnoy specialization with a dog (spaniel bitch) nicknamed Katya. Waking up in the area (shorter than daylight), he did not find a dog that slept in the legs at night. Deciding that Katya had left for dog business and found a need for herself, only a human being, the cynologist left the tent and did not find his partner within sight, began to call out quietly at first, not to wake the camp, and then louder - Katya, Katya where you are. With this appeal began to bypass all the nearest streets and lanes of the camp, the dogs where not nebylo. And then he was visited by a terrible thought (reinforced with not completely evaporated pairs of anti-stress medication) - The dog was lost !!! Board in a couple of hours, it can not be canceled, in general, a complete PI! With these thoughts and groans already in full voice - Katya, Katenka where you are my girl, went to the main street (where the headquarters, dining room, etc.) which was already coming out to the launch. Then a girl&apos;s head protrudes from one of the tents and says it playfully: &quot;I&apos;m here, and at the same time Katya appears from the next tent, expressing herself guilty for what she did (evidently she went to the smells of eating). At the cynologist, a man&apos;s tearful tear stitches away, he does not restrain from the soul, but the soul demands retribution and the soul gives out to the whole camp - Oh, you&apos;re a bitch, oh, you&apos;re a prostitute, on someone else&apos;s tent sharisya. A second later, the camp is covered with wild cackling.
It turns out (well, it coincided), l / s celebrated the birthday of the local serviceman Katerina, which lasted until the morning and no one imagined that a namesake would temporarily appear in the camp and with her would happen such an unpleasant story, which was later recalled for a long time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_afgan_talk">
		<text>I heard that some stalkers served in hot spots. Do you know anything about the Afghan and Chechen wars? May be stories of eyewitnesses?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_afgan_end">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_1">
		<text>One friend recently told a story. Now I&apos;ll tell you. The intelligence department of the 5th Khad Office managed to introduce its agent to the dushmans. In Pakistan, he was rebuffed and sent back to Kabul with the task to blow up the school, gave out two kilograms of plastic, a piece of a fire-cord about a meter in length and two detonator caps. He brought all this to Khad and reported on the assignment received. The KGB advisors asked me to conduct an examination and give a conclusion: is this really an explosive? I pinched off a piece of plastic and held a lit match. The people shied in different directions. The plastic flared with a bright flame. The fire-proof cord also caught fire as expected. Everything is fine, the quality is excellent. To test the detonators, one of them will have to be tested. However, the advisers did not want too much noise in the arrangement. Thinking what to do next. You can not blow up a school and do not perform a test task to an agent. The school was located in the airport area and was a two-storey wooden structure, similar to a barn. I put my eye on the &quot;imported&quot; explosives and offered to advisers:
  - Guys, give it to me. Imported explosives are needed for foreign shares. In return, I will make you a bomb from Soviet plastic. The explosion will be all right: in the whole district, glasses will fly out, and the school will not suffer.
  The senior adviser narrowed his eyes cunningly.
  - And maybe you decided to decorate it as your trophy?
  - Ugh! - I was offended and left.
  The next day, from my Afghan colleagues, I was the first to learn about the nightly dushmans sabotage. A patrol in the darkness noticed a man fumbling over a cable well near the school and called to him. The unknown man started off. Sarbozy [4 - Sarboz - soldier.] Bent over the hatch to see what was the matter. At that moment, there was an explosion. Two soldiers were injured. In addition, the power cable was closed and the wooden school was burnt to the ground.
  In the morning, I congratulated the advisers on the successful operation. They turned pale and rushed to their sub-cedars. Returned sour, reported to their superiors. The chief reacted to what had happened philosophically:
  - But how cool we have encrypted the agent!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_2">
		<text>I heard something. This is our coach on the cordon at the fire told me. Now remember and tell. Unarmed Khochal approaches the gates of the villa, where our hero took refuge. Here, on his troubles jeep &quot;jeep&quot;. Hoshalu almost point-blank from the PM a bullet in the neck. Seeing the fallen Khoshal, the soldier of the operational regiment beats on the &quot;jeep&quot; from the RPG-7. Two more militants are sneaking along the wall. Wounded and also shell-shocked by a nearby grenade explosion, Khoshal picks up a gun from which he just got a bullet and shoots militants. Khoshal is being carried away. The car is on fire. The villa was hiding. On the stage, Rashid&apos;s friend appears. He instructs the grenade launcher to open fire on the windows. However, both grenades go just above the roof and explode somewhere in the city. Rashid sends the driver with the keys from his office. He has four one-time American-made M-72 grenade launchers under my couch (my gift). Soon the driver returns with grenade launchers. Rashid neatly inserts into each window a shot. Hearing cries, smokes smoke. The sobered and frightened prince from the basement calls the MGB on the phone, asks him to stop the fire. He has a bunch of corpses. He surrenders.
  We visit Khoshal in the hospital. Two of his submachine gunners are on duty at his bunk and the doors of the ward around the clock. The prince managed to order his subordinates to liquidate the entire command of the operational regiment along with the advisers. He, of course, got excited. We have absolutely nothing to do with it. However, our leadership has sounded the alarm:
  - Fuck with them, with several advisers, it will be worse if we lose Kandahar!
  Prince can not be killed, you need to calm. He is immediately sent to Sochi with two faithful wives. With him, he took two bags of money: one with dollars, the other with checks of &quot;outsourcing&quot;.
  For the sake of justice, it should be noted that the Pope-King publicly condemned the trick of his unreasonable offspring. Upon his return from the Union, the prince returned to his fiefdom, in Kandahar. However, the relatives of the murdered militants ran into the prince. He escaped the cordon. Soon he sent a tearful letter to one of the KGB advisers, invited him to ... Pakistan.
  Khoshal croaked quickly. Surprisingly, the 9 mm Makarov bullet passed between the trachea and the carotid artery, not catching the vital nerves, vessels and skeleton.
  Rashid was in the stupid role of the enemy&apos;s blood enemy yesterday&apos;s friend and drinking companion. We need to prepare for disassembly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_3">
		<text>Yes, it used to be poisoned by guys who are older than campfires. Recently, that&apos;s what I told you. A narrow path, near by the aryk with water. Around thick thickets. After a few meters nothing is visible. The path winds and disappears behind the turn. An ambush in the forehead! A 50-meter piece detonating cord, to it every 5 meters attached hand grenade, only ten grenades. All this fits into the irrigation ditch with water and is masked from above by grass. This time we will carry out a detonation using an electric detonator. Garnet rings are pulled out. Their trigger arms are held by twine wrapped around the cord. By moving closer to the enemy&apos;s head patrol, the demoman presses the button. Explosion! How will a normal fighter do if he explodes half a meter from his leg? Naturally, he will fall on the path. If even the Mujahideen quickly come to their senses and start turning their heads around, it will be too late: grenades are lying around.
  Cracked grenade ruptures! Now our machine-gunner should be pressed to the ground of the remaining &quot;spirits&quot; with long bursts in the bushes, while the demolisher flees with all his might!
  Since in the &quot;zelenok&quot; head patrol moves at a distance of visibility (5-10 meters) from the core of the column, we with our minami-grenades necessarily catch from five to seventeen &quot;spirits.&quot; Trophies are useless. Our task is to embed them properly, so that more of our street is not walking. For educational purposes we use grenades RGD-5. In the combat situation will have to put the F-1. The radius of solid defeat F-1 is 3.7 meters. For accuracy, reduce to 2, 5 meters. Therefore, if every five meters in the column of the enemy, even lying on the ground, explode on a grenade - will not seem a little.
  Tests on the testing range showed that a detonating cord can be thrown grenades F-1 at a distance of 0.5 to 15 meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_4">
		<text>I did not want to remember this much. From the words of one experienced warrior I&apos;ll tell you perhaps one bike. As the workload in the Pagmansky school increased, so did the number of accidents. However, without fatalities. Several times I got myself. The main reason for &quot;PE&quot; was that we used exclusively captured ammunition, often spoiled in dushman crude dumps (others I simply did not give).
  So, every third or fourth mine to the 82-mm mortar did not fire. Imagine the kind of hassle the extraction of a mine from the trunk turned into? Trouble was also brought to the Chinese RPG-2 grenade launcher. Their knock-out charges equipped with black, smoky powder, had a nasty property of dampening. So, twice instead of a shot, the gunpowder burned slowly, and the grenades, flying their trunks, fell a few meters from the gunner. One, thank God, did not explode. And the other, jerking, crooked splinters of three, including myself. This incident occurred during the second business trip. At the villa, soaping under the shower, I found on my body a lot of small acne, which somehow scraped palms. Looked closer - smaller pieces. I had to pick with a needle. A neighbor on the bunk, Alexander Ivanovich, seeing my belly garnished with belly, became alarmed:
  - Go to the doctor, sepsis may start!
  - Yeah, the doctor will report to the authorities, I will be arranged on a knuckle and will not be allowed to work.
  I found a large fragment in a leather purse, which was in my trouser pocket: it got stuck without breaking a thick pack of money - &quot;afghani&quot;. If the fragment had hit the width of the palm to the right, it would have ended sadly. In this regard, Counselor Vitaly the next day, poisoned a fresh anecdote:
  - Beck returns from a business trip, the joyful spouse meets him, asks what gift he brought from Afghanistan? And sad Beck takes out of his pocket a dried man&apos;s nature on a string.
  Another reason for the accidents was that at the special forces school I was still preparing &quot;supplies&quot;. The needs of the front required a large number of qualified fighters. They should not be afraid of close explosions and the whistle of bullets. As an example, I can compare the effectiveness of the work of two teachers sent from Moscow: for half a year my colleague, who was preparing pyrotechnics for a special laboratory, released ten Afghans. Over the same period I learned more than a hundred special forces. But this does not mean that their preparation was worse. Observant Afghans concluded: explosions are feared by either absolutely uninformed people or by professionals who know a lot. My students, it turns out, occupied an intermediate stage of nothing afraid of semi-professionals.
  What did not happen during the class. Once they shot at their feet from the AGS-17, another time a heavy trophy mine of 82-mm mortar fell in twenty meters from the gunmen. The cadet by mistake, instead of a regular knockout cartridge, was equipped with a mine by a cartridge of a hunting rifle of the 12th caliber.
  A nightmare episode occurred when an OGM-72 jumped mine landed in the hands of an Afghan! If it exploded, two thousand balls would turn us into mince! Fortunately, the mine was without a detonator capsule, so she just flew up into the air for about twenty meters and, slightly touching the Afghan tangent on her forehead, sent him to a deep knockout, and we, all sitting around, fell into a stupor for a few seconds.
  Cadets often received scratches, throwing hand grenades RGD-5 and RKG-3m standing. There were two explosions when they picked up unexploded ordnance at the site. The main thing at the training ground is to protect your eyes, you need to wear protective goggles.
  One unpleasant incident was remembered especially. I conducted classes on hand grenades with a group of employees of the special laboratories of the 5th UMGB. I have a lot of trophy grenades. All grenades are conditionally divided into two classes according to the type of fuse: instantaneous action and with a retarder, triggered a few seconds after the throw. The first type is our anti-tank RKG-3, another cumulative with a parachute, a plastic case in the form of a half liter bottle, or Chinese, or Pakistani production, our anti-personnel RGO and RGN, as well as a defensive grenade of a completely nightmarish design, Egyptian production. It was cylindrical, with an enameled body, wrapped in the middle of a thin elastic metal tape. It is pierced through with a check pin, the ring of the check has a lead seal. When you pull out a check, throw a grenade, in flight the elastic spring unwinds and flies off the body. When you touch the grenade on the surface, an explosion occurs. The most terrible thing is that under her body there are jagged metal gears, crushing during the explosion into many fragments, the size of a fingernail of a little finger.
  To the second class, I include our native F-1, RGD-5, RG-42, with fuses UZRGM, similar to them English, American and Belgian. I also include German ones with a long wooden handle and American M-46 with tear ignitors.
  So, he told the Afghan comrades about the grenade device, the rules for handling them and brought them to the training ground. I explain that with grenades of instantaneous action, you should handle cautiously, throw high and far, and immediately hide. With grenades of the second class, you can especially not stand on ceremony, for example, even F-1 does not throw, but simply lowered for a blow. One dumbass mixed up everything, and threw an Egyptian grenade of instant action nearby. She fell into the mud and did not explode, because the spring did not have time to unwind to the end. I warned the duty officer about the unworked grenade and instructed the sergeant to destroy her with an overhead charge. He did not. After lunch, an Afghan lieutenant went to those parts in need and, seeing an interesting toy, picked it up. A spring sprang to a click. He threw it aside. Explosion! As a razor, he was chopped off one foot to the knee.
  With the American grenade M-46 in the 40th Army there was a more sad case. One lieutenant-paratrooper decided that since she had a teething igniter like a rocket launcher, it was smoke. Seeing the soldier in the smoking room, he decided to play a trick, pulled the string and threw it into the middle. The soldiers did not stir. As a result, a dozen corpses. The officer shot himself.
  I had an average of one or two accidents a month. In this regard, it is difficult to describe your psychological state: most likely this can be called fatalism. And what else could I do? After all, it was in no way possible to show cadets timidity and fear. The instructor should be absolutely fearless person. In the end, gradually, fatigue accumulates, which even alcohol does not remove. Nervous breakdowns begin, sometimes completely unreasonable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_5">
		<text>In vain reminded. This is a painful topic for many. But I will tell perhaps one story. The commander of the operational regiment (at that time our battalion grew up to the regiment) invites advisers to the holiday &quot;Kurban-Mayram&quot;. But the leadership, fearing possible excesses, does not allow participating in the Muslim holiday. The Afghans are sulking at us. The regiment&apos;s regiment laments:
  &quot;We bought snacks for 20,000 afghanis, and you did not come!&quot; This is a mortal offense. Serega instructs me as a Muslim to settle the incident. Besides, at this time I was on a business trip in the provinces, so I did not seem to have anything to do with the incident.
  I swear to the partners that the advisers have nothing to do with it, and that we are also worried about what happened. We are ready to atone for our guilt.
  The next day the whole group come to the regiment. In a car - a &quot;pill&quot;, except for a few liters of cognac, vodka, champagne and a box of dry wine, we carry several different trunks. At the regimental shooting range, spread out the cloak-tents. They lay a German machine gun MG-42, nicknamed &quot;Hitler&apos;s saw,&quot; a PK machine gun, an American M-16 rifle, as well as our PKK, AKS-74.
  Two soldiers-translators stuff horns and equip machine-gun belts.
  After three obligatory toasts, I announce a competition: a drink for someone who hits the target! The Afghans are trying: the lines are rattling. Gradually, all enter into excitement. With my side vision, I notice that Dean Mamad, as soon as the shooting begins, quietly creeps back. And while all compete in accuracy, he manages to overturn an extra glass, obligingly substituted by an interpreter, and crawl back to the firing line. We all like MG-42: the rate of fire is 1300 per minute and the almost complete absence of dispersion: for 800 meters in a small target, the turn is put!
  Shooting ammunition and lakirnuv champagne, in an embrace with partners, we return to the headquarters. The incident is over. Dean Mamad - a large, slightly stooped fellow, arrived in the battalion of the &quot;commandos&quot;, ruschisch - rake to the knees, buzzing in my ear: he offers to go to Kabul to the girls. He&apos;s got a good &quot;chicken coop&quot; somewhere. However, he only has the strength to get to his bunk. So it is cut off, the poor fellow, with his eyes open. I close my eyes:
  &quot;Sleep well, friend Dean Mamad ...&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_6">
		<text>One friend recently told a story. As soon as we entered the control sector of the Chechen militants, she recalled their commander and spoke for a long time, pointing to me. Then she said to me: &quot;They thought you were an agent of the FSB, they wanted to shoot him or take him to the mountains, but I defended you.&quot; Of course, I crumbled in thanks, but if you think logically - who could call me a security officer? Maybe she just did not believe it or did not have time to deal with me? Her son named Ruslan after the year 96 gladly helped me to travel throughout Ingushetia - first on my &quot;nine&quot;, then on the sports &quot;Porsche&quot;. Talking with him was not about anything, except about women, but for work very convenient. Whatever is, but still familiar. &quot;Brother&quot; ... On the eve of October 4, when he volunteered with a breeze to throw up a checkpoint at Mozdok, I was struck by one thing. Ruslan told that he has a beautiful girlfriend, whom he goes to almost every night, and then reported that he is married and has two children. I asked: &quot;Does the wife know? What does she say?&quot; He replied calmly: &quot;What can I say to her? She cries.&quot; In this calmness was such cruelty that I felt uneasy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_7">
		<text>I heard something. I&apos;ll tell you from the mouth of an eyewitness. In the morning of October 4, I overslept. Having barely rinsed, he grabbed his belongings and went down to the hotel lobby. Ruslan was already there. It was embarrassing for me that he had to wait, I fussed, leaving the hotel and paying for all telephone calls. Neither when we circled around Nazran and Ruslan ran about his affairs to different addresses, or on the route Nazran-Malgobek, I did not remember the passport forgotten by the hotel&apos;s administrators. And no suspicions arose. Anyway, I would be in Mozdok for lunch and maybe even have time to be accredited in the press center of a group of federal troops preparing to throw into Chechnya. With luck at all could be in the evening in the position of some advanced unit. With luck ... Most likely the decision to &quot;sell&quot; me came from Ruslan only upon his return to Nazran, when he again started calling at different addresses. I even imagine such a dialogue: &quot;I have a journalist sitting in my car ...&quot; &quot;Yes, who?&quot; &quot;Like from the Moscow News.&quot; &quot;One?&quot; &quot;Yes ...&quot; &quot;Wait, wait ...&quot; Ak ... Go to Magomed home, tell him everything, let your guys quickly and quickly collect. And then you will go to the hospital, you will find Said. He will pay you back. With him decide where to place ... &quot;Ruslan worked his money well - I did not even think of anything like that. The day was warm and sunny in summer and I handed over one of the materials, and he was put in the room, there were five more days ahead of him, so there was a chance to excel and do something for the newspaper. In general, the mood was excellent ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_8">
		<text>Yes, it used to be poisoned by guys who are older than campfires. The narrative will be from the words of an eyewitness. The first days in captivity, the moment of capture, I recalled with horror and pain. Stupid, bastard cattle, greedy creatures, imagining themselves supermen! After all, they were already bombed with terrible force, the federal troops were brought to full combat readiness, and the situation did not in any way suggest kidnapping - this is not the 97th year when the bandits were simply besieged with impunity, stealing journalists one by one! After all, the federal troops are what they are, but not the rabble, called Maskhadov&apos;s &quot;presidential guard&quot; and &quot;subdivisions of the Ministry of Shariah state security!&quot; No matter how the Russian army decomposes, it is even impossible to imagine that its officers themselves took part in abductions of strangers, As did the Chechen bandits in the uniforms of sovereign Ichkeria! Now, remembering that terrible moment when the Judas left me alone in his car on the orders of the republican hospital, and himself went allegedly to his beautiful girlfriend, and the inconspicuous white &quot;six&quot; with the Ingush numbers stopped nearby, I understand that such a noiseless and impetuous The operation became possible only because I was confused for a split second. If I managed to yell with good mate or at least start a fight, then everything would have turned out differently. After all, just around the corner of the hospital, there was a busy place - a bus stop, several shopping pavilions. This completely relaxed me, and when a blond man in military uniform without shoulder straps peeped in the door of the Porsche with the prudent Judas lowered his glass: &quot;Your documents! Checking the passport regime, &quot;I again did not think anything wrong.&quot; Just got out of the car and went to the white &quot;six&quot; ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_9">
		<text>I did not want to remember this much, but it was. It is our life. History told me this, my former partner. I will pass from his words. Pushing me into the back seat of his &quot;six&quot;, the bandits wheezed in the ear: &quot;Shut up, bitch! I was going to kill myself !!! &quot;, for the sake of persuasiveness in the side I was painfully poked with barrels of pistols.&quot; In the cellophane bag, the air ran out very quickly, and I began to choke, especially since I constantly tried to scream. &quot;From that moment, time crumpled to me like a piece of paper. Remember that the machine instantly surged through the streets of Nazran, someone&apos;s sure hands tore c me napojasnuju handbag, where were all the documents and money and wrist watch &quot;komandirskie&quot; gift of mother, I swam with scuba diving in Crete in the year 98, someone forces from all over still clutched my head to her knees, and somewhere in the outside world, beyond the package causing thugs talking jerky phrases on the Chechen or Ingush language. I remember, from the shock, I shouted all sorts of nonsense: &quot;Basayev will kill you for me! Release or regret! Well, please do not shoot! Then kill me, do not carry anywhere!&quot; The bandit poking at me in the side with a pistol shouted: &quot;Another word - I swear, I&apos;ll shoot like a dog, right here!&quot; - and hit the handle of the gun somewhere above the ear. Slightly, but very painful. Very soon I was weak from lack of air. He gasped and now no longer required, but begged to give a little breathe. The car was still racing at full speed and, as far as I can tell now, all the time on the asphalt surface. Somehow croaked: &quot;You are Chechens! Better cut, do not smother!&quot; One gangster replied: &quot;We are not Chechens. We are Arabs, &quot;and all four were booed with hideous, vile, deliberately vile voices, but the edge of the package was lifted, and the air of the car&apos;s saloon, stinking with the bodies of five sweaty peasants, seemed refreshing like a sea breeze. 
		Then they put him in another car: &quot;Get out quickly, bitch, I&apos;ll kill you! Come here!&quot; - And then in the third. Bandits everywhere changed. In the second car they were &quot;kind&quot; - they raised the package so that I could breathe not only with my mouth, but with my nose, and gave a smoke. In the third car there were again &quot;bad&quot;, silent and embittered. I remember the softness of the earth when I was put under a fruit tree (&quot;Yeah, it&apos;s not far from Assinovskaya!&quot; Once there was a fruit and berry state farm, Salam Aleykum, Chechnya ... &quot;I lay face down, arms and shoulders from the ropes were already stiffened, And two submachine gunners were forbidden even to move, so as to somehow reduce the unbearable pain in their shoulders. In five minutes or an hour after the trees, the sound of an approaching car was heard, the bandits kicked me up (with incredible difficulty getting up with twisted arms) and again drove off like a ram, accompanied by senseless evil cries. It was already dark when I was brought to zindan. My new residence (for a short while, just for two weeks, as I found out later) was an unfinished garage among the ruins and piles of broken bricks. Then I could not believe that just a few hours ago I was free, I could plan further steps and &quot;swing the rights&quot; if someone wants to interfere. Now I can not believe that I was a hostage - that is, not entirely human and not even a person - and that any of the bandits, with their own understanding and mood, would do absolutely anything to me with impunity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_10">
		<text>In vain reminded. This is a painful topic for many. That&apos;s what our commander told us. Now, when a wave of panic horror, pain and constant tension subsided, I often think: but could it be otherwise? After all, all the circumstances that led to that fatal moment on October 4, 1999, at about 15-16 pm, when four bandits forcibly took me away in their car, now look like a chaotic set of accidents and nonsense. Now, if on the eve of the day I suddenly decided not to visit the friends of Nazran ... If the hotel porter of the Assa hotel were not so nice and friendly girls who did not want to offend distrust (two days before the seizure I went up to them and jokingly asked: &quot;And my passport will not be lost to you?&quot; The girls got agitated and Offered to return it to me, to which I replied: &quot;No, no, you will have it wholeheartedly - I always lose everything&quot;) ... If it were not for my damned forgetfulness ... If the Judas by the name of Ruslan had some old &quot;Zhiguli&quot;, and not a sports double &quot;Porsche&quot;, where you can get to Mozdok quickly and comfortably ... From these &quot; If &quot;there is any business trip - it does not matter, in the&quot; hot spot &quot;or in a prosperous country. But no matter how many trips I had during the years of work in the Moscow News, the circumstances always developed as best as possible. Probably, the limit of luck and luck was exhausted and on that last trip to Ingushetia on the eve of a new big war something bad would necessarily happen. Happiness, that it was &quot;only&quot; capture by the hostages. Happiness, that always, even on the darkest days, there was a tiny hope.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_11">
		<text>One friend recently told a story. More precisely, this is not even a story but an outline of eyewitnesses. Remembering now the people who knew me from the year 96, who called the &quot;nephew&quot; and &quot;brother&quot; and coolly directed the bandits against me, I feel a quiet, quiet disappointment, besides the thirst for vengeance and hatred. Not so much in their decency, as in their mind. What a stupid and greedy person one must be in order not to masquerade and not sweep the tracks, to bring me into the clutches of the bandits! Back in zindan I found only two explanations for such perfidy - or they themselves considered me to be a complete fool who could not draw the simplest conclusions, or they were told that I would not stay alive. The second explanation became bad. I will not name &quot;gunners&quot; - mother and son, although their name has already sounded in the &quot;Moscow News&quot;. This couple is now sitting in the remand center, and the story of my captivity is just a small episode of the turbulent activity of a fun family. Mother even earlier, in the year 96, looked somewhat suspicious - too businesslike, &quot;bolted&quot;, whether that, she then was, with extensive connections in international humanitarian organizations and among Chechen fighters. She told that she had an unselfish and noble nature, that at the call of the soul she was engaged in the release of Russian prisoners of war, that in this difficult matter she had repeatedly looked into death&apos;s eyes. For the sake of justice, it should be noted that she really was not too afraid when the two of us arrived on March 7, 96 in Grozny, engrossed in battles. Then I did not understand why she needed it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_12">
		<text>I heard something. More precisely read the last essays of the former commander. Here, listen. On April 4 at about 15.00 the gunner of the BMP pushed us: &quot;Get up, let&apos;s go soon!&quot; And really, in 15 minutes we moved forward ... 600 meters to the road we crossed an hour and a half. The spirits were higher and shot us like in a dash. On the road from our company came 2nd and 3rd platoons, and the 1st and company control remained at the position two hundred meters behind, the 2nd and 6th companies went around Goyskoye to the left. 
We decided to go for the road, asked to cover up, but I do not shoot SVD: a grenade splinter fell into the bolt. I have disassembled the rifle. In the receiver, there were still some glands, it is also visible fragments. I checked everything, I tried the rifle - nothing, it works. 
Our group went after the road, pelting grenades with grenades. First, a pair of machine-gunner mounted on the spot. And the others left under cover. We beat the spirits out of position. Apparently, there were about twenty of them. Leaving, they left five for cover. These unfortunate grenades were blown to shreds. Did not help them and dug under the road holes. 
We are entrenched. At this time, the 6th and 2nd companies fought a fierce battle in the &quot;green&quot;. Eleven people, together with the platoon, who performed the duty of the company, lay down there. Two weeks later, the spirits were asked to pick up the corpses, since they had already decayed. But it&apos;s later, but for now we blocked the right flank of the 2nd and 6th mouth. In one of the burrows a live &quot;Czech&quot; was discovered, which managed to overwhelm the kid who found him. No matter how we tried to smoke a Czech, it was all wasted. We poured kerosene into the hole, and set fire to it, and threw grenades. Apparently, the course in the shelter was cranked, so it did not get ... 
While the court is yes, we look, the main forces of the company have approached. It turns out that they, having lost four, could not overcome the field. Our platoon mate with the company about their late approach. Mouth shouts: &quot;There were no clear instructions from the battalion commander!&quot; Platoon: &quot;The battalion commander was drunk in the trash.&quot; It was necessary to make the decision himself! &quot; While they were understanding, we inspected the Chechen trenches and dug-outs, finished off the wounded. After a while, the co-manda: &quot;Leave!&quot; That this is nonsense, it is clear to everyone. One of the conscripts-demobilists tried to explain by the radio station supposedly to be fixed, because if not we, then the spirits will come here, and again we will have to seize the position with losses. He shouted hoarsely, with matyugami, but, of course, nobody could convince. 
Having provided the output of the 6th company, they began to withdraw. SAU from 324 msp began to hollow Goiskoe, and we divided into two groups. The first departs with all the belongings, the second closes. We departed normally as a whole, but it was not without jokes. The last tank left the number 420. He covered all, &quot;to the heap.&quot; During the assault, the spirits were burned by two infantry fighting vehicles: one of our, one of the 6th company. To be faithful, the tank pierced the padded BMP. And then some kind of gunner-operator from the &quot;two&quot; on it as sharahnet! Tankmen then said: &quot;We are, of course, in fact, but when you retire your own they are hammered in the ass ...&quot; Who fired, they did not find out.
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_13">
		<text>Yes, it used to be poisoned by guys who are older than campfires. One of them had a military campaign in the past. That&apos;s what he told them. Dirty and boring, around scurrying newcomers from some sort of a brigade airborne troops. For three days together with the paratroopers we made an impregnable fortress out of Khankala. Now it&apos;s a little calmer. The spirits stopped their ridiculous forays at night, we were no longer chased about and without reason. Yes, we have cowardly generals, a whole brigade of VV and a battalion of paratroopers have been assigned to guard the tiny Khankala, they also promise to send a regiment of motorized rifles. Where they will only fit? But this is all the lyrics, and there is nothing to do at the moment. I go to the radio operators, you need to be aware of the events, or the war will end and you will not know. 
- It&apos;s great &quot;Broom&quot;.
- A &quot;Moscow&quot; come in, do you smoke?
&quot;Let&apos;s find what&apos;s new?&quot;
- Yes, nothing, Marines, landing party, motorized rifles, and Sofrintsy peck
A minute ago Dudayev asshole is not well-known, shorter life is shit, and the sun is fucked
lamp!
&quot;Have you heard that we can hear from our brigade?&quot;
- Nothing concrete, we wait, along the way we guard the &quot;shakal&quot;
command...
Trying to configure another wave on the two-way radio, crackling ether interrupted &quot;Chukotka&quot; laryngeal speech, one Russian, not hell sucks go further, find a rifle part talks they clamped &quot;spirits&quot; in the five-story building, no callsigns and TP, boric mate from which left that kind of Ensign Zinoviev had sexual intercourse with one of BMPS in place that it&apos;s difficult to imagine on bmp ...
A good stretch thing, a regular campaign of spirits behind our &quot;beps&quot; was noticed on time. Well-fed &quot;Broom&quot; during my radio interceptions had time to &quot;sleep&quot; and under-jumping probably half a meter, he snuggled off his chair crawling along the kunga trying to simultaneously attach the armor, the pouch for the grenades eventually he stumbled on the helmet and fell wildly to the floor with a wild crash. And it would be very funny, if it were not so ne-pawalno. 
In a matter of seconds I reach the technics with the eyes of a platoon commander, he agitated behind a piece of armature and with great enthusiasm hrenachit on dusman who, by virtue of natural dullness, climbed out onto an open site. Toli we are in truth a not-bad army, and not a flock of deer as the battalion commander explained to us in the &quot;training&quot;, toli the fools fell to us like dumb ones, but we kept Khankala on conscience and there were almost no losses in personnel. Two &quot;two hundredth&quot; in six days in January 95 in Chechnya is not bad, although it&apos;s bad, very bad because it could not be them either.
A few minutes later we collected a combined platoon of kol-vo near the office and went to the web, naturally there were no spirits in the neighborhood any more, we put several stretches and &quot;lanterns&quot; for not a horse-radish without our knowledge in the district to fumble.
Another day has passed, on another war ... Who needs all this ...
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_14">
		<text>I did not want to remember this much. This is from the words of an eyewitness. After passing militant guards in Grozny, we penetrated into the quarters, completely controlled by &quot;spirits.&quot; Army camouflage and our unshaven, blackened, cheeky faces gave us a chance to completely descend for the militants in case of a sudden encounter with the &quot;soldiers of Ichkeria.&quot; The mess in the militants was analogous to the brothel that reigned in the disposition of our troops. The system of omissions and passwords in the conditions of general confusion among the militants sometimes did not work, and it was enough to shout &quot;Allah Akbar&quot;, so that they would take us for their own.
Our goal was to conduct reconnaissance in the territory behind militant militant orders and disorganize the enemy communications system by mining to introduce a sense of chaos and panic into its ranks.
They moved only in the evening, but before dark. With the onset of darkness, advancement through the city is dangerous, as at this time the belligerents doubled the attention behind all actions from the contiguous side. At night we sat in smelly cellars or in abandoned private houses, which we selected after preliminary reconnaissance so that all approaches to our shelter could be clearly seen.
It&apos;s already getting dark. We are circling in the area for the second day, we can not find a passage to the neighboring region, teeming with bearded men with green armbands armed militants. It is necessary to sit out this night, and at dawn go to the next street. I noticed this afternoon that the militants designated on our map had been turned into a stronghold for a breakdown of Russian tanks, having overwhelmed it with various large-sized trash consisting of broken cars and a half-burned bus.
The sixth sense told me that for sure this improvised barricade is &quot;guarded&quot; by the &quot;spirits,&quot; therefore, one should not fool around there.
After exposing the guard and the observer, we lay down to rest on the pile of broken brick. Bricks stick in the back, and internal tension does not allow to fall asleep. Turning on my stomach, lay down on bent hands, - the posture is not comfortable, but I force myself to fall asleep, tomorrow is a difficult day.
It can not be called sleep. Closing your eyes, you fall into a trance of forgetting, continuing to somehow control the environment. I came to myself suddenly. Silence. However, in the stomach it became cold and uncomfortable. A second later he heard a crunch of garbage, heavy footsteps, and saw carefully the roaming beam of a torchlight.
&quot;Have you spotted, where is the observer, is it really already lying with a cut throat?&quot; - my condition was close to panic.
I can not hear my companions breathing next to me. So they do not sleep, and just like me, hiding, they squeeze into a pile of bricks.
People with a flashlight (probably it was a patrol of militants) stopped near the entrance to our shelter.
There was a silence, which seemed to me a lifetime. His heart rolled to his throat.
In the morning I read &quot;Our Father,&quot; and God will save me, &quot;- this thought, if not soothing, at any rate makes me get rid of the paralyzing animal fear of the unknown and prepare for action.
The machine is at hand. The fingers of the other hand grope for the cold ribbed surface of the F-1 grenade, the purpose of which is to not be captured alive.
The steps began to move away. &quot;Have not found&quot;.
The tension subsided. However, the alarm for the guys who were on the watch did not pass.
A conditional signal. &quot;Our!&quot; Two figures, like shadows, slipped to us.
As it turned out, the gunmen appeared suddenly from some basement, to which we at first did not even pay attention. When it began to dawn, we cautiously left our shelter, having previously left several &quot;guests&quot; in the form of two MON-50. Coming out of the basement and looking around, they found an unobtrusive passage to the basement, which later turned out to be a through passage to the street where we could not get to before.
Having mined this passage, which the fighters are likely to try to use, our group leaked out behind the &quot;spirits&quot; in the area of ??the tram park. We did not have much time to linger here. The depot of the tram park and the adjacent territory were swarming with militants, since Maskhadov&apos;s headquarters were here, and the militants could run into our &quot;guests&quot; and realize that other people have appeared on their territory. Collecting intelligence through visual observation, trying to quickly get rid of cargo - installing and masking mines, we began to prepare for a retreat. The departure route, developed by us and coordinated with the command of the units, to the border of which we had to leave after the operation, turned out to be useless. Rather, it will be said that by this time, while we were in the rear of the enemy, the situation has changed. The frontiers of contact with the enemy moved, in some directions the militants created new strong points. Based on the current situation, we had to conduct additional exploration and look for new escape routes.
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_15">
		<text>In vain reminded. This is a painful topic for many. Listen to the essay of a veteran. Despite the fact that in our group there were children who lived up to all these events in Grozny, it was very difficult to navigate in a ruined city. In some places five days ago there were enemy positions, and now they can be occupied by ours, as a result of which there is a high possibility of getting under federal fire. Although there are no &quot;smart&quot; deaths, it is foolish to get a bullet from your own.
To prevent this from happening, we had to constantly conduct additional reconnaissance of the area.
As a witness of the consequences, when our reconnaissance groups attacked their own, I became in January 1995.
Similar to our reconnaissance group under the command of Vadim flew to the &quot;Volgo-Grad&quot; (part of the 8th Army Corps under the command of General Rokhlin) in one of the districts of Grozny. The lack of interaction played a tragic role, the Vadim group was accepted by the &quot;Volgograds&quot; for the enemy, and fire was opened on it for defeat. One of the group was killed. Vadim jumped out of the hiding place and started shouting: &quot;Do not shoot, we are ours!&quot; After he was &quot;detained&quot; run up fighters, it turned out that he had no documents. Trying to explain himself to the &quot;Volgograd&quot; Vadim was severely beaten and almost shot. After clarifying all the circumstances of the case and asking for confirmation to the higher headquarters, Vadim was critically put in a hospital at Severniy.
I was standing by his bed, and it hurt to listen to his jerky, stuttering speech, in which he only often repeated: &quot;T-t-you-p-p-pee-pee, I-I in Af-fgane p- To-kon-tuziyu, and z-z-here m-me to-to-the-end ... &quot;Two hours later a special turn-key was brought to Mozdok, and then to the hospital on the&quot; big earth &quot;.
Having run a small square, through the arch we jump into the courtyard. He seems to be from another life. The war spared him so much that the ruins on the neighboring streets give the impression that the arch through which we entered this courtyard was a gate from one world to another. Silence is unfamiliar.
The fact that silence in the war is sometimes deceptive, we made sure in a few minutes. Having trusted in the silence and apparent calm, we made a mistake that almost led to a tragic ending for us. We violated the basic rules of movement on the territory occupied by the enemy, which read: &quot;Do not believe your eyes and ears. Trust only the instinct and instinct.&quot; Seven times check ... &quot;and other principles according to which we have no right to relax.
From the window of the second floor of the neighboring house we were called in Chechen. We are confused ...
Not having received an answer, they opened fire on us. But either the arrows turned out to be fucking, or because these &quot;animal instincts&quot; awoke in us again, only one person from our group was slightly injured in the side, and then tangential, as we immediately found ourselves behind high concrete slabs, Hiding from enemy fire.
In order not to waste ammunition in vain, we decided not to carry out an intensive targeted shooting on the enemy who was in the building, and, consequently, in a favorable position, especially since we were not aware of their forces and intentions. Being under the cover of these same concrete slabs, snapping short bursts and single fire, we tried to gain time for the adoption of the very &quot;only correct decision.&quot;
Through the windows of the basement, we entered one by one into the three-story house behind our backs. Cursing and swearing for carelessness, the first thing they did was help the wounded. Two went on scouting. The rest took up defense. Returning from intelligence brought a joyful message: in some distance from us are the lines of the Russian troops storming the city. Apparently, the immediate proximity of the federal troops did not allow the militants who fired at us in the courtyard to take more decisive action against our group, who settled in this three-story house. Or maybe it was similar to our enemy group, whose task is not to conduct a protracted open battle. In any case, we quickly established contact with the command of the federal troops, to the frontier of which came out, and within an hour we were sent to the Northern Fleet on armored personnel carriers.
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_16">
		<text>One friend recently told a story. Now I&apos;ll tell you. &quot;Armistice&quot; the next morning turned into a bloody tragedy. At 10 o&apos;clock in the morning on Staropromyslovskoe highway, militants undermined the landmine installed on the roadside. Splinters of a 152-mm howitzer projectile (tanks and howitzer shells used by militants as the main landfill bomb) penetrated armored personnel carriers, instantly killing the driver-mechanic. The unguided BTR at a speed of 70 km / h, jumped to the opposite side of the highway and cut off the concrete column of illumination, stopped, filled with blood and spattered by the brains of servicemen of the 101st BB brigade.
Four soldiers died in a matter of seconds, the fifth, who was torn apart by the explosion of his legs, died on the way to the hospital, the sixth died on the operating table. Near the place of the tragedy was an elderly Russian woman, who covered her face with the cloak of the cloak, unable to hide her tears. She has to hide her tears from the crowd of Chechen youth gathered at a crossroads and cheerfully discussing what happened.
On the same day, five-fighters captured at one of the roadblocks were taken to GUOSH. Dressed in black clothes, more like uniforms, they carried weapons, half of which were equipped with devices for noiseless shooting. You-coming from Shali after a federal operation there under the leadership of General Shamanov in May 1996, this group tried to penetrate Grozny.
The senior group of militants, as it turned out during the investigation, was simultaneously a commander of a reconnaissance group from the detachment of Shamil Basayev. Captured militants have shown that they arrived in Grozny to carry out terrorist attacks. This was evidenced by the list of persons included in the government of Chechnya found with them, indicating the positions and locations of the working classrooms. During the interrogations it was found out that the militants had also been ordered to take out from Grozny, prior to June 10, the family and relatives of militants fighting in the mountains. All this gave grounds to believe that militants use &quot;truces&quot; for their own purposes, and they are far from peaceful. The atmosphere in Chechnya was getting worse every day.
The unwillingness of the military and political leadership of Russia to live according to the laws of the not-declared, but still war, led to the tragic events in Grozny on August 6,
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_17">
		<text>I heard something. Just here one story was remembered. It has long been true. My company was raised to disarm one Chechen gadyushnik, and the &quot;Vovan&quot; (special forces of the Interior Ministry) worked, and we only closed it. When the elders of the village were brought to the commander of the Vovans, he demanded 24 AKs to be handed over to them within two hours. On which one of the elders began fucking in the style of Lukashenka. He said that in their village there is a legitimate detachment of self-defense, but they do not have enough automatic weapons, so the feds are obliged to immediately issue another 20 AK. Vovany from such borzoty slightly prizhuhli, but we are not confused. The ugly elder in front of everyone received a turn in the bread-cutter, and while his legs were still twitching, the other elders heard a delicate request to hand over not 24 AK and 100. And not for two hours, but for an hour. The Chechens met in forty minutes, handing over exactly 100 automatic rifles.
And the moral of this story is this: politics and diplomacy are good for a partner who remains within certain limits. For the &quot;partner&quot; who lost the shore, there must be a different set of tools.
I saw the columns of buses, to which because of the stench could not be approached for a hundred meters, because they were stuffed with bodies of slaughtered Russians. I saw women, ditch-nenki sawn along the chainsaw, kids, planted on poles from traffic signs, artistically wound on the fence of the intestine. We, Russians, have been cleansed from our own land like dirt from under our nails. And it was 1992 - until the &quot;first Chechen&quot; remained two and a half years.
And then it became quite fun. The village came militants and began to clean it from the Russians. At night, people could be heard shouting and being raped and slaughtered in their own house. And no one came to their aid. Everyone was for himself, everyone was shaking with fear, and some managed to bring the ideological base to this matter, they say, &quot;my house is my fortress&quot; (yes, this phrase I heard at that time. The man who uttered it is no longer alive - his Vainakhi intestines were wound on the fence of his own house). That&apos;s how we, cowardly and stupid, were cut out singly. Tens of thousands of Russians were killed, several thousand were slaves and Chechen harems, hundreds of thousands fled Chechnya in their underpants. 
So the Vainakhs solved the &quot;Russian question&quot; in a single republic.
And they succeeded only because we were insignificant, full of shit. We&apos;re still shit, though it&apos;s not that liquid anymore - steel pellets began to fall among the shit. And when these grains come together - there are kondopogi. There are not many of them yet, but Vainakhs are good fellows. Real orderlies of the forest. As a result of their cultural and educational mission in Russia, Russian sheep again become human beings.
In general, those who crossed paths with Chechens have something to hate.
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_18">
		<text>Yes, it used to be poisoned by guys who are older than campfires. A couple of veterans had a hike there. Here, listen. In the same place, in the war, fate brought me with one Jew - Lev Yakovlevich Rokhlin. Initially, our participation in the New Year&apos;s storm was not expected. But when we lost contact with the 131st MSR and the 81st MSP, we were thrown to the rescue. We broke through to the location of the 8 AK, which was commanded by General Rokhlin, and arrived at his headquarters. Then I first saw him in person. And he did not seem to me at first sight: hunched, chilled, with cracked glasses ... Not a general, but some tired agronomist. He set us the task of collecting the scattered remains of the Maikop brigade and the 81st regiment and leading them to the pvd of the Rokhlinsky intelligence battalion. This is what we were doing - we collected meat from the fears and took them to the location of the Rokhlin scouts. In total there were about two mouths. Initially, Rokhlin did not want to use them, but when all the other groups retreated - 8 AK remained alone in the operational environment in the center of the city. Against all militants! And then Rokhlin built this &quot;army&quot; opposite the structure of his fighters and addressed them with a speech. I will never forget this speech. The gentle words of the general were: &quot;fucking monkeys&quot; and &quot;piedaras.&quot; In the end, he said: &quot;The militants outnumber us fifteen times, and we can not expect help from anybody, and if we are to lie down here, let each of us be found under a bunch of enemy corpses.&quot; Let&apos;s show how the Russian fighters and the Russians are able to die Generals, do not fail, my sons ... &quot;
Leo Yakovlevich is no longer alive - he was sorted out without you. One Jew is less, is not it?
I already told you about Rokhlin&apos;s speech. But I did not tell you about what happened next. And then there was a terrible, terrible battle, in which of my platoon of 19 people left six alive. And when the Chechens broke into the location and it came to grenades, and we realized that we all get fucked up - I saw real Russian people. Fear was gone. There was some kind of merry anger, detachment from everything. There was one thought in my head: &quot;Dad&quot; asked me not to let him down. &quot;The wounded themselves bandaged themselves, cheated with promedol and continued the fight. 
Then the Vainakh and I met in hand-to-hand combat. And they ran. This was a turning point in the battle for Grozny. It was a confrontation between two characters - Caucasian and Russian, and ours was harder. It was at that moment that I realized that we could do this. This solid core in us is, it only needs to be cleared of the adherent shit. We took prisoners in hand-to-hand combat. Looking at us, they did not even whine - they howled in horror. And then we read the radio interception - on the radio networks of the militants, Dudayev&apos;s order was passed: &quot;scouts from the 8K and special forces of the Airborne Forces are not taken prisoner and tortured, but immediately finished off and buried as soldiers.&quot; We were very proud of this order.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_19">
		<text>I did not want to remember this much. Troubled time was then. Between Goysky and Komsomolsky - gardens, and behind them the spirits of the position of ATGM. The operator was classy, ??they got three versts in a lagoon for three. Moreover, he tried to cover KP 324 th regiment, fired at the roadblock, and before him all four kilometers. This ATGM was aimed at us by a battalion commander. We proceeded from the assumption that the position is well guarded, and if the operator falls, then noiselessly. Therefore, they asked the battalion commander to write out Vintorez from the warehouse of the RAV VSS. He ordered the rifle, but someone had to go with her along with the chief of the missile and artillery armament service. In the regiment, we decided to go on a passing column. 
The situation in Goi is as follows: the spirits could not break the confrontation in their direction, since we surpassed them in fire weapons (artillery, aviation, etc.), and we could not take Goiskoye because of its small numbers. Anyway, we got the spirits, and they told us that if any other unit of 245 msp were to go to Goisky, they would block the gorge and block the regiment. 
In the Lower Atagi, where we waited for the column, she came at half past two. In its composition were to follow in the regiment of conscript-conscripts from the raiding party, as well as those who went to take out on leave for family reasons. (Naturally, they, like me, were not taken into account anywhere, and therefore later, when the battle was over, the exact number of losses in our ill-fated column was difficult to calculate. In particular, the &quot;Ural&quot; with the demobilization, which was a man of 20, was burnt after one hit &quot;Bumblebee&quot;. They carried food, and the boys sat on bags from above - so everything was burnt ...) 
I went through the column to find out about the mail - there were no letters. I go back, I look - four consoles in a row, and one of them has a good friend and countryman Arkasha. It turned out that he was a deputy of the platoon of the liquidators. Well, lucky! &quot;Arkasha, there is an empty seat in the cockpit?&quot; It did not fit the sniper - the white man - to shake in the armor on the armor. &quot; He says: &quot;Come, look!&quot; He went in, pushed a packet of vodka, which he was carrying to someone for his birthday. Nothing, I&apos;ll fit myself. 
At about 2 pm we started off. At 14.10 Chishki passed and before the entrance to the gorge they jerked the gates. Arkasha says: &quot;Look, some women and children.&quot; And I literally yesterday guys from the 324th regiment said: &quot;If the road guys, women and children - everything is fine .If some women - cranks, soon an ambush.&quot; 
The column stretched out on the &quot;mother-in-law language&quot; (this is a serpentine). On it, the fins were barely unfolding, and the MAZs, which were pulling the faulty machinery, do not know how they passed at all. Everything is quiet, calm. We&apos;re going, we&apos;re jamming the jokes. Yaryshmardy drove past, the head of the column had already left for the turn, the bridges had passed through the dry channel. And then - the explosion ahead, we look - because of the hillock the tower of the tank was thrown, the second explosion - also somewhere in the head of the column, and the third just banged between the one ahead and our lime. The explosion tore off the hood, pinched glass. I was first shocked. Arkasha got out of the car already, and I got confused in the two handles of the door - well, I was just crazy. Finally fell out of the cab. The fire is very dense, but I have already started to think and from the fins of the meter to 15 ran away, despite the fire of the spirits. I found some deepening in the roadside, pushed my backside into it. Near the soldier-lieutenant lay down. The first shock passed - I watch how things are. And things are not important. The pourers stood on the road. The guys from the platoon of cavalry fire back in all directions as they can, where the spirits are, is not yet clear. Arkasha from under the wheel of his lime wets in white light. 
Then a pomegranate passes by me like a sharahnet into the lorry, that behind us came. The lining is burning. I estimate that if it explodes now, then we will all be very hot. I&apos;m trying to understand where this thing came from. I look, like someone is crouching meters in 170 from us. I looked at the sight, and the &quot;dusher&quot; is already preparing a new grenade ... I knocked him off the first shot, I liked it myself. I start to look for the target in the sight. Another &quot;dushok&quot; in the trench is sitting, from the machine guns. I shot, but I can not say for sure if he killed or not, because the bullet hit the upper edge of the breastwork at the level of the chest behind which he was sitting. The spirit disappeared. Whether I still got it, or he decided not to tempt fate any more. Again I aimed at the sight, I saw that the spirit &quot;on four bones&quot; was creeping up the hill. The first shot I just scared him. He moved his limbs more actively, but did not manage to escape. The second shot, like a good kick in the ass, had already been thrown over his head. 
While I was scorching the spirits, Arkasha drove the burning larva out and threw it off the road. He listened, like a machine gun works. Behind something set fire, and black smoke went to our side along the gorge, because of him in the sight of a fig is not visible. We figured with Dmitry - so the ringleader was called, that it&apos;s time for us to leave this place. Gathered and jerked across the road, fell behind the concrete blocks in front of the bridge. The head can not be raised, and the machine-gunner, meanwhile, is hammering on the fins, and it is not unsuccessful. He set them on fire. We lie with Dima, and past us in the direction of the bridge there flows a river of burning kerosene a meter and a half wide. From the flame it is hot unbearably, but, as it turned out, this is not the worst thing. When the fiery river reached the Urals with charges for the ACS, all this good began to explode. I look, some things with rags are flying out of the car. Dima explained that these are lighting shells. We lie, we think: Dima said that there were about 50 of them in the car. Meanwhile, the second &quot;Ural&quot; with high-explosive shells caught fire. It&apos;s good that he did not completely detonate, shells exploded in explosions. 
I lie and think: &quot;Damn, what is it that no one commands us?&quot; As it turned out later, Khattab planned everything so competently that, literally at the very beginning of the battle, all the controls that were traveling on the two command cars were cut by the fire of small arms, and the KSM itself remained untouched during the whole battle. 
Suddenly in the second Ural with high-explosive ammunition something exploded so that the rear axle with one wheel of a candle for 80 meters went up, and, according to our reasons, it was to fall flat on us. Well, we think, have come. But lucky: he fell about ten meters. Everything in the smoke, everything explodes. Because of the smoke, nothing is visible in sight. The shooting is erratic, but the machine gunner of spirits stood out against the general background. We decided to get out of this hell, get out, ran into the &quot;zelenok&quot;. Distributed with Dima sectors of the shelling. I am firing along the front, and he covers my rear and looks to the spirits from above did not go. Crawled to the edge, and the tank, which in the tail of the column stood, the spirits of the RPG grind. Once eight got, but to no avail. Then they broke through the tower from the side of the commander&apos;s hatch. Smoke poured from her. Apparently, the crew was wounded, and the mechanic began to take back. So backwards he went through the whole column and, they say, got to the regiment. 
An hour passed since the beginning of the battle. The shooting began to subside. I say: &quot;Well, everything, Dima, pull at the end of the column!&quot; They ran under the bridge, I look, some people are sitting in the &quot;Afghan&quot;, seven people, next to two dead bodies. We run up. One of the seated turns. Oh my God! He has a black beard, a nose with a hump and wild eyes. I throw up my rifle, press on the descent ... The others turn around-ours. Well, I did not finish it. The bearded contractor turned out to be. He without me, stunned, sits, stammers, can not say anything. I shout: &quot;Uncle, I almost knocked you down!&quot; And he does not cut it. 
In our side the BMP &quot;limping&quot; creeps, picking up the wounded. She was in a torsion, and she stumbles. They threw the wounded inside, drove to the road - around the car burned out, something is torn in them. The skirmish almost subsided. 
Let&apos;s go. Somewhere closer to Argun on the road, the peasants shout: &quot;Guys, we have wounded people here. Help!&quot; I jumped to them, and the car went on. I go up to the guys. They say: &quot;We have a major wounded.&quot; The major is in camouflage, with the sign of the Marine Corps on his sleeve. End-to-end wound in the arm and in the chest. All pale from the loss of blood. The only thing that I had was a tourniquet. I stretched out my hand to him. They talked, it turned out that he was a deputy battalion of the battalion in the Pacific Fleet. At this time, one of the guys remembered that they were carrying beer, cigarettes, juice, etc. in the car. I covered the guys, and they ran off bringing all this good. We lie, drink beer, smoke. Darken the beginning. I think: &quot;It&apos;s getting dark now, the spirits will come down, there&apos;s no help, and we are shaking!&quot; We decided to choose a better position. Have fondled пригорочек, have borrowed it, we lay, we wait. The guys from the RMS show me the situation. Machines with ammunition spirits were burned from RPGs, and those with food were simply sowing from small arms. 
The artillery was working, very carefully, only on the slopes, and not touching the settlement or us. Then came four MI-24s, worked on the mountains. It&apos;s getting darker. We hear, from the side of the 324th regiment - an eerie roar. It turns out that the help rolls. Ahead of the T-72, behind him the infantry fighting vehicle, then again the tank. Not reaching 50 meters, he stops and points us at the gun. I think: &quot;Everything! The spirits did not crash - they will finish their own with fright!&quot; We jumped up, hands mash - they say, their own. The tank shook the barrel, turned around and as sharahnet in the &quot;zelenok&quot; 20 meters away. With this &quot;help&quot; people povyzkakivalo - on the grass creep around itself from submachine guns watered. We told them: &quot;Guys, are you creeping? There&apos;s no one there.&quot; It turns out that it was the reconnaissance of the 324th regiment. I approached the officers, I said: &quot;Why are you fighting here? You have to go to the head of the column!&quot; And they told me: since you&apos;ve been here before, and think, take ten people and move with them, where he himself said. 
I was like, I found the scouts, and we moved forward. I counted more than forty burnt corpses. Judging by what cars were left intact, the spirits had clear information that where is located. For example, the medical MTLB in general remained untouched, only the mechanics of small arms were filled up, and Zuushka was literally turned into a sieve. Then we asked why the help came so late: if they had come an hour and a half early, then someone would have survived in the column&apos;s head, and so up to the last one BRDM resisted, in which almost all were killed. 
As the guys from the 324th regiment later told us, when they reported that they were wetting our column in the gorge and would have been good to rush to the rescue, they were told not to jerk and stand where they stood. Help came to us after two and a half hours, when it was all over.
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_afgan_20">
		<text>In vain reminded. This is a painful topic for many. It was found in the diaries of one of the dead. Heck! If I get out, I&apos;ll quit smoking, drinking, and the like, but later!
Now we must hold out! Where is the bloody BON!
&quot;Maly&apos;s bitch call for reinforcements, they&apos;ll bitch bitch!&quot;
&quot;They told you ten times, they will not be there in an hour, if they do not burn on the way.&quot;
- Yes, in an hour we can be buried in a matchbox!
- Well, ask the spirits to stop shooting ?.
- We must retreat, the company was killed! BON where it was lost, the landing party also fell asleep ...
Tired! A few more such conversations and I myself will fall into a fit of hysteria, one must hold on, get distracted, as soon as it is possible in the conditions of this hell.
Then, as if on command, the fire from the spirits ceased. The mines stopped whistling, the ricochet stalled, and the &quot;aboriginal&quot; cries were not heard. There was a silence that was worse than a whistle of mines.
- Do they have ammo?
- Yes, hell, they&apos;re planning something for a bitch.
Then the roar of the firing sounded from the opposite side.
&quot;What is it?&quot;
- Who knows!
- Guys are desantura! Exactly the elite! No one else!
- Hooray!
&quot;Damn the devil!&quot;
Without a team, without anything, they all rose from the fortifications as one and rushed to the unpretentious two or three story buildings. Perfume quickly realized that they are now fucked on both sides. Some of them went on a breakthrough, but was almost without losses cut out, the rest were finished long and tedious. I remember vaguely the cleaning of the buildings (on the way to Khankala, a little bit of contusion).
And then our long-awaited BON and landing units came up. And then a whole minibigade of the &quot;fathers of commanders&quot; and ... Quiet (as far as possible in Chechnya) winter evening, I sit on the steps of the new headquarters, smoke and I think that finally it all ended. We are BB - it means cops, and the matter of cops is guarded. So Grozny is going to drop the landing party, but I&apos;m done, fought! 
Six days later our brigade was sent to Grozny ... 
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_aneki_talk">
		<text>Can you tell us a joke?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_aneki_end">
		<text>Heh, it&apos;s the same.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_1">
		<text>Well, listen. Male solidarity. We sit somehow in the summer with a friend in the car, we drink beer. The windows in the house near are open to many. Silence around, only we have music playing. From the second floor, screams and groans began to ring, we pushed the music down, we sat listening, we burned) Suddenly, the groans ceased and the girl screamed: &quot;Is that all?&quot; Yes, even the children did not have time to finish the song! My friend stuck his head out and shouted: &quot;Do not slap the boy, we&apos;ve paused!&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_2">
		<text>Well, listen. At the university at a lecture on psychology. Professor: - Today we will study, on an example, three initial stages of the human psyche: surprise, irritation and anger. Taking the phone, the professor dials the first number. - Hello, and Vasya can? - And here such does not live. &quot;There,&quot; said the professor, smiling, &quot;this is a slight surprise. Then dials the number again. - Hello, and Vasya did not fit? - Yes there are no such. Rubbing her hands, the professor conspiratorially winks at the audience and dials the third time. - So Vasya is not? - Yes you have gone! &quot;Well, I hope the example is clear.&quot; From the first desk a student gets up. &quot;Forgive me, Professor, but you have forgotten the fourth stage.&quot; - This is what? - Stage ohuyvaniya. Approaching the chair, the student dials a number. - Good afternoon. This is Vasya. Nobody called me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_3">
		<text>Well, listen. The case was on December 31. It&apos;s ten o&apos;clock in the evening. We are going to celebrate the New Year. We carry three decent bags - it is clear with what. Well, they themselves, of course, are no longer sober. And now, only 5 minutes remain, we are already looking forward to the fun, and suddenly ... At ten meters, the police car brakes gently. From there the sergeant climbs and heads straight for us. Thoughts, naturally, are the darkest - at best money shakes, at worst - the New Year in the monkey. But how will you meet ... Sergeant comes up: - Put the bags! - dutifully put bags on the snow. To my friend: - Hands stretch, - he stretches out his hands. - A handful! - he puts his hands in a surprised handful. The sergeant climbs into his pocket and pours a handful of chocolates into his hands. Then he turns and goes to the car. From the car turns around and says: - Well, you are waiting for some miracle in the New Year!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_4">
		<text>Well, listen. Morning build. A frown of a company inspects the structure of the young recruiting. And then his gaze stops at the recruit without a belt. &quot;Comrade soldiers.&quot; Where is your belt? To which the soldier, obviously from an intelligent family, but already slowly began to learn the subtleties of the army vocabulary, in a voice striving to cause understanding, reports: - Comrade Major. Spizdili. - In the army there is no such word &quot;spizdili,&quot; - answers the company, and our soldier begins to blush with freckles to the ears, realizing that with such a cheeky formulation he touched the thin soul of the commander. But the next phrase of the company put everything in its place. - The army has the word &quot;fucked&quot;.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_5">
		<text>Well, listen. After the battle sit soldiers, evil all - many wounded-killed, the Germans from the height and not knocked out. They start to invent, if Hitler is caught, what to do with him? One suggests: &quot;In a shit drown!&quot;. The rest: &quot;No-ee, it&apos;s painfully simple.&quot; The sergeant-major smokes. The second: &quot;Quarter of the bastard!&quot; All: &quot;Nope, it&apos;s too fast.&quot; The foreman smokes. The third one: &quot;Bind them in an anthill, let them eat it!&quot; &quot;No-ee, it&apos;s hard to see&quot; The foreman finished: &quot;Now listen, sons, what we&apos;ll actually do! Take the iron rail, heat one End, and the other in his ass shove! &quot;Grave silence. At last the youngest dared: &quot;Comrade Sergeant, why is it cold? It&apos;s the other way around!&quot; The foreman is instructive: &quot;And that the allies are not dragged out !!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_6">
		<text>Well, listen. They go to the open land, the Emperor Alexander III, Prince Golitsyn and lieutenant Rzhevsky - on guard. Suddenly a narodovolt runs out of the crowd and throws a bomb. Rzhevsky succeeds in intercepting it and throwing it into the Neva. The emperor to him: - Lieutenant, I owe you your life - ask what you want! He without hesitation: - I ask the hands of Princess Golitsyna. The emperor - Golitsyn: - Prince, did you hear? He crumples: - Your Majesty ... - Prince, I understand you. Your daughter&apos;s hands are asked by General Rzhevsky. &quot;But, Your Majesty, we are one of the oldest families in Russia ...&quot; &quot;Very well, prince, I agree.&quot; The hands of your daughter are asked by General Count Rzhevsky. &quot;Ah, Your Majesty!&quot; After all, there is still an opinion of the world! &quot;Prince, I accept all your conditions.&quot; Your friend&apos;s hands are being asked by my personal friend General Count Rzhevsky. Golitsyn: - I agree. A Rzhevsky shoves him off, flops next to the emperor on the seat and slaps the autocrat of all Russia on his knee: &quot;San, this princess fuck us!&quot; There, how many women around!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_7">
		<text>Well, listen. A young guy in a cafe drinks coffee and looks at a beautiful girl at a nearby table. Finally decides to come: - Girl, can I sit down? The girl at all cafes as zaoret: - Yes, I will not sleep with you! People turn around and smile. The guy, reddening, returns to his table. Then the same girl sits down to him. - You, of course, excuse me, but the point is that I am a psychologist and write a thesis on &quot;The behavior of different types of people in inadequate situations.&quot; The guy, all of a sudden, at all the cafes: - WHAT ?! DO TWO BANKS ?! !! ? The girl runs out into the street. The guy calmly gathers, comes out, comes up to her and says: - Very pleased, I&apos;m a lawyer, and I know how to make people feel guilty ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_8">
		<text>Well, listen. Scientists have created a unique computer with artificial intelligence, a wide knowledge base, a speech processor and an emotion synthesizer. According to the idea of ??the creators, he had to answer all questions. Before putting it on public display, we decided to ask him a question of povakovyristey. - Can a peasant fuck a woman? Asked one of the creators. &quot;Maybe, but it&apos;s immoral to beat a woman,&quot; the computer answered. &quot;What a stupid fellow he is!&quot; Laughed the creators. &quot;I will not answer anything else,&quot; said the computer. &quot;Fuck you.&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_9">
		<text>Well, listen. One father built a church. And everything would be fine, but the bell tower fell all the time. Build - it will fall. They will build again - it will fall again. And so the angel of God appeared to the priest and said: &quot;Put your wife in the foundation and in the ages your temple will stand.&quot; His wife was very fond of his young father, but he also loved the Lord. And the temple needs to be built. I was hurt, I cried, I said goodbye to my wife (and she was a God-fearing young lady, I must do it so badly), and I immured myself. And the bell tower still fell. Because you do not fuck with it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_10">
		<text>Well, listen. They stumbled at the crossroads 600 and a penny. Out of the 600th, a bull with chains in his hand comes out thick, and from the penny exactly the same climbs. I drove the 600th: - Well, you got on a new car, exactly the same! Second: - This is you! - Calls on the mobile. An hour later, they bring a zero gelding. Second: - I got you a new one for an hour ?! First ofigevshi: - Well, yes ... - And now you are to me a new penny! In an hour! Time has gone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_11">
		<text>Well, listen. The guy tries to &quot;glue&quot; the drunken girl in the bar: &quot;I bet 10 bucks that I can fuck you as cool as you have not seen, and yet I will not even touch you.&quot; &quot;You&apos;re an idiot, it just can not be. Someone, break it! &quot;Struck by the hands, the guy brought the girl to his house and fucked her all night until the pulse lost.&quot; In the morning she woke him and said: &quot;It was really the best moment in my life, but you always touched me.&quot; &quot;Take on your table The top ten, &quot;the guy muttered through his sleep and turned to the wall.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_12">
		<text>Well, listen. A terrible woman, a muzzle with a brick, comes into the mall with two sons, looking at everyone like Lenin to the bourgeoisie, and shpynaya kids on the slightest occasion. The saleswoman addresses her: - Hello, welcome. What pretty little kids! Twins? &quot;What the fuck are you kidding, frivolous?&quot; One 9 years old, the other 8! Are you blind or just an idiot? - No, neither that, nor another. I just could not believe that someone dared to fuck you twice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_13">
		<text>Well, listen. In the rest home, a plain little peasant pestered a luxurious lady for an intimate connection for a long time. She just mocked him, they say, with your talents ... Then the peasant argued with her that he could fuck her twenty times in a row. The only condition that everything should happen in complete darkness and after every time he should go wash himself. The stove was a car, and the woman agreed. Night fell, and the man set to work ... Once, second, third ... after the seventeenth time the woman could not stand it and begged: &quot;That&apos;s all!&quot; I lost! I can no longer, light the light! The light came on, and she saw before him a completely unfamiliar hefty peasant. - Who are you! ? She screamed. - What are you doing here? And where is the one, small, plyugovenky? - Ah, that&apos;s probably the mass-entertainer? So he sells tickets at the entrance ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_14">
		<text>Well, listen. Attention! A new way of fraud! You need to know! A group of young girls is working. Act as follows: You leave the supermarket, go to the car, boot up and want to leave. At that moment two pretty pussies run up to the car and they are tearfully asked to bring them to the subway, they were stolen by money, and there they will be met by their mother. You agree. One sits on the front seat, the other back. And suddenly the one that bends forward and begins to suck your cock, and the second, while you are mering, eats, * point, your products. Questions to which many in search of an answer: 1) Which supermarket they are looking for? 2) What does the one that sits behind have to eat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_15">
		<text>Well, listen. The schoolgirl is going to the prom. She approaches her mother: - Mom, and if I kiss with the boy on the lips, then I can get pregnant? Mother (smiling): No, of course. - And if you kiss with a tongue? Mother (tensed): No, also. - And if I make him a minet? Mother (shocked): No, you will not become pregnant. - Well, what about the antal? Mother (in a half-synapse): My God, daughter, you&apos;re going to do all this at the graduation ?! !! - No, Mom, do not worry. I&apos;m just figuring out who the father is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_16">
		<text>Well, listen. Grandfather, a participant in the Great Patriotic War, the children were sent to the tourpot in Germany. At the embassy, ??the grandfather fills out a questionnaire, and there are the following questions: - Date of last visit to Germany. He writes: April - May 1945. - The type of transport visited (underscored) ... and the list: airplane, train, car ... other. Grandfather missed everything and wrote: Tank T-34!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_17">
		<text>Well, listen. The investigator of the prosecutor&apos;s office reports to the president: &quot;Vasilyeva showed Serdyukov, Serdyukov to Chubais, Chubais to Surkov, Surkov to Medvedev, Medvedev to ...&quot;. &quot;Enough ...&quot; interrupts Vladimir Vladimirovich - and it is already quite obvious that no one is to blame for anything ... &quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_18">
		<text>Well, listen. A competent insurance salesman: The newly arrived soldiers were driven into the room, the Insurer stepped onto the stage, smiled and said: &quot;Guys, I know that you do not want to listen to all kinds of stuff for a long time, so I&apos;ll explain to you about the insurances in one minute. The meaning of insurance is simple: if you do not have it, you were sent into battle and you were killed - the government will send your family a letter of condolences. If you have it, you were sent into battle and you were killed - the government will send your family $ 20,000. Then he paused, looked around the room with his eyes and asked: &quot;What do you think, guys, who will be the first to be sent into battle in this situation?&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_19">
		<text>Well, listen. The husband and his wife are lying down asleep, the husband is already asleep and, through a dream, says: - Light ... His wife was hurling with all his strength on his forehead, he, poor fellow, had already raised his eyes: - For what? &quot;What the fuck is Sveta?&quot; I&apos;m Galya! - What are you, Galya ?! You stupid fuck! Turn off the light!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_aneki_20">
		<text>Well, listen. One person has committed a crime. He was caught and brought to court to the king. The death penalty was reserved for his deed, but the king offered to choose his own destiny: either to be hanged, or to get behind a big, black, terrible steel door. The criminal thought and chose the gallows. When a loop was thrown around his neck, he suddenly said: &quot;I was curious: what is there, behind that door?&quot; The king laughed: &quot;Yes, you see, it&apos;s a funny thing.&quot; I all offer this choice, and everyone chooses the gallows. &quot;What&apos;s behind the door?&quot; - asked the criminal. &quot;I still will not tell anyone,&quot; he added, pointing to the noose. After a pause, the king replied: &quot;There&apos;s freedom.&quot; But people are so afraid of the unknown that they prefer a rope!</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="dm_about_zonanews_talk">
		<text>Tell me some story about the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_about_zonanewsend">
		<text>Interesting...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_1">
		<text>We climb, then, into that hangar. Around the dust, cobwebs - generally under the roof; Detectors complete nonsense spoil: they say, not that there is nobody around, but we are not in nature either. We went to positions on the perimeter: Sanyok ahead, we cover ... And then - Brzezin! Beams huge such iron, rusty under a ceiling, so one breaks down - and downwards! As Sanyok dodged, he does not know, but this crap stuck right into exactly where he was standing. Well, he fell down and rolled back, did not get up on his feet at all, and so let&apos;s lie down! The others were also frightened, idiots, and went to put themselves in white light. Then Sanya started yelling something about the creature in the corner. I look - no creature I do not see ... In general, we went, not an operation, but a concrete mess ... brothel ... We went on these ruins to walk; They walked for about five minutes - carefully so that under the beams of these no longer be. And nonsense, well, complete nonsense: then one, then another something prividitsya, they let the queues in a shoe polosovat in an empty place. And the two were not lucky at all: one walked on a flat floor, and suddenly fell into the pit, the second ripped through the door across the back stretched. Well, here we are in general wound up - it&apos;s clear after all that the creature has some fun! They cut down the psy-defense, in all corners of the gas grenade - well, we wait, who will appear, and fingers on the descent. We are waiting, waiting ... And the creature, as it turned out later, was a flying thing, or ... While we were lying down at the bottom of the whole stupid fool, she sat quietly under the ceiling and had a good time, bitch ... It only came to us late, and then accidentally almost. Gadina this shattered a couple more beams - half the roofs and itched, it was right on us and it was like, four kids in a cake in place ... Here we got it! As Sanya heard shaburshanie at the top, so on the machine and gave a turn - the most useful, damn, reflex! Well here and squeal! We, too, clearly jumped up, gave out of all the trunks ... The creature poured from above with such cries that it was direct ears pawned. Well, here we were given the soul: who beat the butt, who simply walked with his feet, Sanya, so that knife got out, so that she could piss off with it ... The commander, of course, all with difficulty, but pushed, From the floor had to scrape ...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_10">
		<text>Have you heard about the Explorer? The very first of the stalkers. The first to go to the Zone began, and is still alive. They say, will spend anywhere. Another thing is that it is problematic to find it - the poster with the address does not paste ... And to hold too far not everyone agrees. Bablosov seems to take a lot, but if he found it and agreed, be sure - he&apos;ll bring you iron where you need to. Here with whom to wipe. He must have seen what was behind the radar ...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_11">
		<text>Ponts beat and with the bubble to be - these are two big differences ... What did you think, there&apos;s a loot for it so? No fucking hell! For so only you only a ugly one shava or stalker will be overwhelmed ... It is necessary to think. There it is necessary to think, and here it is even better. The bulls do not hold out very long. Can not it, without an attic if ... In short, it was like this. The three of us with Bruce and Chain deceased walked through the gondola - the road, in short, was cut off. We look - the deer is scratching. Well, we snapped. And he passes by us - does not notice. Small such, and a bag pulls - be healthy. And the machine is cunningly hanging - just a little, with olives nasypiguet. Well, the bruise to me is like, let&apos;s feel the brains, what&apos;s he got there? And I told him: &quot;Quiet, woodpecker! It&apos;s better to see where he pulls his hood. &quot;Well, chu ... Here the deer as it fell through somewhere - we did not even understand. Well, we wait.&quot; He stood up and got out about twenty minutes later, while Zepa came quietly back to him and poltykva from The trellis demolished. They began with the bruise body to disembowel: the armor on it was classy, ??and the spade should be ... I poured away - my boys will always give me, I&apos;m on life in the share. Then he croaks! .. In short, suffered that was not simple: he Th-something cunning navorotil that rvanulo, if from his armor someone will shoot. I knocked it out quickly-very few people would have shot at the shot and the explosion would come ... It came a month later. From the chain with the bruise and the deer - at least a bone. Generally by zeros. In short, I figured out where he was diving into ruins, and he climbed there ... Well, there were three rooms - a nerdy! Then I look, in a corner a pile of beds is piled up. Why the hell are there so many sunbeds? In short, I started raking. It&apos;s razed. I look - my mother is a woman, hatch! I lift, therefore, the lid, the candle with a flashlight. Yeraresete! I&apos;m in paradise! .. Well, Che was there - my business ... I did not stay in vain. And I would hang my ears-I would have been a fool for a long time, or have been running barefoot so far, barked ... like some ...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_12">
		<text>They say that there is one group of comrades ... They are called shamans, and when the druids. They say they do not carry any electronic equipment at all - they are closer to nature, and all that ... Well, they say that the Zone is for electronics ... On radiation any electromagnetic reacts more strongly ... Yes, and monsters on you set off. As in their turn it turns out, so the Zone is a living organism. You can not, they say, climb into it with devices - the right person and without any extra weight will cope. True, they carry machines with them, goats, drag ... No teeth and claws to try ... On the other hand, they die in the Zone, it seems not so much. They do not bother us more often ... So maybe they got it right ... They, however, seem to come more and more from the Belarusian side to the Zone ... And it would be nice to look at them ... let&apos;s check at the same time how many They have artifacts on their pockets ...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_13">
		<text>Who-thread, maybe, knows about the labs secreted deep in the Zone? .. They seem to be still working ... Well, yes, yes ... It&apos;s unclear how anyone could survive at all ... without supplies, energy ... That raises the question - maybe, there are not any people working? I talked to a guy here alone ... He did not see the lab himself ... ... No, I did not see it myself, but some strange talks on &quot;Yantar&quot; were caught on the scanner. They talked about a laboratory. And another man, this one, swore that he had stumbled somehow on a figure in a suit of the Stalker type, but more sophisticated ... And like that figure, this translucent said to him to get out of here. &quot;Do not bother, they say, leave, we are working here.&quot; Well, the guy&apos;s messed up ... understandable! Who among us has seen this before? .. On the other hand, it seems to have happened near the radar ... Well, you understand ... Well, yes. So it&apos;s hardly true ... But on the other hand ... mutations, they are different, probably, are? Maybe it&apos;s not people, but some energy entities? And? .. Come on, Th you ... Just a little, just neigh ...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_14">
		<text>You know what I&apos;ll say? In this part of the Zone, it&apos;s almost impossible to sleep ... I&apos;m lucky, I can not fall asleep ... and people have such nightmares that sometimes they do not wake up in the morning ... from a heart rupture, for example ... Who moves horses , But who has a roof specifically ... Recently, though, the rumor has gone that there is a remedy. If you strongly sleep, it is advisable to find a bucket of old ... well, or a pan at least a big ... boiling out there ... The main thing is that the whole ... You shove your head there - and sleep like a god in your bosom ... Well, laugh, laugh. I&apos;ll look at you in a couple of days, when you&apos;ll start to fall from fatigue. Clever ... But tell me yourself, which, then, is that, the fuck, the warriors here have recently begun to shuffle in helmets helter? Well yes! Earlier, for two years already, neither the rumor nor the spirit, and lately have become frequent! Helmet they have some new ones - they found the body of one, told. The mesh is there inside of a thin copper wire, attached to the balaclava. So think - what kind of harness, why is she such? In general, this is &quot;zh-zh&quot; is not for nothing, I&apos;m telling you exactly. Of the anomalies, there is nothing to choose here - not those grounds, on the other sites and safer, and there are pieces of fattier ... I think so, the approaches they plan. The bridgehead is being prepared. I want to make my way to the Sarcophagus, remember my word. So soon, the guy - no one will not seem a little. Remember my word ... The main thing is for us to be away from here at that time ...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_15">
		<text>Listen, guys, do you know something about &quot;Interception&quot;? Well, they say, specials, personnel soldiers! But how do they work? How they work! These are not assholes in cordons! Not only that in the most zazhope lazyat, so still sit in the Zone for months! Yes, I do not drive! Their bases, several pieces at once, are crammed to the skins, and to the perimeter they put supplies to the perimeter. The commander they have Gromov some ... I think the surname is bullshit, not real - they are his &quot;Major&quot;, then &quot;Thunder&quot; is called. Do not believe me ?! So Pakhomych intercepted somehow! Caught - and God forbid his feet, otherwise he would have spiked for a healthy life ... Secrecy, so her! Do you all know Pakhomych? Well, that&apos;s it! It&apos;s not bullshit, it&apos;s a serious team. Horseradish knows what they have drawn so interesting, but they work - my dear mother! To me in a third - not, ten percent would be so! - would have a house in Sochah floors for ten would have built ... They, they say, this thing is ... a monster for two hundred meters to mark. Any creature! Is clear horseradish, then, and in the Zone go-pop ... And then, they say, there are some figures ... It&apos;s not warriors, it&apos;s kind of like ours ... In general, some of them made their way to the center of the Zone. It&apos;s not enough that they made their way - they, they say, can tame the creatures! They do not go around the perimeter, to the Big Land - and to them, too, no one ... well, except for those, probably, who to write to the sarcophagus on the family is written ... Already the artifacts of them - at least rub it! &quot;Dolgovtsy&quot; is something they know about them ... they know, reptiles, they are fighting - and they are silent! You will ask which of these policemen: &quot;Fairy tales&quot;, - said. Well, not bitches, well ?!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_16">
		<text>Brothers, did you hear about unbelievers who broke through to the antennae? Fortunately, the Monolith guided us and the brothers picked them off just in time. One was eliminated immediately, the other two ran away. Cowards! They’re all cowards! True faith leaves no room for fear! Two managed to escape, but the Monolith is wise and omniscient. It would not have let them live without a reason.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_17">
		<text>Brothers, the Monolith summoned me last night and I spoke with it. It was awesome in its greatness, nearly blinding me, but its light filled me with powers beyond mere mortal comprehension! I know, I feel its power within us all! Only firm faith can overcome evil. It told me its power can fill only those who have faith. Finally, it revealed to me that our victory is at hand!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_18">
		<text>I think that ... Not even what I think - so, I&apos;m figuring ... And suddenly everything - that&apos;s all there is to it, - what kind of experiment is it over people? This, mozhbyt, some green people ... And what? Not worse than the other version ... I wonder: if it&apos;s something like a test site, then what exactly are they running around here? Check, by what artifacts are we the most drooling? Or is it any bombs at all, eh? They grew up all over the world, according to the laboratories of every kind, the rich have rasskraskolilis ... No, well, that&apos;s cool! .. That would be with my pleasure! .. We bought from under the floor some crap ... a lot of bubble fell off ... Type &quot;we are cooler than all&quot;, jealous, sheep ... and it ... it ... ka-ak peck! .. Oh, class ! .. Oh, I can not! .. Oh ... uf-ff ... And in general, of course, FIG knows what, in fact ... Is the one who went for the radar, can tell about it ... Well, yes, they, maybe, know, just do not say Can - moo and drool. Maybe that&apos;s why they let them go ... Eh ... That&apos;s what all sorts of thoughts come up with ... It&apos;s sad at all ...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_19">
		<text>I was in the Dark Valley. There are a lot of infidels, because the power of the Monolith has not yet reached these places. We guarded. We were attacked at night. We fought fiercely with these animals. The merits of the brothers were great: soon Monolith called them to him. For me, he prepared another test. My weapons did not fire anymore. But then the Monolith said to me: &quot;You are with me, and my strength is with you. If you are firm in your faith, you will crush my enemies and come closer to me! &quot;Then I became a shadow.&quot; I ducked and walked them to the right. &quot;Silly spies did not notice anything. They thought they had done with us and laughed at the empty bodies of our Brothers, but I already saw their backs, and then the power of the Monolith struck from my hands, so he killed them all, I&apos;m happy to serve you, Perfect! ..</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_2">
		<text>We with my partner to this research institute have long been eyeing. It hurts the place is deserted. No beasts in the neighborhood, no mutants. Only whoever went there, or frightened vusmert, from the reels came back, or did not see them anymore. We decided to explore on our own. They drove out in the dark, and as they got to the place, it&apos;s already getting light. They left the car in the decay, went to the edge of the forest. They stopped there, the partner remained below, and I climbed up a tree with optics - look around what is happening in the neighborhood. I see - the hulls, and not so completely abandoned, the glass is almost intact, in the courtyards of the grass a little, not that in other places - to the waist ... It all went on that they live here, but the silence is utterly complete and there is no movement. Suddenly, queues struck a little on the right - someone from the machine hit short. I optic there. I see that on the roof of one of the buildings an unfamiliar man as a rat is hunted and shoots indiscriminately in all directions. In whom - I can not see and understand: he was alone there. And here ... it began ... I saw everything on my palm. The machine from his hands flew by itself ... As if the wings of a piece of iron have grown! .. A man opened his mouth, evidently, yelled something, took out a knife and exposed it in front of him. And here - a Christmas tree-winnowing! - I look, and before him one more hangs. That&apos;s the way it hangs in the air and nobody hangs it. What happened next was not to tell the night ... Five minutes later that man was cutting. Little by little, bitches, their mother by the leg - there is a cut, there is an injection ... The poor fellow was soon all covered with blood ... Then, as he began to become stiff in his legs, his knife also knocked out; Here the peasant as lifted into the air, as wrapped a couple of times ... I did not see such a thing in my life - naturally, like a rag rotated ... I became wet in three seconds ... Then ... No, everything, I will not ... In general, as I caught my breath, another five minutes fumbled around the neighborhood. His hands trembled, the optics from wet sweat became ... Well, at least one creature! And in the usual range and in infrared - no-che-go. As I climbed down, my partner looked at me, and asked me to change my mind. And how did they return to the base, I wagged a week before my brows, did not dry out ... Then, as I left a little bit, I asked our people-maybe someone had heard of such things? Only people began to look at me askance - did not they? That&apos;s it…</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_20">
		<text>Brothers, as we were patrolling the outskirts of the Dark Forest we came upon an unfaithful loner. We did not kill him, seeing as he was already on his way to conversion, although he was still half-way in his animal state… Such is the wisdom of the Monolith: once again it revealed to us the true countenance of our enemies. Now our faith is even stronger! It is at hand, brothers! The victory over the unbelievers is at hand. Soon the Monolith will fulfill our greatest desires! Those who are truly faithful to it will be drawn to it, to its glory, its greatness! We shall abide in its radiance forever!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_3">
		<text>In general, my friendship is what I told. It was picked up, in short, in the middle of the night the authorities - like running to the laboratory, the load came. He is sleepy, does not understand: what kind of cargo? They told him: you&apos;re a black, drunk alcohol treasury? Trupak fresh on the table, eat! In short, he comes, and to the table. And there it is ... He, in the course of the game, saw the blinkers from the Zone in his lifetime: you were torn, and fried-VARENE, and mutants caught more than a dozen, but here in the stomach a dinner began to walk. In short, at first sight - without two minutes a person, only a cat on a normal one is not like a fig: a healthy pumpkin is tuberous. Well, the body is a concentration camp, a pancake, skin and bones. But he then disassembled it, and at first, he says, I look, a mash of some sort: everything is in the reverse direction, it&apos;s stained with an orange-red dirty trick - the blood of a type ... These ammunition did not pity the Hondurans. Do-olg ... search for anomalous objects, damn ... do not fucking find yourself! .. This, he said, was a cross between a colander and a torn hot-water bottle ... ... and in general they clearly walked about it in their geeshes; Not an object, a pancake, but a piece of meat in a black rag. In short, he spent the rest of the night and half the morning hunchbacked. In the process, it turns out, this is the same creature that the locals know for an illusionist: black rags, visions of stalkers, a meter meter in girth ... It&apos;s cool what his face, who saw, believed - it&apos;s like a topic. No, he has a natural personality, only a small one at all: the stilts do not open and the nose is like a pin, although the jaw is a hefty, straight jamb at the gate. He walks, evidently, and hangs his head on his chest - I do not have the strength to hold ... the brains ... And figure out what these creatures eat for dinner. Fungi! Mushrooms! In short, everyone saw - in the Zone of mushrooms is full, so &quot;old men&quot; tooth give, that these creatures from them juice squeeze. Gourmets, damn ... And do you know what else was hidden in his bag on his side? Well? Yes, where you! In short, his brains were dried up there. And do you know whose? Controller! ..</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_4">
		<text>It was nailed to us here fool alone ... Cheshem, then we&apos;ll take a five-minute rest, and he immediately to the fifth point - and relaxes. And how to go - so he takes the last ass off the ground. Well, preasslablyalsya ... behind, and then his controller - for brains zap! - and it&apos;s ready. Who is a beginner, in our business, remember. The rustle there or the breeze is suspicious ... Let the bunny run though ... although the bunnies are here - God forbid ... In a word, you have to be ready every second. To shops and grenades at hand and the machine on the continuous. If you see that, drop off immediately polrogolka; If there is something behind the bushes, too, then ask. Here the course of a young fighter is this: they do not hang clothes, but they will devour with giblets, you will not have a fart! Yes, about the controllers - a separate story. Suppose you shot at the rustle - and fall right away, at the same moment! Though on the back, at least as. The controller clings, if he sees you - he needs to concentrate, or what. While sunbathing in the tent, listen to both ears - rustle, whether there is any rubbish to you. You can quietly re-click the store, and garnets too, it is not out of place to cook ... In general, if everything is quiet, you count to three and ... And fall! Go to hell! Well, sucked? Eh, Salazhat ... You take care of yourself every second - only here you can survive ...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_5">
		<text>I think that ... Not even what I think - so, I&apos;m figuring ... And suddenly everything - that&apos;s all there is to it, - what kind of experiment is it over people? This, mozhbyt, some green people ... And what? Not worse than the other version ... I wonder: if it&apos;s something like a test site, then what exactly are they running around here? Check, by what artifacts are we the most drooling? Or is it any bombs at all, eh? They grew up all over the world, according to the laboratories of every kind, the rich have rasskraskolilis ... No, well, that&apos;s cool! .. That would be with my pleasure! .. We bought from under the floor some crap ... a lot of bubble fell off ... Type &quot;we are cooler than all&quot;, jealous, sheep ... and it ... it ... ka-ak peck! .. Oh, class ! .. Oh, I can not! .. Oh ... uf-ff ... And in general, of course, FIG knows what, in fact ... Is the one who went for the radar, can tell about it ... Well, yes, they, maybe, know, just do not say Can - moo and drool. Maybe that&apos;s why they let them go ... Eh ... That&apos;s what all sorts of thoughts come up with ... It&apos;s sad at all ...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_6">
		<text>So ... I remember someone asked me something yesterday, but I forgot ... Ah, I remembered. There are, therefore, curious, why in the Zone only our eggheads swish, and foreigners and nose do not seem to, although here the material of the Nobles is three thousand ... So, I answer the points. Firstly, why should we go here, when can we give our grant, but with such conditions that he will bring everything he needs to you on a silver platter? Well, if in the second place, they actually were here, and a lot. This last year, two zabugortsy in the Zone are afraid to climb ... happened to them one major bummer. Now they only buy up materials and information. Pay in general is not bad, so many singles work for them, and marauders too ... What, did not hear about this story? Well, give! The whole Zone was on your ears, and you fell from the sky. In general, the transfer was great. Some scientists are thirty people from the middle of the world ... everything was shining, of course, back and forth ... We were preparing seriously: money was charged - at least one place you eat, equipment - mountains. They took with them a platoon of military experts for guarding, three of our conductors, on the BaTaRa, the screened ones plunged and sailed off. Something ... We returned a week later ... twelve people on the killed in the trash of BaTeRe. They came to the thorn in the Rotten Forest, and there they were already waiting ... looters ... Yes ... This do not care where people broke out ... They put almost everyone. For the perimeter, only three got out - two of us and one egghead. The man moved from the impressions with powerful attic ... Well, he quickly by the scruff of the neck - and heal. He now writes a book about the Zone. Our something else - experience helped. Although ... also, probably, in their own way moved: one went to the radar and disappeared, and the second to the Greater Land moved. Well, the rest of the Zone took. About the town-thirty-two heard? That&apos;s where they got. At first everything seemed to be quiet ... well, within ... They were taking pictures-measured, samples collected, in an anomaly they poked with instruments ... And then they began to be in a state of insanity. Mass. The people began to slowly ride the roof. I&apos;m ours - the one who went to rest - told ... Who started to tear his throat with fingernails, who broke his head against the wall, and who simply - the trunk in his mouth, and ... And then the beast pierced. Who in himself was barricaded in the house. Presented, yes? Outside the night and all the surrounding creatures, and inside people fly from one reel one after another. In a word, in the morning, those who could still think, somehow broke away. Back they drove straight, without a road; Even a couple of anomalies hooked ... They reached the Rotten Forest ... And of those who remained there, no one was found. The guys only say that in those places the controllers have sharply increased. Yes ... Since then, no one pokes into Gorodok-thirty-two, and you do not entice a foreigner into the Zone ...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_7">
		<text>So that&apos;s what I wanted to say. When the &quot;duty&quot; of that illusion was taken, I was near! Yes, I happened to be in those parts at all! At my wheelbarrow, at &quot;Niva&quot; at my mine, the right forward flew: bolts on a hummock cut off. And for the spare parts a full zero. I pomaterilsya as it should, and then give, I think, the plant go, select the right. Well, there was a kilometer to go, back and forth - for half an hour! Yes, and I&apos;ve been there before ... Then suddenly I see - &quot;duty&quot;! Yes, not just a patrol, but half a piece! Well, I think a pancake-compote! .. As he stood, he fell into the bushes. &quot;If you notice and start combing,&quot; I think, &quot;then I&apos;m a Trindec.&quot; I&apos;m in the hole, in short, and try not to breathe. And then shooting! To ensure that such queues are used, I only heard once in my life ... when the First base was taken - the old people, remember? In general, I lie, listen in both ears ... It bows to myself, and then again and how it will crash! .. In five minutes it calms down and no one seems to come to me. Well, I impudently typed, got up a bit and look through binoculars. And these are quickly pulled out of the shop ... crumpled such, their clowns with a bunch of dragging and an illusion on the tarpaulin ... the scraps are already alone from the illusion left ... Draped into the hollow. Then I hear - the engines roared, and the sound went away. I still waited - like no one. I&apos;m inside. Well, it&apos;s clear that after the &quot;Debt&quot; you&apos;ll find the horse-radish! But it is interesting! This, I&apos;ll tell you, there was something! Walls they almost podkyryvili. The beams cross the floor across the floor, the roof slump collapsed. A knee case is a natural shooting range. Blood, scrapes of some kind ... Useful, however, did not find anything - so, two horns full, but the machine was lying about, the beam crushed, not pull ... I forgot about bolts, of course, ... I returned to the wheelbarrow, thought for five minutes, took the bolt off the other wheels ... Well, I drove slowly ... And I went there earlier for half an hour ... Hmm ...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_8">
		<text>Yes, so I went right up to the very edge of the Pripyat. Well, I decided to look around first. I found a point higher - there the big boiler house was with a pipe. Well, I went in carefully ... like, I look, like chiki-peaks everything - the dust lies, there are no traces ... I got into the furnace and crawled: there were steps inside the pipe. Normally climb, even the carbon is not getting dirty anymore - it&apos;s petrified ... I step out cautiously ... Beauty! Half the city as in the palm of your hand! I pulled out the binoculars and looked around ... (a small pause) Well, on and on ... It&apos;s already going down, so it&apos;s creeping down, and then the thought jumps: what&apos;s under the nose itself is going on, and has not looked! I crouch a little over the edge, look at one side, then the other ... Both-on! Here it would get! In the courtyard the dwarf walks! The main thing is, I&apos;m almost down already! And then it&apos;s okay that he does not see me yet. Only the tower I can not demolish to him: &quot;Kalash&quot; hangs on the back, and the pipe is narrow at all, do not turn around. From the &quot;Makarov&quot;, that under the mouse - shit, it&apos;s about fifty meters, and the difference in height ... in short, if I do not get there right away - and yet I do not get - then it&apos;s just a kerdyk. I sit, I reflect. Well, I&apos;m looking at what he&apos;s doing there. And he does something incomprehensible. At first bodrenko so, with a spark, rummaged in a pile of rubbish - only pieces to the right and left flew. And then suddenly as he stood, he froze. It seems to listen. Well, there was a mess completely. The garbage in that heap itself began to stir. The dwarf quickly jumped back, became such a column, put his hands to his head, somehow managed to twist his palms cunningly ... and he would fly to him! From all sides! .. Iron, bricks, ruberoid, branches ... It&apos;s so covered with his head. Well, I think that&apos;s all. Pipets kitten, more pissing will not ... Neither a fig! Two seconds of trash this lie down, and then just like ka-ak splashes in all directions! There pruned pipes, so they are straight into the concrete fence stuck. I stood there for another half a minute, I made a mistake for myself, and then turned around and stumbled into the building. I took a minute to translate the spirit. &quot;Well, I think - a little bit of a good thing, it&apos;s time to get out of here.&quot; And then suddenly the smoke pulled. And then it began to get hot. Yes, you go to the stump! Fire someone from below blew! After a minute - everything, there was already nothing to breathe. Somehow I grabbed to the edge of the pipe - there is no platform, I sit, my legs hang ... Only the smoke still eats the eye, there is not enough air ... it&apos;s necessary to bring down urgently! Thank God, I dragged forty meters with myself all the time for a fire accident ... exactly like a fireman ... In general, I folded it in half - he was not very thick - I fixed it on the pipe, the neck scarf tore it in half, wound up the spineless ones From above, and it&apos;s useful, to all the gods praying ... In the head one thought: just do not fall! Neither insurance, nothing, a cord of a hand cuts ... Well and, certainly, under the law of meanness of meters of five up to the earth it did not suffice. I had to shine. What is there to do? Oh, I&apos;ve thundered! I was lucky, though I did not break anything ... But I took off my right leg and pulled it - be healthy! Then I thought that I had torn the bundles at all. And then he pulled out from there so that the gold medal in the race, probably, would have won ...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_zonanews_9">
		<text>And then I could not believe my eyes. Now, it would seem, there are beautiful girls, right? But this one was ... she ... Perfection. Yes. Here. &quot; Perfection. It was a feeling that the world around her was black and white and blurred, she was alone in color and harshness. How she moved! I have never seen this before. I already fell in my throat. Well, this science succumbed to it! What is there to do in the Zone? .. Well, yes, in the Zone. By evening it was ... At the bus station there is a separate building. First something in the window on the first floor flashed. I quickly took the kalash out of the fuse, and then I look - it comes out of the entrance ... I wanted to wipe my eyes - is it too little, what can one expect of the Zone? And she&apos;s coming. And I&apos;m standing like a fool, I&apos;m staring ... I&apos;ve got an automatic machine, though I&apos;ve got it ready - habit already ... Then she noticed me ... Smiled ... She said hello ... And I listen and do not hear, I&apos;m looking at her. She was in a blue overalls, bright such ... but not balakhonist, and almost tight-fitting ... The figure of her - something fantastic! It only occurred to me that I did not listen at all what she was saying-I stood and smiled to the ears ... She turned out to be from the research group. I asked if I had the opportunity to help her. Her! Yes, I would go to the anomaly for her sake! .. She said that she is dealing with these, as their ... endemic to the Zone. Well, plants that only here are found. She said she escaped from the guard, because with them there is no freedom of action, and she came here alone. I do not know. I believed it. Agreed to help - to bring her something. Two days later I came, as agreed. About five times I almost covered myself while I was collecting. I&apos;m walking, but I have one thought in my head: now I&apos;ll see her again! And nothing. I did not even see the house where she met her. So ... But what was it like! She was directly glowing from the inside ...</text>
	</string>	
</string_table>
