<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="st_af_baloon_descr">
		<text>A piece of tightly compressed snowflakes and the smallest parts of the victims of the anomaly, shaped like a heart. Has a weak psi effect, considering the heart, a person sinks into a state of icy calm, concentrates ... However, the main property of an artifact is the ability to instantly stop bleeding. Anything. A small cut, a bullet wound, lacerations or an extremity torn off in an anomaly - it is only necessary to rub the artifact and tie it to the wound, the blood will stop after a few seconds, the pain will disappear, the affected area will numb, as after the injection of novocaine. The action ends in an hour, after the artifact has melted.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_baloon_name">
		<text>&quot;Frozen heart&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mincer_izumrud_name">
		<text>&quot;Emerald Hunk&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mincer_izumrud_descr">
		<text>This artifact can be found only in the depths of the Zone among radioactive anomalous fields. Having absorbed in itself the best properties of artifacts of Emerald and a hunk of meat, it represents both thermal protection and chemical protection. Perhaps the disadvantages are radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_amk_snezhok_descr">
		<text>A small artifact, radioactive, slightly accelerates the healing of wounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_amk_snezhok_name">
		<text>&quot;Snowball&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_amk_mox_descr">
		<text>Quite a rare artifact, not everyone has heard of it. With such an artifact it is very convenient to go to distant raids, it allows you to carry extra weight, strangely affecting its owner. Reduces the recovery of forces, apparently the artifact causes the body to spend energy mainly on carrying. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_amk_mox_name">
		<text>&quot;Moss&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_amk_kogot_descr">
		<text>A little-studied artifact, afflicted with the Electra anomaly, dulls the hunger of its owner. Increases bullet resistance, in some cases, saving lives.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_amk_kogot_name">
		<text>&quot;Claw&quot;</text>
	</string>
   	<string id="st_amk_ice_s_descr">
		<text>The artifact generated by the Gravi anomaly, than it looks like an ice cream, is a rare artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_amk_ice_s_name">
		<text>&quot;Ice Spear&quot;</text>
	</string>
   	<string id="st_amk_elektron_descr">
		<text>Quite an inconsistent artifact. Despite the fact that the artifact is generated by chemical artifacts, it produces radiation well. Has a spherical appearance and allows you to carry extra weight. Has cons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_amk_elektron_name">
		<text>&quot;Ball&quot;</text>
	</string>
   	<string id="st_amk_chelust_descr">
		<text>The artifact quite strongly resembles a jaw, apparently because of this it was so called. The artifact will give a feeling of satiety, but there is a minus in it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_amk_chelust_name">
		<text>&quot;Jaw&quot;</text>
	</string>
   	<string id="st_amk_fonar_descr">
		<text>Artifact, which as a result of energy collapse causes an easy feeling of hunger. But the artifact will increase the psi protection of the owner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_amk_fonar_name">
		<text>&quot;Slime&quot;</text>
	</string>
   	<string id="st_amk_zhelch_descr">
		<text>A fairly common artifact, amazed by the anomaly of Electra. The artifact is not expensive, it protects a little from radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_amk_zhelch_name">
		<text>&quot;Scar&quot;</text>
	</string>
   	<string id="st_amk_ear_descr">
		<text>In appearance, it reminds me of a spider, it increases the electrical protection. Artifact is not expensive, and therefore meets often enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_amk_ear_name">
		<text>&quot;Spider&quot;</text>
	</string>
   	<string id="st_amk_repei_descr">
		<text>It is named so apparently because of the fact that it looks like an uncomplicated plant. However, the artifact itself is valuable enough and can partially protect you from chemical effects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_amk_repei_name">
		<text>&quot;Agrimony&quot;</text>
	</string>
   <string id="st_amk_yoyo_descr">
		<text>It looks like two heads from mushrooms, which look exactly the same, perhaps that&apos;s why they called it so. The artifact will increase your electrical protection, although with him and the hood will have to drag a little less.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_amk_yoyo_name">
		<text>&quot;Twins&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_glass_descr">
		<text>By properties - a typical healing artifact, has an unusually high price, and, if not a panacea, it is able to cure most diseases known to science, heal even the heaviest wounds and lead a person out of the state of coma. It is a bluish ball in a greenish frame with a certain concentration of energy, gradually consuming when using an artifact to its destination. After exhaustion gets black. It is known that the artifact is inert towards the blood, which can not even adhere to the surface of the artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ameba_cubic">
		<text>&quot;Cube&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_ameba_cubic_descr">
		<text>A semi-transparent artifact of an unknown breed. Accelerating the metabolic processes in an unknown way, increases the body&apos;s immunity. Absorbs some radiation. Perhaps this is what causes an easy, dull feeling of hunger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_wish_name">
		<text>&quot;Dream&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_wish_descr">
		<text>A rare artifact. The best of all found, protecting from radiation, with complete absence of negative effects. For which he received the name. It really is the dream of any stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristal_drops_name">
		<text>&quot;Tears of the sky&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristal_drops_descr">
		<text>Artifact of ice origin, is formed in the cold season. It is a lump of snow and ice, like a tear. Increases the resistance to radiation, as well as the owner of the artifact freezes skin, as a result of which the skin becomes resistant to bullets, but it is necessary to pay for reduced mobility.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_black_name">
		<text>&quot;Black stone&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_black_descr">
		<text>A truly amazing thing. Black stone protects from adversity, but instead slowly kills the owner. Among the stalkers, it is considered that it is a fragment of the Monolith.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_zelonka_name">
		<text>&quot;Zelenka&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_zelonka_descr">
		<text>Like the eponymous medicine, it is very appreciated and used. Perfectly heals wounds and increases psi-protection. Despite the radioactivity, many stalkers use the artifact if they find it, but do not sell it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_kashtan_name">
		<text>&quot;Chestnut&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_kashtan_descr">
		<text>The artifact looks like a jagged chestnut-outgrowth with sharp spines, because of which the resistance to bleeding is apparently reduced. Thin needles attract energetic discharge and the body reduces resistance to lacerations. This artifact absorbs toxins and radiation from the air well, and the needles partially suppress the psi signals.</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_izumrud_name">
		<text>&quot;Emerald&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_izumrud_descr">
		<text>Very rare and expensive artifact in the zone. It looks like a crystal, but only greenish. Near its owner is formed a barely noticeable, green plaque. No, it&apos;s not a disease. All this will increase your thermal protection, and also add a little space in your backpack. There are only a few people who have found this artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gauss_name">
		<text>&quot;Gauss&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gauss_descr">
		<text>According to rumors, it is these particles that the Monoliths use to charge their guns of the same name. The artifact was found quite recently, a stalker named Lun. In the artifact is a charge of energy, but strangely enough it is not radioactive. Many minds puzzle over the mystery of this thing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_setka_name">
		<text>&quot;Heart of Danko&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_setka_descr">
		<text>An artifact of unknown origin. Increases the carrying capacity of the carrier, and also increases the healing of wounds, working as a second heart. Without having negative characteristics, the artifact is very valuable.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_af_plenka_name">
		<text>&quot;Film&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_plenka_descr">
		<text>Such an artifact is not a rare rarity. Outwardly it looks like a pacifier. You can meet him often enough, but he is well appreciated for his properties. It occurs very rarely, and the demand for it was asleep.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_sverlo_name">
		<text>&quot;Drill&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_sverlo_descr">
		<text>The drill is one of the rarest artifacts found in the exclusion zone. The first specimen was discovered by a stalker named Lemur. His name was given for an intricate, elongated cylindrical shape casting silvery color. The main properties have not been studied before, so their practical application in the field conditions of the zone is impossible. The price is extremely high.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_oreh_name">
		<text>&quot;Nut&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_oreh_descr">
		<text>Another rare of the artifacts of the zone. It is a ball of a dark brown color the size of a walnut, for which it actually got its name. Gives to its owner vivacity and saturation effect. The main of its properties is the possibility of treating various rare diseases such as brain cancer and some others. It is unconvincing that such money is offered for him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_blacksoul_name">
		<text>&quot;Black soul&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_blacksoul_descr">
		<text>Analog of an ordinary soul, which is black and red. The effect of the black soul is clearly the opposite of the effect of the &quot;soul&quot; of the ordinary. It absorbs the life force of the owner, for a short time bringing the body to exhaustion. It also has a negative effect on the psyche, causing aggressiveness, suspicion. If the artifact is split, a bright greenish flash is generated, which outstrips the light grenade in power. It is extremely rare, in places where a large number of living creatures have died in the carousel anomaly. It is extremely dangerous, it is not recommended to come into contact. Only scientists and finished collectors can be interested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_chertyaico_name">
		<text>&quot;Devil&apos;s Egg&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_chertyaico_descr">
		<text>The size and shape resembles a chicken egg, has a deep black color and gleams in the light. If you split it, a very strong impulse of an unknown nature arises. It heals cancer and blood diseases and some other diseases. He also cures the negative impact of the devil guardian, while leaving his positive impact untouched. Incorrectly broken eggs, as well as whole, are deadly, the slightest contact with this artifact leads to instant death. Also, the &quot;Egg&quot; gradually burns metal and wood. Maternal anomaly: Devil&apos;s web. A devil&apos;s egg has a negative weight, so look for it under the roofs of dilapidated buildings, under the ceilings of the cellars, which prevent it from soaring into the sky. Probably, this is the reason for the extreme rarity of the devil&apos;s eggs: most of them after the occurrence just fall up and disappear forever in outer space. It is necessary to extract and store this artifact with great care.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_sluda_name">
		<text>&quot;Mica&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_sluda_descr">
		<text>The most powerful (and, accordingly, useful) artifact of the Kholodtsa. Increases blood clotting several times. Almost transparent, but with a solid ball. He is very rare and expensive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_djoker_name">
		<text>&quot;Joker&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_djoker_descr">
		<text>A large transparent spherical crystal with a reddish tint. It protects against practically all the dangers of the Zone, including bullets, and anomalies. In addition, enhances the innate psi-ability of the carrier. But the activity of the artifact is not constant, non-systematic periods of rest are observed, which does not allow to rely on its protection in dangerous situations. Maternal anomaly: a complex of anomalies Black Angel, which generates and destroys the Joker. Extremely rare and incredibly expensive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_oko_name">
		<text>&quot;Eye&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_oko_descr">
		<text>It is a translucent pale blue-green on the edges of a ball the size of a fist. The center of the artifact has a dense matte color. The eye has a truly unique ability to record events occurring next to the artifact and then reproduce them within themselves. That is, a video camera. In addition, it provides additional protection against chemical and electrical damage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_vedsleza_name">
		<text>&quot;The Witch&apos;s Tear&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_vedsleza_descr">
		<text>Quite the same artifact spread out in the center of the zone. Has an oblong form of a reddish drop with a green tint. Will recover near the frying anomaly. Increases the resistance to high temperature. Radioactive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_raibloko_name">
		<text>&quot;Paradise apple&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_raibloko_descr">
		<text>Iridescent sphere the size of an apple, which slowly rotates about a meter and a half above the ground. Publishes a subtle, on the verge of audibility squeak. Has zero-gravity, gives a weak protection against psi-exposure, in places with an increased radiation background it becomes very hot. Maternal anomaly: Orchestra (Echo). The sale price is high. I&apos;m interested in scientists and collectors.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mebiusring_name">
		<text>&quot;The Mobius Ring&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_mebiusring_descr">
		<text>Blue, with a multicolored overflow ring of light glassy material. Being planted on a thin horizontal rod and slightly untwisted, continues to move until the force is stopped. The first &quot;eternal engine&quot; found in the Zone. The price is large enough, scientists are interested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_korostelgod_name">
		<text>&quot;The Coronado God&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_korostelgod_descr">
		<text>Looks like a rough figure sitting man. The material from which it is made is similar to glass, metal and stone at the same time. According to scientists, such material can not exist in our system. Properties have not yet been identified. Maternal anomaly - swell. It is beyond Radar and beyond. It is very rare and expensive, although it interests mainly collectors. Extremely radioactive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_partsky_name">
		<text>&quot;Shard of the sky&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_partsky_descr">
		<text>Blue transparent crystal. Has the ability to enhance the psi effect, which makes it extremely dangerous to wear in the Zone. It is the catalyst for some other artifacts. Under special conditions, the color changes to green and turns into the Seed of the Zone. The tree puppeteer is the root of the plant anomaly. It is very difficult to obtain. Digging under the Tree-puppeteer can only be a suicide, so the only way to get a Shard of Heaven is to find such a hill with the Puppeteer, at the base of which there are natural voids and get it from below. The price of this artifact is at the level of two hundred and fifty thousand and it&apos;s going to decrease in vryatli, as its ability to degenerate into a unique Seed of the Zone can not be underestimated.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cepen_name">
		<text>&quot;Tapeworm&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_cepen_descr">
		<text>Grayish-white twisted spiral with golden tint. The number of loops differs from several tens to several hundreds. Properties: It is a powerful super-high frequency current generator and can be used to power not only various vehicles, but also hand-held laser and MKV rifles. Useful and expensive artifact. With joy take the military, scientists. The number of turns determines the cost. For proper storage, it is placed in two layers of insulation and in a porcelain cup.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_poipruz_name">
		<text>&quot;The Singing Spring&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_poipruz_descr">
		<text>Quite a rare, though not very expensive artifact. It is generated by the anomaly of the echo, it has the shape of an elongated spring. A little radiation. The side properties, if any, have not yet been studied.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_oblivion_name">
		<text>&quot;Oblivion Lost&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_oblivion_descr">
		<text>A small, fist-sized, bluish-white ball. Like an ice with small dark blue blotches. Is able to disperse any object (bullet) passing through it, to unprecedented speeds. Additionally protects against psi effects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_healthwind_name">
		<text>&quot;Healing wind&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_healthwind_descr">
		<text>It is a small ingot of milky white. When activated, it flickers blue. Very rare artifact, which has unique healing properties. Most analogs heal exclusively mechanical damage by strengthening the regeneration of the body, but this artifact treats any diseases. Unfortunately, the artifact works only once, after which it crumbles into fine white sand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_polynslitok_name">
		<text>&quot;Wormwood ingot&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_polynslitok_descr">
		<text>One of the so-called panacea zone. According to rumors, only the Swamp Doctor can assemble this assembly of twenty unique artifacts. As a result, an artifact is obtained that can protect against any abnormal effects and heal any ailments.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_indeikam_name">
		<text>&quot;Indian stone&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_indeikam_descr">
		<text>Light gray stone of round shape the size of a goose egg. A darker color on it as if drawn intricate wavy lines and dotted. In the Zone, &quot;Indian stone&quot; can enhance or, on the contrary, extinguish, partially or completely, the properties of other artifacts. On the Great Earth loses power. Used in assemblies. The sale price is average.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_seaej_name">
		<text>&quot;Sea urchin&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_seaej_descr">
		<text>Rare and expensive artifact, generated by the anomaly &quot;Burning Pooh.&quot; The exterior looks really like a hedgehog. It is covered with a lot of needles. When worn, increases blood pressure and simultaneously it is pricked, causing bleeding. But together with them from the body comes the accumulated radiation. The use is fraught with great difficulties, as bandages are constantly required to stop the blood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_obrychmedusa_name">
		<text>&quot;Jellyfish wrap&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_obrychmedusa_descr">
		<text>A &quot;glass&quot; translucent hoop, glows in the dark with a bright blue light. Strengthens the mental potential of the carrier. Develops psi-abilities, if they are. Maternal anomaly: Phantom focus. Hoop Medusa is forbidden to come into contact with any metals, contact can lead to an explosion of the artifact, paralysis of the owner, etc.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_kriskol_name">
		<text>&quot;Crystal Thorn&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_kriskol_descr">
		<text>The crystal spine is an artifact crystallizing in the anomaly &quot;Burning Pooh&quot;. It releases radiation from the body naturally through the ears along with some blood. Possible loss of blood through other openings. It is infrequent and quite effective, which is why it has a stable price in the artifact market.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_kaplya_name">
		<text>&quot;A drop&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_kaplya_descr">
		<text>Black drop-shaped artifact, covered with cracks. It removes radiation from the body, but weakens it at the same time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_kolokol_name">
		<text>&quot;Bell&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_kolokol_descr">
		<text>Large formation of black color. The form corresponds to the name. The possibilities of the artifact are not fully understood, but it is already clear that it can be used as a shielding helmet. Namely: being put on the head, the &quot;bell&quot; makes the normal stalker look like an idiot. But it protects from the impact of Radar, and this in itself is very, very useful. In addition, the &quot;bell&quot; is likely to be conjugated with the help of the paraneyron adapter with the chromosome ganglions of the Bloodsucker. Which ultimately promises to turn it into a real invisibility cap. Very expensive and very rare. Scientists tear off the shoulders with their hands.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_angrytzvet_name">
		<text>&quot;Flower of Evil&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_angrytzvet_descr">
		<text>Dark glassy formation, really resembling a flower. Allow the wearer to temporarily acquire visual and instrumental invisibility. The effect is short-lived, the artifacts need recharging. Outside the Zone, all properties are lost. Very rare and expensive. They are interested in scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_podsolnuh_name">
		<text>&quot;Sunflower&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_podsolnuh_descr">
		<text>It looks like a translucent biconvex lens with a dark center. Under the beam of light, orange petals appear, emerging from the center to the edges. Well takes away the bullets. However, this is not its main feature. According to the fragmentary data, preserved after the experiments, it is known that the &quot;sunflower&quot; can influence the space-time continuum. Maternal anomaly: Boiler. Additional information: A rare artifact of great value. Very useful for stalkers. With the joy of buying scientists, because it is believed that not all properties of the artifact are disclosed at this time. In combination with the funnel anomaly, it can cause the effect of a &quot;temporary hole&quot;, i. E. Practically move objects in time. The process is not monitored, there are no data on people accidentally caught in the field of action. It is only known that to create a hole anomaly and artifact is not enough, we need some special conditions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_ulitka_name">
		<text>&quot;Snail&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_ulitka_descr">
		<text>Small rounded black formations resembling the shell of a snail. The form defined the name. Snails attached to the temples within a few hours do not allow the death of brain cells, stimulate the nervous system, leveling blood pressure, can relieve the headache and increase the overall tone. They are also capable, to some extent, of resisting mental impulses. The cost of this artifact is average, although it is quite rare.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_skripka_name">
		<text>&quot;Violin&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_skripka_descr">
		<text>A circular flickering formation with zero-gravity. &quot;Violin&quot; has only aesthetic value - the artifact hangs half a meter above any surface and brightly shimmers with all the colors of the rainbow. In addition, from the slightest breeze, a melodious ringing is produced in different keys. Despite the lack of useful properties, the artifact has a decent price. They are mostly interested in collectors and other eccentrics from the Big Land.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_spiral_name">
		<text>&quot;Spiral&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_spiral_descr">
		<text>It looks like a spring made of thick wire, dimly lit by dark cherry light. At the time of formation, it has a high temperature. Used in assemblies, for example with the Wolf Vine for the discharge of anomalies. Explosive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cepsudiby_name">
		<text>&quot;Chain of fate&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_cepsudiby_descr">
		<text>Small, the color of dark malachite, with golden veins oblong stone. It is easily divided into two parts. After separation, it is introduced into the body of carriers, binding them with strong empathic bonds. Wounds, obtained by one of the carriers, appear in the second. In this case, the stones transfer part of the vital energy from the carrier to the carrier. Extraction of the stone leads to death. In the case of the death of one carrier, the second one also dies. An exception is the case when an artifact is extracted from a dying person and acquires a new medium. The selling price is very high.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_semya_name">
		<text>&quot;Seed of the Zone&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_semya_descr">
		<text>A large glowing crystal of green color, a modifier of the Sky fragment. In the presence of a weak radiation background, it emits anomalous energy, creating around itself a local Zone. Allows to exist on the Great Earth mutants and Dark. Very expensive, it is of great interest for scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_polynstar_name">
		<text>&quot;Star-Wormwood&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_polynstar_descr">
		<text>A large, up to 9 kg weight, formation of pure platinum, reminiscent of a sea urchin with a large number of short blunt needles. The star has a clear demutagenic property, i.e. Reverses the changes that have occurred with living organisms under the influence of the anomalous energy of the Zone. It is also capable of forming something like a local stability zone thanks to the radiated energies, which makes it possible to move through the Voronka type anomalies, according to the latest data, which is a system of interconnected gravity vessels. Most likely, these are not all properties of this artifact. Maternal anomaly: Vertical scourge. The cost of this artifact is astronomical. The rarity of a maternal anomaly and an insignificant chance of forming an artifact make it one of the most expensive in the Zone. Especially suffer from the absence of the &quot;Star&quot; scientists, since its properties could help to find answers to many questions of concern to them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_lifekam_name">
		<text>&quot;The Stone of Life&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_lifekam_descr">
		<text>A gelatinous translucent sphere, covered with a damp film, warm, almost hot to the touch. When contracted with the body sticks to it and begins to gradually absorb. Accelerates regeneration, increases the strength and speed of reaction, reduces pain sensitivity. In fact, it makes a person practically invulnerable, since even bullet wounds are almost not felt, and, it seems, do not cause serious harm. However, the process does not stop there. Gradually, the person who applied the stone of life begins to change. Changes affect the mind, emotions turn off, memory wears out. The body also undergoes a certain transformation, becomes more dense, flexible. In the end, the only known pattern disappeared from the camp of scientists, leaving behind three corpses. More about him nothing is known.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_bluekorb_name">
		<text>&quot;Blue Carbuncle&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_bluekorb_descr">
		<text>A blue transparent stone the size of a ping-pong ball. When coming in contact with the body of the carrier neutralizes the pain. Maternal anomaly: Phantom focus. Very rare, dear. An irreplaceable thing for long-distance transitions. Unfortunately, this artifact is found only deep in the Center.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_girya_name">
		<text>&quot;Weight&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_girya_descr">
		<text>A very valuable acquisition for any stalker. Allows you to carry the weight by almost a third more than your own weight. Radioactivity is minimal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mayatnik_name">
		<text>&quot;Pendulum&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_mayatnik_descr">
		<text>Rarely rare. It occurs only in the northern regions of the Zone. The basic properties have not yet been studied.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_venez_name">
		<text>&quot;Crown&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_venez_descr">
		<text>Not a very valuable artifact, despite the fact that it is rare. Of the properties only the ability to partially extinguish psi-radiation was revealed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_pearl_name">
		<text>&quot;Pearl&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_pearl_descr">
		<text>A unique and very rare artifact. To date, only three samples of this artifact have been found. The maternal anomaly has not yet been identified. It is practically a universal catalyst for most chemical reactions. In addition, it significantly reduces the weight of the load.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gubka_name">
		<text>&quot;Sponge&quot;</text>
	</string>
        <string id="st_af_gubka_descr">
		<text>A fairly common emerald viscous substance is generated by an anomalous cold. When wearing this artifact creates a special chemical field that protects from harmful effects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_ognivo_name">
		<text>&quot;Flint&quot;</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_af_ognivo_descr">
		<text>This artifact is generated by the anomaly of frying, has a very specific shape of an elongated slice with golden tint. With special activation, it is possible for a long time to emit directional light radiation, which simulates a light bulb. Radioactive.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="st_cev_plastin_1_name">
		<text>&quot;Assembling artifacts of the 1st type&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cev_plastin_1_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Item Bonus:\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Increase of bullet resistance %c[255,238,15,26](%c[255,1,128,54]+5%c[255,238,15,26])\n%c[default]Specialized transmutation assembly of gravitational artifacts, with which you can increase the protection from radiation. In addition, the assembly gives one more positive effect - this is a special gravitational field that increases bullet resistance. This assembly allows you to reduce bullet-proof by 5%.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cev_plastin_2_name">
		<text>&quot;Assembling artifacts of the second type&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cev_plastin_2_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Item Bonus:\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Increase of bullet resistance %c[255,238,15,26](%c[255,1,128,54]+9%c[255,238,15,26])\n%c[default]Specialized transmutation assembly of thermal artifacts, by means of which it is possible to increase protection against thermal effects. In addition, the assembly gives one more positive effect - this is a special gravitational field that increases bullet resistance. This assembly allows you to reduce bulletproofness by 9%.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cev_plastin_3_name">
		<text>&quot;Assembling artifacts of the third type&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cev_plastin_3_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Item Bonus:\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Increase of bullet resistance %c[255,238,15,26](%c[255,1,128,54]+13%c[255,238,15,26])\n%c[default]Specialized transmutation assembly of chemical artifacts, with which you can increase the protection from chemical attack. In addition, the assembly gives one more positive effect - this is a special gravitational field that increases bullet resistance. This assembly allows you to reduce bullet penetration by 13%.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cev_plastin_4_name">
		<text>&quot;Assembling artifacts of the 4th type&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cev_plastin_4_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Item Bonus:\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Increase of bullet resistance %c[255,238,15,26](%c[255,1,128,54]+17%c[255,238,15,26])\n%c[default]Specialized transmutation assembly of electrostatic static artifacts, with which you can increase protection against electrostatic effects. In addition, the assembly gives one more positive effect - this is a special gravitational field that increases bullet resistance. This assembly allows you to reduce bullet-proofness by 17%.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cev_plastin_5_name">
		<text>&quot;Assembling artifacts of the 5th type&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cev_plastin_5_descr">
		<text>%c[default]Item Bonus:\n%c[255,238,153,26]• %c[default]Increase of bullet resistance %c[255,238,15,26](%c[255,1,128,54]+25%c[255,238,15,26])\n%c[default]Specialized transmutational assembly of psi-static artifacts, with which you can increase the protection against psy-impact. In addition, the assembly gives one more positive effect - this is a special gravitational field that increases bullet resistance. This assembly allows you to reduce bullet-proof by 25%.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_geliy_name">
		<text>&quot;Helium&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_geliy_descr">
		<text>Bright (in the literal sense of the word) representative of the family of electrostatic artifacts. Isolates a gaseous substance that can cause the release of adrenaline into the human blood. Visibly reduces the weight of the backpack. Due to its high efficiency, it is in great demand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_monolit_name">
		<text>Monolith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_monolit_descr">
		<text>The strongest representative of the family of artifacts. As they say in people, it is a fragment of the legendary Monolith. The main property of the artifact is its magnetic field, which is capable of deflecting bullets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_vaselisk_name">
		<text>&quot;Vasilisk&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_vaselisk_descr">
		<text>The only artifact in the zone, which copes with all types of damage to its owner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dragon_eye_name">
		<text>&quot;Dragon Eye&quot;</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dragon_eye_descr">
		<text>Possibly, it has a weak psi effect. However, it does not show any abnormal properties. The sale price is high. It is popular with psychics and predictors outside the Zone as an improved analog of the crystal ball. It is a catalyst for artifacts of other species that change their properties in the presence of the Dragon&apos;s Eye. Used to build assemblies.</text>
	</string>	
</string_table>
