<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<game_dialogs>

			
			
	<dialog id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_dlg">
<has_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_1_dlg</has_info>
<has_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_2_dlg</has_info>
<has_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_3_dlg</has_info>
<has_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_4_dlg</has_info>
<dont_has_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_5_dlg</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>Well, I’m not sure, but it seems I’ve found the spy. I can point him out and bring him in.</text>
        <next>1</next>	
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>Well then, let’s hear it.</text>
        <next>2</next>		
        <next>3</next>	
        <next>4</next>	
        <next>5</next>			
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
        <text>I think it’s the first brother I talked to. He was way too nervous.</text>	
        <next>6</next>			
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="3">
        <text>I feel like it’s the second brother I spoke with. He’s too reserved, hiding something, I’d say.</text>	
        <next>6</next>			
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="4">
        <text>Seems like it’s the third brother I talked to. Way too chatty, and he even came here just for the money… couldn’t come up with a better excuse.</text>	
        <next>7</next>			
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="5">
        <text>Definitely the fourth brother I spoke with. He’s odd, way too proper. Tried too hard to please me, bastard.</text>	
        <next>6</next>			
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="6">
        <text>You’re a shitty detective, brother. You thought I’d just let this slide? Our guys were keeping watch, so the “traitor” has already been dealt with. You didn’t earn a reward and you failed my expectations. Head to Radar, meet with the “Wings” group, they could use some help now.</text>
	<give_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_5_dlg</give_info>	
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_3_dlg_final_message_to_rad</give_info>		
	<action>dialogs_mlr_monolith.give_main_monolith_mlr_task_3_3</action>
	<disable_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2_dlg_new_covers</disable_info>	
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="7">
        <text>Good job, you could say you guessed right. I had a couple of my men keep an eye on you of course—I couldn’t leave such a serious matter solely in your hands. Don’t worry, the infiltrator has already been taken care of. Griffin sent a message, head to Radar, the “Wings” group needs your help. Oh, and take this shotgun—you’ve earned it. It’ll come in handy.</text>	
	<give_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_5_dlg</give_info>
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_3_dlg_final_message_to_rad</give_info>		
	<action>dialogs_mlr_monolith.give_main_monolith_mlr_task_3_3</action>	
	<action>dialogs_mlr_monolith.main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2_present</action>	
	<disable_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2_dlg_new_covers</disable_info>
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>	

<dialog id="newbee_monolith_stalker_1_dlg">
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2_dlg_1</has_info>
<dont_has_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_1_dlg</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>Hey, how do you like it here?</text>
        <next>1</next>	
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>A bit uneasy. But that’s always the case in a new place, brother. I heard the Mentor will be summoning all of us for something?</text>
        <next>2</next>				
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
        <text>I’ve heard that too. What do you think about it?</text>
        <next>3</next>					
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="3">
        <text>I’m afraid I botched my first trial. No joke, going into an anomaly zone? I think he suspects I grabbed the wrong artifact or brought it from the wrong place… God. Leave me be for now, man.</text>
	<give_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_1_dlg</give_info>				
    </phrase>		
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="newbee_monolith_stalker_2_dlg">
<has_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_1_dlg</has_info>
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2_dlg_1</has_info>
<dont_has_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_2_dlg</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>Hey. I heard the Mentor is calling each of us one by one?</text>
        <next>1</next>	
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>Yeah, I heard. So what? Means he needs it that way.</text>
        <next>2</next>				
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
        <text>And how do you like it here?</text>
        <next>3</next>					
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="3">
        <text>I’m not in the mood to talk. I’m preparing for my third trial.</text>
	<give_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_2_dlg</give_info>					
    </phrase>		
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="newbee_monolith_stalker_3_dlg">
<has_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_2_dlg</has_info>
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2_dlg_1</has_info>
<dont_has_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_3_dlg</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>Hello, brother. Everyone’s so quiet. Got a minute to chat?</text>
        <next>1</next>	
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>Why not. How do you like it here?</text>
        <next>2</next>				
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
        <text>Eh, not bad. Most importantly, I’m under the wing of the people who’ll eventually fulfill my dream.</text>
        <next>3</next>					
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="3">
        <text>And what’s your dream?</text>
        <next>4</next>				
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="4">
        <text>If you blab about your dreams to every passerby, then it’s not a dream anymore, it’s a goal. And what are you here for?</text>	
        <next>5</next>		
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="5">
        <text>Well, basically for money. What else would an honest stalker dream of? Anyway… You’re a good guy, but I’d like to take a break from talking. Heard too much already today…</text>	
	<give_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_3_dlg</give_info>			
    </phrase>		
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="newbee_monolith_stalker_4_dlg">
<has_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_3_dlg</has_info>
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2_dlg_1</has_info>
<dont_has_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_4_dlg</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>Hello. How do you like it here, in Monolith?</text>
        <next>1</next>	
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>You know, I’m an experienced wanderer, and I had this sort of “childhood” dream of joining Monolith. And here I am, halfway there already.</text>
        <next>2</next>				
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
        <text>And what do you expect from the Brotherhood?</text>
        <next>3</next>					
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="3">
        <text>I just want to give myself fully to this cause, without second thoughts, you understand? Out there, in the Big Land, no one is waiting for me anymore. Anyway, I still need to sort out the junk from the second trial. Farewell, brother.</text>
	<give_info>newbee_monolith_stalker_4_dlg</give_info>				
    </phrase>		
</phrase_list>
</dialog>


<dialog id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_talk">
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1</has_info>
<dont_has_info>wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_talk</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>Wind, I presume?</text>
        <next>1</next>	
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>Yes.</text>
        <next>2</next>				
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
        <text>Care to tell me about yourself?</text>
        <next>3</next>					
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="3">
        <text>No.</text>
        <next>4</next>					
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="4">
        <text>Why not?</text>
        <next>5</next>			
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="5">
        <text>[...]</text>			
	<give_info>wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_talk</give_info>			
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>


<dialog id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_talk">
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1</has_info>
<dont_has_info>wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_talk</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>You’re Pegasus, right?</text>
        <next>1</next>	
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>Hey, man. Wanted to get acquainted?</text>
        <next>2</next>				
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
        <text>Well, you could say that, yeah. How did you end up here?</text>
        <next>3</next>					
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="3">
        <text>Just crossed the army cordon and here I am. You probably want to know why, right? Oh, but I doubt I can really answer that—you wouldn’t understand me. It’s very personal, and it’s enough that “C-Consciousness” can lead me to my dream. I ended up in “Wings” as one of the best marksmen, though honestly, I don’t really like sniper rifles.</text>
        <next>4</next>					
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="4">
        <text>Who are “C-Consciousness”?</text>
        <next>5</next>			
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="5">
        <text>I don’t believe you’ve never heard of them—or are you asking my opinion? Anyway, it’s simple: they’re not some mythical beings, but a real group of scientists who somehow gained access to the noosphere. I once got into a military lab up north in the Zone, and you know, their tech impressed me. All those holograms, monstrous equipment… hard to believe today’s Ukrainian government nurtured all that on the remnants of Soviet tech right under their noses. And you know what? I’d rather be with those who inspire my trust than with those lunatic Duty fanatics.</text>			
	<give_info>wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_talk</give_info>			
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_talk">
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1</has_info>
<dont_has_info>wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_talk</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>Hello, Sparrow.</text>
        <next>1</next>	
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>Hello.</text>
        <next>2</next>				
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
        <text>How’s your mood?</text>
        <next>3</next>					
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="3">
        <text>Alright, though it’s a bit overwhelming. Never thought I’d end up in Monolith voluntarily.</text>
        <next>4</next>					
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="4">
        <text>And how long have you been here, where are you from?</text>
        <next>5</next>			
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="5">
        <text>I’m a veteran, been roaming the Zone for a long time. Lately I was hanging around the Bar, drinking non-stop, when all that mess started here at Radar. Then I got curious about what happened, and chaos broke out everywhere! Soldiers were swarming around, Monolith guys were completely disoriented… I stumbled upon some experienced Monolith fighters, we almost shot each other by mistake. I helped them out a little after the shock, then we decided to head to their base, and well, I guess I kind of settled in here.</text>	
        <next>6</next>			
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="6">
        <text>Why did you decide to stay?</text>
        <next>7</next>			
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="7">
        <text>I can’t live without the Zone. I thought about quitting, but whenever I remembered what life was like in the Big Land… unemployment, no prospects, no freedom. Yeah, yeah, even here there’s more of that than out there. Anyway, we’ll have time to whine later at the base—if I survive, that is.</text>
        <next>8</next>			
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="8">
        <text>Thanks for the chat.</text>
	<give_info>wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_talk</give_info>			
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>


<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_1">
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_3</has_info>
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_1</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>Greetings, Mentor. What’s this “trivial” task?</text>
        <next>1</next>	
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>You need to capture a stalker base on the outskirts. The brothers believe they’ll interfere with our plans, and in the long run they could pose a threat to the Brotherhood.</text>
        <next>2</next>		
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
        <text>Am I going there alone?</text>
        <next>3</next>	
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="3">
        <text>No, not alone. You’ll meet another one of our groups, they serve as assault troops. I give newcomers some time first with one group, then with another, so it’s easier for them to find their place in the Brotherhood. Too bad the third group is already dead. Anyway, off you go to your mission.</text>	
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_1</give_info>		
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>


<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_2">
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_1</has_info>
<has_info>stalker_defenders_pri_a16_mlr_mon_task_5_nil</has_info>
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_2</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>Greetings, are you the Inquisitor? Mentor told me I’m now under your command.</text>
        <next>1</next>	
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>You’ve been a great help to us, finally he’s recruiting some solid guys. Here, take a good gun and get some rest. You can head over to our base at the KBO. We’ll clean things up here, and I’ll call for you.</text>
        <next>2</next>		
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
        <text>Alright.</text>	
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_2</give_info>			
        <action>monolith_event.monolith_event_start</action>	
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>


<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_1">
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_2</has_info>
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_1</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>I don’t feel too comfortable asking, but Mentor mentioned some third squad that was wiped out. Who did he mean?</text>
        <next>1</next>	
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>The “Crystal” group. Once, it was our most powerful force, focused on protecting “C-Consciousness,” the Monolith itself, the Sarcophagus, and the surrounding territory.</text>
        <next>2</next>		
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
        <text>But what happened?</text>		
        <next>3</next>			
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="3">
        <text>Then, as you know, some bastard—or a group of bastards—broke through our protective barrier called the “Brain Scorcher,” and in poured the army, all sorts of “adventure seekers,” even those scum. I don’t have much information, since at that time Preacher and I were busy with some crap… sorry, too many blanks in my past life. Anyway, I digress: the whole group was wiped out, they held on to the last man. Whether they managed to stop the threat or not, you’ll have to see for yourself. By the way, you can search around the Sarcophagus, maybe find some information, or perhaps weapons. Just don’t forget to bring something to deal with the radiation.</text>		
        <next>4</next>	
        <next>5</next>			
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="4">
        <text>I’ll probably go. I’m curious about the fate of that group.</text>	
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_1</give_info>
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_1_begin</give_info>	
	<action>dialogs_mlr_monolith.give_main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1</action>
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="5">
        <text>No, that’s too dangerous.</text>		
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_1</give_info>			
    </phrase>
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_2">
<precondition>dialogs_mlr_monolith.has_sar_crystal_pda_mlr</precondition>	
<precondition>dialogs_mlr_monolith.has_sar_crystal_pda_mlr_1</precondition>	
<precondition>dialogs_mlr_monolith.has_sar_crystal_pda_mlr_2</precondition>	
<precondition>dialogs_mlr_monolith.has_sar_crystal_pda_mlr_3</precondition>	
<precondition>dialogs_mlr_monolith.has_sar_crystal_pda_mlr_4</precondition>	
<precondition>dialogs_mlr_monolith.has_sar_crystal_pda_mlr_5</precondition>	
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_dlg_2</has_info>
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_2</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>Here, take it. Most of the information is either lost, or I don’t know how to read it.</text>
	    <action>dialogs_mlr_monolith.give_sar_crystal_pdas_mlr</action>					
        <next>1</next>
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>I’ll pass it to the Mentor, he’ll deal with it later. Shame about the guys.</text>						
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_2</give_info>		
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_about_leader">
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_1</has_info>
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_about_leader</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>Why did you decide to stay in the brotherhood? From what I understood, you were “zombified” at first.</text>
        <next>1</next>
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>I woke up somewhere near Pripyat with people I didn’t know, and just like them, I remembered nothing. The only thing we had in common was the uniform, and we didn’t let each other down. My previous life was left behind, brother — that’s just how it turned out, and nothing can be fixed here. And I also found my gun with twenty-two notches on it. I don’t think anyone else would take me in.</text>						
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_dlg_about_leader</give_info>		
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_4">
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_3</has_info>
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_4</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>Hello, brother. I was supposed to receive something from the “Wings”.</text>
        <next>1</next>
        <next>2</next>		
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
	<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_3_actor_not_wings</has_info>	
        <text>Yeah, here’s your Abakan.</text>	
	<action>dialogs_mlr_monolith.give_abakan_from_wings</action>			
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_4</give_info>		
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
	<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_3_actor_now_wings</has_info>
        <text>So, you’ve earned the respect of the “Wings”? Well done, you’ll go far. Take our squad’s signature suit.</text>	
	<action>dialogs_mlr_monolith.give_suit_from_wings</action>			
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_4</give_info>		
    </phrase>		
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_3">
<has_info>heart_of_station_bloodsucker_wave_1_nil</has_info>
<has_info>heart_of_station_bloodsucker_wave_2_nil</has_info>
<has_info>heart_of_station_bloodsucker_wave_3_nil</has_info>
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1_over</has_info>
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_3</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>You’ve got quite a sour look, is it really beyond repair?</text>
        <next>1</next>
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>Not at the moment. Someone seems to have dismantled the control panel, and that’s only half the trouble. The cooling system is broken too, I’ll have to check it, but I doubt I can handle it alone. But that’s not your problem, right? Tell me, have you been assigned to any squad yet?</text>	
        <next>2</next>				
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
        <text>Not really, the Mentor just told me to come to you in his message, and that’s it.</text>
        <next>3</next>
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="3">
        <text>I think you’ve got some potential. On behalf of our group, I want to thank you and give you our signature suit, you’ve earned it.</text>
        <next>4</next>	
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="4">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_3</give_info>		
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_3_actor_now_wings</give_info>			
        <next>5</next>			
    </phrase>		
    <phrase id="5">
        <text>Great, I’ll inform the base. Go see the quartermaster in Pripyat, he’ll give you our uniform — I think you’ll be pleasantly surprised. By the way, fighter, I hope to see you in our ranks in the future.</text>			
    </phrase>		
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_2">
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1_in_heart_of_station</has_info>
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_2</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>What do you need me to do?</text>
        <next>1</next>
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>Defend this place with the guys while I try to assess the situation. I’m sure the local creatures will bother us more than once.</text>	
	<action>dialogs_axr_companion.remove_companions_from_squad</action>	
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_2</give_info>		
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1">
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>So, you must be our new companion. Well, ready to take a walk and witness the former greatness of this place?</text>
        <next>1</next>
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>Hey, you’re the “Wings”? Tell me about you and the situation—what are we even doing here?</text>		
			<next>2</next>				
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
        <text>“Wings,” or rather, what’s left of them. They call me Griffin, those guys over there are Sparrow and Pegasus, and the skinny man with the SVD is Wind. Listen: once there were many of us here, and this place struck fear into the hearts of the faithless. Until one stalker sabotaged the local brainwashing station, so to speak. What followed… you had to see it. Duty, Freedom, loners, and the military—our best detachments took the brunt of the assault, and in the end: all dead. But in truth, no one managed to claim this place. I don’t know what exactly happened, but now it’s swarming only with monsters and zombified ones.</text>	
			<next>3</next>					
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="3">
        <text>[...]</text>		
			<next>4</next>				
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="4">
        <text>Now we need to head to the bunker beneath the so-called “Brain Scorcher” and assess the situation, to answer one of the key questions our Brotherhood faces: “Is it possible to restart the installation?” Are you ready?</text>	
			<next>5</next>	
			<next>6</next>				
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="5">
        <text>I’m ready, let’s go.</text>		
    <action>dialogs_axr_companion.become_actor_companion</action>			
	<action>dialogs_mlr_monolith.give_main_monolith_mlr_task_4</action>	
	
	<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_4_dlg_1</give_info>				
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="6">
        <text>Not yet, I’ll look around here a bit more.</text>						
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_dlg_1">
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_3_dlg_1_start</has_info>
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_3_dlg_1</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>I came about the task.</text>
        <next>1</next>	
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>Those “Cossacks” were snooping around, watching our patrols at the Radar and Pripyat outskirts. I want you to decide how we should deal with this—that will be a test of your thinking skills.</text>			
        <next>3</next>	
        <next>4</next>			
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="3">
	<dont_has_info>border_freedom_keeper_max_squad_dead</dont_has_info>	
        <text>I think we should hit their nearest stronghold—the Barrier. We need to beat the urge to spy out of them.</text>
        <next>5</next>	
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="4">
        <text>We should find the rest of the recon group. I doubt they were working in pairs.</text>
        <next>6</next>	
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="5">
        <text>Yeah, in that case you can go on the assault. Here’s a dozen grenades, let’s see how you handle it—since it was your idea. The Brotherhood has no other soldiers to spare.</text>	
		<action>dialogs_mlr_monolith.give_main_monolith_mlr_task_3_1</action>
		<action>dialogs_mlr_monolith.main_monolith_mlr_task_3_give_present</action>		
		<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_3_dlg_1</give_info>	
		<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_3_1_dlg_1</give_info>			
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="6">
        <text>And you’re damn right. But here’s the problem: judging by their PDA logs, one of our recruits—the ones you stood guard with earlier—was supposed to steal a handful of Monolith suits from the warehouse and hand them over to the saboteurs. We’ll take care of the remaining recon fools ourselves, but you must find this spy. I’ve summoned the recruits, they should be here. They also know I plan to have a serious talk with each of them. Casually find out what they think I want from them.</text>
		<action>dialogs_mlr_monolith.give_main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2</action>		
		<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_3_dlg_1</give_info>	
		<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_3_2_dlg_1</give_info>					
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_1">
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_2</has_info>
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_1</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>What is my next trial?</text>
        <next>1</next>
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>Follow me.</text>		
		<action>dialogs_mlr_monolith.give_main_monolith_mlr_task_2</action>			
		<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_1</give_info>
		<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_to_prisoners</give_info>		
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_2">
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_talk_to_teacher</has_info>
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_2</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>See those beauties? Take them and kill them. That will prove your loyalty to our cause. Come on, brother, without a shadow of doubt.</text>
        <next>1</next>
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>Alright.</text>				
		<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_2</give_info>	
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_3">
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_2</has_info>
<has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_prisoners_dead</has_info>
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_3</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>Well done! As you may have noticed, those were guys from "Freedom", apparently scouts. Our people are determining why they were here — come to me later and we’ll decide what to do next.</text>
        <next>1</next>		
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>Alright.</text>
		<disable_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_to_prisoners</disable_info>			
		<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_2_dlg_3</give_info>	
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_1">
<has_info>talk_to_teacher_monolith_mlr</has_info>
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_1</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>Well then, I welcome you, brother. Why are you here?</text>
        <next>1</next>		
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>I’ve come here for my deepest desire.</text>	
		<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_wish</give_info>			
        <next>2</next>		
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="2">
        <text>That’s exactly what keeps people like us in the Brotherhood. In general, Monolith is not what it used to be. Roughly speaking, the Brotherhood is kept alive by a handful of enthusiasts. Many left the ranks after the Brain Scorcher was shut down. Some stayed simply because they would die outside the Brotherhood, though that doesn’t mean they won’t leave sooner or later. And some, like us, stayed because we want to build our own personal paradise — and the "C-Consciousness" technologies make that possible...</text>
        <next>3</next>		
    </phrase>		
    <phrase id="3">
        <text>You mentioned some trials?</text>	
        <next>4</next>		
    </phrase>	
    <phrase id="4">
        <text>All in good time, newly-made brother. Remember, your former life is coming to an end. Over time the Brotherhood has become fewer in number but far more hardened. What you will have to endure here — especially during the trials — will seem like true horror to any objectively normal person. To start, I want to see your will: I want you to kill the pseudo-giant that has taken up residence nearby. How you do it — with bare hands, with the help of brothers, or using found weapons — I do not care. This will show you what you’re capable of to reach your goal and what means you are likely to resort to.</text>
        <next>5</next>			
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="5">
        <text>Uh, fine.</text>	
		<action>xr_effects.staff_out_from_actor_by_monolith_main_task_1</action>		
		<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_1</give_info>		
		<give_info>close_blue_box_mlr_mon</give_info>				
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

<dialog id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_2">
<has_info>monolith_main_task_pseudogiant_die</has_info>
<dont_has_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_2</dont_has_info>
<phrase_list>
    <phrase id="0">
        <text>The creature is dead. But why do we kill them — couldn’t they become our allies in the fight against... the faithless?</text>
        <next>1</next>
    </phrase>
    <phrase id="1">
        <text>The C-Consciousness forces don’t have enough power even to keep a handful of people in check, and you’re talking about mutants. When you’re ready for the next trial, come back.</text>		
		<give_info>main_monolith_mlr_task_1_dlg_2</give_info>
		<disable_info>close_blue_box_mlr_mon</disable_info>		
    </phrase>	
</phrase_list>
</dialog>

	
	

	
</game_dialogs>
