<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>

<string_table>
<string id="st_grenade_rgo">
    <text>RGO Grenade</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_rgo_short">
    <text>RGO</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_rgo_descr">
    <text>Defensive hand grenade. The RGN and RGO grenades are equipped with an impact-time fuse (UDZ) — their standard detonator.\n
    A heavy defensive fragmentation grenade with high lethality and a large effective radius. Used in open combat or from cover — throwing it at your feet is not recommended. Thanks to its steel body, it creates a dense cloud of deadly fragments, effectively covering enemy positions.\n
    The UDZ fuse operates in two possible scenarios:\n
    Contact (impact) detonation — the grenade explodes about 1.3 seconds after hitting a surface (e.g., ground or object).\n
    Time (distance) detonation — if the grenade does not hit a surface, it explodes about 3.2–4.2 seconds after being thrown.\n
    Advantages of the UDZ fuse:\n
    Increases the chance of air detonation (useful against targets in cover).\n
    Eliminates "ricocheting" grenades common with traditional delay fuses.\n
    More predictable in combat conditions compared to classic UZRGM fuses.\n
    Stalkers appreciate UDZ grenades because you can "place" the grenade almost directly under a mutant — or detonate it in the air above the enemy. Especially useful against fast-moving targets or in confined spaces.\n
    In the Zone, it is valued as a "guaranteed farewell" to a group of mutants or bandits if thrown accurately. However, it requires caution and proper positioning: after throwing, it's best to take cover.\n
    The military's main complaint about existing grenades concerned the timed fuse. Therefore, a new design was created to meet requirements. The result of research, testing, and technical proposals was the UDZ fuse ("Impact-time fuse"). As the name implies, it can detonate the grenade either several seconds after throwing or upon impact with a surface.\n\n
    %c[ui_gray_2]SPECIFICATIONS: \n
    %c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Weight: ~530 g.\n\n
    %c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Detonation time: 3.2–4.2 sec.\n\n
    %c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Effective radius: up to 20–25 meters.\n\n
    %c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Body: Steel, ribbed.\n\n
    %c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] Mechanism: Impact with delay.\n\n
    </text>
</string>

</string_table>

