<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>

	
<!-- Spectrum -->	
<string id="spectrum_guard_outfit_name">
    <text>Spectrum Suit</text>
</string>
<string id="spectrum_guard_outfit_description">
    <text>%c[ui_gray_1]The "Spectrum" suit is supplied and manufactured by unknown parties. It is the standard equipment for fighters of the Spectrum group. The suit is designed in a blue-orange color scheme. Compared to the "Zarya" Suit, it provides decent protection against anomalous effects, but its protection against bullets and explosions is its weak point.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="spectrum_scientific_outfit_name">
    <text>Scientific Suit "Seginus"</text>
</string>
<string id="spectrum_scientific_outfit_description">
    <text>%c[ui_gray_1]The "Seginus" scientific suit is an upgraded version of the "SEVA" suit. It comes in a blue-orange color scheme. It is an excellent choice for Zone exploration. This version boasts improved protection against explosions and bullets, though its protection against anomalous effects is worse than that of the "SEVA" suit.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="spectrum_proto_exo_outfit_name">
    <text>Prototype Exoskeleton "Betelgeuse"</text>
</string>
<string id="spectrum_proto_exo_outfit_description">
    <text>%c[ui_gray_1]The "Betelgeuse" prototype exoskeleton, produced by unknown parties, never entered mass production due to numerous creation errors. However, this prototype turned out to offer excellent protection against bullets and explosions. It has a blue-orange color scheme. Despite its flaws, it is a good choice for a fighter.\n \n</text>
</string>

<string id="spectrum_exo_outfit_name">
    <text>Exoskeleton "Arkabe"</text>
</string>
<string id="spectrum_exo_outfit_description">
    <text>%c[ui_gray_1]The "Arkabe" exoskeleton is made from high-quality materials, supplied and manufactured by unknown parties. It comes in a blue-orange color scheme. It is an improved version of the "Betelgeuse" prototype exoskeleton. Despite the inherent flaws common to other exoskeletons, this suit still provides unmatched protection.\n \n</text>
</string>


</string_table>
