<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>

<!--
	Devices
-->

<string_table>

<string id="st_memory_stick_name">
    <text>Flash Drive (Memory Card)</text>
</string>
<string id="st_memory_stick_name_descr">
    <text>
A common way to store and transport large volumes of data in compact form, though accessing the data requires a computer.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] low energy consumption
    </text>
</string>
	
<string id="st_pda_name">
    <text>PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_pda_descr">
    <text>
A standard stalker PDA, carried by every Zone-walker. Contains digital logs, detailed maps of the area, and anomaly locations. If you find the “right” trader, selling discovered PDAs can bring in a decent profit.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] low energy consumption
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_pda_1_name">
    <text>PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_pda_1_descr">
    <text>
A slightly outdated PDA with basic functionality, still used by many stalkers. An essential tool for daily news exchange. Includes a built-in GPS module for time tracking, user positioning, and geo-data delivery.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] low energy consumption\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_pda_2_name">
    <text>PDA (Model 2.0)</text>
</string>
<string id="st_pda_2_descr">
    <text>
One of the latest PDA models with extended functionality. Contains digital logs, detailed zone maps, and anomaly locations. A crucial tool for daily communication. Includes a built-in GPS module for time and location tracking. This model can detect and relay the coordinates of other PDAs within a 300-meter radius. A highly desired model among stalkers.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] low energy consumption\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] displays player faction squad locations\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_pda_3_name">
    <text>PDA (Model 3.1)</text>
</string>
<string id="st_pda_3_descr">
    <text>
Arguably the most advanced PDA model currently available. Features a refined algorithm that detects and relays data from other PDAs within a 300-meter radius. Unlike standard GPS modules, this one relies on key sets to directly access network-connected devices for data retrieval. These capabilities make it highly coveted among stalkers.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] low energy consumption\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] displays neutral squad locations\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_detector1">
    <text>“Echo” Detector</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector1_descr">
    <text>
An outdated model of anomaly detector. Emits an audio signal when anomalous particles enter a special chamber, indicating proximity to anomalies. Can also register the presence of artifacts and measure the distance to the nearest one — indicated by the frequency of the sound signal. Artifact search mode activates by raising the front antenna panel. Due to its simple design, it can only detect the most common artifacts.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medium energy consumption\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_detector2">
    <text>“Bear” Detector</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector2_descr">
    <text>
Previous-generation anomaly detector. Equipped with an anomaly locator and LED panel to display artifact direction. Capable of detecting artifacts and estimating distance. Artifact search mode activates by raising the antenna panel on the front. Unfortunately, its list of detectable artifacts is permanently hardcoded and already somewhat outdated.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medium energy consumption\n
    </text>
</string>

	
<string id="st_detector3">
    <text>“Veles” Detector</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector3_descr">
    <text>
A next-generation scanning detector used by scientists. Thanks to three advanced registration chambers, artifact positioning relative to the detector is displayed on a special screen. Capable of registering both radiation and the presence of anomalies. Artifact search mode is activated by raising the indicator panel on the front; in this mode, the detector can locate all artifacts currently known to science.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high energy consumption\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_detector4">
    <text>Prototype “Svarog” Detector</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector4_descr">
    <text>
Prototype of an anomaly zone scanner with extended functionality. Includes a program capable of recognizing static anomaly fields based on internal database entries, while maintaining artifact detection functionality. Both anomaly zones and artifacts are displayed relative to the detector on a specialized screen. The artifact search program, activated by raising the front-facing indicator panel, has been upgraded—potentially enabling the discovery of anomalous phenomena unknown to science.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high energy consumption\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_detector9">
    <text>RF Receiver</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector9_descr">
    <text>
A small device equipped with a highly sensitive radio-frequency module used for basic communication. Fairly common among military personnel, despite being based on outdated technology. Capable of interacting with signals within a 200-meter radius and processing radio waves in the 30–300 MHz frequency range.\n\n
%c[0,56,166,209]User Manual%c[ui_gray_1]:\n
To begin using the device, it must be held in your hand.\n
Frequency switching is done as follows (with a free right hand):\n
• LMB increases the frequency.\n
• RMB decreases the frequency.\n
• Holding L-Shift changes the frequency in 10 Hz steps.\n
• Holding L-Alt changes the frequency in 50 Hz steps.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medium energy consumption\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_detector8">
    <text>Anomalous Activity Measurement Device</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector8_descr">
    <text>
The first prototype was developed in 2008 within the mobile scientific lab at Yantar under Professor Sakharov's supervision. After successful field trials, several more copies were produced. The device can process and log measurements and data of anomalous fields. Enhanced sensors and durable construction ensure functionality even under the harshest conditions: its high sensitivity during scans or tracking makes it usable in a wide range of environmental scenarios.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medium energy consumption\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_broken_pda">
    <text>Broken PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_broken_pda_descr">
    <text>
This PDA appears heavily damaged — the screen is half-shattered, and the GPS module is malfunctioning. The internal components, however, remain mostly intact.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_device_torch_name">
    <text>Headlamp</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_torch_descr">
    <text>
A regular headlamp that helps prevent you from getting lost in the dark. For less cautious stalkers, it might also attract unwanted attention—from both hostile individuals and mutants.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medium energy consumption\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_device_torch_nv_1_name">
    <text>Headlamp with 1PN93-1</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_torch_nv_1_descr">
    <text>
A standard headlamp bundled with the 1PN93-1 night vision device. Delivers Gen 2+ image clarity, particularly useful for nighttime operations and low-light environments.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] night vision device: %c[ui_gray_1]1PN93-1\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medium energy consumption\n
    </text>
</string>

	
<string id="st_device_torch_nv_2_name">
    <text>Headlamp with PN21KL</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_torch_nv_2_descr">
    <text>
A head-mounted flashlight useful for stalkers caught on the road at night—though it might also draw some unwanted attention. Features Gen 2+ image intensification from IIT and is intended for nighttime operations in both natural low-light and total darkness with the IR illuminator enabled.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] night vision device: %c[ui_gray_1]PN21KL\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medium energy consumption\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_device_torch_nv_3_name">
    <text>Headlamp with NVG “Oracle”</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_torch_nv_3_descr">
    <text>
This headlamp comes with an enhanced NVG featuring upgraded drive unit, lenses, and software that eliminates visual noise and significantly improves the PN21K’s performance. Essentially, it functions as a full-fledged Gen 3 IIT night vision device.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] night vision device: %c[ui_gray_1]“Oracle”\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medium energy consumption\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_device_flashlight">
    <text>Handheld Flashlight</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_flashlight_descr">
    <text>
A regular handheld flashlight, clearly used judging by its worn casing. An essential survival tool when wandering through the Zone. Unfortunately, it can’t be used with most weapons since only one hand remains free.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medium energy consumption\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_batteries_dead">
    <text>Old Batteries</text>
</string>
<string id="st_batteries_dead_descr">
    <text>
Only one in ten batteries found in the Zone still holds a usable charge. Most stalkers probably tossed them after use, since compatible chargers are rare. Their corroded and grimy exteriors are a clear sign these batteries are "dead." Still, like many things in the Zone, they can serve a purpose—such as squeezing out a bit more juice for frequent recharging of handheld devices.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_batteries">
    <text>Battery Pack</text>
</string>
<string id="st_batteries_descr">
    <text>
These batteries have already seen some use, with about half their original charge remaining. Designed for use in flashlights, PDAs, night vision devices, and other electronics. Don’t forget to replace them regularly.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
    </text>
</string>

	
	<string id="st_batteries_ccell">
	<text>Military Battery Pack</text>
</string>
<string id="st_batteries_ccell_descr">
	<text>
A set of fully charged batteries used in military units. Highly valuable and in great demand due to the constant battery shortage in the Zone. Used by all factions and stalkers of all ranks, from rookies to veterans. Often distributed by corrupt army officers trying to earn extra income in the Zone.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_geiger_dead">
	<text>Geiger Counter</text>
</string>
<string id="st_geiger_dead_descr">
	<text>
A dosimeter that measures ionizing (radioactive) radiation. Capable of detecting alpha, beta, and gamma radiation.\n
First invented in 1908, the Geiger counter remains a popular and essential tool, commonly used in healthcare, physics, industry, geology, and more. These devices are built from relatively simple electronic circuits.\n\n
%c[0,56,166,209]FEATURES%c[ui_gray_1]:\n
• Displays real-time background radiation and accumulated exposure while held – switch modes using “SHIFT+8”.\n
• Displays readings when pressing hotkey “8” (by default), even while stored in inventory.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] measures radiation levels\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medium energy consumption\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_electric power">
	<text>Universal Charging Unit (UCU)</text>
</string>
<string id="st_electric power_descr">
	<text>
A small, portable power unit from the Cold War era, comparable in size to a compact radio. Compatible with almost any type of battery or accumulator. Extracts every last drop of energy and transfers it via included thin wires to electronic devices. Can power nearly any equipment, regardless of complexity or age. A must-have tool for keeping stalker tech functional in the Zone.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] portable power source\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] supports most modern devices\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] supports all battery types\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] capacity: %c[ui_gray_1]3 Ah (ampere-hours)\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="extension_pda">
	<text>PDA with Player and Chat</text>
</string>
<string id="exten_sion_pda">
	<text>
An expensive, water- and shock-resistant PDA with an integrated music player and access to the stalker communication network.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] allows music playback and use of the stalker network\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_gps_tracker">
	<text>Military GPS Module</text>
</string>
<string id="st_gps_tracker_descr">
	<text>
A prototype of next-generation GPS navigation devices. Only a few units exist, originally distributed among high-ranking military officers—though a few have already found their way into other hands.\n
Guaranteed to function in even the most hostile environments. Unlike standard GPS modules, this prototype uses access keys to communicate directly with connected devices on the network and can transmit coordinates of other GPS modules within a 300-meter radius. However, its energy consumption is extremely high. Automatically powers down after 20 seconds of continuous scanning.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] very high energy consumption\n
	</text>
</string>


	<string id="st_musicplayer">
	<text>Radio</text>
</string>
<string id="st_musicplayer_desc">
	<text>
A modified radio designed to search for other stations and filter out as much interference as possible.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_2]SPECIFICATIONS:\n\n
%c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_weather_radar">
	<text>Doppler Weather Radar Kit</text>
</string>
<string id="st_weather_radar_descr">
	<text>
An advanced meteorological equipment set, including a Doppler weather radar. This setup is considered a true marvel in meteorology: using a magnetron connected to a parabolic antenna via a waveguide, the radar emits focused microwave pulses lasting about a microsecond to gather meteorological data.\n
Two scientific researchers discovered that placing a "Meat Chunk" artifact near the antenna greatly amplifies the pulse strength, allowing the signal to reach the upper atmosphere, where it can alter ions—and with them, the properties of the atmosphere itself.\n\n
%c[ui_gray_3]SPECIFICATIONS:\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological device\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] meteorological equipment\n
%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] powered by a Meat Chunk artifact\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_dosimeter_mode">
	<text>Dosimeter Mode</text>
</string>

<string id="st_actor_rads">
	<text>Accumulated Dose</text>
</string>

<string id="st_environment_rads">
	<text>Ambient Radiation</text>
</string>

<string id="st_device_lighter">
	<text>Zippo Lighter</text>
</string>
<string id="st_device_lighter_descr">
	<text>
A standard Zippo lighter. It doesn’t stand out among other lighters of the same brand, but an engraving on the back reads: “Good hunting, stalker,” signed “from the developers of H.A.Z.E.”
	</text>
</string>

</string_table>