<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>

<string_table>
	<string id="st_nj_nokia">
    <text>Nokia 3310</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_nokia_descr">
    <text>A very well-known phone used by the elderly, children, and everyone in between since the early 2000s. Still popular among criminals today due to its affordability and wide availability. The screen is somehow damaged and frozen.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological item\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] everyday item\n
        %c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value, can be sold.\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_siemens">
    <text>Siemens A-35</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_siemens_descr">
    <text>A very simple mobile phone with very limited functionality. Its only advantage is the extremely low price. Not the most popular choice when better options are available. The screen doesn't turn on. The word "Pharaoh" is etched into the back cover.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological item\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] everyday item\n
        %c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value, can be sold.\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_samsung">
    <text>Samsung SGH-X495</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_samsung_descr">
    <text>The Samsung SGH-X495 is a fairly basic mobile phone that was popular in the early 2000s and is still in demand today due to the large number of features it has for a basic phone. The screen doesn't turn on.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological item\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] everyday item\n
        %c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value, can be sold.\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_motorola">
    <text>Motorola Razr V3</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_motorola_descr">
    <text>Although the Motorola Razr V3 was released in 2004, it is still a very functional flip phone. Nowadays, it's very popular among drug dealers. The screen doesn't turn on.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological item\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] everyday item\n
        %c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value, can be sold.\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_mp3player">
    <text>MP3 Player</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_mp3player_descr">
    <text>This is an old music player that was once a very popular device for listening to music—until smartphones took over. Some people still prefer these over PDAs for music. It probably has a dead battery, as it doesn’t power on.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological item\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] everyday item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_calculator">
    <text>Scientific Calculator</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_calculator_descr">
    <text>A very common scientific calculator. It works on both batteries and solar power. It works perfectly fine, but unless you're a scientist or a trader, it won’t be of much use to you.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological item\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] everyday item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_earbuds">
    <text>Earbuds</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_earbuds_descr">
    <text>Standard Chinese-made earbuds. The sound quality isn’t great, but they’ll let you listen to music just fine. Using someone else’s earbuds is unhygienic.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological item\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] everyday item\n
        %c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] low quality\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_screwdriver">
    <text>Broken Transmitter</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_screwdriver_descr">
    <text>Transmits a signal within a 150-meter radius to nearby mobile receivers. Allows two transmitters to work on the same channel. Includes a detailed configuration menu. Comes with a plastic clothing clip and a neck lanyard.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] tool\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] everyday item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_hammer">
    <text>Broken Shoulder Flashlight</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_hammer_descr">
    <text>Military-style angle mini-flashlight. Comes with four interchangeable lenses—red, green, yellow, and blue. Uses a bright krypton bulb. The case is waterproof and made of impact-resistant ABS plastic.\n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] tool\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] everyday item\n
    </text>
</string>

	
	<string id="st_nj_sandpaper">
    <text>Icon in a Gold Frame</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_sandpaper_descr">
    <text>An old icon in a golden frame, which seemingly may hold some historical value.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] rare\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_pliers">
    <text>Broken Tactical Module</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_pliers_descr">
    <text>A tactical module is a device that combines one or more laser and light functions. For example: visible and infrared laser sights with infrared and visible flashlights, in various combinations and with adjustable brightness and modes. Tactical modules are mainly used on assault weapons for indoor illumination, target lighting, and aiming assistance.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] everyday item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_silverring">
    <text>Silver Ring</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_silverring_descr">
    <text>A silver ring. It may be worn as a symbol of marriage or simply as decoration. It's quite valuable.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_goldring">
    <text>Gold Rings</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_goldring_descr">
    <text>Gold rings. They may be worn as a symbol of marriage or simply as decoration. They're quite valuable.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_sunglasses">
    <text>Shoe Care Travel Kit</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_sunglasses_descr">
    <text>A travel shoe care kit — an ideal choice for athletes, active travelers, soldiers, or anyone who values comfort regardless of the situation.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_glasses">
    <text>Sunglasses</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_glasses_descr">
    <text>Aviator-style sunglasses — due to their shape and simplicity, they’ve become popular with local hitmen and anyone who wants to look cool. Traders buy them quite well.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_wallet">
    <text>Brick</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_wallet_descr">
    <text>An artifact that lost all its properties due to an energy collapse is called a Brick. Despite this, these artifacts are still valuable to scientists, as they emit light and antigravity energy. Scientists pay good money for them.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable item\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] unusual item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_keys">
    <text>Keyring</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_keys_descr">
    <text>A bundle of random keys with no clear purpose. As a result, not very useful.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_belt">
    <text>Memory Card</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_belt_descr">
    <text>A memory card compatible with many devices. The A1 performance class ensures faster app loading. This storage device provides high performance for shooting photos and Full HD videos.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

	
	<string id="st_nj_socks">
    <text>Diary with Notes</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_socks_descr">
    <text>A personal diary belonging to one of the residents, filled with fairly recent entries. It might contain some useful information.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_gloves">
    <text>Bank Card</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_gloves_descr">
    <text>A regular plastic card from a bank on the mainland. In the Zone, it loses most of its value due to its uselessness in local circumstances, though it might still hold some funds.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_pencil1">
    <text>Pencil</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_pencil1_descr">
    <text>A black pencil with a rubber eraser on the opposite end. Still in good condition.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_penink">
    <text>Ink Pen</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_penink_descr">
    <text>A high-quality ink pen that requires a cartridge to operate. Considered a mark of elegance in this region. More valuable than regular pens. Commonly used by stalkers for note-taking.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_newspaper1">
    <text>Newspaper</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_newspaper1_descr">
    <text>A folded Ukrainian newspaper. Highly valued in the Zone, as it can be used for entertainment, fire-starting, or as toilet paper.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_newspaper2">
    <text>Newspaper</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_newspaper2_descr">
    <text>A folded Belarusian newspaper. Highly valued in the Zone, as it can be used for entertainment, fire-starting, or as toilet paper.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_note1">
    <text>Paper Note</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_note1_descr">
    <text>A piece of paper with some observations about the Zone, likely written by a local stalker.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

	
<string id="st_nj_note2">
    <text>Paper Note</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_note2_descr">
    <text>A piece of paper with some references to local events, likely written by a local stalker.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_sling">
    <text>Assault Rifle Sling</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_sling_descr">
    <text>A sling used for carrying an assault rifle in both combat and travel-ready positions. Made from a 35mm-wide strap, one end has a carabiner attached via a metal plate and ring, while the other forms a loop with a buckle and keeper. The length is adjustable to fit the individual needs of the rifleman.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_cleankit">
    <text>AK Cleaning Kit</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_cleankit_descr">
    <text>A cleaning kit included with AK-series rifles. Contains various tiny brushes and tools for field disassembly and cleaning. Still in good condition.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_maskpouch">
    <text>GP-5 Gas Mask Bag</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_maskpouch_descr">
    <text>This is a Soviet gas mask pouch. The gas mask, filter, and cleaning kit are missing, making it essentially an empty bag. Made of durable material, it’s perfect for repairing gear or attaching to a belt for carrying extra items.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] wearable on belt\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_flare">
    <text>Blank Key</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_flare_descr">
    <text>A blank key highly valued in the Zone. With the right skills, it can be cut to fit a specific lock, useful for making stashes. Moreover, this is a military-grade key, which means it might also be used to power certain equipment.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_anomac_scanner">
    <text>Portable Anomaly Activity Analyzer</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_anomac_scanner_descr">
    <text>A measuring device widely used by ecologists in the Zone. Quite heavy, but essential for scientific analysis of anomalies — it can create thermal maps of anomalous activity, measure density, and perform various other readings. Not very useful for stalkers, but mobile scientific labs would gladly pay for its recovery.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] scientific equipment\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable\n
        %c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] can be handed over to mobile science lab personnel\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_oscillograph">
    <text>Oscilloscope SI-65A</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_oscillograph_descr">
    <text>The SI-65A oscilloscope is used in mobile scientific labs across the Zone. It's employed for various measurements and tests, particularly with electronic devices and some anomalous phenomena. It detects electrical and gravitational fluctuations caused by anomalies. Not very useful for stalkers, but mobile labs would pay well for a recovered unit.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] scientific equipment\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable\n
        %c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] can be handed over to mobile science lab personnel\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_scanner1">
    <text>Scientific Flash Drive</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_scanner1_descr">
    <text>A high-quality flash drive with a large memory capacity. It bears engravings that may indicate it belongs to scientists from mobile bunker labs throughout the Zone.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] scientific equipment\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable\n
        %c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] can be handed over to mobile science lab personnel\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_scanner2">
    <text>Military Flash Drive</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_scanner2_descr">
    <text>A top-quality flash drive with a large memory capacity. The cap has engravings that may indicate affiliation with scientists from mobile bunkers throughout the Zone.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] scientific equipment\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable\n
        %c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] can be handed over to mobile science lab personnel\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_geigercounter">
    <text>Scientific Geiger Counter</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_geigercounter_descr">
    <text>A scientific Geiger counter used more for analyzing radioactive zones than for personal use. Therefore, it’s not very useful for stalkers, but mobile scientific labs would gladly pay for its recovery.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] scientific equipment\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable\n
        %c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] can be handed over to mobile science lab personnel\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_pda">
    <text>Scientific PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_pda_descr">
    <text>This PDA once belonged to a field researcher from a local mobile science lab. It requires a special password that cannot be bypassed with common Zone software, making it useless to most stalkers. However, mobile science labs would gladly pay for its recovery.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] scientific equipment\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable\n
        %c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] can be handed over to mobile science lab personnel\n
    </text>
</string>

	
<string id="st_nj_acanalyser">
    <text>Acoustic Analyzer</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_acanalyser_descr">
    <text>This device is an acoustic analyzer used to capture sound signals emitted by anomalies to analyze their characteristics. Sound is an important factor in anomaly research, but this device is of little use to any stalker in the Zone. However, mobile scientific labs would gladly pay for its restoration.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] scientific equipment\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable\n
        %c[d_orange] • %c[ui_gray_2] can be handed over to mobile science lab scientists.\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_akmparts">
    <text>Pine Rosin</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_akmparts_descr">
    <text>Rosin is a resin from coniferous trees purified through a special process. Its main component is abietic acid. It has a glass-like appearance and is essential for soldering. During soldering, it acts as flux, removing the oxide layer that covers metal surfaces. Heated to 150°C, it effectively clears the surface for proper bonding.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_bayonet">
    <text>Broken Bayonet</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_bayonet_descr">
    <text>A broken army bayonet. It cannot be repaired without replacing the blade entirely, but may still be useful for repairing another knife or axe.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_toiletpaper">
    <text>Golden Pendant</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_toiletpaper_descr">
    <text>A golden pendant shaped like a bullet, a popular accessory among military personnel. Highly valued by enthusiasts and collectors.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_bugspray">
    <text>VHS Tape</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_bugspray_descr">
    <text>A cartridge containing magnetic tape for helical-scan video recording. This type of media was used for storing and playing television video and audio via VCRs or video cameras. The data can be analog or digital.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_cyan] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_brokenpda">
    <text>Broken PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_brokenpda_descr">
    <text>A PDA with a badly cracked screen and damaged frame. Restoration is difficult, and access to the memory chip is uncertain. It's better to salvage it for spare electronic parts.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] technological item\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] everyday item\n
        %c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] broken beyond repair\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_coppipes">
    <text>Copper Pipes</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_coppipes_descr">
    <text>A few small copper pipes, likely stolen from a factory or similar facility. Copper is a highly valuable material, and traders would gladly buy these.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] construction material\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_cards">
    <text>Golden Pocket Watch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_cards_descr">
    <text>A foldable golden pocket watch from pre-war times. It can function as a stopwatch, and the inner lid can hold a small photo or note.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

	
<string id="st_nj_scarf">
    <text>Golden Bracelet</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_scarf_descr">
    <text>A wrist bracelet made of high-quality gold, greatly favored by local bandits for its rugged look. Fairly valuable to traders.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_beanie">
    <text>Floppy Disk</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_beanie_descr">
    <text>A removable data storage medium used for multiple recordings and data storage. It consists of a flexible magnetic disk encased in a plastic protective shell.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_latex">
    <text>Medical Supply Pack</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_latex_descr">
    <text>A civilian medical aid kit used by emergency services, containing various useful tools and light medications. Highly valued by local medics in the Zone.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_nj_tooth">
    <text>PSP</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nj_tooth_descr">
    <text>A portable gaming console by Sony Computer Entertainment. Due to its ease of maintenance and ability to kill time, it is in high demand among Zone inhabitants. Helps brighten grim days and is easy to repair.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] personal item\n
        %c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_doc_mil_scanner">
    <text>Device Documents</text>
</string>
<string id="st_doc_mil_scanner_desc">
    <text>A sturdy white case with documents marked as classified. The number on the case matches the one found on the device near the wagon.\n \n
        %c[ui_gray_1]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
        %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] valuable information\n
        %c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] quest item\n
    </text>
</string>

	
</string_table>