<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_0">
    <text>Well, I'm not sure, but I think I found a spy. I can show you and bring him in.</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_1">
    <text>Let's see.</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_2">
    <text>I think that's the first brother I spoke with. He's pretty nervous.</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_3">
    <text>Seems like the second brother I talked to. He's closed-off, hiding something, I reckon.</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_4">
    <text>Probably the third brother I talked with. Too chatty, and he came here for money... couldn't come up with a better excuse.</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_5">
    <text>Definitely the fourth brother I spoke to. He's odd — too proper. Wanted to please everyone, damn.</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_6">
    <text>You make a terrible investigator, brother. Did you think I'd just let this slide? Our people were watching you, so the "traitor" has already been handled. You don't deserve a reward and you've disappointed my expectations — go to the Radar and meet with the "Wings" group, they could use help right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_5_7">
    <text>Good job — you can say you guessed right. I sent a couple of my men to keep an eye on you; I couldn't leave such a serious matter solely in your hands. Don't worry, the infiltrator's been dealt with. Griffin sent word — head to the Radar, the "Wings" need your help. And take this shotgun, you earned it. It'll come in handy.</text>
</string>

<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_1_0">
    <text>Hey, how do you like it here?</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_1_1">
    <text>A bit uneasy. But it's always like that in a new place, brother. Heard the Mentor will be calling each of us for some reason?</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_1_2">
    <text>I heard. What do you think about it?</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_1_3">
    <text>I'm afraid I failed my first trial. I mean, going into an anomalous zone? I think he's worried I got the wrong artifact or brought it from the wrong place... God. Leave me alone for now, man.</text>
</string>

<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_2_0">
    <text>Hi. Heard the Mentor is calling us in one by one?</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_2_1">
    <text>Heard, sure — but what's it to me? If he needs it, fine.</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_2_2">
    <text>So, how do you like it here?</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_2_3">
    <text>Not in the mood to chatter — I'm preparing for my third trial.</text>
</string>

<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_3_0">
    <text>Hey, brother. Everyone's so quiet. Got a minute to chat?</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_3_1">
    <text>Why not. How do you like it here?</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_3_2">
    <text>Uh, it's alright. The important thing is I'm under the wing of guys who will make my dream come true eventually.</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_3_3">
    <text>What's your dream?</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_3_4">
    <text>If you tell your dream to every passerby it becomes a goal, not a dream. Why are you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_3_5">
    <text>Mostly for the money. What else would an honest stalker dream of? Alright. You're a good man, but I need a break from talking — I've heard enough today...</text>
</string>

<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_4_0">
    <text>Hello. How do you like it here, in the Monolith?</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_4_1">
    <text>You know, I'm an experienced runner and I had this childish dream to end up in the Monolith. I'm already one foot in.</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_4_2">
    <text>And what do you expect from the Brotherhood?</text>
</string>
<string id="newbee_monolith_stalker_4_3">
    <text>I just want to throw myself into this cause with no second thoughts, you know? Back on the outside nobody's waiting for me anymore. Alright, I still have to sort out the crap from the second trial here. Farewell, brother.</text>
</string>

<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_0">
    <text>Wind, I suppose?</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_1">
    <text>Yes.</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_2">
    <text>Will you tell me about yourself?</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_3">
    <text>No.</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_4">
    <text>Why not?</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_3_5">
    <text>[...]</text>
</string>

<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_0">
    <text>You're Pegasus, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_1">
    <text>Hey, man. Want to get acquainted?</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_2">
    <text>Well, yes. How did you end up here?</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_3">
    <text>Just crossed the army checkpoint and found myself here. You probably want to know why, right? Well, I probably won’t tell you — you wouldn’t understand. It’s very personal, and "O-Consciousness" will guide me to my dream. I ended up in the "Wings" as one of the best marksmen, though I’m not a big fan of sniper rifles.</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_4">
    <text>Who are these "O-Consciousness" people?</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_2_5">
    <text>Don’t tell me you’ve never heard of them, or are you asking my opinion? It’s simple — they’re not mythical beings, but a real group of scientists who somehow reached the noosphere. I once visited a military lab there, up north in the Zone, and their technology impressed me: holograms, monstrous equipment… it’s hard to believe the current Ukrainian government nurtured all this on top of old Soviet tech. And you know, I’d rather trust those I can believe in than some crazy dolgars.</text>
</string>

<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_0">
    <text>Hello, Sparrow.</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_1">
    <text>Hello.</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_2">
    <text>How’s your mood?</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_3">
    <text>Normal, though a bit overwhelming. Didn’t think I’d voluntarily end up in the "Monolith".</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_4">
    <text>And how long have you been here? Where are you from?</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_5">
    <text>I’m experienced, been roaming the Zone for a long time. Lately hung out in the bar, not drying out when all this chaos started at the Radar. Then it got interesting — what happened? And look, what a mess started! Military everywhere, Monolith guys in total confusion, almost shot each other by accident. I helped the guys a bit after the shock, went to their base, and somehow got settled in.</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_6">
    <text>Why did you decide to stay?</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_7">
    <text>Can’t live without the Zone. Thought about quitting, but remembered life outside — unemployment, no prospects, no freedom. Yeah, even here there’s more than there. Well, we’ll have time to complain at the base, if I survive, of course.</text>
</string>
<string id="wings_soldier_mon_mlr_1_8">
    <text>Thanks for the talk.</text>
</string>

<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_0">
    <text>Hello, Mentor. What’s the "trivial" task?</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_1">
    <text>You need to capture a stalker base on the outskirts. The brothers think they’ll interfere with our plans and may pose a threat to the Brotherhood in the future.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_2">
    <text>Am I going there alone?</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_3">
    <text>No, not alone. You’ll meet another one of our groups — they act as assault troops. I let newcomers spend some time with each group so it’s easier to find their place in the Brotherhood. Unfortunately, the third group is already dead. Alright, go on the mission.</text>
</string>

<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_2_0">
    <text>Hello, are you the Inquisitor? The Mentor told me I’m now at your disposal.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_2_1">
    <text>You helped us a lot — finally he’s recruiting stronger guys. Here’s a good weapon, rest up, you can walk to our KBO base. We’ll tidy up here and I’ll call for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_2_2">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>



<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_1_0">
    <text>It’s a bit awkward to ask, but the Mentor mentioned some third squad that was destroyed. Who did he mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_1_1">
    <text>The "Crystal" group. Once it was our most powerful force, focused on protecting "O-Consciousness," the Monolith itself, the Sarcophagus, and the surrounding areas.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_1_2">
    <text>But what happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_1_3">
    <text>Then, as you know, some bastard or a group of bastards broke our defensive barrier called the "Incinerator," and Ukrainian forces poured in, along with various adventurers — even those scoundrels. I don’t have much info, as we were doing some crap with the Preacher at the time… sorry, too many gaps in my past life. Anyway, I digress: the whole group was wiped out, the guys held out to the last, whether they prevented the threat or not, see for yourself. By the way, you can check around the Sarcophagus, maybe find some information or perhaps a weapon. Just don’t forget to take something for radiation protection.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_1_4">
    <text>Alright, I’ll go. I’m curious about this group’s fate.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_1_5">
    <text>No, that’s too dangerous.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_2_0">
    <text>Here, take it. Most of the information is either lost or I don’t know how to read it.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_2_1">
    <text>I’ll pass it to the Mentor, he’ll handle it later. Shame about the guys.</text>
</string>

<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_about_0">
    <text>Why did you decide to stay in the Brotherhood? As I understand, you were "zombified" at first.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_5_1_about_1">
    <text>I woke up somewhere near Pripyat, with people I didn’t know and remembered nothing, like them. We were united only by the uniform, and we didn’t let each other down. My previous life is behind me, brother — it is what it is. I also found a gun with twenty-two notches on it. I don’t think I’d be accepted anywhere else.</text>
</string>

<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_4_0">
    <text>Hello, brother. I was supposed to receive something from the "Wings".</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_4_1">
    <text>Here, your "Abakan".</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_4_2">
    <text>So, huh — earned the respect of the "Wings"? Well done, you’ll go far. Here’s the squad’s signature suit.</text>
</string>

<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_3_0">
    <text>Your face looks grim, is it beyond repair?</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_3_1">
    <text>Not at the moment. Someone apparently disassembled the control panel, but that’s only half the problem. The cooling system is also broken; it will need inspection, though I doubt I have enough strength here. But that’s not your problem, right? By the way, have you been assigned to any other squad yet?</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_3_2">
    <text>Not yet, the Mentor told me to come to you and that’s all.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_3_3">
    <text>I think you have potential. I want to thank you on behalf of our group and give you our signature suit — you’ve earned it.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_3_4">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_3_5">
    <text>Great, I’ll notify the base. Visit the quartermaster in Pripyat, he’ll give you our uniform — I think it will pleasantly surprise you. By the way, soldier, I hope to see you in our ranks in the future.</text>
</string>

<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_2_0">
    <text>What’s required of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_2_1">
    <text>Defend this place with the guys while I try to assess the situation. I think the local creatures will disturb us more than once.</text>
</string>

<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_1_0">
    <text>Ah, you’re apparently our new companion. Well, ready to walk and see the former glory of these places?</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_1_1">
    <text>Hello, you are "Wings"? Tell me about yourselves and the situation, what did we even forget here?</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_1_2">
    <text>"Wings", or rather what remains of them. I’m called Griffin, those guys over there — Sparrow and Pegasus, the skinny guy with the SVD is Wind. So listen: there used to be many of ours here, and this place struck fear into the hearts of unbelievers. Until one stalker sabotaged the local zombification station. And what started here, you had to see — "Duty," "Freedom," loners, and the military. Our best units took the heaviest hit, result: all dead. But in essence, no one managed to take this place — now it’s inhabited by all sorts of creatures and the zombified.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_1_3">
    <text>[...]</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_1_4">
    <text>Now we need to go to the bunker under the so-called "Incinerator" installation and assess the situation, answering one of the main questions facing the Brotherhood: "Is it really possible to restart this installation?" Are you ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_1_5">
    <text>I’m ready, let’s go.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_4_1_6">
    <text>Not ready yet, I’ll look around here first.</text>
</string>

<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_1_0">
    <text>I’ve come regarding the task.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_1_1">
    <text>These "Cossacks" have been sniffing around our patrols at Radar and the outskirts of Pripyat. I want you to make a choice on how we deal with this — it will be a test of your reasoning skills.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_1_3">
    <text>I think we need to deal with their nearest stronghold, the barrier. We need to take away any desire they have to spy.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_1_4">
    <text>We should find the rest of the recon group. I don’t think they acted alone.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_1_5">
    <text>Alright, in that case you can go on the assault. Here’s a dozen grenades — let’s see how you handle it, since you suggested it yourself. The Brotherhood has no other soldiers.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_3_1_6">
    <text>And you’re damn right. But here’s the mess according to their messages on the PDA. One of our rookies, the ones you were standing with earlier, was supposed to steal five Monolith suits from the warehouse and hand them to the saboteurs. We’ll deal with the rest of the hapless recon ourselves; you need to identify this spy. I’ve gathered the rookies; they should be here and they know I’ve planned a serious talk with each of them — ask casually what I might want from them.</text>
</string>

<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_1_0">
    <text>What is my next trial?</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_1_1">
    <text>Follow me.</text>
</string>

<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_2_0">
    <text>See those guys? Take them out. That’s how you’ll prove your loyalty to our cause. Come on, brother, without a shadow of doubt.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_2_1">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>

<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_3_0">
    <text>Well done! As you may have noticed, they were members of "Freedom," probably scouts. Our guys are determining their purpose here; come to me later and we’ll decide what to do next.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_2_3_1">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>

<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_1_0">
    <text>Well then, welcome, brother. Why are you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_1_1">
    <text>I came here for my innermost desire.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_1_2">
    <text>That’s exactly what keeps people like us in the Brotherhood. Overall, the Monolith isn’t what it used to be. Roughly speaking, the Brotherhood is now maintained by only a handful of enthusiasts. Many left the ranks after the Incinerator was shut down. Some stayed because they would die outside the Brotherhood, but that doesn’t mean they won’t leave eventually. And some of us remain here simply because we want to build our own personal paradise, and the "O-Consciousness" technology allows it...</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_1_3">
    <text>You mentioned some trials?</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_1_4">
    <text>All in due time, newly minted brother. Remember, your old life is coming to an end. The Brotherhood has grown fewer in number, but much harsher. What you will experience here, especially during the trials, will seem like true horror to any objectively normal person. First, I want to test your will: I want you to kill the pseudo-giant nearby. How you do it — bare hands, with the brothers’ help, or using found weapons — doesn’t matter to me. This is how you will prove to yourself what you are capable of to achieve your goals, and what means you will likely resort to.</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_1_5">
    <text>Uh, alright.</text>
</string>

<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_2_0">
    <text>The creature is dead. But why are we killing them? Couldn’t they become our allies against... the unbelievers?</text>
</string>
<string id="main_monolith_mlr_task_1_2_1">
    <text>The C-Consciousness forces aren’t enough to even control a handful of people, let alone mutants. When you’re ready for the next trial, come back.</text>
</string>


</string_table>