<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<!-- Диалог 2 -->
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_2_0">
    <text>Hey, what’s wrong, man?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_2_1">
    <text>No time to talk, blood poisoning could start any moment. The snork seems to have a bruise and almost bit my hand off! My medical bag is in that lair — without it I’m a dead man.</text>
</string>

<!-- Dialogue 3 -->
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_3_0">
    <text>Here’s your bag.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_3_1">
    <text>Alright, I’ll take a couple of pills for now and bandage the wounds... ah, damn it!</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_3_2">
    <text>[...]</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_3_3">
    <text>Okay, I’m good. Here, take a couple of medkits just in case. Let’s head to the village.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_3_4">
    <text>Lead the way.</text>
</string>

<!-- Dialogue 4 -->
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_4_0">
    <text>How are you feeling?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_save_task_mlr_dlg_4_1">
    <text>My head’s spinning a bit and my vision’s dim... can’t believe I even made it here. I’ll lie down and sniff some ammonia, then I’ll have to stitch the wound. Take some money from the lower pocket of my backpack if you need it, and come back in a couple of days if you need help. Oh, by the way, I never introduced myself — name’s Kashpirovsky, I’ll be treating the local stalkers around here. Phew, I better get going, my legs can barely hold me.</text>
</string>

<!-- Dialogue after injuries -->
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_after_wounded_0">
    <text>How’s it going, hero?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_after_wounded_1">
    <text>Oh, hey. Healing up slowly. Good thing I stitched it up, though that bruise still reminds me of itself. That thing kicked me hard.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_after_wounded_2">
    <text>So why did you even go in there?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_after_wounded_3">
    <text>Looking for some adventure, I guess. Rumor had it that after the emission the tunnel partially collapsed and something strange was found there. Some said creatures moved in — bodies were found around, just gnawed bones, and no weapons, which was the weirdest part. I only found out what it really was later... shame I didn’t manage to run away, even without my bag. Damn, good thing you grabbed it. Those beasts just crawled out from under the ground! Total nightmare.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_after_wounded_4">
    <text>Yeah, you really got yourself into it. Don’t go sticking your nose anywhere again — you’ve got a useful skill, just stay here and make some money. It’s not like working in a clinic patching up old Soviet grannies for peanuts.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_after_wounded_5">
    <text>You’re right, I got carried away. Alright, take care, my friend — I’ve got some ampoules to sort out. Good luck!</text>
</string>

<!-- Healing dialogue -->
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_heal_0">
    <text>Looks like I’ve been hit.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_heal_1">
    <text>Let me take a look, buddy...</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_heal_2">
    <text>No, don’t worry, you’re fine. Take something for psi protection.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_heal_3">
    <text>[next...]</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_2_12_medic_mlr_heal_4">
    <text>Alright, here we go... hold on a sec... okay, we’ll bandage it up and you’ll be back on your feet in no time!</text>
</string>


</string_table>