<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_1_talking_0">
    <text>Nimble sent me. He asked me to tell you to focus surveillance on the movement of mutants and Bandits in Dark Valley. Here, these are special surveillance devices.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_1_talking_1">
    <text>Understood. But what are these devices for?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_1_talking_2">
    <text>I don't know. He just said to pass them along and that he'll explain later.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_1_talking_3">
    <text>Another fancy gadget from the talented folks in Duty, I guess.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_1_talking_4">
    <text>Maybe. Well, see you around.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_2_talking_0">
    <text>Nimble sent me. He asked me to tell you to focus surveillance on the movement of Stalkers in Cordon. Here, these are special surveillance devices.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_2_talking_1">
    <text>Alright. But what are these devices for? Some kind of biolocator?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_2_talking_2">
    <text>I don't know. He just said to pass them along and that he'll explain later.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_2_talking_3">
    <text>That's just like him. Instead of a good weapon or sturdy armor, he sends this.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_2_talking_4">
    <text>Well, take care then.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_3_talking_0">
    <text>Nimble sent me. He asked me to tell you to focus surveillance on the movement of Bandits in Agroprom. Here, these are special surveillance devices.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_3_talking_1">
    <text>Alright. But what are these devices for? How do we use them on people?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_3_talking_2">
    <text>I don't know. He just said to pass them along and that he'll explain later why they're needed.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_3_talking_3">
    <text>I see, that's just like him. Instead of providing some gear, he sends this.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_3_talking_4">
    <text>Well, take care then.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_4_talking_0">
    <text>Nimble sent me. He asked me to tell you to focus surveillance on the movement of Stalkers in the Bar. Here, these are special surveillance devices.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_4_talking_1">
    <text>Alright. But what are these devices for? Some kind of biolocator?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_4_talking_2">
    <text>I don't know. He just said to pass them along and that he'll explain later why they're needed.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_4_talking_3">
    <text>I see, another fancy gadget from Duty I suppose.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_4_talking_4">
    <text>Well, take care then.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_5_talking_0">
    <text>Nimble sent me. He asked me to tell you to focus surveillance on the movement of mutants in the Swamp. Here, these are special surveillance devices.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_5_talking_1">
    <text>Alright. But what are these devices for? Some kind of biolocator?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_5_talking_2">
    <text>I don't know. He just said to pass them along and that he'll explain later why they're needed.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_5_talking_3">
    <text>I see, that's just like him. Instead of a good weapon or sturdy armor, he sends this.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_foush_quest_dialog_npc_5_talking_4">
    <text>Well, take care then.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_1_talking_0">
    <text>Do you have any work for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_1_talking_1">
    <text>Here's the deal. Despite being a neutral territory, Duty plays a crucial role in the Bar. The command has issued an order to strengthen the positions and ensure overall security, which I help with my area of expertise, radio-electronic warfare. A large number of wanderers of all sorts from the Zone gather here, various deals and negotiations take place, different methods and communication channels are used. Eavesdropping on potential competitors or victims is one of the favorite tactics of local mercenaries. We have a very serious problem that may be related to this. Several groups of stalkers have recently gone missing in the Bar area. The situation has Mercenaries and Bandits written all over it. We need to find out who exactly is behind these disappearances.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_1_talking_2">
    <text>I'm willing to assist Duty in this investigation.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_1_talking_22">
    <text>Not right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_1_talking_222">
    <text>No, I won't take on this task.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_1_talking_3">
    <text>Great. We already have some ideas on how to tackle this, we're going to approach it in a non-standard way. Go and see the radio operators, take the short training course on working with radio electronics. After that, we'll try to identify the extremists through their radio communications. Also, here, take the money for the training course.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_a6_stalker_radiobattle_rpg_1_dialog_0">
    <text>Nitro sent me. He said you would teach me the necessary skills in radio-electronic warfare.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_a6_stalker_radiobattle_rpg_1_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah, I know. Just be aware that you'll have to undergo gradual training, and it's not free. I'll provide you with specific information on radio-electronic warfare, from basic to advanced levels. You'll be able to apply the skills of radio-electronic warfare in practice this way, setting up frequency jammers, bypassing them and whatnot.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_a6_stalker_radiobattle_rpg_1_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm ready to learn the necessary skills.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_a6_stalker_radiobattle_rpg_1_dialog_3">
    <text>I'll take advantage of this opportunity later.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_a6_stalker_radiobattle_rpg_1_dialog_4">
    <text>I don't have enough money right now. Strange, Nitro didn't warn me that it would cost money.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_2_talking_0">
	<text>I have completed the training course. I had to spend quite a sum though.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_2_talking_1">
	<text>Well, those radio operators are quite cunning. Despite my recommendations they didn't want to do it for free, since you're not with Duty. By the way, here's your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_2_talking_2">
	<text>What should I do now?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_zero_quest_dialog_2_talking_3">
	<text>We'll decide the best course of action. Wait while I gather the necessary materials for now.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_1_talking_0">
    <text>So, have you decided yet?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_1_talking_1">
    <text>You'll have to help me conduct radio reconnaissance by performing various measurements using a special device - an oscilloscope. This might allow us to find out how these groups are operating.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_1_talking_2">
    <text>Okay. I didn't expect that the war against extremists would come down to electronic warfare, but not everyone fights in open fields and between anomalies I guess.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_1_talking_3">
    <text>We've been fighting on two fronts from the start. Now listen, we'll have to jam the frequencies of Mercenaries and other illegal formations while also protecting our own communication channels. For that, we'll use modulation and signal transformation. You will be working on the first front. Check the old abandoned hangar. Our guys from the combat squads recently searched it and stumbled upon a gathering of radio equipment. Someone might be using it for their purposes. Here's the oscilloscope, it's not too hard to use. Just test the equipment frequencies if there are any, and bring me the results. We'll think about the next steps based on those readings.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_2_talking_0">
    <text>I managed to gather information from the radios.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_2_talking_1">
    <text>Any problems?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_2_talking_2">
    <text>Yes. I was attacked by a group of mercenaries. They were most likely warned about our plan.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_first_quest_dialog_2_talking_3">
    <text>I'll keep that in mind, they couldn't have deduced anything from the information provided by Barkeep though. We'll continue once the data you obtained is processed and decide what to do next then, I'll also inform my superiors. That said, we've already obtained some information. We need to start working with the Clear Sky faction, because there's a possibility that this provocation was prepared by agents hiding among them. Go see Nimble, the leader of the Clear Sky group. He is their key coordinator, but most importantly, he is loyal to Duty. You'll be working with him.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_2_talking_0">
    <text>Nitro sent me. We're investigating the extremist groups' attacks on stalkers in the Bar. According to the information we've obtained, the threads lead to your people.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_2_talking_1">
    <text>Yes, I'm aware. I've already informed Nitro that I'll help you in any way I can. Here, take this special radio. Here's the plan: We need to narrow down the search area. The mole is either among the southern squads who are currently at Garbage, or somewhere else nearby.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_2_talking_2">
    <text>Alright, where do I need to establish contact and what exactly do I transmit over the air?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_2_talking_3">
    <text>First, head to Misty Forest, then to the tallest tower in the Bar. The radio station is already set up, all you need to do is test all five channels we use for communication.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_2_talking_4">
    <text>Understood. I'll do it.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_3_talking_0">
    <text>I've transmitted the false signal at the locations you said, here's the radio. What do I do now?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_3_talking_1">
    <text>Now we wait for the results. Nitro and the radio operators have already joined the operation. However, you need to prepare for our next step right away.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_3_talking_2">
    <text>What exactly do I need to do? And who do you think is most likely involved in this mess - your southern squads?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_3_talking_3">
    <text>Most likely, but anything is possible. For now, we need special listening devices, they're like personal bugs. Once we identify the squad, we'll need to pinpoint the specific agent. Go to the Duty supplier for the necessary supplies.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_second_quest_dialog_3_talking_4">
    <text>Okay, I'll go see the supplier.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_1_talking_0">
    <text>Hey there, Nimble sent me. He said you'll give me everything I need to create the special listening devices.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_1_talking_1">
    <text>Yes, I know. I've already prepared everything you need. Here, take it and sign off. It's all in perfect condition. Go to Nitro - he'll give you a soldering station.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_1_talking_2">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_2_talking_0">
    <text>So, it seems like Nimble and I have reached an agreement about the job. I need to prepare individual bugs to identify the mole among the Clear Sky faction. I need the soldering station - the supplier said I should get it from you.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_2_talking_1">
    <text>Yes, of course. Here you go. Once you've crafted the bugs, report back to Nimble and give the soldering station to him. We should have fully decrypted the intercepted signals by then. After that we'll know for sure whether to search Garbage or here for the spies.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_2_talking_2">
    <text>Got it.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_3_talking_0">
    <text>Alright, I've crafted the bugs. Here's the soldering station. What's next?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_3_talking_1">
    <text>Excellent. We managed to pinpoint the exact source of the threat.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_3_talking_2">
    <text>Where is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_3_talking_3">
    <text>As we suspected, the southeastern Mercenary brigades and several Bandit groups in Garbage are involved. Their informant is among our people at the flea market. You need to go to Garbage fast, identify and then eliminate them.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_third_quest_dialog_3_talking_4">
    <text>Understood. I'm heading to Garbage.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_azot_fouth_quest_dialog_1_talking_0">
    <text>Well, my friend, I managed to complete the task. I was able to identify the mole among the Clear Sky members. He led me to the extremist group, which has now been eliminated.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_fouth_quest_dialog_1_talking_1">
    <text>Excellent work. That Clear Sky member has also been taken care of. Nimble also thanks you for your assistance.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_fouth_quest_dialog_1_talking_2">
    <text>How much am I owed, in monetary terms?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_fouth_quest_dialog_1_talking_3">
    <text>Here's your share. You did a great job, my friend. If you ever need anything don't hesitate to ask. I believe we can continue working together in the future.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_azot_fouth_quest_dialog_1_talking_4">
    <text>Certainly. Thank you.</text>
</string>


<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_0">
    <text>Tell me about the rules of the Arena.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_1">
    <text>We have six types of battles here: Duel, Hunt, Bodyguard, Partner, Survival, and Avenger. Which type would you like to know more about?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_21">
    <text>About Duel...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_22">
    <text>About Hunt...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_23">
    <text>About Bodyguard...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_24">
    <text>About Partner...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_25">
    <text>About Survival...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_26">
    <text>About Avenger...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_31">
    <text>In this battle you go one-on-one with an opponent. I'll provide you with the necessary gear for the fight, and then it's off to the Arena. The one who survives and leaves their opponent as a lifeless sack wins. With each new stage, I'll match you against stronger opponents. On the fifth and final stage, you'll compete for the title of Arena Master in the Duel class. And remember, the door to the Arena remains electrified until the end of the duel.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_32">
    <text>In this battle you face mutants on your own. I'll equip you with sufficient gear for a successful hunt. With each new stage, I'll select stronger monsters for you to hunt. On the fifth and stage, you'll compete for the title of Arena Master in the Hunt class. And remember, the door to the Arena remains electrified until the end of the duel.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_33">
    <text>In this battle your task is to protect your unarmed partner. Grab a weapon and armor and get to work. To win, you must kill all the attackers while ensuring your partner survives. If both your partner and the attackers end up dead, you won't receive a reward, and it's unlikely you'll continue fighting in this format. With each new stage, the attackers become stronger and more numerous. On the fifth and final stage, you'll compete for the title of Arena Master in the Bodyguard class. And remember, the door to the Arena remains electrified until the end of the duel.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_34">
    <text>In this battle your task is to destroy the enemy squad together with your partner. Grab your weapon and get into the fight. To win, none of the enemy squad members should survive. On the other hand, your partner must stay alive too. If he dies, you won't receive a reward for the battle and won't be able to continue fighting in this format. With each new stage, the enemy squad becomes stronger and larger. On the fifth and final stage, you'll compete for the title of Arena Master in the Partner class. And remember, the door to the Arena remains electrified until the end of the duel.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_35">
    <text>In this battle you'll face mutants on your own. I'll provide you with minimal gear. Your task is to survive for a certain period of time. You can shoot at the mutants of course, but you're unlikely to have enough bullets for all of them, and it may attract even more. With each new stage, I'll select stronger monsters for you to face. On the fifth and final stage, you'll compete for the title of Arena Master in the Survival class. And remember, the door to the Arena remains electrified until the end of the duel.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_36">
    <text>In this battle your task is to single-handedly destroy the enemy squad. You have enough weapons and ammunition. To win, none of the enemy squad members should survive. With each new stage the enemy squad becomes stronger and larger. On the fifth and final stage, you'll compete for the title of Arena Master in the Avenger class. And remember, the door remains electrified until the end of the duel.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_41">
    <text>Interesting.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_42">
    <text>Cool.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_43">
    <text>Who came up with all that?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_44">
    <text>Oh, come on.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_45">
    <text>Nice.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_about_arena_kostolom_dialog_46">
    <text>Is that so?</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_after_arena_fight_dialog_0">
    <text>Did you handle it? Well done! Hand over all the gear.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_after_arena_fight_dialog_1">
    <text>Here's everything I have.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_after_arena_fight_dialog_21">
    <text>Your personal gear is in the safe in the corridor, and Kalgan has your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_after_arena_fight_dialog_22">
    <text>Your gear, as usual, is in the safe.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_after_arena_fight_dialog_31">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_after_arena_fight_dialog_32">
    <text>Understood, thank you.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_0">
    <text>I'm here for my reward for winning at the Arena.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_100">
    <text>I've already given everything I owe you.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_111">
    <text>Here's the reward for Avenger Stage 1.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_112">
    <text>Here's the reward for Avenger Stage 2.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_113">
    <text>Here's the reward for Avenger Stage 3.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_114">
    <text>Here's the reward for Avenger Stage 4.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_115">
    <text>Here's the reward for Avenger Stage 5.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_121">
    <text>Here's the reward for Bodyguard Stage 1.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_122">
    <text>Here's the reward for Bodyguard Stage 2.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_123">
    <text>Here's the reward for Bodyguard Stage 3.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_124">
    <text>Here's the reward for Bodyguard Stage 4.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_125">
    <text>Here's the reward for Bodyguard Stage 5.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_131">
    <text>Here's the reward for Duel Stage 1.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_132">
    <text>Here's the reward for Duel Stage 2.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_133">
    <text>Here's the reward for Duel Stage 3.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_134">
    <text>Here's the reward for Duel Stage 4.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_135">
    <text>Here's the reward for Duel Stage 5.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_141">
    <text>Here's the reward for Partner Stage 1.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_142">
    <text>Here's the reward for Partner Stage 2.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_143">
    <text>Here's the reward for Partner Stage 3.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_144">
    <text>Here's the reward for Partner Stage 4.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_145">
    <text>Here's the reward for Partner Stage 5.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_151">
    <text>Here's the reward for Hunt Stage 1.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_152">
    <text>Here's the reward for Hunt Stage 2.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_153">
    <text>Here's the reward for Hunt Stage 3.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_154">
    <text>Here's the reward for Hunt Stage 4.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_155">
    <text>Here's the reward for Hunt Stage 5.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_161">
    <text>Here's the reward for Survival Stage 1.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_162">
    <text>Here's the reward for Survival Stage 2.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_163">
    <text>Here's the reward for Survival Stage 3.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_164">
    <text>Here's the reward for Survival Stage 4.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_165">
    <text>Here's the reward for Survival Stage 5.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_take_rewqard_dialog_2">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
</string>


<string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_0">
    <text>Do you participate in Arena fights?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah, for sure.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_10">
    <text>Well, you're a cool dude. Come by when you're really ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_21">
    <text>Tell me about your specialization.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_22">
    <text>I also want to participate in Arena fights. Do you want to join me in a Bodyguard fight?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_31">
    <text>I'm Vasya Rod from the Burnt Brigade. I decided to make some quick cash at the Arena. It's kind of scary, but Kalgan promised good money for protecting clients. I don't have decent armor, but I'll back you up like a fly on shit. Those clowns won't get a chance.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_32">
    <text>No problem, as long as you don't screw up.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_41">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_421">
    <text>Yeah, fine by me.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_422">
    <text>Not yet, I'll think about it.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright. Let's kick some ass at the Arena.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_1_naim_dialog_6">
    <text>See you at the Arena.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_0">
    <text>Do you participate in Arena fights?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_10">
    <text>I'm always here if you change your mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_21">
    <text>Tell me about your specialization.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_22">
    <text>I also want to participate in Arena fights. Do you want to join me in a Bodyguard fight?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_31">
    <text>I'm Petr Bolotnik from the Swamps, as you can guess. I used to be with Clear Sky, but now I'm working in the Arena. I have decent armor and a helmet, but they restrict my movement a bit, so keep a close eye on me.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_32">
    <text>I'm fine with it if it suits you.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_41">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_421">
    <text>Yeah, everything's fine by me.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_422">
    <text>Not yet, I'll think about it.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright. See you at the Arena.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_2_naim_dialog_6">
    <text>See you.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_0">
    <text>Do you participate in Arena fights?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_1">
    <text>As Monolith is my witness - yes.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_10">
    <text>I'm always here if not in prayer.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_21">
    <text>Tell me about your specialization.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_22">
    <text>I also want to participate in Arena fights. Do you want to join me in a Bodyguard fight?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_31">
    <text>I'm Innocent Frostbitten, a former follower of great Monolith. Nowadays I do Bodyguard fights at the Arena. Praise Monolith I have powerful armor, but it's also quite bulky, so you need to wait for me to catch up.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_32">
    <text>If it's the will of Monolith, I don't object.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_41">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_421">
    <text>Alright then.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_422">
    <text>Not yet, I'll think about it.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_5">
    <text>That's good. May Monolith protect you.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_3_naim_dialog_6">
    <text>See you at the Arena.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_0">
    <text>How was the last fight in the Arena?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_100">
    <text>We haven't fought yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_111">
    <text>You knocked them down nicely.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_112">
    <text>Not bad, but they almost got you.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_113">
    <text>Listen buddy, if things keep going like this, we'll be wearing Versace sneakers.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_114">
    <text>Imagine if I had stumbled, damn, keep an eye on those idiots.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_115">
    <text>Wow, buddy, you smashed them. I've got some serious cash.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_121">
    <text>It's alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_122">
    <text>Yeah, everything went well, I guess.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_123">
    <text>Not bad, not bad. A couple more times and I'll have enough for a cottage in the village.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_124">
    <text>Phew, I was on the brink of death, thank God it all worked out.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_125">
    <text>Great, you took care of them. Now I've made some decent money and don't have to take risks like that.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_131">
    <text>Everything's fine.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_132">
    <text>Awesome, everything is going really well.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_133">
    <text>Everything is perfect, praise Monolith.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_134">
    <text>It's fine, just a little damage to the armor.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_135">
    <text>Everything's great, I'm alive and well, and the armor is intact. Praise Monolith.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bodyguard_after_fight_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_0">
    <text>Do you participate in the Arena fights?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah, brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_10">
    <text>Anyway, I'm here if anything.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_21">
    <text>Tell me about your specialization.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_22">
    <text>I want to participate in the Arena fights. Do you want to join as my partner?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_31">
    <text>I'm Gena Shovel from the Sopatogo Brigade. I just love brawling alongside a partner you know? My armor is weak, but I've got a solid gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_32">
    <text>No problem, I can bash someone's skull in right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_41">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_421">
    <text>Okay then.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_422">
    <text>No, wait, I'll think about it some more.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_5">
    <text>Bye for now. See you on the battlefield.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_1_naim_dialog_6">
    <text>See you at the Arena.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_0">
    <text>Do you participate in the Arena fights?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_10">
    <text>Understood. I'll wait if you change your mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_21">
    <text>Tell me about your specialization.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_22">
    <text>I want to participate in the Arena fights. Do you want to join as my partner?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_31">
    <text>I'm Kolya Lucky from the Free Stalkers. I earn my bread with fights alongside a partner. As you can see, my jacket is not super, but I have some decent weapons.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_32">
    <text>I'm okay with it if it suits you.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_41">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_421">
    <text>Yeah, everything suits me.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_422">
    <text>No, wait, I'll think about it some more.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright. See you at the Arena.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_2_naim_dialog_6">
    <text>See you.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_0">
    <text>Do you participate in the Arena fights?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_1">
    <text>Affirmative.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_10">
    <text>Come by later if you change your mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_21">
    <text>Tell me about your specialization.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_22">
    <text>I want to participate in the Arena fights. Do you want to join as my partner?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_31">
    <text>I'm Mitya Brace, a former soldier, now a deserter and a free shooter. I'm up for earning some cash in a fight with a competent partner. My armor is lightweight military gear, but I only have a simple pistol for weapons.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_32">
    <text>I'm in if it suits you.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_41">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_421">
    <text>Yeah, everything suits me.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_422">
    <text>No, wait, I'll think about it some more.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright. See you at the Arena.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_3_naim_dialog_6">
    <text>See you at the Arena.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_0">
    <text>How was the last fight at the Arena?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_100">
    <text>We haven't fought yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_111">
    <text>Awesome, but I didn't warm up enough.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_112">
    <text>Great, I was just blasting away with my gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_113">
    <text>We simply tore them apart, brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_114">
    <text>Man, it was tough.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_115">
    <text>Brother, we're like two terminators.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_121">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_122">
    <text>Good, we're managing well together.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_123">
    <text>Wonderful, we crushed them.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_124">
    <text>Not bad, but I couldn't help looking behind.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_125">
    <text>That's it, we're champions. Now we'll meet all the babes.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_131">
    <text>Not bad, you move skillfully and provide good cover.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_132">
    <text>Getting better and better, we'll definitely make a great team.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_133">
    <text>Excellent, with you, it's like a brave special forces unit, we crushed everyone.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_134">
    <text>It was tough, but we didn't miss a shot, took down the enemies.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_135">
    <text>Great, we're champion brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_after_fight_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_medic_need_health_care_0">
    <text>I need medical assistance.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_medic_need_health_care_1">
    <text>No problem, let me take a look...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_medic_need_health_care_11">
    <text>[continue...]</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_medic_need_health_care_2">
    <text>Are you kidding? You're very healthy!</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_stard_dialog_barman_text">
    <text>Hello my friend, what brings you here? How's life treating you?</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_0">
    <text>I want to sign up for a fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_1">
    <text>What type of fight do you want to sign up for?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_10">
    <text>Whatever you say.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_21">
    <text>I want to sign up for Duel.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_22">
    <text>I want to sign up for Hunt.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_23">
    <text>I want to sign up for Bodyguard.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_24">
    <text>I want to sign up for Partner.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_25">
    <text>I want to sign up for Survival.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_26">
    <text>I want to sign up for Avenger.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_27">
    <text>No, I don't think I'll risk losing my life.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_311">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 1 of the Duel.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_312">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 2 of the Duel.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_313">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 3 of the Duel.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_314">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 4 of the Duel.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_315">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 5 of the Duel.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_321">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 1 of the Hunt.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_322">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 2 of the Hunt.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_323">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 3 of the Hunt.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_324">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 4 of the Hunt.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_325">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 5 of the Hunt.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_331">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 1 of the Bodyguard.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_332">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 2 of the Bodyguard.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_333">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 3 of the Bodyguard.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_334">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 4 of the Bodyguard.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_335">
    <text>All right, I'm signing you up for Stage 5 of the Bodyguard.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_337">
    <text>For this fight, you need a partner whom you will guard. Make a deal with one of the stalkers, they usually hang out in the tunnel near the fans.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_338">
    <text>I already told you, make a deal with one of the stalkers to participate in the fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_339">
    <text>Unfortunately your previous partner died, no one wants to associate with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_341">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 1 of the Partner fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_342">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 2 of the Partner fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_343">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 3 of the Partner fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_344">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 4 of the Partner fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_345">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 5 of the Partner fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_347">
    <text>For this fight, you need a partner. Make a deal with one of the stalkers, they usually hang out in the tunnel near the fans.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_348">
    <text>I already told you, make a deal with one of the stalkers to participate in this fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_349">
    <text>Unfortunately your previous partner died, no one wants to associate with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_351">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 1 of the Survival fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_352">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 2 of the Survival fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_353">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 3 of the Survival fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_354">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 4 of the Survival fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_355">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 5 of the Survival fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_361">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 1 of the Avenger fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_362">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 2 of the Avenger fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_363">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 3 of the Avenger fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_364">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 4 of the Avenger fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_365">
    <text>Okay, I'm signing you up for Stage 5 of the Avenger fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_4">
    <text>Agreed.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_5">
    <text>Personal belongings go in the safe.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_7">
    <text>Here's the equipment for the fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_811">
    <text>Let's go.</text>
</string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_812">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_813">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_814">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_815">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_821">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_822">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_823">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_824">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_825">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_831">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_832">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_833">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_834">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_835">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_841">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_842">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_843">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_844">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_845">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_851">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_852">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_853">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_854">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_855">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_861">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_862">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_863">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_864">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_865">
        <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kostolom_dialog_9">
    <text>Good luck!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kalgun_dialog_0">
    <text>I see the Arena is up and running again?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kalgun_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes and not only that, we have expanded and now have several types of fights on the Arena, with five stages each.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kalgun_dialog_2">
    <text>Great, I would like to participate in the fights.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kalgun_dialog_3">
    <text>No problem, you can learn the details and rules from my assistant - Crusher. You can also sign up for fights by talking to him, he handles the equipment too. You will receive your rewards for winning fights from me.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_start_arena_kalgun_dialog_4">
    <text>Got it, we'll meet again then.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_medic_need_health_care_111">
    <text>There you go, now you're all patched up. You'll live.</text>
</string>
	
	<!------------------------------------------------------------------------>
	<!--------------------------- СЮЖЕТНЫЕ ДИАЛОГИ БАРА ---------------------->
	<!------------------------------------------------------------------------>
	
	<!------------>
<string id="bar_first_talk_barmen_dialog_0">
    <text>Phew, we barely made it! Hello, are you the one in charge here?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_first_talk_barmen_dialog_1">
    <text>Quite an emission today, I don't like this at all... Who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_first_talk_barmen_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm Shroud. My friend and I made it to Garbage through an underground laboratory from Cordon, following Sidorovich's lead. There were some heavily armed people there trying to kill us. They gassed us, we barely survived.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_first_talk_barmen_dialog_3">
    <text>I see, Sidorovich informed me about you. Rest up for now, recover, we'll talk after the emission is over. I'll have a job for you then.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_first_talk_barmen_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_doc_barmen_dialog_0">
    <text>We found some documents in the laboratory under Cordon. It seems to be fragmentary information about what was happening there. Sidorovich asked me to give them to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_doc_barmen_dialog_1">
    <text>Show me what you have.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_doc_barmen_dialog_111">
    <text>Document-1</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_doc_barmen_dialog_112">
    <text>Document-2</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_doc_barmen_dialog_113">
    <text>Document-3</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_doc_barmen_dialog_2">
    <text>I'll look through them in my spare time. If there's anything useful, I'll let you know. Oh, I almost forgot, here's something for your trouble.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_doc_barmen_dialog_3">
    <text>That's all I have, thank you.</text>
</string>


	
	<!------------>
<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_0">
    <text>What's the matter? Tell me.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_1">
    <text>I already know from Sidorovich that you're interested in finding the Pendulum artifact and that you witnessed the damned chaos surrounding it. People are ready to tear each other apart for that one... So, just recently I received a lot of interesting information regarding this whole affair. It seems like you guys are reliable and can be trusted. Interested?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_2">
    <text>Of course. Go on.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_3">
    <text>Here's the deal... An unknown but very wealthy artifact collector has announced an incredible reward for whoever finds Pendulum. It's known that a private military company called "Spectrum" organized an expedition to search for it in the Zone, but they can't seem to find it, lacking the necessary information. I don't know where these rumors come from, but some claim that the Monolith faction still guards this artifact and that it's stored somewhere underground in the Zone. Everyone's gone crazy over the money offered for its discovery... Bandits, Mercenaries, Stalkers, loners, they all roam underground areas and dive into anomalies just to find this mysterious Pendulum.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_4">
    <text>Do you have any information about where it might be?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_5">
    <text>All of this is very strange, there hasn't been such a frenzy since Strelok deactivated the Brain Scorcher and everyone rushed to the center. New stalkers are entering the Zone, and retired experienced ones are returning from far away. But enough about that, yes, I have some information. Sidorovich vouched for you, so I think we can work together.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_6">
    <text>I'll discuss your proposal with my partner.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_7">
    <text>Alright, I'll give you a couple of days to think it over. Just be careful not to take too long, I have other interested parties in mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barmen_dialog_8">
    <text>See you soon.</text>
</string>
	
    <!------------>
	
<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_0">
    <text>Oh, you're up.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_1">
    <text>How are you? We got beat up pretty badly huh? I thought it was all over... I even started recalling my prayers. Anyway, enough sentimentality. Barkeep here is offering us a good job, would you be interested?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_2">
    <text>Yeah... Man, my head is killing me... I can't shake off the effects of poisoning. So, what's he offering?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_3">
    <text>He says he has information about the possible location of the Pendulum artifact. I feel like it won't be as easy as it sounds, but I still want to give it a try and find it.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_4">
    <text>Everyone at the Bar is talking about that artifact. They say people are searching all over the Zone for it. So many have disappeared... some shot by Bandits, others lost in anomalies. There are whispers about some group called "Spectrum" as well. I've had enough adventures and fed up. Plus, I don't like this whole story about an unbelievably large reward. I think I'll try to return to the outside world once I regain my senses. That's my final decision. Sorry brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_5">
    <text>So you're not with me?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_6">
    <text>No, no, no - don't even try to persuade me. I've had enough of this dealing with Sidor, now I'll be smarter. I don't recommend you to get involved either. Barkeep is a real schemer, he's already sent so many people to their doom with his tasks. Do you know why he chose you? Because he doesn't care who he sends to those deadly places, just to confirm his guesses.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_new_details_barland_dialog_7">
    <text>Well, I'll still try my luck. Farewell, my friend!</text>
</string>
	
   <!------------>	
   
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_0">
    <text>Here I am.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_1">
    <text>What's your decision?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm ready to cooperate.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_3">
    <text>Great, where's your buddy?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_4">
    <text>He decided not to join me.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, no problem, your share will be bigger that way. So, here's the deal: The Duty faction captured one of Logopedist's lieutenants, a Bandit boss in Cordon. You've probably crossed paths with him... Your task is to go and speak with Duty's leader, Voronin. They extracted some information from the Bandit during the interrogation before they took him out.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_6">
    <text>Is that all? I just have to go and talk with him?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_7">
    <text>Yes, that's it for now. Go and take care of that. I need to clarify a few things through my channels and cross-reference the information from your documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_8">
    <text>Wouldn't it have been easier for you to find out everything from him yourself?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_9">
    <text>When did you get so smart? If I say go and talk, then that's what needs to be done. Come on now, get moving.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_dialog_10">
    <text>Okay, I'm going.</text>
</string>  


   <!------------>	
   
<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello! Barkeep sent me.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_1">
    <text>So, you're the guy... the one who stirred up all this commotion? I'll give you the information we managed to extract from that scumbag, but I'll need you to do a little job for me in return. Agreed?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_2">
    <text>Agreed.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_3">
    <text>So, we spotted our Bandit friend when he crawled out of some hole and tried to break through the Duty base to get outside. We had a polite conversation with him and learned the following: You know that Monolith member who disguised himself as a Freedomer? Turns out he scoured the entire neighborhood. He was seen multiple times, even lingered here for quite a while, supposedly came far away using secret tunnels. Apparently, there's an underground complex beneath the Rostok factory, where we are right now. From there, a secret underground railway leads straight to the closed city of Kurchatov, that's where he came from. Haven't seen anyone who's been there even once, there are ominous rumors about it. Anyway, the Bandit didn't know what's happening inside the city, he turned out to be rather dense. To get into these tunnels, you need to get past the locked metal door here in our base. We keep it under constant surveillance... just in case.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_4">
    <text>That's informative. What do I have to do in return for this information?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_5">
    <text>No big deal! You just need to stand guard with my guys at the checkpoint. Recon reported that mutants have multiplied to an absurd extent in Wild Territory. They might attack the Bar, most likely very soon too. Stand guard there for a day, then you're free.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_7">
    <text>I'll let you know when your shift starts. Don't wander too far from the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_voronin_dialog_8">
    <text>Deal.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_general_dangerous_duty_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, listen carefully. You'll be taking up your position here and stand with my soldiers for a day. I'm increasing the manpower at the checkpoint today, because we're expecting an onslaught of mutants from Wild Territory. Unauthorized leaving of the post is considered desertion and is punishable under wartime laws. Understood?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_general_dangerous_duty_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, I'll start my duties.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_general_dangerous_duty_2_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, hero, our guys got your back. You took a little nap but now you're as cool as a cucumber! It was a bit heavy huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_general_dangerous_duty_2_dialog_1">
    <text>A bit, you say?! My ears is still ringing and my left eye keeps twitching.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_general_dangerous_duty_2_dialog_2">
    <text>Calm down man, the main thing is that you're alive. You've fulfilled your duty and are free to go now.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_dolg_general_dangerous_duty_2_dialog_3">
    <text>I'm leaving.</text>
</string>
	

<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_0">
    <text>Well... What's up...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_1">
    <text>I saw how they dragged you in here. I thought we'd meet on the other side. But you're as tough as a dog! So, tell me... what did you learn from Voronin?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_2">
    <text>Yeah, got a little roughed up, not the first time. Anyway, he says there are underground tunnels under the Bar. Some kind of laboratory or something... it's sealed with a locked door. Apparently, my "Monolith guy" came out of there recently. Have you heard of Kurchatov?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_3">
    <text>Hmm... Interesting coincidence. I've actually been digging up information about that closed city recently. I sent a group of stalkers there for reconnaissance not long ago. They went through the Army Warehouses and haven't been in touch for a week. A few days ago, one guy barely made it back, saying that all hell is breaking loose there! Mutants and zombies are rampant... a real nightmare. I think it would be safer for you to reach Kurchatov through the catacombs.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_4">
    <text>Are you sure it's possible to reach the city that way?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_5">
    <text>I have some maps showing the underground sections leading to Kurchatov. Some details were missing since mice chewed up the exact place where the underground descent points were marked. Based on Voronin's information, these tunnels could connect the Bar with Kurchatov.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_6">
    <text>But how do we get there? Voronin said the passage is sealed?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_7">
    <text>Let me think... Hmm... You said it's sealed right? I have some ideas...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_8">
    <text>Spill the beans already.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_9">
    <text>We have a small acid swamp nearby, and there's a house there where some clearly deranged guy is settled. I don't have reliable information about him, who he is or where he's from, and I don't really care. People say he used to work in the Consciousness laboratories, doing experiments on humans, they say that's what drove him mad. I don't believe it myself. Go see him, maybe he knows how to get into the laboratory. And... be on your guard.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_expectation_barmen_part2_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright, I'll go. I'll try to find out something.</text>
</string>
	

<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello my dear friend! Long time no see. I suppose you've been busy with work... How's the wife?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_1">
    <text>What?! Are you out of your mind?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_2">
    <text>Hold on now, Senka, don't confuse me!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_3">
    <text>I'm not Senka, uncle. I'm here on business. I need the key to the laboratory. Can you help me out?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_4">
    <text>Shh... keep it down, it's always winter there, turn off the light. I can give you the key. I bet you've been looking into the hospital.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_5">
    <text>Hey, look at me, concentrate. The key to the entrance door. The key. To the laboratory door. Where is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_6">
    <text>Ha, pencil, sharpener, swamp – artifact! Trade. Paid for with state funds, I swear.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_7">
    <text>Pfft... will you start making sense?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_8">
    <text>Artifact! Artifacts!!! Everything shifts, I can't concentrate. It's all like a dream. I'm not dreaming, am I?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_9">
    <text>No, you're not dreaming. Do you need artifacts? I'll trade them for the key if you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_10">
    <text>Yes... no, yes, yes. I'll trade. And the key is golden too! All life on Earth springs from it...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_11">
    <text>Man, you're out of your... Well, you need artifacts? I'll gather everything here in this swamp. After that you'll give me the key though, otherwise I'll take it myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_12">
    <text>Yeees, yes! Trade... (continues mumbling something inaudible)</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_otshelnik_dialog_13">
    <text>Wait here.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_walker_lab_barmen_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello again.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_walker_lab_barmen_dialog_1">
    <text>Why are you covered in mud? Ugh... and you stink too. When was the last time you took a shower?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_walker_lab_barmen_dialog_2">
    <text>No no, it's because of the swamp. The one near the crazy old man's house... may he rest in peace.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_walker_lab_barmen_dialog_3">
    <text>Rest in peace? Did you kill him or something?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_walker_lab_barmen_dialog_4">
    <text>It wasn't intentional, I had to! He was out of his mind... babbling about something. But never mind what he said. Long story short, I have the key to that door. Why did you call me?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_walker_lab_barmen_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright, since you have the key, it means you'll soon go to that laboratory. I don't know what or who awaits you there. I'm very interested in you surviving and coming back here with the loot though, so I'm giving you a gun and a bulletproof vest. Just don't even think about running away and selling them! They're rare... If they show up in the inventory of any trader I'll be the first to know, and you'll have to answer for it. Understand?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_walker_lab_barmen_dialog_6">
    <text>Yeah, I'm not a fool. I'm off.</text>
</string>
	
	
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey there!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_1">
    <text>Did Hoarse sent you?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_2">
    <text>Who is Hoarse?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_3">
    <text>Alright, forget it. I'm waiting for a guy here. Been waiting for a while now... Maybe you've heard anything about him?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_4">
    <text>No, I haven't heard anything. Who are you and what are you doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_5">
    <text>Who's asking?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_6">
    <text>I'm Shroud. Just passing by, seeing some friendly faces, thought I'd ask who you are. Maybe I can get a job or something.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_7">
    <text>I'm not the employment agency. Go talk to Barkeep; he's always happy to give people something to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_8">
    <text>Well, thanks, but I've already talked to him. Seems like you're not in the mood for conversation.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_9">
    <text>How can you tell? Listen, ever heard of the Clear Sky faction? We're all that's left of it.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_10">
    <text>We've crossed paths, but I don't know much about you guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_11">
    <text>Are you new around here or something?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_12">
    <text>Well, you could say that... I'm not exactly a veteran, but I've tasted gunpowder and felt anomalies on my backside.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_13">
    <text>I see. So, our faction was settled in the Swamps. We were involved in various activities. Our eggheads mostly studied artifacts, while we provided gear and security for the whole operation. Everyone was doing fine until we got the crazy idea to go to CNPP. It's a long story, maybe someday I'll write a book about it and you can read it. Anyway, we got hit by a massive emission there. Most of us didn't expect such a turn of events and died on the spot. I had enough time to hide in a shelter. When I came out, all I saw were corpses. They say someone even made a game about it on the outside world. Maybe someone from our survivors... I don't know.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_14">
    <text>Yeah, man. The Zone got to you. So, what are your plans now? Who are you waiting for?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_15">
    <text>Us Clear Sky survivors have gathered here. We're thinking of revisiting our old stomping grounds. The places where Lebedev and Suslov used to hide artifacts. It was an interesting thing they did, studying the artifacts and then returning them to the Zone, I don't know why. So that's it, we're preparing to go to that area.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_16">
    <text>So, you're planning to search for artifacts?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_17">
    <text>Of course, I'm tired of digging around in the damp and dirt here. I'm freezing my ass off and my knees have been aching for the past two years. Think about it, why not give it a try when the money is very good? We're waiting for Hoarse, if you happen to meet him, tell him that. He's been off the radar for a couple of days now.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_18">
    <text>I'll pass on the message if I see him. Take care.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_npc_nimble_dialog_19">
    <text>You too, stay safe.</text>
</string>


	
	
</string_table>
