<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_0">
    <text>Halt, who are you!? Speak quickly and don't make up any stories!</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_1">
    <text>My name is Shroud and my friend's is Borland. Sidorovich showed us the way to the laboratory, we have something for Barkeep.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_2">
    <text>Barkeep you say? That changes things. Your friend seems severely poisoned, probably from inhaling that gas down there. There's no guarantee you haven't been affected either.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_3">
    <text>What gas? We survived, didn't we?</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_4">
    <text>Not exactly. No one knows what that gas is, but there have been cases where diggers died because of it. They seem to make it out, then an hour later, they drop dead.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_5">
    <text>Really?</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_6">
    <text>One guy seems to have survived, but nobody knows how. If you manage to find him, you can help yourself and Borland.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_7">
    <text>Thanks for the warning, commander. Where can I find him?</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_8">
    <text>Who knows, around here in Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_start_dialog_talking_9">
    <text>Alright then, thanks again.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_borland_start_dialog_talking_101">
    <text>I'm feeling awful, Shroud. Seems like we inhaled something nasty in the underground.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_borland_start_dialog_talking_0">
    <text>I know, Borland, but the squad leader said there's a digger who managed to deal with this poisoning. Do you know someone like that in Garbage?</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_borland_start_dialog_talking_1">
    <text>I've heard that there's a mound nearby, next to the containers. They say he's somewhere in that area. Many have tried, but no one has found his den yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_borland_start_dialog_talking_2">
    <text>We don't have much of a choice. If you can't go, then I'll find him myself. It wouldn't hurt to learn something about the catacombs too. He must have been there multiple times.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_borland_start_dialog_talking_3">
    <text>Go for it, I'm counting on you. Just don't stay there long once you find the antidote, or the Zone might take me.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_borland_start_dialog_talking_4">
    <text>Got it, I'll be quick.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_borland_second_dialog_talking_0">
    <text>Shroud, I knew you'd keep your word.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_borland_second_dialog_talking_1">
    <text>Alright, Borland, here's the antidote.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_borland_second_dialog_talking_2">
    <text>Thanks.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_borland_second_dialog_talking_3">
    <text>You rest up, I'll talk to the local authorities in the meantime.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_second_dialog_talking_00">
    <text>Shroud, the scientists warned us, there's an unprecedented emission coming. The only safe place from that is the Bar's underground area. If you don't want to die, follow us to safety. Make your decision fast, we'll close the passage so that mutants don't get in and drop our chances of survival to zero.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_second_dialog_talking_0">
    <text>Are they certain?</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_second_dialog_talking_1">
    <text>They don't joke about such things. If you noticed, Garbage is already deserted. Everyone who values their life evacuated yesterday. By the way, what was that gunfire I heard?</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_second_dialog_talking_2">
    <text>I don't know, some kind of heavily armed unknown unit. They're like a bad omen. I barely escaped them while in the laboratory and now they are causing trouble here.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_second_dialog_talking_3">
    <text>Them showing up in our area isn't a good sign. Alright, no time to speculate. Make your decision, are you with us?</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_bagretcev_second_dialog_talking_4">
    <text>Yes, of course.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_dolg_guard_dialog_0">
    <text>Move faster, the emission is about to hit! We'll wait for one more squad and follow you.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_a2_dolg_guard_dialog_1">
    <text>Good luck.</text>
</string>
</string_table>
