<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>  
<string id="ui_gui_document_caption_1">
    <text>Document.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_document_caption_1_1">
    <text>Instructions.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_razia_caption">
    <text>Radio Receiver R-250M2 Kit-M2</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_a2_quest_2_guk_text_1">
    <text>Encrypted message received in response to the request. Control communication session was successfully established.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_a2_quest_2_guk_text_2">
    <text>Encrypted message not received in response to the request. Control communication session was not established.</text>
</string>
<string id="mar_a2_quest_4_guk_text_1">
    <text>Eighth, eighth. This is ninth on the line. Points 34, 56, 21 is under our control. Two groups will take positions at checkpoint 527.</text>
</string>
	
<string id="st_notepad_type_second_1_text">
    <text>After an unsuccessful attempt to transport the "Monolith Shard" and the resulting local accidents (as reported in the document dated 18.04.2010), part of the personnel was urgently evacuated beyond the perimeter of the Exclusion Zone.

The evacuation of the second group is planned for 21.04.

By the evening of 19.04, the freezing of the laboratory had reached about 50% of the working areas. The staff was accommodated for the night in reserve rooms with increased isolation.

During the night of 19.04 to 20.04, there was a sharp increase in the intensity of thermal absorption by the artifact. Several rooms were frozen along with the employees sleeping in them. Six people died. Based on a brief examination of the affected individuals, it can be concluded that they died simultaneously, as if the freezing occurred very intensely, with a huge temperature difference.

In the morning, after the incident was discovered, the entire staff was alerted. At an emergency meeting, we decided to leave the laboratory as soon as possible. No one paid proper attention to the inappropriate behavior of the junior employee Bykov, which later led to tragic consequences.

Attached to the report is a video recording from surveillance cameras placed in the laboratory.

Four people died from gunshot wounds, including Bykov himself, who took his own life with a shot to the head during a seizure.

During the attack, some employees took shelter in remote rooms and were unharmed.

Psychological and medical assistance has been provided to everyone.

The morale of the majority is low, which is attributed to the increasingly evident psychotropic effects of the anomalous formation on living organisms. In particular, several employees independently described hallucinations of the same content.

At the moment, it can be stated that we were not prepared to encounter an artifact with such devastating effects.

There is no need to discuss the rescue of equipment and the continuation of research on the anomalous formation.

We anxiously await evacuation.
.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_notepad_type_second_2_text">
<text>On April 10, 2010, at 23:58, a strong sound explosion and light emission were recorded by external monitoring devices near the GPS point. It was established that the newly formed object under number #1256-XM was discovered at the same coordinates the next day. I assume that the aforementioned circumstances and the discovered artifact are directly related to its appearance. On April 11, 2010, at 10:00, a group consisting of 4 employees of the research institute (junior employee Bykov, engineer Savin, junior employee Nilov, Prof. Markeev) went to the location where the aforementioned events were recorded. In the vicinity of the anomalous formation #1256-XM, a freezing zone of about 5 meters was detected. Inside, the research institute employees found 3 frozen dogs and 4 frozen rats. Field measurements showed that the formation does not emit any radiation, psi effects, and toxic emissions. As a result, a decision was made to place it in a container for transportation and deliver it to Laboratory X-||||||||. When attempting to take a sample with the manipulator's "tongs," the artifact demonstrated active absorption of thermal energy from the surrounding space, resulting in engineer Savin suffering second-degree frostbite on the fingers of his right hand. A robotic manipulator was used for loading the anomalous formation. It is worth mentioning that it partially malfunctioned due to the freezing of lubricating fluids in the pistons. After that, the group arrived at the research center in full composition by 12:30. Savin received medical assistance, and his health is not at risk.

As a result of the initial investigation of the artifact, the following was established:
A) It has an irregular shard-like shape of stone material. It weighs 2.3 kg.
B) It is not radioactive.
C) It is not toxic.
D) It does not exert psi effects.
E) It emits light energy in the range of 440-480 nm (blue).
F) It is endothermic, which is the basis for all its main properties. The temperature difference between the artifact and the surrounding area is -43 degrees Celsius. The intensity of absorption "pulses," and the algorithm of this process cannot be determined. Further research is required.
G) When attempting to interact with it, the heat absorption activity increases.

I propose:
A) Conduct a series of in-depth studies of the anomalous formation according to Scheme A-405.
B) Name the artifact "Monolith Shard," as some laboratory personnel already call it due to its unusual shape. I would like to add that such properties of formations have not been recorded before. We have obtained a fascinating specimen of the interaction of anomalous energy with the environment. The reasons for its appearance are yet to be determined, but it seems to me that we are on the threshold of significant discoveries!
</text>
</string>
	<string id="st_notepad_type_second_3_text">
		<text>From April 11, 2010, to April 16, 2010, after the discovery, delivery, and necessary documentation of the artifact to Laboratory X-||||||||, the following methods of interaction were carried out: A) High-intensity light (laser) B) Chemical (acid, alkali, neutral liquids) C) High-intensity physical (impact, compression, etc.) D) Biological (viruses, living organisms)
Details are provided in the corresponding attachments to this message. Please pay attention to the conclusions, which indicate that any interaction with the artifact triggers its so-called "protective reaction" - it increases the intensity of thermal energy absorption.

I hereby notify you that, in addition to the known properties, the "Monolith Shard" possesses previously unknown psychotropic properties, the effects of which have been observed on the entire laboratory staff and test animals.

Animals (mice, rats, dogs) almost stopped sleeping altogether after the artifact was delivered to the laboratory, and some have already died due to exhaustion. We had to arrange for their containment outside the laboratory in a special facility.

The laboratory staff who had contact with formation №1256-XM have reported the following complaints to the medical staff:
A) General discomfort
B) Poor sleep, characterized by repetitive abstract dreams and nightmares
C) Increased anxiety
D) Heightened excitability
E) Depressed mental state
F) Unexplained sense of fear
G) Obsessive states

As a result, a tense situation has developed in the laboratory. Some of the staff members are willing to leave the facility, terminating their contracts unilaterally, with the loss of annual bonuses and penalty payments.

We are currently facing a difficult situation, with the potential loss of part of the personnel, without which the normal functioning of the laboratory is impossible, leading to its shutdown and equipment evacuation.

Following a comprehensive meeting, we have concluded that it is dangerous to continue housing the anomalous formation in our laboratory. We request that you consider the possibility of transporting it to a laboratory with enhanced protection measures and isolated accommodation for the personnel as soon as possible.

The corresponding documents have been sent to the Transportation Department and addressed to the acting head of the AEZO Research Institute.
.</text>
	</string>	
<string id="ui_mm_osc_s_text">
    <text>Work stages:</text>
</string>
<string id="st_search_pitanie">
    <text>Supply power</text>
</string>
<string id="st_search_vzlom">
    <text>Hack electronic lock</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_help_1">
    <text>?</text>
</string>
<string id="st_menu_rukzak_close">
    <text>Close</text>
</string>
<string id="st_menu_vzl_1_close">
    <text>Finish</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_vzlom_zamka_caption">
    <text>"Electronic hacking scanner"</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_vzl_1_caption">
    <text>"Scanning and frequency conversion"</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_vzl_2_caption">
    <text>"Radio pulse decryption"</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_vzl_3_caption">
    <text>"Source code generation"</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_vzl_use_1">
    <text>Recognition</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_vzl_use_2">
    <text>Decryption</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_vzl_use_3">
    <text>Generation</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_zam_about_use_item_1">
    <text>Description of the first action. Signal recognition. By clicking on the button an identical window will open, in which you need to perform a specific sequence of actions. During the recognition operation it is necessary to scan the signal frequency, pass it through bandpass filters, and determine the carrier frequency of the RF pulse. This value is then passed to the LF converter for preparation for decryption.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_zam_about_use_item_2">
    <text>Description of the second action. Decryption. By clicking on the button an identical window will open, in which you need to perform a specific sequence of actions. During the decryption operation the received LF signal needs to be passed through a set of decryptors. The decrypted values are transmitted in binary code and then passed to the decimal code generator.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_zam_about_use_item_3">
    <text>Description of the third action. Final binary code generation. By clicking on the button an identical window will open, displaying the generated code and providing an input field for the code to be used in the hack. You can simply close this window to finish the operation.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_vzl_use_1_text">
    <text>RF signal passed through the bandpass filter...desired F found...converted to LF signal</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_vzl_use_2_text">
    <text>Primary and secondary decryption performed</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_vzl_use_3_text">
    <text>Electronic code generation completed...lock hacked.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_vzlom_zamka_item_1">
    <text>RF signal filtering:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_vzlom_zamka_item_2">
    <text>LF signal converter:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_vzlom_zamka_item_3">
    <text>LF signal decryption:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_vzlom_zamka_item_4">
    <text>Secondary conversion:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_vzlom_zamka_item_5">
    <text>Generate code sequence:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_vzlom_zamka_item_6">
    <text>Enter the received code:</text>
</string>
<string id="st_vzlom_zamka_1_use_1">
    <text>Solve</text>
</string>
<string id="st_vzlom_zamka_3_use_1">
    <text>Convert</text>
</string>
<string id="st_vzlom_zamka_1_use_3">
    <text>Generate</text>
</string>
<string id="st_vzlom_zamka_1_use_2">
    <text>Hack</text>
</string>
<string id="st_vzlom_zamka_1_close">
    <text>Close</text>
</string>
	
<string id="ui_gui_osc_caption">
    <text>"Oscilloscope C1-65A"</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_osc_s_text">
    <text>Work stages:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_osc_use_1">
    <text>Calibration</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_osc_use_2">
    <text>V/div;T/div</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_osc_use_3">
    <text>Signal</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_osc_use_1_text">
    <text>Video pulse reference parameters: Frequency-1kHz, Amplitude-1.5mV.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_osc_use_2_text">
    <text>Scale: R input-1 MOhm, C input-30 pF; X coefficient-20 V/div, Y coefficient-50ms/div</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_osc_use_3_text">
    <text>Electrical signal form: Sinusoidal, Period-0.2s, Amplitude-20V.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_oszill_1_caption">
    <text>"Calibration"</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_oszill_2_caption">
    <text>"Scaling"</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_oszill_3_caption">
    <text>"Signal"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_menu_oszill_1_use_1">
    <text>Set</text>
</string>
<string id="st_menu_oszill_1_use_2">
    <text>Set</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_oszill_1_item_1">
    <text>Set F = 1000 Hz</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_oszill_1_item_2">
    <text>Set A = 1500 V</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_oszill_2_item_1">
    <text>Set X = 20 V/div</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_oszill_2_item_2">
    <text>Set Y = 50 ms/div</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_osc_about_use_item_1">
    <text>Description of the first action. Calibration. By clicking on the button a window with the same name will open, where you will need to perform a specific sequence of actions. During the calibration operation, you need to enter numerical values of the reference video pulse parameters (Amplitude and Frequency). The data is entered into special fields. The actual values will be specified in the calibration window.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_osc_about_use_item_2">
    <text>Description of the second action. Scaling. By clicking on the button a window with the same name will open, where you will need to perform a specific sequence of actions. During the scaling operation, you need to enter numerical values of the coefficients for the X and Y axes. The data is entered into special fields. The actual values will be specified in the scaling window.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_osc_about_use_item_3">
    <text>Description of the third action. Signal visualization. By clicking on the button a window with the same name will open, where the visualization of the obtained oscilloscope result will be displayed. This window can simply be closed, ending the operation.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_menu_oszill_2_close">
    <text>Stop</text>
</string>
<string id="st_menu_oszill_1_close">
    <text>Apply</text>
</string>
<string id="st_menu_close">
    <text>Close</text>
</string>
<string id="st_menu_stop">
    <text>Stop</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_s_text">
    <text>Select channel:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_use_1">
    <text>Channel 1.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_use_2">
    <text>Channel 2.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_use_3">
    <text>Channel 3.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_use_4">
    <text>Channel 4.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_use_5">
    <text>Channel 5.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_racnpc_1_text">
    <text>Radio frequency:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_1_text">
    <text>Radio frequency range, channel number, and type:</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_npcs_text">
    <text>21.975 MHz</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_s1_text">
    <text>Channel 1; frequency 20.5 MHz; closed by peacekeeping forces.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_s2_text">
    <text>Channel 2; frequency 16.5 MHz; closed by "Duty" group.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_s3_text">
    <text>Channel 3; frequency 11.5 MHz; closed by "Freedom" group.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_s4_text">
    <text>Channel 4; frequency 19.5 MHz; closed by "Mercenary" group.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_s5_text">
    <text>Channel 5; frequency 22.5 MHz; closed by "Monolith" group.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_sq1_text">
    <text>Channel 1; frequency 20.5 MHz.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_sq2_text">
    <text>Channel 2; frequency 16.5 MHz.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_sq3_text">
    <text>Channel 3; frequency 11.5 MHz.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_sq4_text">
    <text>Channel 4; frequency 19.5 MHz.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_mm_rac_sq5_text">
    <text>Channel 5; frequency 22.5 MHz.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_razia_1_hint">
    <text>By clicking the button you will stop its application.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_rac_about_use_item_all">
    <text>By clicking the button, you will tune the radio station to receive signals from the frequency of the first open channel. Switching to a closed channel without special firmware is not possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_rac_about_use_item_1">
    <text>Description of the first action. By clicking the button, you will tune the radio station to receive signals from the frequency of the first closed channel of the peacekeeping forces. To stop reception, you need to press the "Stop" button. Switching to another channel during operation is not possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_rac_about_use_item_2">
    <text>Description of the second action. By clicking the button, you will tune the radio station to receive signals from the frequency of the first closed channel of the "Duty" group. To stop reception, you need to press the "Stop" button. Switching to another channel during operation is not possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_rac_about_use_item_3">
    <text>Description of the third action. By clicking the button, you will tune the radio station to receive signals from the frequency of the first closed channel of the "Freedom" group. To stop reception, you need to press the "Stop" button. Switching to another channel during operation is not possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_rac_about_use_item_4">
    <text>Description of the fourth action. By clicking the button, you will tune the radio station to receive signals from the frequency of the first closed channel of the "Mercenary" group. To stop reception, you need to press the "Stop" button. Switching to another channel during operation is not possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_rac_about_use_item_5">
    <text>Description of the fifth action. By clicking the button, you will tune the radio station to receive signals from the frequency of the first closed channel of the "Monolith" group. To stop reception, you need to press the "Stop" button. Switching to another channel during operation is not possible.</text>
</string>
	
<string id="st_ach_radiobattle_descr_1">
    <text>Level 1. Working with soldering stations. Ability to solder microchips.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ach_radiobattle_descr_4">
    <text>Level 2. Working with radio equipment such as high-frequency radios, oscilloscopes, spectrum analyzers.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ach_radiobattle_descr_2">
    <text>Level 3. Radio electronic intelligence. Studying the principles and basics of radio electronic intelligence, which involves collecting information based on the reception and analysis of electromagnetic radiation.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ach_radiobattle_descr_5">
    <text>Level 4. Radio electronic suppression. Studying the principles and basics of radio electronic suppression, which is achieved through the creation of active and passive interference, the use of false targets, traps.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ach_radiobattle_descr_3">
    <text>Level 5. Radio electronic protection. Studying the principles and basics of radio electronic protection, aimed at ensuring the stable operation of electronic systems in the presence of intentional radio interference.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_radiobattledet1_1_hint">
    <text>For a certain amount of money (1000 rubles), the basics of radio electronic suppression will be studied.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_radiobattledet1_2_hint">
    <text>For a certain amount of money (2500 rubles), the basics of radio electronic protection will be studied.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_radiobattledet1_3_hint">
    <text>For a certain amount of money (2500 rubles), the basics of radio electronic intelligence will be studied.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_radiobattledet1_4_hint">
    <text>For a certain amount of money (5000 rubles), the basics of comprehensive technical control will be studied.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_radiobattledet1_5_hint">
    <text>For a certain amount of money (5000 rubles), the possibility of electromagnetic effects will be studied.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_rpg_attach_1">
    <text>Learn skill 1</text>
</string>
<string id="st_rpg_attach_2">
    <text>Learn skill 2</text>
</string>
<string id="st_rpg_attach_3">
    <text>Learn skill 3</text>
</string>
<string id="st_rpg_attach_4">
    <text>Learn skill 4</text>
</string>
<string id="st_rpg_attach_5">
    <text>Learn skill 5</text>
</string>
<string id="st_radiobattleachiva_form_title">
    <text>Improving EW specialty skills.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_need_precondition_to_use_1">
    <text>Missing the previous skill required to learn this one.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_need_money_to_buy">
    <text>You don't have enough money to perform this operation.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_conventer_juk_title">
    <text>Lukey-853D soldering station</text>
</string>
<string id="st_conventer_detector_title">
    <text>Personal soldering station</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_guk_2_caption">
    <text>Parameter readings</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_guk_1_caption">
    <text>Computational problem</text>
</string>
<string id="st_conventer_guk_attach_use1">
    <text>Computational parameters</text>
</string>
<string id="st_conventer_guk_attach_use4">
    <text>Conversion</text>
</string>
<string id="st_conventer_guk_attach_use2">
    <text>Reference data</text>
</string>
<string id="st_conventer_guk_attach_use3">
    <text>Device soldering</text>
</string>
<string id="st_need_guk1_box_text">
    <text>To create listening devices, you need to have 5 special microchips, 15 capacitors, and 10 inductance coils, each with its own special marking.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_guk_item_1">
    <text>"Initial measured values:"</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_gui_guk_item_2">
    <text>"Accepted calculated parameters:"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_guk_type_one_1_text">
    <text>It is necessary to determine what range of radio waves our radio receiver (beacon) can receive, if the capacitance of its oscillating circuit can vary from 50 pF to 200 pF and the inductance is 50 mGn.\n
If the capacitance of the oscillating circuit is C and the inductance of its coil is L, then the corresponding period of oscillation is calculated by the formula: T=2p(LC)^0.5. Therefore, the frequency n=1/T=1/2p(LC)^0.5 \n Possible range options: \n 93 - 186 kHz. \n 58 - 269 kHz.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_guk_1_use_1">
    <text>Check</text>
</string>
<string id="st_guk_1_use_2">
    <text>Accept</text>
</string>
</string_table>