<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="yan_actor_destroy_wave1">
		<text>Zombie spawn location</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_actor_destroy_wave1_name">
		<text>Do not let zombies near the stalkers on the roof.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_actor_destroy_wave1_text">
		<text>You must cover the stalkers on the roof while they work with the valve installation. Do not let zombies near this repair team.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_actor_destroy_wave2">
		<text>Zombie spawn location</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_actor_destroy_wave2_name">
		<text>Do not let zombies near the stalkers in the hangar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_actor_destroy_wave2_text">
		<text>You must cover the stalkers in the hangar while they work with the valve installation. Do not let zombies near this repair team.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_actor_go_base_defence">
		<text>Defend the scientists' base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_actor_go_base_defence_name">
		<text>Defend the scientists' base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_actor_go_base_defence_text">
		<text>Defend the scientists' base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_actor_go_base_science">
		<text>During the zombie attack, the scientists' bunker doors are locked. You need to repel the zombie attack to enter the bunker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_actor_go_base_science_name">
		<text>Talk to Sakharyov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_actor_go_base_science_text">
		<text>You need to reach the base and talk to Professor Sakharyov.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_actor_go_to_stalker">
		<text>Clarify position</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_actor_go_to_stalker_name">
		<text>Clarify position with the group leader</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_actor_go_to_stalker_text">
		<text>Clarify position with the group leader</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_main_quest_line">
		<text>Do not let the repair team perish</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_main_quest_line_name">
		<text>Hold your position!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_main_quest_line_text">
		<text>Hold your position!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_otnesti_doc_saharavy">
		<text>Take documents to Sakharyov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_otnesti_doc_saharavy_name">
		<text>Take documents to Sakharyov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_otnesti_doc_saharavy_text">
		<text>Take the documents to Sakharyov. They may explain the cause of the strong psi-radiation on the Yantar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_proriv_k_ystanovke">
		<text>Break through to the installation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_proriv_k_ystanovke_name">
		<text>Break through to the complex territory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_proriv_k_ystanovke_text">
		<text>The outskirts of the complex are crawling with zombies. Together with the Lefsha group, you need to break through to its territory. You must hurry: the psi-radiation level could reach a critical level at any moment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_quest_doc">
		<text>Find the documents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_quest_doc_name">
		<text>Find the PDA with the documents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_quest_doc_text">
		<text>A group of stalkers found important documents on the complex's territory that may help Sakharyov figure out the cause of the powerful psi-radiation on Yantar. The group's signal was lost as they exited the complex. You need to find the PDA with the documents.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_quest_levsha">
		<text>Meet with Lefsha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_quest_levsha_name">
		<text>Meet with Lefsha's squad</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_quest_levsha_text">
		<text>The stalker group is preparing to break into the complex during the decline of psi-radiation levels. You need to meet with the squad commander, Lefsha.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_repair_defend">
		<text>Take position on the hangar roof</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_repair_defend_name">
		<text>Follow the stalker to the roof of the hangar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_repair_defend_text">
		<text>Lefsha has ordered everyone to take positions. You need to follow the stalker to the roof to your position.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_recover_item_1_name">
		<text>Bring the "Little Flower"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_recover_item_1_text">
		<text>Help me, mercenary. There's an artifact in the Zone we call "Little Flower". It's useless for stalkers... but women love it so much that any woman would dream of having such a souvenir. With such a gift, any woman will fall for you. I have a date coming up soon, and I desperately need that "Little Flower", that's why I'm still here in the Zone, it was recently seen here. This artifact looks like a magical flower, it glows day and night. Get me that artifact, and I’ll reward you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_recover_item_2_name">
		<text>Return the souvenir grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_recover_item_2_text">
		<text>Mercenary, I need something... I lost a souvenir, it looks like a grenade... but it's not a real grenade... it's a training grenade... Anyway, bring it back to me... When I was roaming the factory grounds, there was a huge explosion... my mind got scrambled, and I almost forgot who I was... I only came to my senses here, and the grenade is probably still there. Bring it back to me.</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
