<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>

<!--
	Medical Items + Drugs
-->

<string_table>
	
	<string id="st_antirad">
    <text>Anti-radiation drug</text>
</string>
<string id="st_antirad_descr">
    <text>Radioprotective drug "Mexamine", widely spread in the Zone. When used, it causes constriction of peripheral blood vessels and oxygen deprivation, which in this case serves as prevention and treatment of radiation sickness. Well tolerated by the vast majority of people. In rare cases: mild nausea, dizziness, pain, less often - vomiting.\n \n        
    %c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] 1 dose removes ~1400 mSv\n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] quick use (syringe)\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_bandage">
    <text>Bandage</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bandage_descr">
    <text>Individual dressing pack for stopping bleeding and preventing infection from entering the wound. In case of light bleeding, it allows you to dress the wound, and in case of heavy bleeding, to compress an artery.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] instantly stops bleeding (1500 ml/min)\n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] first aid item\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] quick use\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_bandage_homemade">
    <text>Homemade Bandage</text>
</string>
<string id="st_bandage_homemade_descr">
    <text>A makeshift bandage made from a piece of cloth, heavily soaked with strong alcohol for disinfection. May help with light bleeding and prevent dirt from entering the wound, but don’t expect much more.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] instantly stops light bleeding (750 ml/min)\n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] first aid item\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] quick use\n
    %c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] low quality\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_drug_coagulant">
    <text>"Barvinok"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_drug_coagulant_descr">
    <text>An improved analogue of Yadulin. Its main effect is increasing blood clotting. Popular among stalkers, as it helps the body heal torn wounds faster. Has a long-lasting effect. Taken as 2 tablets.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 5%\n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
    %c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls mild pain\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_drug_anabiotic">
    <text>Anabiotic</text>
</string>
<string id="st_drug_anabiotic_descr">
    <text>Experimental drug developed for research groups operating in the Zone. Its formula includes tetrodotoxin, known as "zombie powder", which causes complete paralysis of the central nervous system. Presumably, it may allow survival outside cover during an emission. After six years of field trials, most sensible stalkers now keep a couple of these just in case of sudden emissions.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[0,153,255,255] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
    %c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] causes temporary memory lapses\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_drug_psy_blockade">
    <text>"Psy-blockade"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_drug_psy_blockade_descr">
    <text>Narcotic drug that blocks avalanche-like nerve impulses. An interesting side effect: after taking the drug, all emotions briefly disappear. In the Zone, it is used to counter anomalous fields of high psi-activity. Outside, it found no use. Has a long-lasting effect. Taken as 2 tablets.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
    %c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] causes severe dizziness\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_drug_antidot">
    <text>Antidote</text>
</string>
<string id="st_drug_antidot_descr">
    <text>The drug "Antitoxicant IP2" is a complex of antidotes: metoclopramide, pyridoxine, thiamine, riboxin, and others. Introduces into the bloodstream substances capable of breaking down protein toxins, as well as absorbers of synthetic poisons. Not very popular, as most stalkers rely more on gas masks and protective suits. Nevertheless, some stalkers still keep a few packs hidden for emergencies. Has a long-lasting effect. Taken as 1 capsule.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
    %c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] causes mild dizziness\n
    %c[d_green] • %c[ui_gray_2] enhances detoxification 100x for 420 sec\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_drug_booster">
    <text>"Hercules"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_drug_booster_descr">
    <text>The main component is an artificially created steroid, chemically similar to testosterone. Used by stalkers during long treks to raise the fatigue threshold of muscles. Helps significantly increase carried weight. Long-lasting effect.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] drink\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] mild sobering effect\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_drug_radioprotector">
    <text>Radioprotector</text>
</string>
<string id="st_drug_radioprotector_descr">
    <text>Radioprotector "Indralin-B190" was included in the personal first aid kits of nuclear power plant workers. Appeared in the Zone as a replacement for the overly toxic cystamine hydrochloride (RS1). Reduces the effects of gamma radiation on living tissue. It is recommended to use preventively, before exposure, since it does not have an instant effect. Long-lasting. Taken as 1 capsule.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
    %c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] mild dizziness\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_akvatab">
    <text>"Aquatabs"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_akvatab_descr">
    <text>A small plastic pack of tablets designed to disinfect water from harmful bacteria, viruses, and radiation. Taken as 2 tablets. Despite its intended use, some stalkers in emergencies ingest it to remove radiation when there’s no other alternative.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] 1 dose removes ~190 mSv\n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] slow use (dissolving tablets)\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_medkit_ai1">
    <text>Medical Kit (Basic)</text>
</string>
<string id="st_medkit_ai1_descr">
    <text>A medical kit containing drugs for treating minor injuries. The total value of the drugs in this set is estimated at about fifteen thousand.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CONTENTS:\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Bandage (2)\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Tourniquet\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Yadulin\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Tetanus vaccine\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Small glucose injection\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Diclofenac sodium\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Chlortetracycline\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Sulfadimethoxine\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Homemade stimpack\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Aquatabs\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] set of medications\n
    </text>
</string>

	
	<string id="st_medkit_ai2">
    <text>Medical Kit (Army)</text>
</string>
<string id="st_medkit_ai2_descr">
    <text>Army medical kit containing a large number of stimulating medications. Allows dealing with various types and degrees of injuries: wounds, burns, poisonings. The total value of the drugs in this set is estimated at about thirty-seven thousand.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CONTENTS:\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Bandage (3)\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Tourniquet (2)\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Homemade stimpack\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Large glucose injection\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Ampoule of metamizole\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Barvinok\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Potassium iodide\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Cystamine\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Etperazin\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Tablets 027-R\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Caffeine tablets\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Ampoule of morphine\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Military stimulator\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] set of medications\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_medkit_ai3">
    <text>Medical Kit (Scientific)</text>
</string>
<string id="st_medkit_ai3_descr">
    <text>A medical kit assembled specifically for scientific personnel working in the Zone. Contains a wide range of drugs aimed at prevention and protection against radiation, chemical and psi threats. The total value of the drugs in this set is estimated at about forty-nine thousand.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CONTENTS:\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Bandage (3)\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Tourniquet (3)\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Anti-radiation drug\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Radioprotector\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Antidote\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Psy-blockade\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Adrenaline\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Military stimulator\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Scientific stimulator\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Anabiotic\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Hercules\n
    %c[d_cyan] • %c[default] Large glucose injection\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] set of medications\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_analgetic">
    <text>Diclofenac Sodium</text>
</string>
<string id="st_analgetic_descr">
    <text>Non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drug (NSAID) from the group of phenylacetic acid derivatives. Its mechanism of action consists in dulling nerve activity. Due to the huge number of side effects – such as headache, dizziness, drowsiness, in some cases memory disorders, disorientation, irritability – it is not used for medical purposes in most countries. However, in the Zone it gained popularity because of its side effect: suppression of CNS sensitivity, which allows enduring severe injuries such as gunshot and shrapnel wounds.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 15%\n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
    %c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls moderate pain\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_jgut_zhgut">
    <text>Medical Tourniquet</text>
</string>
<string id="st_jgut_descr">
    <text>Hemostatic rubber tourniquet. Applied to the injured limb in case of severe bleeding. Judging by its appearance, it’s quite old and worn, as microcracks have already formed on the rubber. This clearly indicates a high probability of it snapping even after just one or two uses.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] instantly stops heavy bleeding (3750 ml/min)\n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] first aid item\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] quick use\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_yadylin">
    <text>Yadulin</text>
</string>
<string id="st_yadylin_descr">
    <text>A remedy created in the Zone that accelerates recovery by boosting metabolism. Popular among stalkers, as it improves condition through a mild pain-relieving effect and is the most accessible, albeit weak, regeneration drug. Rumors say that an unknown group of stalker-chemists managed to synthesize it from mutant bodies. Be that as it may, the active substance of this remedy speeds up recovery, although it is toxic.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 5%\n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
    %c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls mild pain\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_medkit">
    <text>First Aid Kit</text>
</string>
<string id="st_medkit_descr">
    <text>General-purpose medical kit. Includes painkillers, a regeneration drug, tetanus vaccine, and glucose. Despite containing an outdated tissue regeneration drug, this kit is still popular due to its availability. It is not very useful in combat, but is good for healing wounds in a calm environment. The active substances in this kit cause a significant buildup of toxins in the body, so it should not be used often.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 10%\n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] general-purpose use\n
    %c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] slow use (field kit)\n
    %c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls very mild pain\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_medkit_army">
    <text>Army First Aid Kit</text>
</string>
<string id="st_medkit_army_descr">
    <text>Specialized medical kit developed by scientists for soldiers serving in the Zone of Alienation. Unlike the common general-purpose kit, this one includes more modern and effective drugs. This allows faster recovery after various injuries. Despite the improved regeneration formula, using the kit still causes intoxication of the body.\n \n
    %c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 15%\n
    %c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
    %c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military item\n
    %c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] slow use (field kit)\n
    %c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls mild pain\n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="st_medkit_science">
	<text>Scientific Medkit</text>
</string>
<string id="st_medkit_science_descr">
	<text>The most advanced medical kit, containing the best drugs for rapid rehabilitation after various types of injuries. The regenerative drug in this kit has been improved, reducing toxicity and enhancing the body's recovery capabilities.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 20%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high value\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high quality\n
	%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] slow use (field kit)\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls moderate pain\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_glucose_s">
	<text>Small Glucose Injection</text>
</string>
<string id="st_glucose_s_descr">
	<text>The glucose injection is used in severe diabetes cases - hypoglycemia. Stalkers, however, use it as a stimulant – the instant increase in carbohydrates quickly boosts energy and strength.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 5%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast use (syringe)\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_glucose">
	<text>Large Glucose Injection</text>
</string>
<string id="st_glucose_descr">
	<text>The glucose injection is used in severe diabetes cases - hypoglycemia. Stalkers use it as a stimulant – the instant carbohydrate boost rapidly increases energy and strength. Contains a higher dose of the drug.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 10%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast use (syringe)\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_stim_impro">
	<text>Improvised Stimpak</text>
</string>
<string id="st_stim_impro_descr">
	<text>Improvised stimulants (stimpaks) are very popular among novice stalkers because they are easy to obtain and relatively cheap. Made from widely available Zone ingredients without proper purification or specialized equipment, which causes strong intoxication and dizziness when used. High doses of the regenerative drug allow wounds to heal visibly fast. The included painkiller lets you continue fighting despite injuries. Rapid metabolism consumes huge amounts of nutrients, greatly increasing hunger.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 10%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast use (syringe)\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls very mild pain\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_stim_military">
	<text>Military Stimulant</text>
</string>
<string id="st_stim_military_descr">
	<text>Military stimulants (stimpaks) are standard issue equipment for operations in the Exclusion Zone. In reality, regular soldiers rarely get them. They are fairly common on the market and can be purchased at a moderate price. Popular among experienced stalkers, as they are far more potent and fast-acting than improvised versions, ideal for dangerous situations. Despite careful production and refined composition, they remain fairly toxic and may cause side effects, including hunger. Used to treat various injuries in dangerous conditions and to relieve pain, allowing wounded fighters to quickly get back on their feet.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 20%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] military grade\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast use (syringe)\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] moderate health recovery\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls mild pain\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_stim_scientic">
	<text>Experimental Scientific Stimulant</text>
</string>
<string id="st_stim_scientic_descr">
	<text>Produced by the same Chemical Department in Kyiv that developed the famous "SEVA" suit. This stimulant is the most powerful health stabilizer available in the Zone. Top-quality ingredients and an improved formula allow for quick health recovery. Side effects are minimal. Extremely expensive, so only very lucky and successful stalkers use it. Compared to other similar drugs, it is the least toxic.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 30%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high quality\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast use (syringe)\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] rapid health recovery\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls moderate pain\n
	</text>
</string>

	
	<string id="st_sleepingpills">
	<text>Pills 027-R</text>
</string>
<string id="st_sleepingpills_descr">
	<text>A small pack of Alprazolam tablets, 0.25 mg each. This drug is well-known among chemists and pharmacists for its properties that help treat and prevent panic disorders, depression, and anxiety neuroses. An essential item for stalkers exploring dangerous areas like the "Yantar" factory, the Radar, or Red Forest, or when venturing into secret laboratories. Side effects include strong drowsiness after use. For this reason, some stalkers prefer to carry simple caffeine tablets. Best taken with water.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_cocaine">
	<text>Cocaine</text>
</string>
<string id="st_cocaine_descr">
	<text>A small aluminum case containing doses of cocaine and injection tools. Cocaine is a powerful nervous system stimulant. Its effect lasts 15–30 minutes up to an hour, depending on the injection site. Cocaine increases alertness, well-being, euphoria, energy, prolonged activity, a sense of competence, and sexuality. Physical strength may increase in sports requiring sustained attention and endurance. Anxiety, paranoia, and restlessness are common side effects. Overdoses may cause tremors, convulsions, and elevated body temperature. Bandits often sniff it right before raiding bases and camps.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 20%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] stimulant\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] very strong sobering effect\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls very strong pain\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_adrenalin">
	<text>Epinephrine</text>
</string>
<string id="st_adrenalin_descr">
	<text>Epinephrine (also known as adrenaline) is both a hormone and a neurotransmitter. Epinephrine performs multiple functions in the body: it instantly regulates heart rate, dilates blood vessels to improve airflow, and triggers metabolic shifts. Released during the fight-or-flight response from the sympathetic nervous system. Effects include increased blood glucose and fatty acids, providing immediate substrates for energy production across cells.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 15%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high quality\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast use (syringe)\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] very strong sobering effect\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls strong pain\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_morphine">
	<text>Morphine Ampule</text>
</string>
<string id="st_morphine_descr">
	<text>A metal ampule for instant pain relief, designed as a field tech item for soldiers. Contains a powerful dose of morphine. In clinical medicine, morphine is the gold standard opioid analgesic, used to relieve severe and excruciating pain. Like other opioids such as oxycodone, hydromorphone, and diacetylmorphine (heroin), morphine acts directly on the CNS to ease pain perception. Administer into arm or thigh.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 50%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high quality\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast use (syringe)\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls very strong pain\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_salicidic_acid">
	<text>Metamizole Ampule</text>
</string>
<string id="st_salicidic_acid_descr">
	<text>A metal ampule for instant pain relief, designed as a field tech item for soldiers. Metamizole is one of the strongest nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs), especially effective for severe pain and fever. Also useful as an anti-inflammatory in high doses. Administer into arm or thigh.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 30%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast use (syringe)\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls strong pain\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_caffeine">
	<text>Caffeine Tablets</text>
</string>
<string id="st_caffeine_descr">
	<text>Caffeine and sodium benzoate, which make the nervous system operate at maximum efficiency. Significantly reduces drowsiness. Take 2 tablets at a time.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] stimulant\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] strong sobering effect\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_antirad_cystamine">
	<text>Cystamine</text>
</string>
<string id="st_antirad_cystamine_descr">
	<text>Cystamine dihydrochloride. Helps cope with the negative effects of ionizing radiation on the body. Works by binding free radicals, ionized and excited molecules formed in tissues during exposure. Medically used as dihydrochloride.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] 1 dose removes ~700 mSv\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] imported\n
	%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] slight dizziness\n
	</text>
</string>

	
<string id="st_antibio_sulfad">
	<text>Sulfadimethoxine</text>
</string>
<string id="st_antibio_sulfad_descr">
	<text>Long-acting sulfonamide drug. Effective against gram-positive and gram-negative bacteria: acts on pneumococci, streptococci, staphylococci, E. coli, Klebsiella (Friedl?nder bacillus), dysentery pathogens; less active against Proteus; active against chlamydia virus (an infectious eye disease that can lead to blindness); does not affect bacterial strains resistant to other sulfonamide drugs. Possible side effects include headache, digestive disorders, skin rashes, drug-induced fever, and leukopenia (decreased white blood cells).\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 5%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_antibio_chlor">
	<text>Chlortetracycline</text>
</string>
<string id="st_antibio_chlor_descr">
	<text>A tetracycline-class antibiotic. Golden-yellow crystalline powder, bitter taste, water-soluble. One of the first antibiotics discovered after penicillin. Chlortetracycline hydrochloride has a bacteriostatic effect on gram-positive and gram-negative microbes, rickettsiae, and some large viruses.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 3%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_antiemetic">
	<text>Etperazine</text>
</string>
<string id="st_antiemetic_descr">
	<text>Coated tablets containing 4, 6, and 10 mg of perphenazine. This drug is a neuroleptic – an antipsychotic with anti-allergic, sedative, muscle-relaxing, antiemetic, mild anticholinergic, hypotensive, and hypothermic effects. Its effectiveness comes from blocking D2 receptors in the mesocortical and mesolimbic systems. In the Zone, it is used as a cheap antidote substitute.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] anti-poison medication\n
	%c[d_green] • %c[ui_gray_2] enhances detoxification 50x for 420 sec\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_joint">
	<text>Joint</text>
</string>
<string id="st_joint_descr">
	<text>Several joints in a cigarette pack. Thanks to its calming effect, it is quite popular among stalkers often exposed to psi-radiation. The joint calms nerves and helps to relax for a while. Combined with alcohol, it has an excellent calming effect. Causes hunger. Rumor has it that the Freedom faction has repeatedly managed victories in battle by smoking a joint just before combat, despite disadvantages.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 8%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] stimulant\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] made in the Zone\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] slight drowsiness\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls mild pain\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_rebirth">
	<text>“Rebirth” Narcotic Analgesic</text>
</string>
<string id="st_rebirth_descr">
	<text>This drug was developed somewhere in the Zone’s laboratories and acts as a powerful stimulator, triggering rapid tissue regeneration and strongly dulling pain. The first effect of this potent substance is loss of consciousness. However, upon regaining awareness (if at all), the user experiences a huge surge of strength and invulnerability. Warning! The drug is highly toxic, so do not use it with other stimulants, as it can cause rapid death from severe intoxication.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 30%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast use (syringe)\n
	%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] causes temporary memory gaps\n
	%c[d_purple] • %c[ui_gray_2] dulls strong pain\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_tetanus">
	<text>Tetanus Vaccine</text>
</string>
<string id="st_tetanus_descr">
	<text>The tetanus vaccine contains inactivated tetanus toxins to help prevent infection. Tetanus, also known as “lockjaw,” is caused by Clostridium bacteria entering through open wounds and producing the tetanospasmin toxin. It is potentially fatal as the toxin blocks nerve signals from the spinal cord to muscles. All animals and mutants in the Exclusion Zone carry Clostridium bacteria, which can be transmitted to stalkers via bites. The vaccine boosts immune defense without side effects. It also contains additional antitoxins to expand its use beyond tetanus treatment.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 5%\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] fast use (syringe)\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_antirad_kalium">
	<text>Potassium Iodide</text>
</string>
<string id="st_antirad_kalium_descr">
	<text>Pharmacological action: replenishes iodine deficiency, anti-thyroid, mucolytic, expectorant, antifungal, resorptive, radioprotective. In the Zone, it is used as a cheap alternative to radioprotective drugs. Has several side effects, including digestive disturbances, headaches, and thyroid function disruption.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] medication\n
	%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] slight dizziness\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="st_marijuana">
	<text>Marijuana</text>
</string>
<string id="st_marijuana_descr">
	<text>Homegrown hashish in a bag. Smoking weed is a popular pastime in the Zone, especially among Freedom faction fighters guarding the Barrier. In the Exclusion Zone, marijuana can be bought in bulk. Some believe it helps maintain mental balance and resist psi effects. With a piece of paper, you can roll several joints from this bag.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] helps relax\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] can roll a joint with paper\n
	%c[d_red] • %c[ui_gray_2] must roll the joint to smoke\n
	</text>
</string>

<string id="a_st_survival_kit">
	<text>Emergency Medical Kit</text>
</string>
<string id="a_st_survival_kit_descr">
	<text>A kit for providing medical aid in emergency conditions. Includes a powerful regeneration stimulator and epinephrine, capable of instantly getting a person back on their feet. Also contains a tourniquet to stop severe bleeding and threads to suture deep wounds.\n \n
	%c[ui_gray_3]HEALTH:\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] improves condition by 25%\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] instantly stops severe bleeding (15000 ml/min)\n
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] heals any injuries at 25%/sec for 5 sec\n
	%c[ui_gray_3]CHARACTERISTICS:\n		
	%c[d_blue] • %c[ui_gray_2] high quality\n
	</text>
</string>

	
</string_table>
