<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="scf_deshift_item_desc">
    <text>Anomalous field decoder. Can be used to close a spatial bubble.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Developed by scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_deshift_item_name">
    <text>Decoder</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_sxema_gauss_desc">
    <text>Old schematics describing the components required to assemble the secret weapon "GAUSS". An experienced technician could probably figure this out.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Military development.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_sxema_gauss_name">
    <text>Assembly Scheme «№62»</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_n16_prorok_zapis_desc">
    <text>Addressed to mercenary Jackal:\nJackal... Your people are completely incompetent at their work, got it? My people will soon arrive at the village - and no electronic transmitters! Communicate via carrier pigeons, understood?! I pay you not for eavesdropping! Damn it, you fought, you know what info leaks mean!? Anyway, put more people guarding the basement. I’m leaving a spare keycard here, the note too, forget it, it’ll get lost… My people will approach you through the factory from nearby. Until then, make sure the keycard is securely protected, understood!? Oh, and… "Pendeho" is still alive. Means your bruisers aren’t professionals… He’ll come for me. It’s just a matter of time. So, just delay him as much as possible and try not to die!\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Prophet's personal item.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_prorok_zapis_name">
    <text>Prophet's Notebook</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_n16_wood_key_desc">
    <text>The key has a tag with the letter "P".\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Jackal's personal item.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_wood_key_name">
    <text>Key «P»</text>
</string>

<string id="cld_systemarmor_cardkey_desc">
    <text>Security system keycard. Can be used to forcibly disable the complex's self-destruction protocol.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Developed by scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="cld_systemarmor_cardkey_name">
    <text>Keycard «SB»</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_d3_cardkey_desc">
    <text>Access card for the underground "Collider" complex.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Military development.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d3_cardkey_name">
    <text>Keycard «COLLIDER»</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_v1_box_key_desc">
    <text>A type of key used to open his personal safe...\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Jackal's development.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_box_key_name">
    <text>Special Key «Jackal»</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_v1_shakal_pda_desc">
    <text>Mercenary leader’s PDA. Contains one recent sent message from the user:\n"Fabricat, take four fighters with you and grab a sniper from the warehouse. I warned you - 'Mech' will give the go-ahead. Stalkers started hanging around the church, and one of them clearly saw us last night in the village. They mustn’t get into our business with the Prophet, but they’ll try to see what we’re hiding. By any means necessary - don’t let them reach the basement, understood? Go there fast."\nSome code is also in the files:\n%c[255,248,153,26]7253871\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Carrier's personal item.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_shakal_pda_name">
    <text>PDA «Jackal»</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_n17_merc_pda_desc">
    <text>Mercenary PDA, belonging to a group that ambushed us in the village. Everything is cleared, only one read message from "Jackal" remains:\n"1. Fabricat, take four fighters with you and grab a sniper from the warehouse. I warned you - 'Mech' will give the go-ahead. Stalkers started hanging around the church, and one of them clearly saw us last night in the village. They mustn’t get into our business with the Prophet, but they’ll try to see what we’re hiding. By any means necessary - don’t let them reach the basement, understood? Go there fast."\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Carrier's personal item.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n17_merc_pda_name">
    <text>PDA «Fabricat»</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_item_memory_module_2_dsc">
    <text>Memory module found under an unmanned reconnaissance drone. Lyosha "Digger" dried and unlocked the module, revealing the data collected by the scout: among other things, it contains 4 bearings for radio beacons.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_item_memory_module_2_txt">
    <text>Memory Module (Unlocked)</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_item_memory_module_dsc">
    <text>Memory module found under an unmanned reconnaissance drone. Despite the carrier crashing into the river, the module works – but unfortunately, it is locked.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_item_memory_module_txt">
    <text>Memory Module (Locked)</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_glori_pribor_dsc">
    <text>This device should scan psi-radiation in the waterpark. How to use it – no idea, but fortunately, Gloria will handle it.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Developed by scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_pribor_txt">
    <text>Scanning Device</text>
</string>

<string id="chu_k6_kompromat_dsc">
    <text>A collection of evidence about sectarians’ activities in the Zone.\nIncludes data about camps and bases of these fanatics.\nPhoto reports, recorded conversations, and other materials regarding human trafficking and organ trade on the black market.\nAlso contains information about their plans, routes, and connections outside the Zone.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Highly classified documentation.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_k6_kompromat_txt">
    <text>Compromising Material on Sectarians</text>
</string>


	<string id="chu_letter_prorok_item_dsc">
    <text>Install that contraption we stole from the Radar lab on the church roof. Seems like it really messes with the brain, hehe... Some might drop immediately, but... With it, we will recruit new followers!\nP.S. Your beloved father, Prophet.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Prophet's personal item.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_letter_prorok_item_txt">
    <text>Prophet's Note</text>
</string>

<string id="chu_a2_ecologs_pda_desc">
    <text>Latest audio messages:\n1. Very interesting landscape... Many anomalous jumps recorded from the church. They seem to have a psi-emission effect, but why?! Continuing to explore, but we won’t enter yet; need to check surroundings first and see what our device shows.\n2. Oddities abound nearby... One of the assistants starts seeing strange things; I think it’s time to pack up and return to Professor Bernade. Further experiments are too dangerous. But… the second assistant seems altered, never was aggressive - I knew this person well. Most likely psi-emission! Must leave immediately, pack the devices and return. Assistant, what are you doing, stop!\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Carrier's personal item.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a2_ecologs_pda_name">
    <text>PDA «Pheromone»</text>
</string>

<string id="chu_a2_scanner_psy_item_desc">
    <text>Detector scanner designed to locate various anomalous psi-waves.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Property of scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a2_scanner_psy_item_name">
    <text>Anti-Psi-Emitter Device</text>
</string>

<string id="nii_e55_noo_docs_item_desc">
    <text>Secret schematics for installing and activating an artificially created anomalous shard P-24 - "NOO-spherical shard".\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Property of the Research Institute.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e55_noo_docs_item_name">
    <text>Secret Documents</text>
</string>

<string id="kan_a3_barge_pda_desc">
    <text>Latest audio message:\nMessage:\nThe devil made me leave the "Freedom complex"... Heard in the bar about the canyon, ha! And the rumors about this place are something. No anomalies, no artifacts... Silence. I thought they just fenced off the "tasty" location. But it turns out... they wanted to fence off from the creature that lives here. The forest is indeed quiet...\nBut those tentacles, piercing gaze and... The size of that bloodsucker really scared me! They call such mutants "Strongheads", right? The oldest and most dangerous of their kind. And their size is rare, can be counted on fingers. Ha-ha...\n*coughing turns into vomiting*.\n%c[default]That howl is unbearable, I need a bandage and splint, tie my leg, and somehow limp to the stalkers, to safety... But seems not meant to be... I hear its steps... Getting closer...\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Carrier's personal item.</text>
</string>
<string id="kan_a3_barge_pda_name">
    <text>PDA «Baron»</text>
</string>

<string id="st_mod_biografi_prorok_doc_text">
    <text>In 1999, moved from Spain to Belarus (17 years old).\nIn 2004, moved to Russia (22 years old).\nIn 2006, noosphere explosion occurred in the Zone.\n2007 (25 years old) - 2009 (27 years old) fought in the Chechen war.\n2009-2016 lived in a Khrushchyovka in Bryansk. Practically idle, used drugs, served two years for robbery, drank heavily and barely made ends meet.\nEarly 2017 received a contract in the Zone.\n2018 took Soldier and Macho as partners, went into the Zone.\n2018-2020 attempted to create his own group, without success.\n2021-2023, thanks to connections with trader Garrota and Lieutenant Potapenko, founded his own sect, starting first kidnappings, stalker tortures, etc.\n2023-2024 Sect gains notoriety in the Zone; ordinary stalkers avoid them, sect consolidates power, and Prophet loses his sanity.\nCurrently approximately 42 years old.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_biograf_doc_prorok_item_txt">
    <text>Biographical Document</text>
</string>

<string id="okr2_p3_prorok_item_flesh_dsc">
    <text>Flash drive found in a safe near the stalkers' camp. May contain something useful.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Important investigation item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_p3_prorok_item_flesh_txt">
    <text>Flash Drive from Safe</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_u28_safe_container_desc">
    <text>Box is locked with a sophisticated mechanism. Judging by its weight and rattling, something is inside. Could be sold, but maybe it contains something interesting...\nA skilled technician is needed to unlock it.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Technician-use item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u28_safe_container_name">
    <text>Locked "Freedom" Container</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_acces_card_sanatorii_dsc">
    <text>With this keycard I can access a secret metro station under the sanatorium.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Important item to open path to the sanatorium station.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_acces_card_sanatorii_txt">
    <text>Keycard «M-6»</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_u18_pda_dsc">
    <text>Freedom fighter PDA. Last message from Garrota:\nMessage:\nGrey, don’t fail. This soldier, Voland, must die quietly without witnesses. I left a note on my desk with the coordinates of the meeting place. He’ll come there at night, I’ll mark the location in your PDA. Kill him and take the envelope. Bring it to me; payment will be arranged on site.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Carrier's personal item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u18_pda_txt">
    <text>PDA «Grey»</text>
</string>

<string id="und_u15_convert_dsc">
    <text>Envelope given to me by Tesak in exchange for the case.\nContents must remain intact and delivered to the trader.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Important item for trader Garrota.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u15_convert_txt">
    <text>Envelope for «Garrota»</text>
</string>

<string id="und_prorok_item_flesh_dsc">
    <text>Flash drive found in the hand of an old decayed corpse in the chamber bed at the "Lucky Ones" bar. May contain something useful.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Important investigation item.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_prorok_item_flesh_txt">
    <text>Corpse Flash Drive</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_b54_reker_pda_dsc">
    <text>Mercenary PDA. Contains coordinates of a stash and a message from someone named Markus.\nMessage:\nToday we’ll make a big deal with the bandits, I marked the meeting place. Hurry to the point, I’m waiting for you there!\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Carrier's personal item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_reker_pda_txt">
    <text>PDA «Reker»</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_r5_item_fleshka_dsc">
    <text>Flash drive of a sectarian giving a speech at the sanatorium. May contain something useful.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Important investigation item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r5_item_fleshka_txt">
    <text>Flash Drive "Monk"</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_a5_vagon_item_case_dsc">
    <text>High-tech container, protected from tampering, fire, and drops. Contents likely very important to deliver intact.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Item for the deal between Garrota and Tesak.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_vagon_item_case_txt">
    <text>Case «Garrota»</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_okr_r5_monah_zapiska_dsc">
    <text>The sheet marks a secret underground path leading to the metro under the sanatorium. Mentions a key to open the "Gates". Also contains a note...\nNote:\nDo not harm the errant servant, feed and water him. I will be at our hideout soon, meanwhile - pray, they will come for him soon.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Important investigation item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_okr_r5_monah_zapiska_txt">
    <text>Sectarian Note with Map</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_pda_dyadi_sema_dsc">
    <text>Contains a fresh recording.\nMessage:\nOh my god! I fly straight from America, but ended up in the Bermuda triangle! What is it, where am I? Don’t understand!? Ahhh!\nRecording ends abruptly.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Carrier's personal item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_pda_dyadi_sema_txt">
    <text>PDA «Sam»</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_dizel_instruments_dsc">
    <text>Box of wrenches, spanners, combination tools. Good set for vehicle repairs.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Item for a skilled mechanic.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_dizel_instruments_txt">
    <text>Tool Set</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_s1_item_black_box_dsc">
    <text>Black box found on a plane. Technician needed to unlock and access its data.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Item for technician unlocking.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_s1_item_black_box_txt">
    <text>Flight Recorder</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_s1_item_key_dsc">
    <text>Seems this key can open something on the plane.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Item for unlocking a box.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_s1_item_key_txt">
    <text>Plane Key</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_v3_item_acces_card_dsc">
    <text>Apparently this access card can open doors in the underground complex «V-3».\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Item for opening doors.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_v3_item_acces_card_txt">
    <text>Keycard «V-3»</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_c4_medalion_sekta_dsc">
    <text>Seems like they wear this as a badge of distinction.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Important investigation item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c4_medalion_sekta_txt">
    <text>Sectarian Medallion</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_a5_unblock_pda_dsc">
    <text>This PDA belongs to my brother.\nMessage:\nWe are surrounded... I can’t comprehend how so many of them appeared! They overwhelm us by numbers, they are insane! Charging straight at us, fists, knives, and bullets... Feels like they fear nothing, damn! They are maniacs, no doubt... Retreating to the school, no choice, too many of them.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Carrier's personal item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_unblock_pda_txt">
    <text>PDA Nikita</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_a5_case_art_dsc">
    <text>The nature and properties of this thing are unknown; to learn what kind of artifact it is, one should consult the scientists.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Unknown anomalous item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_case_art_txt">
    <text>Cluster of Chemicals</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_s1_instrum_desc">
    <text>This set is needed by the technician in the camp. With it, he can open the case I brought him.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Technician's item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_s1_instrum_name">
    <text>Technician's Tools</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_c4_item_case_dsc">
    <text>There’s something inside, but the box has a very sophisticated lock.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Important investigation item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c4_item_case_txt">
    <text>Locked Case</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_c4_item_flesh_dsc">
    <text>This flash drive may contain useful information, just need a computer to check its contents.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Important investigation item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c4_item_flesh_txt">
    <text>Sectarian Flash Drive</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_c4_item_pda_dsc">
    <text>The owner locked it, maybe it contained something important.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Carrier's personal item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c4_item_pda_txt">
    <text>Locked PDA</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_c4_doki_info_dsc">
    <text>Military report, apparently for a superior officer. Nothing useful for me in these papers.\n%c[226,90,0,255]• %c[default]Important investigation item.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c4_doki_info_txt">
    <text>Report</text>
</string>


</string_table>
