<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_prorok_death_false_scenario_txt">
    <text>The Prophet is still alive. His plans are pure madness, enough to terrify anyone who knew him even slightly… Soon, his schemes could bring disaster upon all of humanity. Only Voland had the strength to stop him…</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_prorok_death_true_scenario_txt">
    <text>The Prophet is dead. He will harm no one anymore. Voland fought hard to put an end to this sectarian once and for all. Without their leader, the sectarians quickly fell apart, and the Zone became a little calmer… for now.</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_mtrs_kill_prorok_bad_txt">
    <text>Voland killed the Prophet… but his soul remained heavy. He had lost his own brother and comrades, and the metro explosion buried everyone under the rubble. Voland, Kovalsky, and the rest of the team survived, but the memory of that day would haunt them forever…</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_danya_good_txt">
    <text>The local trader, known as "Danya White," eventually launched his own expedition to study anomalous mushrooms, the same ones he once discovered alongside Voland in the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone. Rumor has it that scientists actively collaborate with him, providing sponsors for his research and resources for future discoveries.</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_voland_dream_good_txt">
    <text>Katrin… the girl from Voland’s dreams, was actually one of his former partners on a mission during which he partially lost his memory. She died saving Voland’s life. Thanks to Oleg restoring this memory fragment, he finally remembers everything…</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_voland_dream_bad_txt">
    <text>The girl from Voland’s dreams left only her name: Katrin. Who she really was and why she appeared to Oleg remains a mystery, lingering like a shadow in his thoughts.</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_kvant_good_txt">
    <text>The former sectarian, known as Quantum, vanished from the Zone. No one saw him again. Thanks to the compromising material Voland provided, he negotiated with the military and quietly left the ChEZ. What became of him after that is unknown…</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_afina_good_txt">
    <text>Athena completed her research on the underground laboratory, with Voland joining her expedition. She delivered the findings and secret documents to the research institute, earning a permanent position and securing a promising career ahead.</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_bes_and_lexa_good_txt">
    <text>The diggers "Lyokha" and "Bes" established their own camp in the village of Zalesye, thanks to Voland. They organized a new expedition into the underground catacombs, discovering rare artifacts that had never been documented before, expanding knowledge of the Zone’s secrets.</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_bernada_good_txt">
    <text>With Voland’s help, Professor Bernada studied psi-radiation in the old water park. His research unveiled the true nature of these paranormal phenomena, eventually leading to the discovery of a new technology capable of probing the afterlife itself…</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_doki_bad_txt">
    <text>The documents Voland stole from the research institute fell into the Prophet’s hands. With this knowledge, the sectarians gained access to a secret noosphere project capable of devastating humanity…</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_2_good_txt">
    <text>Voland saved his younger brother Nikita. At last, he could retire peacefully, enjoy his long-overdue vacation, sip strong cognac, and watch the sunset over the sea, free from worry.</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_2_bad_txt">
    <text>Voland couldn’t save his younger brother Nikita…</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_2_xz_txt">
    <text>Nikita’s fate remains unknown… Is he alive? No one will ever know.</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_sherif_good_txt">
    <text>The Sheriff survived. He finally decided to leave the Zone behind. Now, he holds a high-ranking position at the research institute, heading its militarized security division.</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_sherif_bad_txt">
    <text>The Sheriff died. He tried his best to save Nikita, but the sectarians showed no mercy.</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_sherif_xz_txt">
    <text>The Sheriff’s fate after being captured by the sectarians remains unknown… Most likely, the Zone claimed him, as it has with so many of Voland’s friends.</text>
</string>

<string id="choice_atribut_mod_outro_1_phrase_1_txt">
    <text>Time to summarize…</text>
</string>


</string_table>
