<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_0">
        <text>Well, well… Hello, stranger. Who are you, and what brings you into this hellhole?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_1">
        <text>Your buddy looks half-dead. Not gonna give him a hand?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_10">
        <text>Heard some scientists were sniffing around here last week. Then, like always—showed up, poked around, and vanished without a trace. Overheard Professor Bernady blabbing about it. They had some gizmo for scanning psi-emissions, came here to check out this “cursed church.” That device could help us track the poltergeist inside, maybe even fry the bastard. There’s also a strange glow upstairs in the church… bet that’s where it’s nesting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_11">
        <text>So… you want me to handle it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_12">
        <text>Yeah, I know—some random guy begging you to bail out us poor diggers. Can’t deal with this myself right now. I’ll patch Lyokha up with a couple stims, but you—go scout the place, see if you can dig up anything on those missing eggheads. If we get their gadget, we’ve got a chance. Just watch your step out there. I’ll have Lyokha back on his feet by the time you’re back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_13">
        <text>And where am I supposed to look for this device?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_14">
        <text>Somewhere close, has to be. They disappeared around here, and no one’s seen ’em since. Wish I had more to go on… sorry. Help us out and I’ll make it worth your while—best I can do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_15">
        <text>Alright… I’ll check around.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_2">
        <text>He’ll live. Took a hit to the chest, that’s all. We’ll get to that later. Name’s Bes, I’m a digger. This here’s Lyokha, and Max. Maybe you ran into Arthur on your way here… only Lyokha and I made it out. Walked into some freak anomaly when we scouted the church. So, who the hell are *you*?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_3">
        <text>Voland.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_4">
        <text>That’s it? Not much of a talker, huh? Fair enough… At least you didn’t step inside the church. That thing in there would’ve torn you to pieces. Guess I kinda saved your hide without even trying. Don’t thank me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_44">
        <text>That’s it? Playing it close to the vest, huh? Climbing into that church after I warned you… That anomaly in there would’ve eaten you alive. I tried to keep you breathing, but you didn’t listen.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_5">
        <text>So what’s the deal here? What are you guys after?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_6">
        <text>Could ask you the same, Voland. We’re diggers—we poke around ruins, looking for anything worth a damn. Rumor says there are catacombs under this church. Can’t say for sure yet. As for what’s happening here… some kind of ghost, or worse, is holed up inside. No clue how it got here. Locals say the priest was a real psycho—dragged people underground during sermons or confessions. Fits the Zone, doesn’t it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_7">
        <text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_8">
        <text>Look… this place is rotten. We came here and already lost two men. But I’ve got word there’s something valuable under the church. First, we deal with this “cursed soul” before it screws us any worse.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a1_bes_dialog_9">
        <text>What’s your plan?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a2_bes_dialog_0">
        <text>Found the scanner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a2_bes_dialog_1">
        <text>That’s the best news all day, Voland. Now we set it up and flush out that freak!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a2_bes_dialog_2">
        <text>Your buddy holding up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a2_bes_dialog_3">
        <text>As you can see, he’s coming around. Still fuzzy in the head, but he’ll shake it off.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a2_bes_dialog_4">
        <text>So what now? We fire up the scanner?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a2_bes_dialog_5">
        <text>Yeah. Once you’re ready, we’ll end this nightmare.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a2_bes_dialog_6">
        <text>Alright, let’s do it.</text>
    </string>
  <string id="chu_a2_bes_gotov_dialog_0">
        <text>Alright… I’m ready to move, Bes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a2_bes_gotov_dialog_1">
        <text>Good to hear, man. Got your gear in order? Feeling steady?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a2_bes_gotov_dialog_2">
        <text>All set. Let’s deal with this psi-emission crap.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a2_bes_gotov_dialog_22">
        <text>Hold up a minute.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a5_bes_dialog_0">
        <text>How you holding up, champ? Damn glad you’re still breathing… You pulled my ass out of the fire back there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a5_bes_dialog_1">
        <text>Ugh… Yeah. It was that thing upstairs. That device was spewing the psi-emission.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a5_bes_dialog_2">
        <text>Heh, figured as much when we dragged you out. So, how’s your head?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a5_bes_dialog_3">
        <text>I’ve felt worse. I’ll live.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a5_bes_dialog_4">
        <text>You’ll probably outlive us all, Voland. Balls of steel, no doubt. Thanks for the help, brother. Here—this is from me and Lyokha. You earned it, and we don’t regret giving it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a5_bes_dialog_5">
        <text>Appreciate it, guys.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a5_bes_dialog_6">
        <text>By the way, I’m heading down to the catacombs. You in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a5_bes_dialog_7">
        <text>Hell yeah! Looks like our paths cross again. We’ll cover each other’s backs—safer that way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a5_bes_dialog_8">
        <text>Yeah, you’re right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a5_hello_dialog_bes_0">
        <text>Hey, brother. Still kicking, huh?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_a5_hello_dialog_leha_0">
        <text>Voland! Glad to see you’re still on your feet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_0">
        <text>Bes, got a question for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_1">
        <text>Shoot. What’s on your mind?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_1111">
        <text>Heh, yeah! Stalkers always got each other’s backs… when it suits ’em, anyway.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_2">
        <text>How’d you end up in this mess?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_22">
        <text>What’s your read on the situation here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_222">
        <text>Forget it, never mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_2222">
        <text>Got it. Heh…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_3">
        <text>Heh, we were holed up at the Freedom base, knocking back drinks, chilling. Some drifter at the bar starts telling the barman about an old temple… Me being a nosy bastard, I lean in. Turns out he crawled out of the catacombs under this church, pockets full of pricey artifacts he’d hauled for Professor Bernady. I grilled him about the place, and he says it’s crawling with anomalies—just as bad underground as topside. Thought he’d cleaned it out already, but then he pulls me aside, whispers there’s still more loot down there than you could spend in ten lifetimes. So I hit up the professor for a contract. He was all for it—said his team vanished here a week ago, wanted us to check that out too. Gave us gear, meds, even a fat advance. We set off… and, well, you see how that turned out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_33">
        <text>Tough call, man. You’ve seen the kind of crap happening here. And it’s not just this place—the whole Zone’s one giant circus of weirdness.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_333">
        <text>So what’s the plan? You heading down to the catacombs?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_4">
        <text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_4212">
        <text>I’m going into the catacombs. You boys coming?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_4213">
        <text>Damn right! If our paths match, all the better. We’ll cover each other.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_4214">
        <text>You’re right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_44">
        <text>You’re right.</text>
    </string>
   <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_444">
        <text>Damn right! Gotta see what’s buried under that church… but that’s for later. I pinged some boys—more diggers on the way. Just me and Lyokha won’t uncover much on our own, heh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_555">
        <text>Crystal clear.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_666">
        <text>Listen… things are looking better already. No psi crap frying our brains anymore—hell, we could even set up camp here while we sniff out those catacombs!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_777">
        <text>Yeah, maybe…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_bes_self_1_dialog_999">
        <text>Looks like you picked up some fresh blood.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_hello_dialog_bes_0">
        <text>Voland, what’s up? Better be something worth my time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_hello_dialog_leha_0">
        <text>Ugh… My whole body’s busted. Who the hell are you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_leha_self_1_dialog_0">
        <text>Holding up, Lyokha?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_leha_self_1_dialog_1">
        <text>Ugh… Not great, man. My skull’s splitting, still shaking after that nightmare in the church…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_leha_self_1_dialog_11">
        <text>Yeah, feels a bit better now… head’s not pounding anymore, heh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_leha_self_1_dialog_2">
        <text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_leha_self_1_dialog_22">
        <text>Good to hear.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_leha_self_1_dialog_33">
        <text>Ha! Damn right… we’re basically the first to uncover this place. Maybe they’ll write songs about us! Or at least… maybe I won’t look like such a loser to the guys anymore.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="chu_leha_self_1_dialog_44">
        <text>You did good, Lyokha.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="flst_j1_ohrannik_dialog_door_0">
        <text>Boss… let me out already.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="flst_j1_ohrannik_dialog_door_1">
        <text>Heading out? Alright, door’s open.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="flst_j1_ohrannik_dialog_door_2">
        <text>Appreciate it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_0">
        <text>Whoa, easy there, Voland! Chill, I’ll lay it all out!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_1">
        <text>Save it, bastard… I don’t care about excuses. Hand over the keycard—now!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_10">
        <text>It’s documentation, folded into a neat A4. Top-secret schematics for an underground complex beneath the plant. Hidden lab, real hush-hush. I needed those papers for another deal that would’ve made me rich beyond belief! Calm down, soldier… I had no reason to put you down. You’re my golden ticket, see? Only you could’ve handled those mercs at the bar!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_100">
        <text>It’s… documentation, folded up neat. Top-secret schematics for an underground complex beneath the plant. A hidden lab. I needed those for a deal that would’ve made me filthy rich! Relax, soldier… I wasn’t planning to kill you. You’re my golden ticket—only you could’ve handled those mercs at the bar!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_11">
        <text>Speaking of mercs—what do you know about that ambush at their bar?</text>
    </string>
  <string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_0">
        <text>Whoa, easy there, Voland! Chill, I’ll tell you everything!</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_1">
        <text>Save it, bastard… I don’t care about excuses. Hand over the keycard, now!</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_2">
        <text>Here, take it! Don’t lose it, warrior. I’ll explain everything.</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_3">
        <text>Ha… What’s the point? I’ll rearrange your face first, then we’ll talk.</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_4">
        <text>Come on, Voland! I wasn’t trying to take you out—it’s a setup!</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_5">
        <text>Pfft, a setup inside a setup? What kind of nonsense is that, trader?</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_6">
        <text>The sectarians set me up! I swear, cross my heart! I was supposed to meet at the spot in the note, but some hooded prick screwed me over. And that Freedom guy… Seryi—he’s no Freedom fighter, he’s a damn sectarian in disguise!</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_7">
        <text>Goddamn it, Garrota, stop spinning fairy tales. Tell the truth.</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_77">
        <text>That Freedom guy’s dead. I took him out. Not a single trace of sectarian shit.</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_8">
        <text>I didn’t order your hit, think! Why the hell would I want you dead?! You were supposed to deliver that envelope—I’m freaking out like it’s my first time!</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_9">
        <text>What’s in this envelope? Unlike you, I’m still holding my end. Didn’t even peek.</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_10">
        <text>It’s documentation, folded tight. Top-secret schematics for the underground complex under the plant. Hidden lab. Needed them for another deal to make me filthy rich! Relax, soldier… I had no reason to kill you. You’re my golden ticket—only you could’ve handled those mercs at the bar!</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_11">
        <text>Speaking of mercs—what do you know about that bar ambush?</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_111">
        <text>Yeah, about those mercs… what do you know about the ambush at their bar?</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_112">
        <text>I swear, I got no clue! All I know—the sectarians hit them, right when you showed up! But I had nothing to do with it!</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_113">
        <text>Alright… how you gonna prove you’re not lying to me?</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_114">
        <text>Damn it… You’re one stubborn bastard! I got no reason to lie, I don’t screw over my clients!</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_115">
        <text>Fine. Let’s say you’re clean. You’re free to go, but don’t get comfortable. If anything’s off, I’ll be back for you.</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_116">
        <text>Doubting Thomas, huh… Alright, I get it.</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_117">
        <text>By the way, here’s your envelope. I don’t need it anymore.</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_118">
        <text>You’re my savior, Voland. Take this—you earned it! You can count on some discounts from me too. Catch you at the stalker camp.</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_119">
        <text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_12">
        <text>I swear, I got no idea! Sectarians hit them right when you showed up! I’m clean, damn it!</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_13">
        <text>Okay… if you’re not bullshitting me, it’s simpler. That Freedom guy—Seryi—is he really a sectarian? Let’s confront him and settle this, damn it.</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_14">
        <text>Let’s move! If that bastard hasn’t bolted yet!</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_garrota_dialog_15">
        <text>Don’t move a muscle. You’ve got nowhere to run, the guard’s watching. I’ll drag that Freedom guy here—and God help you if you’re lying.</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u21_serie_hello_dialog_0">
        <text>Hey, good guy. How’s life treating you?</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u22_sektant_pryff_garrota_dialog_0">
        <text>You’re right, the Freedom guy slipped out… Maybe you’re worth trusting.</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u22_sektant_pryff_garrota_dialog_1">
        <text>Oh? Doubting Thomas finally at ease? Praise the Monolith. So… can I get my envelope now?</text>
    </string>
<string id="flst_u22_sektant_pryff_garrota_dialog_2">
        <text>Take it. But I’m watching you, trader. Don’t forget that.</text>
    </string>
  <string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_0">
        <text>You said you wanna “take down” the Prophet.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_1">
        <text>You didn’t tail anyone, did you?</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_2">
        <text>Nope.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_10">
        <text>Alright… let’s say I buy it. He’s a sectarian—who knows what twisted sacrifice he’s planning for his “religion.” But you? You’re part of his crew… yet clearly don’t plan on dying under his wing. Smart. How the hell did you even end up in this sect? Apart from those satanic tattoos, you don’t seem completely insane. Might even be a decent guy to talk to.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_11">
        <text>Heh-heh… It’s business, baby! Our sect isn’t about God—it’s about cash. Trade spots in the Zone, connections with the big shots, and plenty outside too. Weapons, people… organs, you name it. *Cough*… Now the Prophet’s planning some insane stunt. Needs stopping. In a perfect world, you’d probably off me right here, but I’m offering a temporary partnership. Got it?</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_12">
        <text>Why the hell would I “partner” with you?</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_13">
        <text>Come on, Voland, don’t play dumb! Prophet’s got your brother—and maybe your friend too, right? You’re here instead of toeing the line. Means you’re open to a deal. Am I wrong?</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_14">
        <text>I need guarantees. My brother and friend stay alive. Get them out of the Zone. No bullets in the back.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_15">
        <text>Obvious. To build trust, here’s the plan. Down in our metro, there’s a woman—Citra. Firecracker, fed up with Prophet’s crap. She’s running the base now. Checked with her: if you help us, she’ll meet your demands. Simple: next to your brother’s cell is Kolobok—a reporter! Sneaked in to dig up dirt. Had his recorder, camera. Prophet used it for videos for families paying to get their kids back. Got it?</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_16">
        <text>Hold up. How do I get Citra to release them?</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_17">
        <text>Buzzkill, Voland! Fine… Tell Citra you’re in on the deal. She’ll ask you to get info from Kolobok—where he stashed his dirt. If it’s gone to the NII, deal’s off.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_18">
        <text>Seriously? You couldn’t break him under torture? Something’s fishy.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_19">
        <text>See for yourself—messed up his face, ripped nails, made him a eunuch. Screamed, whined, but when asked about the stash: “I don’t know.” Tried whispering coordinates on a radio, lucky we caught him. Trained bastard. Eyes gave him away—he’s not scared. Respect, kinda.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_20">
        <text>The stash… worried he found too much? Plan to pin it on Prophet and slip away with your shady biz?</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_21">
        <text>Your idea’s crap, but not entirely wrong… Grab the stash, we free your friends, guarantee you a long life. No catch. You do your part, we do ours. Part ways clean. If you come after us later, we’ll vanish. Deal or not?</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_22">
        <text>Deal. But I want you with me—to make sure you’re not screwing me.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_23">
        <text>Are you nuts? Prophet’s out for me, I spill all this? How long’d I last if I went with you?</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_24">
        <text>So I show up there, no questions asked? Even if Citra’s in charge, Prophet’s goons will notice.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_25">
        <text>Just keep quiet and don’t dawdle. Prophet gave you time, right? Some NII documents, bombs… don’t want everyone turning to ash, yeah? Make up your mind—are you in?</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_26">
        <text>Fine. I’ll risk it for my people.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_27">
        <text>Good. Head to our base, tell Citra you’re from me. She’ll brief you. Go, Voland! Save the world, save us, save yourself!</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_28">
        <text>Yeah, sure.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_3">
        <text>Let’s hope. Prophet’s insane. Last months, it’s been getting in the way, not just for me.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_4">
        <text>You seem saner than the other sectarians. Not all of you are unhinged, huh?</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_5">
        <text>Well, you tell me. How sane do I seem on Newton’s scale?</text>
    </string>
 <string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_6">
        <text>New one. Ha… So far, pretty comfortable “temperature.” Didn’t come here to chitchat.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_7">
        <text>We gotta loosen up a bit, get used to each other, no? Fine… back to business. Prophet’s planning to set off nukes scattered across the Zone, labs, bunkers. Not just the Zone—good chunk of the planet. Sane? I think not.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_8">
        <text>What the hell? Why would he do that? Screwing himself too.</text>
    </string>
<string id="kn_e3_kvant_true_scenario_dialog_9">
        <text>Exactly. Loads of lives lost. Pure idiocy.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_p27_ecolog_medic_need_health_care_0">
        <text>%c[0,140,140,140]Need med help.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_p27_ecolog_medic_need_health_care_1">
        <text>Alright, let’s see what’s wrong.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_p27_ecolog_medic_need_health_care_11">
        <text>%c[0,140,140,140][..continue..]</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_p27_ecolog_medic_need_health_care_111">
        <text>Done! You’re good as new.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_p27_ecolog_medic_need_health_care_2">
        <text>Hmm… You’re fine. Maybe just worn out.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_0">
        <text>Got a couple questions.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_1">
        <text>Go ahead.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_1488">
        <text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_1489">
        <text>Anything else?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_2">
        <text>What’s happening in the Zone?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_22">
        <text>Know anything about this medallion?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_222">
        <text>Forget it.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_3">
        <text>Heard about the sectarians? New faction. Brutal, dangerous.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_33">
        <text>Heard about local anomalies? Weird spots everywhere. That plane, for example… People say you can hear voices—crew screaming, panic… Creepy as hell.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_333">
        <text>Ever heard of “Minotaur’s Labyrinth”? Anomaly that supposedly hides Zone treasures. Guarded by a monster. Path’s dangerous. True or not, who knows.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_3333">
        <text>Know the “Crater”? Meteor hit years back. Left a big anomaly.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_33333">
        <text>There’s the “Hut” anomaly. Floating shack with chunk of ground. Can you believe it?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_333333">
        <text>Sectarians popping up more. Rumor: human sacrifices… Wouldn’t want to meet them, ugh.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_44">
        <text>This belongs to the sectarians. That’s all I know.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_444">
        <text>Toss that junk, friend. Bad omen.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_4444">
        <text>They say people finding medallions like that don’t live long. I wouldn’t risk it.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mod_universal_dialog_44444">
        <text>Just ditch it.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtr_prorok_hello_dialog_dva_0">
        <text>Any results? Don’t see progress, Voland. Don’t piss me off!</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_0">
        <text>Well… You seem upset, my dear…</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_1">
        <text>Listen, joker, what’s with Nikita?!</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_10">
        <text>Don’t interrupt! Hear me?! Or I’ll slit your brother’s throat! Argh… Sorry, got worked up. Tough times… *Cough*… I need the “Oasis,” the start of it all. Where new life is born.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_11">
        <text>What are you talking about? Where do I find this artifact?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_12">
        <text>Shut up! Mouth closed, bastard! When I talk, you listen, piece of shit! Clear?! Ah… manners… I’m exhausted, Voland. Ha-ha… “Oasis”? Not an artifact. I mean the place where artifacts are born…</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_13">
        <text>And… where’s this place?</text>
    </string>
  <string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_14">
        <text>Love it! You’re not asking why I need this place! Adore you for that! Could gut you now, but… you can still find the true path! I’ll help! Ha-ha… I’ll show you, but damn… It’s locked! Path to Paradise blocked by some rusty metal door. To open it… you need to restore power underground, where scary monsters lurk! Ha-ha… Afraid of monsters, are you?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_15">
        <text>Alright, I get it. Guarantee my brother and friend stay alive?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_16">
        <text>Guarantees?! Are you insane?! Ha-ha! Want a bullet in the head, bastard?! I’ll contact you when ready. Do what I asked, your brother lives. Now, get out!</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_17">
        <text>What about Sherif?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_18">
        <text>Sherif? Your cowboy? Ha-ha… No clue. I’ll keep him alive for now, you convinced me! Two prisoners? Unfair. We’ll talk later. First, do what I asked. Get lost. Tell Macho to escort you out. Got it?! Leave!</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_19">
        <text>Easy. Keep it together! %c[0,140,140,140][..leave..]</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_2">
        <text>Ha-ha! Relax, soldier! He’s… on vitamins, get it? Our doc prescribed them. You could use some too, for self-control, my dear.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_3">
        <text>You sick bastard. What do you want? I know you need something for my brother. Right?! Otherwise, why keep me alive?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_4">
        <text>Right on, hermano. Big picture! Want your brother back safe? Work for me. Keep yelling, get sold off in pieces. Harmony, pendejo! You’re shouting in my house!</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_5">
        <text>Punk… What do you want?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_6">
        <text>Perfect! Now we’re talking, Voland! Ha-ha! Save your brother and yourself, do me a couple favors. Fair trade, right?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_7">
        <text>Don’t drag it out. Lay out your terms.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_8">
        <text>Rush? Ha-ha… Time slips, repeats! Weird, huh? *Cough*… Need someone from your kind… What’s the name? Stalker! Yes, yes! You killed my followers, yet I spared your brother, buddy, and you! See the difference? Ha-ha-ha…</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_e8_prorok_dialog_9">
        <text>Ugh… Why need a stalker? What do you want me to do? Enough chatter, spit it out.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k1_citra_dialog_0">
        <text>Citra, I’m from Kvant. He said to talk to you if I agreed to his terms.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k1_citra_dialog_1">
        <text>Right, Voland. Smart choice.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k1_citra_dialog_2">
        <text>What about your prisoner… Kolobok, right?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k1_citra_dialog_3">
        <text>That stubborn masochist stays silent under torture. Guess he doesn’t want to live.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k1_citra_dialog_4">
        <text>Let me try talking. I’m not like you… Maybe he’ll open up.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k1_citra_dialog_5">
        <text>Alright. He’s in the cell with your brother now.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_0">
        <text>Not telling you shit! Kill me, monsters! Filthy bastards!</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_1">
        <text>Easy, calm down. Not a sectarian. Just want to talk.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_10">
        <text>Hah… I tell where the material is, then what? They’ll know we’re in cahoots. If I survived their torture, what happens when they hear you got info from me?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_11">
        <text>We won’t hide their suspicions. Lay it all out.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_12">
        <text>Are you nuts… They’ll destroy the material, kill your people, and you too.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_13">
        <text>Maybe… What’s your name anyway?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_14">
        <text>Artem Nikolaevich. Special ops, undercover. Secret NII mission. No more details.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_15">
        <text>Nice to meet you, Artem. I’m Oleg. Soldier all my life… Almost retired, then bam… Brother signs a contract, back in the Zone to save him. He’s all I’ve got.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_16">
        <text>Touching… Sorry, not big on sentiment. Grew up in orphanage, loner. Love? Never had it.</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_17">
        <text>Will you help me, Artem?</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_18">
        <text>Screw it. Look for the material in “unexplored territories”—east Zone. Dense thickets, church nearby, cemetery not far. That’s where I buried it. They won’t find it. Go. Try not to die, save friends. I’m halfway to the grave already…</text>
    </string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_19">
        <text>Hang in, Artem. I’ll get you out too. Watch my people. Deal? I’ll sort this fast.</text>
</string>
   <string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_2">
        <text>Huh?! Who the hell are you? What are you doing here?! You’re with them, aren’t you?! Get the fuck out!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_3">
        <text>I’m not with them. It’s a forced, temporary deal. My own brother’s in that cell with you… and I’ve got to save him, no matter the cost.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_4">
        <text>So what?! That’s why you’re working with these animals?! You’re a sick bastard, got it?! And your brother’s already lost it… All he does is mumble and drool! That’s what you’re trying to save?!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_5">
        <text>Shut your mouth. Me and my brother haven’t done shit to you. So why the hell are you talking to me like that, you punk?!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_6">
        <text>Whoa, whoa! Oh, I’m so fucking scared! Go to hell, got it?! Screw you, you sectarian lackey!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_7">
        <text>Listen… They’re torturing you, humiliating you, doing shit that’d break most people by now! But you’re holding on, grinning through it, taking it. You a soldier? You’re not hiding your “skills” well. It’s written all over your face—you’re a seasoned guy who’s seen some nasty shit in life. Special forces? Top secret, am I right? I know who you are, man… and it sucks seeing them treat you like this.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_8">
        <text>Sounds like you’re a soldier too… So what? You think I’ll melt and spill why those bastards sent you here? No way… Sorry, soldier, but that’s not happening. If I die, I die, but the compromising material will be found sooner or later… It will… I’m sure of it…</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_9">
        <text>Why not team up, tell me? I’m with them for now, but once I save my people, I’ll come back to finish these sectarians, trust me.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_20">
        <text>Yeah… Go for it, hero. I’ll do what I can…</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k2_kolobok_dialog_21">
        <text>Hang in there, guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_0">
        <text>What did he tell you?!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_1">
        <text>Sorry… I couldn’t get anything out of him.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_2">
        <text>What? Voland, who do you think you’re screwing with? Do I look that dumb to you, huh? What did he tell you?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_3">
        <text>Nothing useful, I’ll say it again.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_4">
        <text>Who do you think you’re joking with, huh? Do you even get who you are, who he is, who they are, and who we are? You’re in a cage, little bird, and you need to tell the truth. It’ll be better for you, and not just you…</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_5">
        <text>Easy, Citra. The compromising material’s somewhere in the unexplored territories, east of the Zone. Give me time, please. I’ll check everything out, just trust me.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_6">
        <text>Ha-ha-ha! My sweet, my darling! A couple more offers like that, and I’ll fall for you completely, you silly!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_7">
        <text>Citra, please, don’t do anything stupid. I’ll bring you the compromising material, just don’t touch anyone, okay?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_8">
        <text>That’s it, I’m in love, soldier… Now I’ll wait for you like a prince… But if you take too long, I’ll have to kill someone, got it? A sacrifice for love!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_9">
        <text>I’ll handle it. Give me time, I’ll get it done.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_10">
        <text>Well then… My hero! Get to it… Time’s ticking.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_11">
        <text>It’ll be done right.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_22">
        <text>I’ve got a lead, but I need to check it out myself first.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_33">
        <text>Oh, really… And why do you think you’ll check it out yourself?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_44">
        <text>If this is a trap, it could piss you and Kvant off even more. Right?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_55">
        <text>Ha-ha-ha! You’re so sweet, Voland.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_66">
        <text>I just want to part ways peacefully.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_77">
        <text>Oh? For some reason, I’ve got a feeling you’re trying to screw us over…</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_88">
        <text>No point in screwing you over. We’ve got a deal! I’m already in too deep, and my brother’s life is the most important thing to me right now!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k3_citra_dialog_99">
        <text>Citra, just trust me. The Prophet will figure things out soon… Better I handle the compromising material search myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e55_german_dialog_0">
        <text>Professor, we’ve got a problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e55_german_dialog_1">
        <text>What’s wrong?</text>
</string>
  <string id="nii_e55_german_dialog_2">
        <text>Your terminal seems to have glitched out. I told everyone, but they asked you to check it yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e55_german_dialog_22">
        <text>Never mind, Professor, my mistake.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e55_german_dialog_3">
        <text>Good lord… They can’t do anything without me! Alright, I’ll go check. Thanks for letting me know.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e55_german_dialog_33">
        <text>Professor, hide those documents on your desk, quick. The sectarians are planning to steal them.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e55_german_dialog_4">
        <text>No problem…</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e55_german_dialog_44">
        <text>My God! Thank you for the heads-up! I’ll put them under guard right now! I knew keeping them here wasn’t safe. Thank you for your help, Mr. Voland!</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e55_german_dialog_55">
        <text>Happy to help…</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_0">
        <text>Greetings, Oleg.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_1">
        <text>Greetings. Sanya, I need your help… My brother’s been captured by the sectarians. And Sherif, you remember him, right? He’s there too… We’ve gotta get them out somehow.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_111">
        <text>We’ll talk later, buddy.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_2">
        <text>Damn, that’s rough… How do you wanna play this? If we storm in guns blazing, there’ll be no one left to save. Got any ideas?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_22">
        <text>Sanya, I’ve got solid intel that the sectarians are planning to steal classified documents from the NII.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_3">
        <text>Makes sense. But leaving them there too long is risky as hell… Alright, if I come up with something, I’ll let you know, cool? If we need to fight through blood and fire, you with me?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_33">
        <text>Got it… I’ll warn the Professor right away. Thanks for the tip!</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_333">
        <text>I need firepower. I want to burn that sectarian trash to the ground…</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_4">
        <text>Of course I’m with you, buddy. Just give me the word for the attack.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_44">
        <text>No problem…</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_444">
        <text>I hear you, Oleg. No problem, just say the word, and I’ll round up fighters for the assault.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_5">
        <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_555">
        <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_666">
        <text>Let’s finish off those sectarians already. I’m ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n4_kovalskie_meet_dialog_8">
        <text>Got anything else you wanted to ask?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_ohrannik_wounded_dialog_0">
        <text>You bastard… You’ll regret this.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_ohrannik_wounded_dialog_1">
        <text>%c[0,140,140,140][..leave..]</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_sherif_dialog_0">
        <text>Alright, time to check out our haul.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_sherif_dialog_1">
        <text>The PDA’s locked. You said you’d handle it, here you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_sherif_dialog_2">
        <text>Right, hand it over. What else we got?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_sherif_dialog_3">
        <text>A case. It’s got some fancy lock on it.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_sherif_dialog_4">
        <text>Take it to Techie. He’ll probably crack it.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_sherif_dialog_5">
        <text>The report’s useless… But there might be something juicy on the flash drive.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_sherif_dialog_6">
        <text>Good point. See the laptop on the table? Use it, knock yourself out.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_sherif_dialog_7">
        <text>Let me know when you crack the PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_sherif_dialog_8">
        <text>You got it, Voland.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_sherif_dialog_9">
        <text>That’s the spirit.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_0">
        <text>Hey there. You need something from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_1">
        <text>What do you do around here?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_1111">
        <text>Alright, your call.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_2">
        <text>Well, a bit of everything! Set up my little shop here, do some trading. If you’re hungry, hit me up. Heh-heh. Got ammo, weapons, armor too—yep, I can hook you up!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_22">
        <text>Know anything about this medallion?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_2222">
        <text>Sweet, here’s the cash.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_3">
        <text>Got it.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_33">
        <text>Oh… That’s a sectarian trinket! Interesting piece… Usually worn by the Prophet’s inner circle.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_4">
        <text>Got any more questions for me, heh-heh?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_44">
        <text>The “Prophet,” huh…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_55">
        <text>Far as I know, he’s the leader of those sectarians… Nobody’s seen him in person, just rumors floating around…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_666">
        <text>Catch you later.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_777">
        <text>You want this medallion?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_888">
        <text>Cool little bauble! I’d buy it off you for two grand. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_999">
        <text>Deal. Here you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_danya_hello_dialog_1_9999">
        <text>I’ll hold onto it for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_fishboy_hello_dialog_1_0">
        <text>Nice weather… You need something from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ilay_hello_dialog_1_0">
        <text>Yo, Voland! What’s good, buddy?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ilay_hello_dialog_1_1">
        <text>You said we had something to talk about…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ilay_hello_dialog_1_2">
        <text>Yeah. Remember why the military had me pinned back then?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ilay_hello_dialog_1_3">
        <text>Oh yeah. You were dealing drugs. Hard to forget, the whole barracks was cracking up.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ilay_hello_dialog_1_4">
        <text>Exactly! Things are picking up now, I’m pushing my “business.” Wanna get in on it?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ilay_hello_dialog_1_5">
        <text>What’s the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ilay_hello_dialog_1_6">
        <text>Help me distribute, and get the goods, obviously!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ilay_hello_dialog_1_666">
        <text>Let’s talk later.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ilay_hello_dialog_1_7">
        <text>Hm… I’ll think it over and let you know.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ilay_hello_dialog_1_8">
        <text>Alright! I’ll be waiting for your decision, Voland. You know where to find me. Heh-heh.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_0">
        <text>Beat it, man. Garrota’s not seeing anyone, quarantine. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_1">
        <text>Who’s Garrota?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_100">
        <text>Obvious, huh? Except I’m thinking if I smack a dumbass like you upside the head, they might even thank me. Ever consider that?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_111">
        <text>Get outta here, don’t piss me off.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_112">
        <text>%c[255,248,153,26][..hit..]</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_113">
        <text>%c[0,140,140,140][..leave..]</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_2">
        <text>What, you don’t even know who he is? Pfft… Alright, man, just go.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_3">
        <text>%c[0,140,140,140][..leave..]</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_33">
        <text>%c[0,140,140,140][..leave..]</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_44">
        <text>Why you acting so tough?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_55">
        <text>Ha! What, you trying to start something with me, jackass?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_66">
        <text>Yeah. Wanna teach you how to talk “by the book,” kid.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_666">
        <text>%c[0,140,140,140][..leave..]</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_77">
        <text>You nuts or what? Think you’re playing soldier here? You’re just a lousy looter, nothing more, at least to me! Ha-ha, get lost.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_88">
        <text>How about I just knock a couple of your teeth out?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_ohrannik_hello_dialog_1_99">
        <text>Use that dumb military brain of yours, man. Start a fight, and everyone’ll know what a hardcore soldier you are, got it? Then they’ll treat you real different.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_stalker_torg_hello_dialog_1_0">
        <text>What you standing there for, Voland? Got business with me? Don’t keep me waiting. If you’re here to buy, show me the cash, heh-heh.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_0">
        <text>Hey! Need some “taxi” services?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_1">
        <text>What’s that supposed to mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_111">
        <text>I need to get to the Venus factory. %c[255,248,153,26](Abandoned Venus Complex)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_112">
        <text>I need to get to the sanatorium. %c[255,248,153,26](Old Sanatorium)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_113">
        <text>I need to get to the residential district. %c[255,248,153,26](Engineers’ District)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_114">
        <text>I need to get to the industrial plant. %c[255,248,153,26](Industrial Plant)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_115">
        <text>I need to get to the village by the old school. %c[255,248,153,26](Old School Outskirts)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_2">
        <text>Exactly what it sounds like, man. I do a bit of taxi work with this truck here. Need to get to the scientists’ base, for example? I’ll take you for a fixed price.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_222">
        <text>I need to get to the sanatorium. %c[255,248,153,26](Old Sanatorium)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_3">
        <text>Good to know.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_333">
        <text>I need to get to the engineers’ district. %c[255,248,153,26](Engineers’ District)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_4">
        <text>So, where was I… Need a ride?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_444">
        <text>I need to get to the industrial plant. %c[255,248,153,26](Industrial Plant)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_5">
        <text>I need to get to the scientists’ base. %c[255,248,153,26](Gas Station)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_55">
        <text>Nah, sorry, don’t need your “taxi” right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_6">
        <text>Alright. A trip to the gas station will cost you 3000 gold. We going?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_601">
        <text>Sure thing. That ride’ll cost you 5000 gold. Ready to roll?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_602">
        <text>Yeah, let’s hit the road!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_66">
        <text>Got it, but let’s wait out the emission first, cool?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_701">
        <text>Yeah, let’s go.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_702">
        <text>text in default</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_77">
        <text>Changed my mind. Not now.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_8">
        <text>Okay.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_801">
        <text>The sanatorium? Hmm… Alright. That’ll be 6500 gold for the trip. We going?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_802">
        <text>Let’s roll, yeah.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_803">
        <text>Let’s go, driver, hit it.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_804">
        <text>Floor it, Solyarych.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_805">
        <text>Yeah, start her up.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_811">
        <text>Engineers’ district it is! That’ll be 3000 gold for the ride. We going?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_821">
        <text>Industrial plant, huh? Cool. That’ll be 4000 gold for the trip. Ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_831">
        <text>As you say. That ride’s gonna cost you 5000 gold. We going?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_88">
        <text>Alright…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_915">
        <text>After the emission, we can go wherever you want.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_dialog_916">
        <text>Got you.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_dialog_0">
        <text>Good to see you, Voland.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_dialog_1">
        <text>Hey, Techie. Got a job for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_dialog_2">
        <text>Tell me, I’m all ears.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_dialog_3">
        <text>I need you to crack open a case without damaging what’s inside.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_dialog_4">
        <text>Let’s see it… Easy enough, but I’ll need some precision tools for the job.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_dialog_5">
        <text>Where the hell am I supposed to find those?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_dialog_6">
        <text>Don’t sweat it, I’ve got a couple of toolkits stashed. Do me a favor, head to the construction site nearby. I’ll mark it on your PDA, you won’t get lost. Left my cache there… Oh, wait, hold up! There’s a… I set up a tripwire near the tools, so be careful, got it? Tools are on a crate, and the trap’s right by it. I don’t need to teach you how to disarm tripwires—you’re a seasoned soldier, battle-hardened. Just don’t blow yourself up, okay? Heh-heh.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_dialog_66">
        <text>Listen, what am I, your errand boy, running back and forth?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_dialog_7">
        <text>No problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_dialog_77">
        <text>Come on, Voland, don’t be dramatic. I’m not exactly young either… Where am I gonna run off to, leaving all my gear unattended? Don’t be a grump, buddy. Just go get it…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_dialog_88">
        <text>Fine, good for a stretch. I’ll go.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_open_case_dialog_0">
        <text>Phew. Here’s the contents… Careful, looks like some kinda artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_open_case_dialog_1">
        <text>What the hell is this? What’s it good for?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_open_case_dialog_11">
        <text>An artifact?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_open_case_dialog_2">
        <text>That’s not my business, friend. I did my part, take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_open_case_dialog_22">
        <text>Yeah, something like that. You should take it to the scientists—they might know how to activate it.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_open_case_dialog_3">
        <text>Ugh… Thanks.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_open_case_dialog_33">
        <text>Activate it?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_texnik_open_case_dialog_44">
        <text>Yeah, activate! They can turn a rusty bolt into ammo… Though, I’ve dabbled in that myself, heh-heh. Anyway, I did my job. Exactly as ordered!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_0">
        <text>Yo, Voland. How can I help?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_1">
        <text>That Hummer yours?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_111">
        <text>Can you take me to the stalker camp? %c[255,248,153,26](Fish Farm Base)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_1488">
        <text>Could you crack open this container? %c[255,248,153,26](Locked Freedom Container)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_1489">
        <text>Uh… Nah, bro. Sorry, but that’s not my thing. Hold up, though—I can’t do it, but our docent might. Ask him, he’s our local tech guy around the camp. I’m… more into vehicles than lockpicking, so my bad!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_1490">
        <text>Got it, thanks for the tip.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_2">
        <text>Mine, all mine. Like it? Heh-heh…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_201">
        <text>Easy peasy… For old times’ sake, I won’t charge you much. 1000 rubles, and we’re on the road. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_210">
        <text>Deal. Let’s roll.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_3">
        <text>Factory engine?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_4">
        <text>Ha! If only… I went and put in a domestic one, my bad. Why you looking at me like that? Yeah, I’m an idiot, so what? Regretting it now, ‘cause this junk doesn’t run as smooth as it could.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_5">
        <text>Does it even run?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_55">
        <text>Catch you later.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_6">
        <text>Sorta… But I wouldn’t take it too far. Scared it’ll crap out. *Cough*.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_666">
        <text>I’ll take you, but only after the emission, alright?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_667">
        <text>Cool.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_7">
        <text>Got it.</text>
</string>
  <string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_77">
        <text>Changed my mind, later.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_8">
        <text>So, what’d you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_dialog_88">
        <text>As you say.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_0">
        <text>Voland, what you got there?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_1">
        <text>%c[255,248,153,26]Found a case. Problem is, it’s locked.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_11">
        <text>%c[255,248,153,26]Found a PDA. Take a look.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_111">
        <text>%c[255,248,153,26]Got a flash drive here. You got a laptop at the camp?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_1111">
        <text>%c[255,248,153,26]Found a report on the sergeant. Check it out.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_2">
        <text>Interesting… What could the military be hauling around?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_22">
        <text>It’s locked, I see. Don’t worry, once we’re back at camp, I’ll hack into it.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_222">
        <text>I’ll find you a laptop!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_2222">
        <text>Hmm… A report to the brass. Guess the sergeant believed they wouldn’t screw him over until the end…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_3">
        <text>Could be anything. Alright, we’ll deal with it later.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_33">
        <text>Sounds good.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_333">
        <text>That’s good.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_3333">
        <text>Guess so.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_4444">
        <text>%c[255,1,255,255]Hang tight here, I’m still looking around.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_5">
        <text>%c[255,248,153,26]I think we’ve checked everything here.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_6">
        <text>You’re right. We’ve already grabbed anything useful.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_7">
        <text>Yeah, that’s right.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_7777">
        <text>%c[0,140,140,140]Check it out, a medallion… Hope it’s not cursed, ha-ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_8">
        <text>Find anything else?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_8888">
        <text>I’d laugh at your joke, but hell if I know what this thing is!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c5_sherif_dialog_9999">
        <text>Killjoy… Fine, forget it.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_0">
        <text>Bingo, my dear.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_1">
        <text>I did what you asked. Let my brother and friend go!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_10">
        <text>Don’t worry. Follow my instructions, and no one will know about your little side hustle, heh-heh-heh! At the Institute, tonight, my guy will be waiting for you…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_11">
        <text>Hold up! You want me to go against my own people?! That’s straight-up betrayal!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_12">
        <text>Listen, Voland, I’ll break both your kneecaps and knock out all your teeth. Interrupt me one more fucking time, got it? Hear me out first.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_13">
        <text>S-sorry… Go on.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_14">
        <text>Tonight, at the Institute, my guy will be waiting. Your job: hand him the documents—specifically, the blueprints. From what I know, it’s a big stack of papers in a wide folder. Instructions for operating and activating the “Noospheric Anomalous Dome.” Ugh… Shit, hope I said that right. It’s simple, Voland. Steal the folder with the docs and give it to my guy. Then, contact me when you’re back in the Zone. Don’t screw around, hermano. I’m waiting for results!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_15">
        <text>%c[0,140,140,140][...]</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_2">
        <text>Huh? What’s that, sorry? You’re… you’re putting me on the spot? Threatening me, yeah? Ha-ha-ha! Voland, don’t piss me off. I promised I’d let your brother go once you do the dirty work. Right? Did I say anything different? Huh? Did I say something else?! Answer!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_3">
        <text>Exactly like you said, sorry.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_4">
        <text>That’s more like it, hermano. Whole different vibe. Now, it’s time for the big finale, and… we’ll part ways, yeah? You and your precious brother go your way, I go mine. Everyone wins, everyone’s happy, that’s what I’m saying, right? Huh? Don’t go quiet when I’m asking you, it gets on my nerves, got it?!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_5">
        <text>Yeah. And Sherif! You’ll let him go too, like we agreed.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_6">
        <text>Uh… Yeah, yeah, sure. Sherif… Him too, you talked me into it!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_7">
        <text>What’s next?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_8">
        <text>I love when you ask the right questions, soldier. It’s simple! You can get into the NII, right? That shitty Institute, yeah? Come on, spit it out quick. Can you?!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_dialog_9">
        <text>Yeah, but why?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_quest_s1_texnik_dialog_0">
        <text>So, where are my tools?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_quest_s1_texnik_dialog_555555">
        <text>I’ll bring them soon, just hold on a bit.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r1_sherif_dialog_0">
        <text>Oh, there you are… Listen, that PDA turned out to be useful. Check it out!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r1_sherif_dialog_1">
        <text>No way. That was my brother’s PDA…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r1_sherif_dialog_2">
        <text>Yeah, and he was definitely kidnapped. You find out anything?</text>
</string>
  <string id="okr_r1_sherif_dialog_3">
        <text>There was a video on the flash drive. The sectarians recorded my brother…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r1_sherif_dialog_4">
        <text>Sick bastards… Where was it?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r1_sherif_dialog_5">
        <text>Looks like the old sanatorium. But the weirdest part isn’t that. We found the flash drive at the school where the attack happened, right? Obvious question—how’d it get there? Someone deliberately brought it and left it, hoping it’d be found later. Same with the PDA. Not sure about the case, though… Hmm… We still need to figure out what this artifact is for.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r1_sherif_dialog_6">
        <text>Yeah… Your reasoning makes sense, but I don’t think the sectarians left the case or the report.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r1_sherif_dialog_7">
        <text>Really? What’s the difference now? The flash drive was definitely them. Otherwise, it couldn’t have just shown up there, you get me?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r1_sherif_dialog_8">
        <text>I get it, Voland. Alright, I’ve got an idea who might help us with the search. I’ll try to reach him now.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r1_sherif_dialog_9">
        <text>Cool.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r2_to_r3_sherif_dialog_0">
        <text>Let’s go meet your scout. I’m ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r2_to_r3_sherif_dialog_1">
        <text>You sure you’re ready? Who knows, might turn into a firefight…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r2_to_r3_sherif_dialog_2">
        <text>Damn sure.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r2_to_r3_sherif_dialog_22">
        <text>Hold up a bit. I’ll be right back.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r3_molag_dialog_0">
        <text>Figured anything out?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r3_molag_dialog_1">
        <text>Hard to miss you, hah. That old rascal Sherif tried to keep our meeting under wraps!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r3_molag_dialog_2">
        <text>Why’d you come back? Got no one to mess with on your vacation?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r3_molag_dialog_3">
        <text>Quiet, you. That’s no way to talk to your elders, punk, ha-ha.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r3_molag_dialog_4">
        <text>Sherif said it’s serious business… Sorry.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r3_molag_dialog_5">
        <text>You’re right. I’m looking for my brother… Let’s talk shop later, focus on the job now.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r3_molag_dialog_6">
        <text>Ahem… I tracked where one of those fanatics was headed. Scoped it out—turns out those bastards are coming out of the sanatorium, or rather, from under it! Bet my teeth they’ve got a base underground. On the surface, it’s like an outpost or something.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r3_molag_dialog_7">
        <text>Should we hit them?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r3_molag_dialog_8">
        <text>Yeah, and preferably quietly. Less noise, the better for us. Here’s the plan: I lead, you guys creep behind me. If shit hits the fan, we scatter and take them out carefully. I reckon they’re shitty fighters, just a bunch of doped-up losers, swear to God.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r3_molag_dialog_9">
        <text>Got you. Lead the way.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_0">
        <text>What do you make of all this?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_1">
        <text>What’s there to think? My brother’s with them. No clue why the hell they grabbed him, but it’s a relief he’s alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_2">
        <text>Damn right. Now we just need to find the keycard for that door to get into their lair.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_3">
        <text>And where do we look for it? Those bums didn’t seem to have anything like that.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_4">
        <text>Well, that’s obvious. Probably only the most trusted of that scum have keycards… But I’ve got a hunch who could get us any key, damn it, for all the “Gates in the Zone.”</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_5">
        <text>Alright, spill it.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_6">
        <text>You know Garrota? Local miser at the stalker camp. Holed up in his trailer.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_7">
        <text>No clue, what about him?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_8">
        <text>Chances are that paranoid bastard’s locked himself in again and isn’t letting anyone in, since you haven’t met him yet. That trader’s actually a big deal in the Zone. If anyone’s got a lead on a keycard, it’s him first.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_9">
        <text>If he’s locked up and not seeing anyone, how do I get to him?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_10">
        <text>Between you and me, don’t sweat it. He’s a real asshole, but his password—for “curfew” situations like this—is dead simple: “Spanish Kitchen.” Got it? Hah…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_11">
        <text>He’s definitely an asshole, but whatever. I’ve heard crazier codes. Got it, good.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_12">
        <text>Perfect. Alright, no reason to stick around here anymore. Sherif and I are heading back to camp. You coming?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_13">
        <text>Yeah, I’m with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_dialog_14">
        <text>You guys go. I’ll catch up later. Wanna look around some more.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_stand_hello_medic_dialog_0">
        <text>Yeah, yeah… Hey, Voland. Feeling sick?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_stand_hello_sherif_dialog_0">
        <text>Yo, Voland. What’s the word?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_stand_hello_texnik_dialog_0">
        <text>Good to see you, Voland. What’s up?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_stand_hello_texnik_dialog_1">
        <text>Here’s the tools, Techie. Let’s crack that case open.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_stand_hello_texnik_dialog_2">
        <text>Perfect. Gimme a sec, it’ll be done!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_stand_hello_texnik_dialog_3">
        <text>%c[0,140,140,140][..next..]</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_standart_hello_dialog_1_0_text">
        <text>[...]</text>
</string>
   <string id="okr_u18_act_dialog_to_freedom_0">
        <text>Easy, man! I come in peace…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u18_act_dialog_to_freedom_1">
        <text>Yeah, I can see that. What were you looking for here?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u18_act_dialog_to_freedom_2">
        <text>An envelope… You were supposed to deliver it to Garrota, right? Listen…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u18_act_dialog_to_freedom_3">
        <text>He sent you?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u18_act_dialog_to_freedom_4">
        <text>Y-yeah. Bro, let’s calm down, okay? Garrota’s trying to screw you over. He’s got some kinda plan for that envelope, no idea what he promised you for it…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u18_act_dialog_to_freedom_5">
        <text>Where’s that bastard?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u18_act_dialog_to_freedom_6">
        <text>In the complex… Our complex. He hired me to kill you… But I can’t do that.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u18_act_dialog_to_freedom_7">
        <text>You’re holding out on me. Why’d you change your mind?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u18_act_dialog_to_freedom_8">
        <text>Let me tell you everything, but in a safer spot, okay?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u18_act_dialog_to_freedom_9">
        <text>Okay.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u18_act_dialog_to_freedom_99">
        <text>No way, you little rat. You’re going down as an accomplice, you scum!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u20_act_dialog_to_freedom_0">
        <text>Here we are. This is our secret entrance to the testing complex… Not many know about it; the scientists asked us to keep it hush-hush. Garrota’s in there now.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u20_act_dialog_to_freedom_1">
        <text>You’re coming with me. I don’t trust you.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u20_act_dialog_to_freedom_2">
        <text>Fine, no problem. Just, uh, watch my back with that crazy trader, alright? He’s got big connections, and I don’t wanna be his next “target.”</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u20_act_dialog_to_freedom_3">
        <text>Yeah, deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u21_act_dialog_to_freedom_0">
        <text>Here’s our complex. Last time, before I went to… you know, get the envelope, well, you—he was at the bar counter. Don’t think he left the complex; the guys would’ve told me. He’s probably still here. So… am I free?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u21_act_dialog_to_freedom_1">
        <text>Scram, scram… You’re free, Freedom boy.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_assistent_hello_dialog_0">
        <text>Huh? Oh, yeah, old man. I’m all ears. What’s up?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_sherif_hello_dialog_0">
        <text>Don’t get mad, Voland. I’ll wait here like you asked. But if I sense something’s off, I’m coming for you, no offense!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_sherif_start_dialog_0">
        <text>So, we hitting this complex of yours and taking everyone out?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_sherif_start_dialog_1">
        <text>No, Sherif. You’re staying here, no discussion.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_sherif_start_dialog_2">
        <text>What? Why? It’d be better with both of us!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_sherif_start_dialog_3">
        <text>I’ve always been better at recon, don’t argue, Sherif. Plus, I need someone watching things out here… And if I don’t make it back, you’ll report it to the NII. We’ll keep in touch via radio!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_sherif_start_dialog_4">
        <text>You serious, you lost it? You’ll be back, where else you gonna go, Voland? Don’t make a drama out of this, I’m begging you. You’ll crawl out of any shit. What’d you say back in basic… Oh, right: “Life’s shit, but we’ve got a shovel!” Ha-ha…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_sherif_start_dialog_5">
        <text>Damn right, Sherif. Good luck to both of us!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_sherif_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Just come back, you hear? Tear ‘em apart, even if it’s through blood and guts, but come back.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_sherif_start_dialog_7">
        <text>Will do.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d30_assis_dialog_1_0">
        <text>How’d you end up here? Were you following me?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d30_assis_dialog_1_1">
        <text>Like I’ve got nothing better to do… Got bored at the Institute, plus my gut’s been acting weird, like I can sense shit now. I’m picking up on artifacts, swear to God… So, I was wandering, chasing this stench of death that’s been itching my nose. And here it is, in this godforsaken village… And my gut didn’t lie—found a shard of the Dreamcatcher!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d30_assis_dialog_1_2">
        <text>Come on, don’t make shit up. You were tailing me.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d30_assis_dialog_1_3">
        <text>Yes and no. I’m serious: I’m sensing all kinds of paranormal crap now, so I followed your trail. And look, it wasn’t for nothing. Saved your life, by the way.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d30_assis_dialog_1_4">
        <text>Well… Thanks for that.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d30_assis_dialog_2_0">
        <text>What was it like? I mean the dreams from that “Dreamcatcher”… You didn’t fall into an eternal sleep like the others.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d30_assis_dialog_2_1">
        <text>Ha! Wish I knew what hooked me to that paranormal bullshit. Maybe the artifact really chose me for its purposes, or maybe I was somehow immune to its effects… Though, immune sounds too badass… That thing fried my brain pretty good. But on the flip side, it gave me something bigger. I’ve changed, like, fundamentally. Picture this… A young, green student suddenly ends up in the Zone, scared of every rustle in the bushes and howling outside the camp walls… And now? You’re looking at a guy decked out in armor head to toe, with a machine gun slung over his shoulder. Think about it, how much has this guy seen? I wouldn’t believe it myself if it hadn’t happened to me… I traded flowers for a rifle and the Institute for the Zone. I’ve lost… a lot of people! But… damn it, I’ve gained so much too…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d30_assis_dialog_3_0">
        <text>You’re something else, kid. You’ve stirred up a lot in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d30_assis_dialog_3_1">
        <text>No point in being humble—I’ve thrown a hell of a party in the Zone, yeah. Ha-ha…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n10_pilot_final_dialog_0">
        <text>Colonel, we’re ready to pick you up right now. We’ll take the freshest routes, straight to the NII.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n10_pilot_final_dialog_1">
        <text>Take Nikita to the NII, I’m staying. %c[255,248,153,26][CONTINUE STORY]</text>
</string>
  <string id="scf_n10_pilot_final_dialog_11">
        <text>Alright. Then we’re moving out now. %c[255,1,255,255][END STORY]</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n10_pilot_final_dialog_111">
        <text>Wait here. I’ll be back soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n10_pilot_final_dialog_2">
        <text>Whoa… Got it, must be urgent. You sure?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n10_pilot_final_dialog_22">
        <text>Roger that, everyone’s ready. Boarding?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n10_pilot_final_dialog_3">
        <text>Yeah. If possible, let me know when you reach the base.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n10_pilot_final_dialog_33">
        <text>Yeah, let’s fly.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n10_pilot_final_dialog_444">
        <text>I haven’t decided yet. Hold on a bit, soldier.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n10_pilot_final_dialog_555">
        <text>Understood. Awaiting your decision, Comrade Voland.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_kolobok_quest_dialog_0">
        <text>You decided to stay… So you obviously want to stop the Prophet, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_kolobok_quest_dialog_1">
        <text>Right. Can’t let that psycho run loose.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_kolobok_quest_dialog_2">
        <text>Couldn’t agree more, Oleg. I’ve got intel that he’s got a deal going down with mercs in this village. Everything’s lining up nicely for us… Just need to figure out exactly where and when. Don’t wanna be late to that party.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_kolobok_quest_dialog_3">
        <text>Any ideas where to start looking?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_kolobok_quest_dialog_4">
        <text>Got a few. Down the slope from the church, in that little village, I saw some shady types poking around. Can’t say for sure if they were sectarians or mercs—couldn’t get a good look… But they were messing with something for a while. Wanna check it out?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_kolobok_quest_dialog_5">
        <text>Alright, let’s go take a look.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_sherif_dialog_0">
        <text>Where we headed, looking all pretty like that?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_sherif_dialog_1">
        <text>We? Buddy, I don’t want to drag you into this.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_sherif_dialog_11">
        <text>Sherif?! What the hell you doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_sherif_dialog_12">
        <text>Kolobok told me you found some basement in that village, then mercs jumped you. So I hauled ass here to check it out—and you vanished like you fell through the damn earth.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_sherif_dialog_13">
        <text>Got it… Listen, friend, I don’t want to pull you into all this…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_sherif_dialog_2">
        <text>Ha! You dragged me into this ages ago, brother. I can’t just sit on my ass knowing you’re gonna get yourself into some shit without your old pal!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_sherif_dialog_3">
        <text>I already put you and Molag in the line of fire once… I feel guilty as hell for all this, sorry.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_sherif_dialog_4">
        <text>Sure, it’s a damn shame about Molag… Kid was so young, eyes full of fire… But nobody forced us into anything, Voland. Those were our choices, his and mine. And if it weren’t for you, I’d still be rotting in that sectarian metro, brainwashed to hell. So do what you want—but I’m not leaving my friend in the lurch. Spill it—what’s your plan, and how do we eat it?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_sherif_dialog_5">
        <text>Ugh… Hang tight here. I need to find out what the mercs are hiding in that basement.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_sherif_hello_dialog_0">
        <text>I’ll wait for you here, brother. Check out the basement—I’ve got your back!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n18_kolobok_dialog_0">
        <text>Well, we’re alive, thank God. Probably my screw-up. Guess they spotted my tail and sent their goons.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n18_kolobok_dialog_1">
        <text>That’s right. The PDA confirms it. And yeah, you’re on point—they’re in cahoots with the sectarians, guarding something real precious in that basement. I think we need to scope out their base. If there’s a key to that door, it’s hidden good. We could blow it open, but then we’ll never see what’s inside that cellar…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n18_kolobok_dialog_2">
        <text>Yeah, you’re right, Voland. Alright, let’s do this: I’d love to help you search, but I need medical attention right now… Funny thing, I’m heading to that sectarian chick Citra to patch up, heh-heh. You good? What’s the plan?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n18_kolobok_dialog_3">
        <text>I’m off to dig for answers at the mercs’ base. You get patched up, good call. I’ll let you know if I find anything.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n18_kolobok_dialog_4">
        <text>Alright, Oleg. Watch yourself. I’ll get fixed up and come find you—just wait for me!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n18_kolobok_dialog_5">
        <text>For sure.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n18_kolobok_dialog_55">
        <text>Let me walk you back to camp. I need to swing by there too.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_kvant_cut_dialog_0">
        <text>Well, as you can see, I kept my word. Your people are alive and well.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_kvant_cut_dialog_1">
        <text>I see. Thanks, Kvant.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_kvant_cut_dialog_111">
        <text>Turn in the Prophet, and I’ll guarantee you protection, plus… after some legal hoops and good connections, we’ll let you walk…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_kvant_cut_dialog_112">
        <text>Ha-ha-ha! Listen, Voland, find him yourself if you need him. I’ll just drop a couple of rumors about him through my contacts, for my own safety. Our deal’s done, and that’s the end of our partnership. Good luck to you and your boys. Don’t call me again, ha-ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_kvant_cut_dialog_2">
        <text>No need for thanks. You owe me the compromising material, if you didn’t forget. Heh-heh…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_kvant_cut_dialog_3">
        <text>Yeah, you’re right.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_kvant_cut_dialog_33">
        <text>What’s with the look? Your people are free, and so are you. From here, we go our separate ways.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_kvant_cut_dialog_4">
        <text>Great, hand it over. Nice work, Oleg.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_kvant_cut_dialog_5">
        <text>Yeah, sure.</text>
</string>
  <string id="scf_n1_kvant_cut_dialog_6">
        <text>What’s your next move?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_kvant_cut_dialog_7">
        <text>I already told you. I’m gonna mess with the Prophet, heh-heh… Hope we don’t cross paths again. Goodbye.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_kvant_cut_dialog_8">
        <text>Goodbye…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_kvant_cut_dialog_88">
        <text>Watch yourself, Kvant… Next time we meet, I’ll be following the law. You’ll be a target for arrest, dead or alive. This ain’t a threat. Hope you get that.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_kvant_cut_dialog_99">
        <text>I know that damn well. That’s why I’m really hoping we never see each other again.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_final_nikita_dialog_0">
        <text>Reporting for duty, big brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_final_nikita_dialog_1">
        <text>Kid… I don’t even have the energy to rant about what a little shit you are…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_final_nikita_dialog_2">
        <text>Hah… Yeah, I know, my bad, Comrade SENIOR Colonel. Heh-heh…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_final_nikita_dialog_3">
        <text>Just tell me why? You ran off to the Zone—contract, captivity. Did you think about your son and wife? You know what they’re going through? You’re a damn punk, got it? You abandoned your family.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_final_nikita_dialog_4">
        <text>I had to join that expedition, Oleg.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_final_nikita_dialog_5">
        <text>What the hell do you mean you *had* to?! Do you even get what you’re doing?! I scoured the whole damn Zone to pull your ass out! Your wife’s crying every day and night! Your son’s growing up without a dad! And you’re what? You *had* to?! Had to join that expedition?! Where’s your expedition now, huh?! You fucked it up! And the scientists you were supposed to protect—they’ve been dead for ages!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_final_nikita_dialog_6">
        <text>Listen, I… Yeah, Oleg, I get what you’re saying. Hold on, calm down… The scientists from the expedition are alive. We just got split up when the sectarians hit us at the school… We were supposed to meet them later at an evac point, which, by the way, is in this village.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_final_nikita_dialog_7">
        <text>Don’t you dare tell me you’re still going to look for them. No, that’s it. You’re going home, no discussion. I’ll drag you to that chopper by your ear if I have to. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_final_nikita_dialog_8">
        <text>Uh-huh… Maybe call the chopper first, yeah? The scientists are out there alone, and you’re probably right, no guarantee they’re even alive…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_final_nikita_dialog_9">
        <text>Stay put, right here, got it? I’m calling the chopper.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_citra_hello_dialog_0">
        <text>Hey, Oleg. How’s it going?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_kolobok_hello_dialog_0">
        <text>Yo, Oleg. Reporting for duty, you could say. Heh-heh…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_nikita_hello_dialog_0">
        <text>Well, hey there, Oleg.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_sherif_hello_dialog_0">
        <text>Voland! Oleg! Ha-ha! Good to see you, brother!</text>
</string>
<string id="und_bar_self_o_stalkers_and_bandits_dialog_0">
        <text>You let both stalkers and bandits in? And… they don’t get into it with each other?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_bar_self_o_stalkers_and_bandits_dialog_1">
        <text>As you can see, the bar’s got rules. Break ‘em, and we’ll shoot you to hell ourselves. Otherwise, it’s all calm and quiet. The bar’s a safe spot. As for those two feuding factions—they leave their grudges and beefs at the door ‘cause they’ve got business here that makes ‘em behave disciplined and proper.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u14_tesak_self_mutants_dialog_0">
        <text>Why do you keep mutants in cages?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u14_tesak_self_mutants_dialog_1">
        <text>We run experiments on ‘em. Freud’s playing mad scientist… We’re not thrilled about it, honestly, but if it pays off, we’ll make some serious cash from the NII.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u14_tesak_self_sektants_dialog_0">
        <text>Where’d you get sectarians in your cells?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u14_tesak_self_sektants_dialog_1">
        <text>Those creeps crawl around everywhere. We nabbed a couple alive and dragged ‘em here.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u15_sherif_dialog_0">
        <text>Well, damn… This bar’s something else, huh? So, you got the envelope?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u15_sherif_dialog_1">
        <text>Yeah. Just gotta hand it to the trader. Keycard’s already in my pocket.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u15_sherif_dialog_2">
        <text>That’s the spirit. Heading back to the surface?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u15_sherif_dialog_3">
        <text>Yeah, let’s go!</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u15_sherif_dialog_33">
        <text>You guys go ahead, I’ll catch up. Got a couple things to handle in this bar…</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u15_sherif_dialog_44">
        <text>Cool. We’ll wait for you at camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u15_sherif_dialog_55">
        <text>Roger, see you soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u15_tesak_dialog_0">
        <text>Turns out the sectarian we had locked up had explosives in his gut. That idiot ate ‘em… Shit, lucky we didn’t get blown to hell. About the case… Sorry, probably freaked you out. Here’s the envelope, pass it to the trader. Seems like this job’s real important to you. Why’s none of my business, so don’t bother explaining, friend.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u15_tesak_dialog_1">
        <text>Thanks. Here’s the case. Glad we’re on the same page.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u15_tesak_dialog_2">
        <text>Well said. Good luck, Voland. Swing by sometime, you’ll be a VIP, heh-heh.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u15_tesak_dialog_3">
        <text>Definitely. Good we understood each other.</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_u10_tesak_quest_dialog_0">
        <text>Ugh… Damn bastards… Those fuckin’ sectarians…</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_u10_tesak_quest_dialog_1">
        <text>Hold on, I’ll patch you up. %c[255,248,153,26][help him up]</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_u10_tesak_quest_dialog_11">
        <text>Wait, I’ll be right back. %c[0,140,140,140][..leave..]</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_u8_tesak_quest_dialog_0">
        <text>From Garrota, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_u8_tesak_quest_dialog_1">
        <text>Yeah. Brought your “mail”…</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_u8_tesak_quest_dialog_2">
        <text>Oh yeah? And what’d you bring me?</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_u8_tesak_quest_dialog_22">
        <text>Nothing… Guess I got the wrong address, I’m out. %c[0,140,140,140][..leave..]</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_u8_tesak_quest_dialog_3">
        <text>Huh? You don’t know? I brought a case.</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_u8_tesak_quest_dialog_4">
        <text>A case, huh? Ahem… That’s good. Just one hitch.</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_u8_tesak_quest_dialog_5">
        <text>What? What are you talking about?</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_u8_tesak_quest_dialog_6">
        <text>Someone already brought me a case.</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_u8_tesak_quest_dialog_7">
        <text>Bullshit. I’ve got the case right here, look. %c[255,248,153,26][show case]</text>
</string>

	
</string_table>	