<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<!-- Secret Developments -->
<string id="scf_gauss_sxema_task_title">
    <text>Secret Developments: deliver the schematic to the Research Institute</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_gauss_sxema_task_descr">
    <text>The secret development of item "No.62" has long been known, and advanced prototypes have been used by our military. Still, the Research Institute would benefit from having this schematic. I found it near a crashed helicopter in the vicinity of the settlement.</text>
</string>

<!-- Dreamcatcher Quest -->
<string id="scf_dreamcatcher_task_title">
    <text>Dreamcatcher: await news from the Assistant</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_dreamcatcher_task_descr">
    <text>The Assistant promised to share information once he learns anything about the Dreamcatcher artifact fragment, which I discovered in the old complex.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_dreamcatcher_task_title2">
    <text>Dreamcatcher: meet the Assistant</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_dreamcatcher_task_descr2">
    <text>The Assistant has some news regarding the artifact and the sectarians. I need to meet him to find out the details.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_dreamcatcher_task_title3">
    <text>Dreamcatcher: meet the Assistant at night near Chernobyl</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_dreamcatcher_task_descr3">
    <text>The Assistant requested help in locating the second fragment of the Dreamcatcher. He will wait at night near the industrial plant in Chernobyl.</text>
</string>

<!-- Secret of the Basement -->
<string id="scf_podval_shakala_task_title">
    <text>Secret of the Basement: investigate the village cellar</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_podval_shakala_task_descr">
    <text>I found a key that likely opens the basement in the village. I need to investigate it carefully.</text>
</string>

<!-- Collider Final Tasks -->
<string id="cld_final_task_title">
    <text>Collider: examine the Prophet's body</text>
</string>
<string id="cld_final_task_descr">
    <text>The Prophet may have a key card for the control room. I need to inspect him and gain access to the system.</text>
</string>
<string id="cld_final_task_title2">
    <text>Collider: disable the security system</text>
</string>
<string id="cld_final_task_descr2">
    <text>I must quickly shut down the security system, or the installation here could trigger a catastrophic event.</text>
</string>

<!-- Hunting Sectarians -->
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_title3">
    <text>Hunting Sectarians: meet with Artem</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_descr3">
    <text>The ambush has been neutralized. Now I need to assist Artem.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_title4">
    <text>Hunting Sectarians: scout the mercenary base</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_descr4">
    <text>Fabricate's PDA reveals a link between the mercenaries and the sectarians. Their base might hold further clues.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_title5">
    <text>Hunting Sectarians: investigate the complex basement</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_descr5">
    <text>The basement of the military complex, home to Jackal's mercenaries, could contain valuable information.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_title6">
    <text>Hunting Sectarians: explore the underground complex</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_descr6">
    <text>Unexpectedly, I encountered the Assistant here, and even more surprisingly—the Dreamcatcher artifact itself. I need to investigate the complex's basement thoroughly.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_title7">
    <text>Hunting Sectarians: acquire a key card</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_descr7">
    <text>There appears to be a secured underground section beneath the military base. I need a key card to enter.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_title8">
    <text>Hunting Sectarians: descend into the underground complex</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_descr8">
    <text>With the access card, I can now enter the Collider underground complex.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_title9">
    <text>Hunting Sectarians: investigate the complex</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_descr9">
    <text>The mercenaries and sectarians are clearly plotting something. I must thoroughly examine the complex.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_title10">
    <text>Hunting Sectarians: shut down the collider</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_descr10">
    <text>The Prophet has activated the collider, and it seems highly dangerous. I must stop it immediately!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_title11">
    <text>Hunting Sectarians: eliminate the Prophet</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_descr11">
    <text>I need to finish off the sectarian leader before he causes more harm.</text>
</string>

<!-- Trap Quest -->
<string id="scf_n17_task_title">
    <text>Trap: track down and eliminate the sniper</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n17_task_descr">
    <text>Thankfully, Artem survived the attack. But I must deal with the sniper who targeted him.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n17_task_title2">
    <text>Trap: inspect the sniper's body</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n17_task_descr2">
    <text>The mercenaries clearly set up an ambush here. I need to examine the sniper; he might hold valuable information.</text>
</string>

<!-- Spatial Bubble / Drone Mystery -->
<string id="scf_prostranbubble_task_title">
    <text>Spatial Bubble: consult Bes about the anomaly</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_prostranbubble_task_descr">
    <text>Bes, being a seasoned "Digger", might know something about these anomalies. I should talk to him.</text>
</string>

<!-- Cordon Task -->
<string id="scf_n17_task2_title">
    <text>Cordon: protect Artem from mercenaries</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n17_task2_descr">
    <text>I must eliminate the mercenaries attacking Artem and myself before it's too late.</text>
</string>

<!-- Leads Quest -->
<string id="scf_n16_task_title">
    <text>Leads: investigate the village</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_task_title2">
    <text>Leads: examine the suspicious door</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_task_descr">
    <text>According to Artem "Kolobok", a deal between the sectarians and mercenaries is set to happen here. The Prophet might even attend. Near the village church, suspicious individuals have been spotted. I need to investigate carefully to uncover useful clues about the sectarians.</text>
</string>

<!-- Drone Mystery / Spatial Bubble -->
<string id="scf_bespilot_tains_task_title">
    <text>Drone Mystery: examine the radio beacons</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_tains_task_descr">
    <text>The drone's memory module contained four radio beacons. I need to investigate them to understand what's happening.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_tains_task_title2">
    <text>Drone Mystery: study the spatial bubble</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_tains_task_descr2">
    <text>After activating all the locators, an anomalous surge occurred at the village tower. I must investigate the newly appeared spatial bubble.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_tains_task_title3">
    <text>Drone Mystery: uncover the drone's secret</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_tains_task_descr3">
    <text>An unmanned drone is trapped inside the spatial bubble. I suspect it is the same drone that was seen in the river.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_tains_task_title4">
    <text>Drone Mystery: request a decoder from the scientists</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_tains_task_descr4">
    <text>To close the spatial bubble, I need a decoder. Such a device can only be obtained from the scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_tains_task_title5">
    <text>Drone Mystery: retrieve the decoder from Phobos</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_tains_task_descr5">
    <text>Professor Ozersky allowed me to take a decoder from Phobos at the warehouse. This will help in closing the anomaly.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_tains_task_title6">
    <text>Drone Mystery: deactivate the spatial anomaly</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_tains_task_descr6">
    <text>I must use the decoder provided by the scientists to close the spatial bubble before it grows uncontrollably.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_tains_task_title7">
    <text>Drone Mystery: report to Bes</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_tains_task_descr7">
    <text>With the spatial bubble successfully closed, I should inform Bes so he can rest easy.</text>
</string>

<!-- Hunting Sectarians -->
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_title2">
    <text>Hunting Sectarians: track down and neutralize the Prophet</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_descr2">
    <text>To end the threat of the sectarians in the Zone, I must find and stop their leader—the Prophet. Stopping him will collapse their plans and greatly reduce the danger they pose.</text>
</string>

<!-- Hunting Sectarians -->
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_title">
    <text>Hunting Sectarians: coordinate with Kolobok</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_mest_task_descr">
    <text>Nikita is safe, and I decided to stay in the Zone. My priority now is to track down the Prophet and stop him at any cost. Kolobok (Artem) contacted me—he also wants to find the Prophet and has information that could help. I should meet with him to combine our efforts.</text>
</string>

<!-- Anomalous Device / Drone -->
<string id="scf_bespilot_task_title">
    <text>Anomalous Device: investigate the drone disappearance</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_task_descr">
    <text>An unmanned aerial vehicle that crashed in the river of Zalesye mysteriously vanished before my eyes. I need to examine the spot where it supposedly fell—something anomalous is at play.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_task_title2">
    <text>Anomalous Device: show the memory module to Lyokha</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_task_descr2">
    <text>At the river where the drone disappeared, I recovered a wet, yet intact (locked) memory module. I should show it to Lyokha, the Digger and technician—he might be able to unlock it.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_task_title3">
    <text>Anomalous Device: wait for memory module to be unlocked</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_task_descr3">
    <text>I need to wait while Lyokha works on unlocking the memory module.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_task_title4">
    <text>Anomalous Device: talk to Lyokha</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_task_descr4">
    <text>Lyokha informed me that he has successfully unlocked the memory module I found. I should review its contents.</text>
</string>

<!-- Strange Woman / NPC dialogs -->
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_citra_task_title">
    <text>Strange Woman: ask Tsitra why she stayed behind</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_citra_task_descr">
    <text>Tsitra seems to have left the sectarian group, but why didn't she leave with Quantum? I need to ask her.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_kolobok_task_title">
    <text>Soldier to Soldier: check on Kolobok</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_kolobok_task_descr">
    <text>Kolobok escaped captivity with my brother and friend. I should speak with him and see how he’s doing.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_sherif_task_title">
    <text>Old Comrade: check on Sheriff</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_sherif_task_descr">
    <text>Sheriff survived and seems sane. I need to talk to him and ensure everything is alright.</text>
</string>

<!-- Final Effort / Attribute Story -->
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_true_final_task_title">
    <text>Final Effort: talk to Nikita</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_true_final_task_descr">
    <text>Nikita is safe. The Sheriff is alive. Everything seems in order… now only the final steps remain.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_true_final_task_title2">
    <text>Final Effort: call the helicopter</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_true_final_task_descr2">
    <text>It’s time to bring Nikita home. The Zone won’t be easy on him, so he must leave safely.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_true_final_task_title3">
    <text>Final Push: wait for the evacuation helicopter</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_atribut_true_final_task_title4">
    <text>Final Push: speak with the pilot</text>
</string>

<!-- Running Errands -->
<string id="mtrs_k5_task_title4">
    <text>Running Errands: deliver the compromising data to Quantum</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k5_task_descr4">
    <text>It’s finally over… the information has been handed over.</text>
</string>

<!-- Mercenary / Jackal -->
<string id="kn_a5_mercs_zasada_task_title">
    <text>Contract for a Good Life: escape or fight the mercenaries</text>
</string>
<string id="kn_a5_mercs_zasada_task_descr">
    <text>Mercenaries started hunting me in the canyon. Who ordered this? I doubt it was Hack. I need to find out the truth personally.</text>
</string>
<string id="kn_a5_mercs_zasada_task_title2">
    <text>Contract for a Good Life: speak with Hack</text>
</string>
<string id="kn_a5_mercs_zasada_task_title3">
    <text>Contract for a Good Life: confront Mercenary Jackal</text>
</string>
<string id="kn_a5_mercs_zasada_task_descr3">
    <text>Jackal’s group of mercenaries follows sectarian orders, and one of those orders was aimed at me. I must deal with him.</text>
</string>

<!-- Ghosts of the Aquapark -->
<string id="flst_glori_task_title">
    <text>Ghosts of the Aquapark: meet Gloria</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_descr">
    <text>Professor Bernad asked me to help his colleague Gloria scan the anomalous psy-effects in the aquapark. Reports mention a strange psy-field… possibly ghosts.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_title2">
    <text>Ghosts of the Aquapark: meet Gloria at the aquapark</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_title3">
    <text>Ghosts of the Aquapark: wait while Gloria adjusts the scanner</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_descr3">
    <text>I need to wait until Gloria finishes calibrating the scanner.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_title4">
    <text>Ghosts of the Aquapark: talk to Gloria</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_descr4">
    <text>The scanner detected strange, eerie sounds. I need to consult Gloria about these anomalies.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_title5">
    <text>Ghosts of the Aquapark: inspect the second floor</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_descr5">
    <text>The device picked up odd conversations coming from the aquapark. The pool seems to be the source.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_title6">
    <text>Ghosts of the Aquapark: eliminate the poltergeist</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_descr6">
    <text>A poltergeist is causing disturbances in the pool. I must eliminate it.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_title6_6">
    <text>Ghosts of the Aquapark: destroy anomalous spheres</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_descr6_6">
    <text>Several aggressive anomalous spheres are in the pool. I need to destroy them to stop further incidents.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_title7">
    <text>Ghosts of the Aquapark: return to Gloria</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_descr7">
    <text>After destroying the poltergeists, I blacked out. I need to return to Gloria and assess the situation.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_title8">
    <text>Ghosts of the Aquapark: locate Gloria</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_title9">
    <text>Ghosts of the Aquapark: follow the woman's scream</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_descr9">
    <text>I heard a woman scream—likely Gloria! I must hurry to help her.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_title9_9">
    <text>Ghosts of the Aquapark: help Gloria stand up</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_descr9_9">
    <text>Gloria seems exhausted. I found her and need to help her regain her strength.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_title10">
    <text>Ghosts of the Aquapark: locate Gloria's scanner</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_descr10">
    <text>The poltergeists likely took Gloria’s device. I need to search the aquapark to retrieve it.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_title11">
    <text>Ghosts of the Aquapark: return the device to Gloria</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_descr11">
    <text>I recovered the device from the pool; now I need to give it back to Gloria.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_title12">
    <text>Ghosts of the Aquapark: report to Professor Bernad</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_descr12">
    <text>The scanning task is complete. Time to report to Professor Bernad and claim the reward.</text>
</string>

<!-- Cave Research / Riddick -->
<string id="flst_ridik_task_title">
    <text>Cave Research: Report Your Readiness to Riddick</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_task_descr">
    <text>Docent Riddick requested my assistance with exploring the underground caves beneath the complex. He warned that only someone equipped with a sealed suit or exoskeleton can survive there—the air is heavily contaminated and the chemical anomalies could kill in seconds.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_task_title2">
    <text>Cave Research: Follow the Scientist</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_task_descr2">
    <text>I need to accompany and protect Riddick while he conducts his research in the caves.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_task_title3">
    <text>Cave Research: Protect the Scientist</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_task_title4">
    <text>Cave Research: Talk to Riddick</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_task_descr4">
    <text>Riddick has finished his work in the caves. I need to meet him and report my findings.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_task_typical_task_show_show_1_available_task">
    <text>Cave Research</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_task_typical_task_show_show_1_typical_task">
    <text>Assist Riddick in exploring the caves under the complex</text>
</string>

<!-- Secret Catacombs / Zalesye -->
<string id="chu_k6_vhod_katakomb_task_title_0">
    <text>Secret Catacombs: Locate the Underground Entrance</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_k6_vhod_katakomb_task_title2">
    <text>Secret Catacombs: Reach Zalesye Through the Catacombs</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_k6_vhod_katakomb_task_title">
    <text>Secret Catacombs: Descend Into the Underground</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_k6_vhod_katakomb_task_descr">
    <text>Quantum said the safest place, where the Prophet is unlikely to search, is near the village of Zalesye. But recent anomalies have blocked all surface routes. The only way is through the unexplored underground catacombs.</text>
</string>

<!-- Errands / Compromising Material -->
<string id="mtrs_k5_task_title">
    <text>Errand: Retrieve the Buried Compromising Material</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k5_task_descr">
    <text>Artyom (Kolobok) buried the compromising material on the sectarians in the graveyard of the unexplored territories. I need to recover it quickly to protect my friends.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k5_task_title2">
    <text>Errand: Negotiate the Deal</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k5_task_descr2">
    <text>The material is now in my possession, but I must meet the sectarians to discuss the deal. I won’t let them deceive me.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k5_task_title3">
    <text>Errand: Arrive at the Meeting Point</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_k5_task_descr3">
    <text>Kvant is waiting at the designated location with the compromising material. I need to reach him safely.</text>
</string>

<!-- Rescue Center / Kolobok & Citra -->
<string id="kn_k1_task_title">
  <text>Rescue Center: Talk to Citra</text>
</string>
<string id="kn_k1_task_descr">
  <text>Kvant said that to save my brother Nikita and my friend Sheriff, I need to comply with his temporary truce. First, I need to talk to Citra at the sectarians' base in the metro.</text>
</string>
<string id="kn_k1_task_title2">
  <text>Rescue Center: Talk to Kolobok</text>
</string>
<string id="kn_k1_task_descr2">
  <text>I need to retrieve the compromising material Kolobok hid. My first step is to talk to him.</text>
</string>

<!-- Cursed Church / Psy-effect -->
<string id="chu_a2_task_title">
  <text>Cursed Church: Give Consent to Help</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a2_task_descr">
  <text>I need to tell Bes that I am ready to assist in dealing with the psy-radiation in the church.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a2_task_title2">
  <text>Cursed Church: Cover Bes</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a2_task_descr2">
  <text>I need to protect Bes while he sets up the device.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a2_task_title3">
  <text>Cursed Church: Eliminate the Poltergeists</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a2_task_descr3">
  <text>The psy-radiation seems to have subsided, but poltergeists remain. I must destroy them!</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a2_task_title4">
  <text>Cursed Church: Find the Source of the Psy-effect</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a2_task_descr4">
  <text>Bes has been affected by psy-radiation. I need to locate its source and neutralize it quickly!</text>
</string>

<!-- Strange Affairs / Bes -->
<string id="chu_a1_task_title">
  <text>Strange Affairs: Talk to Bes</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_task_descr">
  <text>Bes asked me not to enter the church alone and to help him investigate the paranormal activity. I need to talk to him and understand the situation.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_task_title2">
  <text>Strange Affairs: Find the Missing Scientists</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_task_descr2">
  <text>Bes mentioned that poltergeists have occupied the church, preventing anyone from entering safely. I need to locate the scientists' device to detect psy-activity, which may help us track the restless spirits.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_task_title2_2">
  <text>Strange Affairs: Retrieve the Device</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_task_descr2_2">
  <text>I found the scientists' device. I need to retrieve it for further investigation.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_task_title3">
  <text>Strange Affairs: Show the Device to Bes</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_task_descr3">
  <text>I need to show the scientists' device to Bes so he can use it to detect anomalous psy-activity.</text>
</string>

<!-- Reason of Conscience / Nikita & Prophet -->
<string id="nii_e56_bad_task_title">
  <text>Reason of Conscience: Wait for Night</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e56_bad_task_descr">
  <text>I made my choice. I need to wait for night to hand over the secret documents to the Prophet's associate.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e56_bad_task_title2">
  <text>Reason of Conscience: Meet with the Sectarian</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e56_bad_task_descr2">
  <text>At night, I must deliver the secret document to the Prophet's contact.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e56_bad_task_title3">
  <text>Reason of Conscience: Return to the Prophet</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e56_bad_task_descr3">
  <text>I did everything as instructed by the Prophet... I hope he will release my brother Nikita and my friend Sheriff.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e56_bad_task_title4">
  <text>Reason of Conscience: Help Nikita Stand Up</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e56_bad_task_descr4">
  <text>The Prophet lied to me. He killed Sheriff... and Nikita is badly wounded. I must help him stand.</text>
</string>

<string id="nii_e56_good_task_title">
  <text>Reason of Conscience: Talk to Colonel Koval'sky</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e56_good_task_descr">
  <text>I made my choice. I need to coordinate with the military to storm the sectarians' base.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e56_good_task_title2">
  <text>Reason of Conscience: Give the Signal of Readiness</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e56_good_task_descr2">
  <text>My brother and friend might already be dead... but I have nothing to lose. Together with Colonel Koval'sky and the military detachment, I will attack the sectarians' base and eliminate the Prophet first.</text>
</string>

<!-- No Mercy / Metro -->
<string id="okr_e60_ataka_metro_task_title">
  <text>No Mercy: Descend into the Metro</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e60_ataka_metro_task_descr">
  <text>It’s time to end the sectarians. There will be no mercy; I will eliminate everyone in my path.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e60_ataka_metro_task_title2">
  <text>No Mercy: Chase the Prophet</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e60_ataka_metro_task_descr2">
  <text>The Prophet is fleeing through the metro tunnels. He won’t get far—I’m coming for him. He will pay for everything.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e60_ataka_metro_task_title3">
  <text>No Mercy: Finish off the Prophet</text>
</string>

<!-- Difficult Choice / Prophet vs Institute -->
<string id="okr_e54_hight_choice_task_title_0">
  <text>Difficult Choice: Go to the Research Institute</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e54_hight_choice_task_title">
  <text>Difficult Choice: Follow the Prophet’s Orders or Betray the Institute</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e54_hight_choice_task_descr">
  <text>My brother Nikita and my friend Sheriff are prisoners of the Prophet. If I defy him, they will die. But if I betray the institute, I become a traitor. I must make a choice.</text>
</string>

<!-- Revolution / Kvant -->
<string id="okr_e51_kvant_kanion_task_title">
  <text>Revolution: Meet with Kvant or Turn Him In</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e51_kvant_kanion_task_title2">
  <text>Revolution: Talk to Kvant</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e51_kvant_kanion_task_descr">
  <text>Kvant, a sectarian, wants to overthrow the Prophet. Can I trust him? Maybe this is my only chance to save Nikita and Sheriff—or perhaps I should betray him to the Prophet. I need to decide carefully.</text>
</string>

<!-- Solving Problems / Military -->
<string id="okr_help_colab_army_task_title">
  <text>Solving Problems: Request Military Assistance</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_help_colab_army_task_descr">
  <text>This is risky. Asking the military for help might provoke the Prophet to kill Nikita and Sheriff. But it could also be the only way. I need to choose carefully.</text>
</string>

<!-- Chains and Shackles / Prophet -->
<string id="okr2_e15_task_title7">
  <text>Chains and Shackles: Inspect the Underground Complex</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_task_descr7">
  <text>The generator is running, and the path to the “sacred place” is open. I need to inspect the area and report back to the Prophet.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_task_title8">
  <text>Chains and Shackles: Contact the Prophet</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_task_descr8">
  <text>I need to get in touch with the Prophet.</text>
</string>

<!-- Mushroom Field / Danya -->
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_show_1_available_task">
  <text>Anomalous Mushrooms</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_show_1_typical_task">
  <text>Unravel the mystery of the glowing mushrooms.</text>
</string>

<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_title">
  <text>Mushroom Field: Meet Danya before Dawn</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_descr">
  <text>I need to meet Danya before dawn to observe the glowing anomalous mushrooms together.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_title2">
  <text>Mushroom Field: Follow Danya</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_descr2">
  <text>Danya led me to a field of anomalous mushrooms. I should cover him, just in case...</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_title3">
  <text>Mushroom Field: Cover Danya</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_title4">
  <text>Mushroom Field: Bring Danya to Consciousness</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_descr4">
  <text>Danya seems to have succumbed to the mushrooms' fumes and passed out. I need to wake him up.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_title5">
  <text>Mushroom Field: Talk to Danya</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_title6">
  <text>Mushroom Field: Escape from the Room</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_descr6">
  <text>After passing out near the mushroom field, Danya and I are trapped in a room. Trying to leave only returns us back. This must be a teleport anomaly—but who activated it and why?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_title7">
  <text>Mushroom Field: Escape from the Anomaly</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_title8">
  <text>Mushroom Field: Exit the Building</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_descr8">
  <text>The teleport anomaly seems to have deactivated. I need to escape from this house with Danya.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_title9">
  <text>Mushroom Field: Escape from the Mysterious House</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_task_descr9">
  <text>Something—or someone—is preventing us from leaving this building. We must find a way out.</text>
</string>

<!-- Expedition / Athena -->
<string id="okr2_afina_start_task_show_1_available_task">
  <text>Expedition</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_start_task_show_1_typical_task">
  <text>Help Athena with her problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_start_task_title">
  <text>Expedition: Gather a Team for Athena</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_start_task_descr">
  <text>Athena asked me to gather a two-person team for an expedition to the underground laboratory beneath the industrial plant. I should ask around—maybe someone will join.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_start_task_title2">
  <text>Expedition: Find the Second Team Member</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_start_task_descr2">
  <text>I have already found one member for Athena’s expedition. Now I need to find the second person.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_start_task_title3">
  <text>Expedition: Talk to Athena</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_start_task_descr3">
  <text>I have gathered two people for the expedition. I need to discuss the next steps with Athena.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_start_task_title4">
  <text>Expedition: Inform Athena of Readiness</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_start_task_descr4">
  <text>I need to tell Athena that I am ready to start the expedition.</text>
</string>

<!-- Laboratory / Athena -->
<string id="bunk_a1_task_title">
  <text>Laboratory: Follow Athena</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_task_title2">
  <text>Laboratory: Cover Athena</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_task_title3">
  <text>Laboratory: Talk to Athena</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_task_descr">
  <text>We descended into the underground laboratory beneath the industrial plant. Athena will explore it, and I need to assist her.</text>
</string>

<!-- Wonder Fish / Fishboy -->
<string id="okr2_fishboy_task_title">
  <text>Wonder Fish: Inspect the Area</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_task_descr">
  <text>I need to inspect the marshy area—the mutant could be nearby.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_task_title2">
  <text>Wonder Fish: Inform the Stalker</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_task_descr2">
  <text>The mutant was nearby all along and appears to have died from blood loss. I should report this to the stalker.</text>
</string>

<!-- Black Data / Flash Drive -->
<string id="okr2_p3_fleshka_task_title">
  <text>Black Data: Insert the Flash Drive</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_p3_fleshka_task_descr">
  <text>The flash drive I found in the safe near the stalkers' camp might contain some secrets. I need to insert it into the laptop.</text>
</string>

<!-- Chains and Shackles / Power Generator -->
<string id="okr2_e15_task_title">
  <text>Chains and Shackles: Reach the Coordinates</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_task_descr">
  <text>The Prophet needs me to clear the entrance to the "sacred place."</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_task_title2">
  <text>Chains and Shackles: Restore Power to the Hermetic Door</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_task_descr2">
  <text>I need to restore the power supply to the door leading to the "sacred place."</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_task_title3">
  <text>Chains and Shackles: Fix the Power Generator</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_task_descr3">
  <text>I need to fix the power generator. For this, I should find a technician capable of handling it.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_task_title4">
  <text>Chains and Shackles: Assist the Technician</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_task_descr4">
  <text>I need to help Technar with repairing the generator.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_task_title5">
  <text>Chains and Shackles: Start the Power Generator</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_task_title6">
  <text>Chains and Shackles: Check the Hermetic Door Operation</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_task_descr6">
  <text>The power generator is running. I must ensure the hermetic door is functioning and then report to the Prophet.</text>
</string>

<!-- Underground Inhabitants / Mutant -->
<string id="lx24_e34_monster_task_title">
  <text>Underground Inhabitants: Eliminate the Mutant</text>
</string>
<string id="lx24_e34_monster_task_descr">
  <text>It seems a mutant is responsible for the hermetic door being closed.</text>
</string>

<!-- Golden Hands / Technician -->
<string id="lx24_texnar_task_title">
  <text>Golden Hands: Contact the Technician</text>
</string>
<string id="lx24_texnar_task_descr">
  <text>I need to repair the generator. I must contact the technician, "Technar," although the underground connection is poor.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx24_texnar_task_title2">
  <text>Golden Hands: Wait for the Technician</text>
</string>
<string id="lx24_texnar_task_descr2">
  <text>I need to wait for Technar to arrive.</text>
</string>

<!-- Underground Again / Flooded Generator -->
<string id="okr2_e16_task_title">
  <text>Underground Again: Descend into the Flooded Area</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e16_task_descr">
  <text>The generator powering the hermetic door is located in the flooded underground.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e16_task_title2">
  <text>Underground Again: Find the Power Generator</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e16_task_descr2">
  <text>I need to locate the generator in the flooded underground and restart it to power the hermetic door.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e16_task_title3">
  <text>Underground Again: Inspect the Power Generator</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e16_task_descr3">
  <text>I need to inspect the power generator—it may be malfunctioning due to water damage.</text>
</string>

<!-- Control Panel / Valve -->
<string id="okr2_e17_caykard_task_title">
  <text>Control Panel Access: Find Key-Card "V-3"</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e17_caykard_task_title2">
  <text>Control Panel Access: Take Key-Card "V-3"</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e17_caykard_task_descr">
  <text>To activate the water drain control panel, the V3 key-card is required.</text>
</string>

<string id="okr2_ventil_e17_task_title">
  <text>Emergency Situation: Find the Control Panel</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_ventil_e17_task_title2">
  <text>Emergency Situation: Activate the Control Panel</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_ventil_e17_task_title3">
  <text>Emergency Situation: Turn the Valve to Drain Water</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_ventil_e17_task_descr">
  <text>To access the lower floors, I need to locate the emergency water control panel. Turning it off should lower the water level.</text>
</string>

<!-- MTRS / Prophet Tasks -->
<string id="mtrs_e10_task_title">
  <text>Crusade: Go to the Surface</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e10_task_descr">
  <text>The Prophet claims he will spare the lives of my brother Nikita and friend Sheriff. In return, I must carry out his orders.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e3_task_title">
  <text>The Price of Friendship: Help the Sheriff</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e3_task_descr">
  <text>The Sheriff may be brainwashed or in shock from Molag's death. I must help him.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e3_task_title2">
  <text>The Price of Friendship: Fulfill the Prophet's Conditions</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e2_task_title">
  <text>One Blood: Save the Younger Brother</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e2_task_descr">
  <text>My brother Nikita is held hostage by the sect members. I must rescue him.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e2_task_title2">
  <text>One Blood: Talk to the Prophet</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e2_task_title3">
  <text>One Blood: Fulfill the Prophet's Conditions</text>
</string>

<string id="mtrs_e4_task_title">
  <text>Captives: Find a Way Out</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e4_task_descr">
  <text>The sect members are holding us in a cage. I need to escape—but what comes next?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e4_task_title2">
  <text>Captives: Ask About My Brother</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e4_task_descr2">
  <text>My brother is a captive. Their leader, the "Prophet," will reveal what I need to know.</text>
</string>

<string id="mtrs_e7_box_task_title">
  <text>Unloading: Retrieve Personal Belongings</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e7_box_task_descr">
  <text>The sect members took all my equipment, weapons, ammo, and armor. I need to reclaim them.</text>
</string>

<!-- OFC / Nikita's Wife -->
<string id="ofc_o1_task_title">
  <text>Remembrance: Find Nikita's Wife</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_o1_task_title2">
  <text>Remembrance: Answer the Call</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_o1_task_title3">
  <text>Remembrance: Leave the Building</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_o1_task_descr">
  <text>I learned that my brother Nikita planned an expedition to the Zone. I must interrupt my vacation and return. Phones are off, doors locked... Maybe his wife Michelle at the Research Institute knows something.</text>
</string>

<!-- Metro Line / Sect Base -->
<string id="mtrs_f1_start_task_title">
  <text>Metro Line: Reach the Sect Base</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f1_start_task_title2">
  <text>Metro Line: Apply Voltage</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f1_start_task_title3">
  <text>Metro Line: Break Through to the Sect Base</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f1_start_task_title4">
  <text>Metro Line: Eliminate the Sect Member</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f1_start_task_descr">
  <text>We descended into the metro beneath the sanatorium. I must locate the sect base, as my brother is likely held there.</text>
</string>

<!-- Ticket to the Morgue / Secret Station -->
<string id="flst_u22_sanatorie_task_title">
  <text>Ticket to the Morgue: Go to the Secret Station</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_u22_sanatorie_task_descr">
  <text>I have the key card for the underground station beneath the sanatorium. Molag mentioned the sect base is there and Nikita is captive. I must rescue him.</text>
</string>

<!-- Honestly Lying / Garrota -->
<string id="flst_u22_sektant_pryff_task_title">
  <text>Honestly Lying: Verify Garrota's Words</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_u22_sektant_pryff_task_descr">
  <text>If Garrota is truthful, the fake Freedom member has escaped. We need to confirm this.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_u22_sektant_pryff_task_title2">
  <text>Honestly Lying: Talk to Garrota</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_u22_sektant_pryff_task_descr2">
  <text>The fake Freedom member escaped. I should discuss the situation with Garrota; maybe he can be trusted.</text>
</string>

<!-- Bad Manners / Garrota -->
<string id="okr_u20_garrota_task_title">
  <text>Bad Manners: Go to the Test Complex</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u20_garrota_task_title2">
  <text>Bad Manners: Find the Trader</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u20_garrota_task_title3">
  <text>Bad Manners: Detain the Trader</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u20_garrota_task_descr">
  <text>Garrota betrayed me and issued a kill order in my name. He lurks in the underground test complex. I need to find him, neutralize him, and retrieve the key card to the sanatorium station, if he has it.</text>
</string>

<!-- Sanatorium Secrets -->
<string id="okr_u16_secret_door_task_title">
  <text>Sanatorium Secrets: Give the Envelope to the Trader</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u16_secret_door_task_title1_1">
  <text>Sanatorium Secrets: Examine the Trader's Table</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u16_secret_door_task_title2">
  <text>Sanatorium Secrets: Wait for Night</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u16_secret_door_task_title2_2">
  <text>Sanatorium Secrets: Hide the Envelope in the Indicated Place</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u16_secret_door_task_title3">
  <text>Sanatorium Secrets: Deal with the Unknown</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u16_secret_door_task_title4">
  <text>Sanatorium Secrets: Examine the Unknown Corpse</text>
</string>

<!-- Deadly Trick / Lucky Bar -->
<string id="und_bar_u10_task_title">
  <text>Deadly Trick: Destroy the Mutant</text>
</string>
<string id="und_bar_u10_task_title2">
  <text>Deadly Trick: Help Tesak</text>
</string>
<string id="und_bar_u10_task_title3">
  <text>Deadly Trick: Check the Main Hall</text>
</string>
<string id="und_bar_u10_task_title4">
  <text>Deadly Trick: Call the Elevator</text>
</string>
<string id="und_bar_u10_task_title5">
  <text>Deadly Trick: Go Upstairs</text>
</string>
<string id="und_bar_u10_task_title6">
  <text>Deadly Trick: Fend Off the Sect Members</text>
</string>
<string id="und_bar_u10_task_descr">
  <text>Someone attacked the bar. We need to act quickly!</text>
</string>

<!-- Secrets of the Dead / Flash Drive -->
<string id="undbar_fleshka_task_title">
  <text>Secrets of the Dead: Insert the Flash Drive into the Laptop</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_fleshka_task_descr">
  <text>I found a flash drive in a rotten corpse at the "Lucky" bar. I need to check its contents on the camp laptop.</text>
</string>

<!-- Deal with the Devil / Tesak -->
<string id="und_bar_u2_task_title">
  <text>Deal with the Devil: Wait for the Mercenaries' Response</text>
</string>
<string id="und_bar_u2_task_title2">
  <text>Deal with the Devil: Meet with Tesak</text>
</string>
<string id="und_bar_u2_task_descr">
  <text>I'm at the "Lucky" bar. Their fortified base is here. I must find their leader, Tesak, deliver the case, and return to Garrota for the key card.</text>
</string>

<!-- Betrayal / Marcus -->
<string id="okr_b54_predatel_task_title0">
  <text>Betrayal: Find Evidence on Marcus</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_predatel_task_descr0">
  <text>Recker is badly wounded. I need proof that his partner Marcus betrayed him, causing his death.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_predatel_task_title">
  <text>Betrayal: Find and Deal with Marcus</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_predatel_task_descr">
  <text>A severely injured mercenary asked me to find the traitor responsible: Marcus. He usually hangs around the mercenary bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_predatel_task_title2">
  <text>Betrayal: Tell Tesak about Marcus</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_predatel_task_descr2">
  <text>Marcus betrayed Recker, resulting in his death. I need to inform Tesak, the leader of the mercenaries in the bar.</text>
</string>

<!-- Fragments of Personality / Prophet -->
<string id="okr_mod_fragment_prorok_task_title">
  <text>Fragments of Personality: Gather More Information About the "Prophet"</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_mod_fragment_prorok_task_descr">
  <text>The "Prophet" is the main culprit in my brother's kidnapping and leader of the local sect. I must gather more information about him.</text>
</string>

<!-- Digital Media / Flash Drive -->
<string id="okr_r5_fleshka_task_title">
  <text>Digital Media: Insert the Flash Drive into the Laptop</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r5_fleshka_task_descr">
  <text>I found a flash drive from a sect member in the sanatorium. I need to check its contents on the camp laptop.</text>
</string>

<!-- Consult / Advice -->
<string id="okr_g1_sovet_1_task_title">
  <text>Sheriff's Opinion: Consult with the Sheriff</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_g1_sovet_1_task_descr">
  <text>It's worth asking the Sheriff about the deal with Garrota. He might give valuable advice.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_g1_sovet_2_task_title">
  <text>Molag's Opinion: Consult with Molag</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_g1_sovet_2_task_descr">
  <text>It's worth asking Molag about the deal with Garrota. He might provide good guidance.</text>
</string>
<!-- Time is Money -->
<string id="okr_k1_task_title">
  <text>Time is Money: Talk to Garrota</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_k1_task_title2">
  <text>Time is Money: Sit at the Negotiation Table</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_k1_task_title3">
  <text>Time is Money: Discuss the Trader's Requirements</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_k1_task_title4">
  <text>Time is Money: Take the Case from Garrota</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_k1_task_title5">
  <text>Time is Money: Reach the Mercenary Base</text>
</string>

<!-- Sanatorium Secrets -->
<string id="okr_r6_secret_door_task_title">
  <text>Sanatorium Secrets: Obtain the Key Card</text>
</string>

<!-- New Details / Molag -->
<string id="okr_r6_dialog_molag_task_title">
  <text>New Details: Discuss the Situation with Molag</text>
</string>

<!-- Reconnaissance -->
<string id="okr_r3_task_title">
  <text>Reconnaissance: Inform the Sheriff of Readiness</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r3_task_title2">
  <text>Reconnaissance: Talk to Molag</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r3_task_title3">
  <text>Reconnaissance: Set Up an Ambush for the Sect Members</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r3_task_title4">
  <text>Reconnaissance: Eliminate the Sect Members</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r3_task_title5">
  <text>Reconnaissance: Examine the Sect Member</text>
</string>

<!-- Chemical Clot Artifact -->
<string id="okr_art_himikati_task_title">
  <text>"Chemical Clot": Learn About the Artifact's Properties</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_art_himikati_task_title2">
  <text>"Chemical Clot": Wait for Information from the Professor</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_art_himikati_task_title3">
  <text>"Chemical Clot": Talk to the Professor</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_art_himikati_task_descr">
  <text>In the container I found at the school, there was a strange artifact. I need to learn more about this "Chemical Clot."</text>
</string>

<!-- Old Friends -->
<string id="okr_a5_ilay_task_title">
  <text>Old Friends: Talk to Ilae</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_ilay_task_descr">
  <text>In the camp, I met an old acquaintance. I don't remember him well, but he asked me to come see him when I have time to discuss something.</text>
</string>

<!-- Sect Medallion -->
<string id="okr_c4_medal_sekt_task_title">
  <text>Sect Members: Learn About the Medallion</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c4_medal_sekt_task_descr">
  <text>In the old school, I found a medallion on a sect member's corpse. I want to know more about it. Maybe someone can provide information?</text>
</string>

<!-- Scholars' Contract / Compass -->
<string id="okr_kompass_rezak_task_title">
  <text>Scholars' Contract: Obtain the "Compass" Artifact</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_kompass_rezak_task_title2">
  <text>Scholars' Contract: Bring the Artifact to Rezak</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_kompass_rezak_task_descr">
  <text>The stalker Rezak wants to become a courier for Doc but must first fulfill the contract with the scholars to find the "Compass" artifact. According to Rezak, it can be found near electro-anomalies.</text>
</string>

<!-- Medications / Doc -->
<string id="okr_a5_medic_show_1_available_task">
  <text>Medications</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_show_1_typical_task">
  <text>Help Doc with the Supply of Medical Preparations.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_task_title">
  <text>Medications: Talk to the Scholars</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_task_title2">
  <text>Medications: Talk to Rezak</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_task_title3">
  <text>Medications: Help Rezak Fulfill the Scholars' Contract</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_task_title4">
  <text>Medications: Inform Doc About the New Courier</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_task_descr">
  <text>Doc asked me to find a courier so he can receive medical supplies, allowing him to trade in medications.</text>
</string>

<!-- Valuable Information / Flash Drive -->
<string id="okr_a5_flesh_task_title">
  <text>Valuable Information: Insert the Flash Drive into the Laptop</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_flesh_task_descr">
  <text>At the old school, I found a flash drive, possibly left intentionally. I need to check its contents on the camp laptop.</text>
</string>

<!-- Closed Case -->
<string id="okr_a5_case_task_title">
  <text>Closed Case: Talk to Tehnyar</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_case_task_title2">
  <text>Closed Case: Take the Tools</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_case_task_title3">
  <text>Closed Case: Hand Over the Tools</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_case_task_title4">
  <text>Closed Case: Wait for the Case to be Opened</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_case_task_title5">
  <text>Closed Case: Talk to Tehnyar</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_case_task_descr">
  <text>At the old school, I found a closed case. It may clarify details about what happened to Nikita.</text>
</string>

<!-- Hackers / PDA -->
<string id="okr_a5_pda_task_title">
  <text>Hackers: Wait for the PDA to be Hacked</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_pda_task_title2">
  <text>Hackers: Ask the Sheriff About the PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_pda_task_descr">
  <text>At the old school, one clue was a blocked PDA. The Sheriff promised to handle its hacking.</text>
</string>
<!-- Day by Day -->
<string id="okr_a5_task_title">
  <text>Day by Day: Talk to the Sheriff</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_task_descr">
  <text>Nikita's trail ends in the old school, but we found some clues. Now I need to discuss our leads with the Sheriff.</text>
</string>

<!-- Calm and Serene -->
<string id="okr_c3_sledopit_task_title">
  <text>Calm and Serene: Reach the Attack Site</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c3_sledopit_task_title2">
  <text>Calm and Serene: Examine the Entire School</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c3_sledopit_task_title3">
  <text>Calm and Serene: Find More Clues About What Happened</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c3_sledopit_task_title4">
  <text>Calm and Serene: Discuss the Findings with the Sheriff</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c3_sledopit_task_descr">
  <text>The trail to the disappearance of the expedition, in which my brother Nikita participated, leads to the old school. I need to examine it; maybe there are clues left behind.</text>
</string>

<!-- Reconnaissance -->
<string id="okr_r2_task_title">
  <text>Reconnaissance: Go to the Meeting Place</text>
</string>

<!-- One Blood -->
<string id="okr_c3_task_title">
  <text>One Blood: Find the Younger Brother</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c3_task_descr">
  <text>My brother Nikita has disappeared. Before that, he signed a contract with the scholars and joined a scientific expedition as a companion and guard for the ecologists. Contact with him and his group was lost. I must find him at any cost.</text>
</string>

<!-- Nightmare -->
<string id="okr_c1_task_title">
  <text>Nightmare: Talk to the Unknown</text>
</string>

<!-- Generic Task Info -->
<string id="okr_no_info_tasks_descr">
  <text>No additional information about the task</text>
</string>

	
</string_table>
