<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="bunk_a4_afina_dialog_0">
    <text>That’s all the measurements for now. Thanks for the escort — and for lending me your fighters.</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a4_afina_dialog_1">
    <text>The lab still isn’t fully explored.</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a4_afina_dialog_2">
    <text>True. But I’m exhausted at this point, I need a break. I’ll report to the Institute — they’ll probably send a new team here. For now, you’re free to explore the lab on your own if you wish. Here’s your reward. Thanks for the help.</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a4_afina_dialog_3">
    <text>Alright then... thank you! If you ever need something, just ask.</text>
</string>

<string id="coll_a3_bes_and_leha_commanda_dialog_0">
    <text>Just give the word — we’ll help, and try not to get in your way!</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_a3_bes_and_leha_commanda_dialog_2_6">
    <text>Stay by the fire. %c[255,248,153,26](The squad will wait here)</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_a3_bes_and_leha_commanda_dialog_2_7">
    <text>Follow me. %c[255,248,153,26](The squad will follow you)</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_a3_bes_and_leha_commanda_dialog_4">
    <text>Step aside, you’re blocking the way. %c[255,248,153,26](Character is in the way)</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_a3_bes_and_leha_commanda_dialog_5">
    <text>%c[0,140,140,140][..exit..]</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_a3_bes_and_leha_commanda_dialog_6">
    <text>Stay by the fire. %c[255,248,153,26](The squad will wait here)</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_a3_bes_and_leha_commanda_dialog_7">
    <text>Follow me. %c[255,248,153,26](The squad will follow you)</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_bernada_pda_feromon_dialog_0">
    <text>I think I found the PDA from your expedition. They disappeared in uncharted territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_bernada_pda_feromon_dialog_1">
    <text>What? Oh God... I hoped they’d just lost contact... Well, thanks for telling me.</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_bernada_task_dialog_0">
    <text>I’m here about that job, Professor.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_bernada_task_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, yes... Listen, this is a serious matter. I wouldn’t trust it to just anyone. But I believe you can handle it.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_bernada_task_dialog_2">
    <text>I’m listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_bernada_task_dialog_22">
    <text>I’ve changed my mind. Let’s discuss this later.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_bernada_task_dialog_3">
    <text>We’ve registered strong psi-waves near the sanatorium — in the pool of the old water park. They cause hallucinations, sometimes even “people from another world.” Unscientific as it sounds... in short: ghosts.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_bernada_task_dialog_4">
    <text>And what exactly do you want me to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_bernada_task_dialog_5">
    <text>I need you to escort my colleague, Gloria, to the water park. She’s an IT specialist and knows our equipment. She’ll install a device that records psi-effects, while you make sure nothing happens to her. I don’t think she can handle it alone... I hope it all goes smoothly. If you succeed, expect a nice reward — and discounts on my supplies.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_bernada_task_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood, Professor. I’ll find her and discuss the plan.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_bernada_task_dialog_7">
    <text>Excellent. Take the device. She should be at the bar now — I’m sure you’ll find her.</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_bernada_work_dialog_0">
    <text>Professor, got any work for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_bernada_work_dialog_1">
    <text>I would gladly give you something, young man! But right now, it’s vital for my assistant “Riddick” to continue his research in the local caves. If you help him out, I’ll have more work for you afterwards!</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_bernada_work_dialog_22">
    <text>Of course! Since you’ve helped my assistant, I can now entrust you with more profitable tasks.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, kid. I’m from Professor Bernada.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_dialog_1">
    <text>Uncle, next to you I might be a kid, but let’s be honest — not really.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright then, no problem, kid.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_dialog_11">
    <text>I’ve got a name! Glo-ri-a. Got it? And what’s yours?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_dialog_12">
    <text>Oleg. But call me Voland — feels more natural. Alright, see you at the water park. Bye.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_dialog_2">
    <text>So tell me, how’d you end up in the Zone? You’re barely more than a child.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_dialog_3">
    <text>Ugh... not in the mood to talk about it. You said you’re from the Professor. What’s this about?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_dialog_4">
    <text>Yeah. He gave me this device, said you know how it works. You need to set it up in the water park near the sanatorium. Apparently, they registered some psi-activity there.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_dialog_5">
    <text>Ooooh! I’ve heard about that! Ghosts! Hah, don’t tell me you’re afraid of ghosts?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_dialog_6">
    <text>I’m only afraid the next generation will lose their pensions.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_dialog_7">
    <text>You’re such a bore, uncle... Ugh. So what’s the plan? We heading out now?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_dialog_8">
    <text>Basically, yeah.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_dialog_9">
    <text>Great! Then you carry the device to the site, I’ll throw my stuff together and join you. See you there, okay?</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_glori_task_end_professor_dialog_0">
    <text>Professor Bernada, mission complete. Gloria’s fine, data is intact.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_glori_task_end_professor_dialog_1">
    <text>You truly are my esteemed Mr. Voland! I’m very grateful. Here’s your reward, and as promised — discounts on my humble supplies. I’m glad everything worked out, and thank you for helping my colleague!</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, young man. How can I help you?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_prof_self_dialog_1_0">
    <text>Professor, what are you doing here? That’s a reactor behind the wall — it looks both impressive and dangerous!</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_prof_self_dialog_1_1">
    <text>That’s right. But we monitor all parameters closely, and we’re ready to shut down the experiment at any moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_prof_self_dialog_1_2">
    <text>Experiment?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_prof_self_dialog_1_3">
    <text>Exactly. We’re testing ways to generate energy. This very reactor powers the lighting and systems in the lab.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_prof_self_dialog_1_4">
    <text>But the radiation must be building up... what do you do with it?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_prof_self_dialog_1_5">
    <text>We try to keep its level stable, as well as the output of this anomalous reactor.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_prof_self_dialog_1_6">
    <text>Anomalous... so it’s not man-made?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_prof_self_dialog_1_7">
    <text>Exactly. We’re experimenting with a shard of an artifact, similar to the well-known “Incubator.” Sadly, the artifact itself has never been found. As far as I know, Professor Sokolov searched for it, but failed.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_prof_self_dialog_1_8">
    <text>Yeah, right. There was a stalker in their team named “Kramer.” I chased him before he was discharged — still just a kid... They say he later died on the mainland. Poor guy.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_prof_self_dialog_1_9">
    <text>Let’s not dwell on the sad. Humanity still awaits new technologies and discoveries.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_prof_self_dialog_2_0">
    <text>And how did you end up settling here?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_prof_self_dialog_2_1">
    <text>Hard to explain... We came here as part of an expedition into the Zone. Underground, near the airbase, we picked up strange radiation readings. Turned out there was a hidden lab under the base. We took control of it and continued experiments with the reactor down there. 
Heh... Friend, we’ve been here more than ten years now. A lot has happened. Lately though, things have settled, stable enough to keep working. And that’s what matters.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_prof_self_dialog_2_2">
    <text>Wait... you’re saying you boosted that artifact shard yourself, to this level?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ecolog_prof_self_dialog_2_3">
    <text>Exactly. Before us, the radiation here was unstable, weak. When we studied the site, we realized the experiments began back in the ’90s. We just picked up where they left off.</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_j1_kapitan_naymov_start_dialog_0">
    <text>And you are...? Don’t you see I’m busy— Major?! Damn, good to see you!</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_kapitan_naymov_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Naumov? What the hell... You’ve been listed dead for a year! Alive, huh? Well I’ll be damned.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_kapitan_naymov_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Comrade Major, my apologies!</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_kapitan_naymov_start_dialog_3">
    <text>I’m Lieutenant Colonel now. Relax, I’m off duty, captain. Came here on my own. Better tell me where you vanished to... and what you’re doing in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_kapitan_naymov_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Well... Comrade Lieutenant Colonel, I’m off duty too. Operation “Fairway” failed. I was the only one left. Escaped... but after that, I don’t know who I am anymore. Stalker? Deserter? Worse? Freedom found me half-dead and dragged me here. That’s how it went.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_kapitan_naymov_start_dialog_5">
    <text>I see... Good you survived. Don’t worry, captain, I won’t hand you over, haha.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_kapitan_naymov_start_dialog_6">
    <text>And you? Why are you here, if it’s not a secret?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_kapitan_naymov_start_dialog_7">
    <text>I’m looking for my younger brother. Thinks he can be a hero. Long story... family mess.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_kapitan_naymov_start_dialog_8">
    <text>Understood... Sorry for getting in your way.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_kapitan_naymov_start_dialog_9">
    <text>It’s fine.</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_j1_nauk_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Ah, Zone... What hole have you dragged me into now?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ohrannik_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>What do you want? Ugh... I’m sick of rotting in this can, I swear.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ych_1_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey there. Need something?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j1_ych_1_sad_dialog_0">
    <text>If only someone would lend a hand...</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j3_barmen_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Welcome, stalker. What can I do for you?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j3_gloria_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Ha! Hey there, uncle.</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_j3_patalah_self_dialog_1_0">
    <text>Grandpa, if I may... how’d you end up in Freedom? You’re not exactly young anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j3_patalah_self_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Heh, what’s wrong with that, boy? It’s quiet here, calm. Why not join Freedom? Scientists nearby keep things steady. No complaints.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j3_patalah_self_dialog_2_0">
    <text>You got a proper technician around?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j3_patalah_self_dialog_2_1">
    <text>Sadly... no skilled hands for the gadgets we need. Makes life harder.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j3_patalah_self_dialog_3_0">
    <text>What do you think of that reactor the scientists are messing with?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j3_patalah_self_dialog_3_1">
    <text>Honestly, son... I don’t like it. Just hope their tinkering doesn’t blow up in our faces.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j3_patalah_self_dialog_4_0">
    <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_j3_patalah_self_dialog_4_1">
    <text>Not much to tell... I used to be a stalker, but age caught up. Freedom offered me bar work here, said it’s warm near the reactor—hah, a bit too warm maybe. Feels like we’re soaking up rads every day... Anyway. I hunted with Lesnik in Red Forest, tracked beasts, even chased a chimera to the army depots. Barely made it back alive. Freedom patched me up, saved my skin. After that... well, I stayed. Joined their ranks, so to speak.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ohrannik_prismotri_za_torgom_dialog_0">
    <text>Keep an eye on trader Garrota. Better not let him leave the bunker until I’m done checking something, got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ohrannik_prismotri_za_torgom_dialog_1">
    <text>Heh, you’re a funny one... Alright, he’s not going anywhere till you say so.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_patalah_self_garrota_dialog_0">
    <text>You seen where Garrota ran off to?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_patalah_self_garrota_dialog_1">
    <text>Of course! He’s over at the scientists’ complex. Just head through the canyon, you’ll find them there.</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_ridik_go_task_dialog_0">
    <text>I’m ready. Let’s head for your caves.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_go_task_dialog_1">
    <text>You sure? Place isn’t safe... Mutants could be lurking, though with all that acid down there, maybe nothing’s left alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_go_task_dialog_11">
    <text>So you’re set? Where’s your suit? Without it, you won’t last a second — that acid will eat you alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_go_task_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes. I’m fully prepared.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_go_task_dialog_22">
    <text>Hold on.</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_ridik_quest_dialog_0">
    <text>What happened to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_quest_dialog_1">
    <text>I need to explore a cave under the complex. Can’t go alone... and no one else will.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_quest_dialog_2">
    <text>I’ll help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_quest_dialog_22">
    <text>We’ll talk later.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_quest_dialog_3">
    <text>That’s good... but your suit won’t cut it. You’ll need a sealed one, or an exoskeleton at least. Otherwise, those chemicals will melt it... and then you. Don’t even think that “Zaslon” helmet will save you — maybe your lungs, but your body will dissolve in seconds. Not much of a future, eh? Get proper gear, then we’ll talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_quest_dialog_33">
    <text>Really? Perfect. Looks like your suit will hold. I’ll wait until you’re ready.</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_ridik_task_end_dialog_0">
    <text>We made it... still alive. Hah... Feels like the fumes in there weakened, but I wouldn’t risk taking the suit off. Let’s get back to base fast.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_task_end_dialog_1">
    <text>Let’s move.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_ridik_task_end_dialog_2">
    <text>Wait, let me check the area.</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_scfbespilot_bernada_dialog_0">
    <text>Professor Bernada, stalker Bes said you could lend me a decoder...</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_scfbespilot_bernada_dialog_1">
    <text>Decoder? And what for?</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_scfbespilot_bernada_dialog_2">
    <text>A spatial bubble opened in the settlement. We need to shut it down before it grows.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_scfbespilot_bernada_dialog_3">
    <text>Hmm... You’re right, not something to mess with. Here, take it — I trust you.</text>
</string>

<string id="flst_u21_garrota_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Why are you staring at me like that? I’m not guilty, damn it...</text>
</string>

<string id="hirsa_self_o_ekspidicii_dialog_0">
    <text>You said you’d just returned from a mission when you came to the Zone. What kind of mission, if you don’t mind me asking?</text>
</string>
<string id="hirsa_self_o_ekspidicii_dialog_1">
    <text>Recently, Professor Zadorov’s expedition under Captain Smirnov reestablished contact. Their signal was jammed by some device under Yantar, until one brave stalker disabled it... they called him “Assistant”, can’t recall. Anyway, I went to extract them. Smirnov said the plan failed, and Zadorov... ran off with the artifact they were studying. Didn’t hear the rest, rotor noise drowned it out. That’s the story.</text>
</string>
<string id="hirsa_self_o_ekspidicii_dialog_2">
    <text>So Captain Smirnov made it back? Where is he now?</text>
</string>
<string id="hirsa_self_o_ekspidicii_dialog_22">
    <text>I see.</text>
</string>
<string id="hirsa_self_o_ekspidicii_dialog_3">
    <text>At the Research Institute, of course. Waiting for clearance... for the NPP assault, they say.</text>
</string>
<string id="hirsa_self_o_ekspidicii_dialog_4">
    <text>Got it. Thanks.</text>
</string>

<string id="hirsa_self_o_sebe_dialog_0">
    <text>This might be personal... but what happened to your hand and face?</text>
</string>
<string id="hirsa_self_o_sebe_dialog_1">
    <text>Normally, that’d be rude to ask a woman. But I’m not your “normal” woman... so I don’t mind, if you really want to know.</text>
</string>
<string id="hirsa_self_o_sebe_dialog_2">
    <text>I’m listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="hirsa_self_o_sebe_dialog_22">
    <text>You’re right... not my business.</text>
</string>
<string id="hirsa_self_o_sebe_dialog_3">
    <text>I’ve got a mechanical implant instead of my right hand... and my face was burned. Operation “Fairway.” I was piloting when Monolith hit us with Gauss rifles. Helicopter was on fire, barely under control... but I landed it. Rough landing, but I lived. People from the Institute found me and patched me up.</text>
</string>
<string id="hirsa_self_o_sebe_dialog_4">
    <text>And you still fly after that? Most would quit.</text>
</string>
<string id="hirsa_self_o_sebe_dialog_5">
    <text>As you see, I’m not broken. Fire still haunts me... but I’ll manage.</text>
</string>
<string id="hirsa_self_o_sebe_dialog_6">
    <text>You’re a strong one. Respect.</text>
</string>
<string id="hirsa_self_o_sebe_dialog_7">
    <text>Heh... Thanks for saying that.</text>
</string>

<string id="mod_hirsa_hello_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello... Need something?</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_sekt_kvant_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>I’ve heard of you... Looks like the Prophet’s got himself a new toy for dirty work. Why the long face? Am I wrong? Heh...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_sekt_kvant_hello_dialog_dva_0">
    <text>Do you like it here? The fog... the creaking trees, the whispers in the bushes... Feels like something’s about to tear into you from behind. Cute, huh?</text>
</string>

<string id="mod_self_o_proroke_v_nii_dialog_0">
    <text>I’ve got solid info — the cultists are planning to steal classified documents from the Institute.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_self_o_proroke_v_nii_dialog_1">
    <text>Damn... I need to report this fast. Thanks!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_self_o_proroke_v_nii_dialog_2">
    <text>Glad to help.</text>
</string>

<string id="mtr_citra_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>You fight well, Voland. Been watching you a while... Too bad we’re enemies.</text>
</string>

<string id="mtr_e7_nikita_dialog_0">
    <text>A... Attr... Attribute!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtr_e7_nikita_dialog_1">
    <text>Nikita! Snap out of it, brother!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtr_e7_nikita_dialog_2">
    <text>A... A... A-t-t-r-i-b-u-t-e... Attribute!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtr_e7_nikita_dialog_3">
    <text>Hey, what’s happening to you?!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtr_e7_nikita_dialog_4">
    <text>Attribute... I serve... I serve the Attribute!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtr_e7_nikita_dialog_5">
    <text>What have they done to you... %c[0,140,140,140][...end dialogue...]</text>
</string>

<string id="mtr_nikita_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>A... Attr... Attribute! I serve the Attribute! Who’s there!? Attribute!</text>
</string>

<string id="mtr_penis_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>What do you want, sinner?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtr_prorok_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>A-a... You’re my guest today? Still breathing? Strange... What questions do you bring me, sinful soul?</text>
</string>

<string id="mtrs_e10_penis_in_baza_dialog_0">
    <text>I need to reach your base.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e10_penis_in_baza_dialog_1">
    <text>No traces left, understand!? Fine... mask on. Let’s move!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e10_penis_in_baza_dialog_2">
    <text>Start it.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e10_penis_out_baza_dialog_0">
    <text>I need to get to the surface.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e10_penis_out_baza_dialog_1">
    <text>I’ll guide you out. Put the mask on — you won’t remember the way back here. That’s it, let’s move.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e10_penis_out_baza_dialog_2">
    <text>Lead the way.</text>
</string>

<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_dialog_0">
    <text>Ah, my dear guest... Look at this! Isn’t it beautiful? Simply wonderful, watching your friend... Seems he couldn’t withstand my hypnosis! Ha-ha-ha.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_dialog_1">
    <text>You... Where’s my brother!?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_dialog_11">
    <text>Let my brother go!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_dialog_2">
    <text>Ha-ha-ha! Humans are cruel... But I’ll make a man out of you! Don’t raise your voice at me, hermano. I’ve dug through your head — tik-tak... and learned so much! You can be useful! And do you know the worst part? Alive! Yes... you’re useful to me alive! Ha-ha-ha! Because your dear brother... Nikita — is now under my special control. This is a test, a path for both of us! I haven’t killed him or sold him for organs yet. Coincidence? Nonsense! I knew... I knew he was worth much more! Ha-ha-ha-ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_dialog_22">
    <text>Have you seen him already? Eh... Humans are cruel... But I’ll make a man out of you! Don’t raise your voice at me, hermano. I’ve dug through your head — tik-tak... and learned so much! You can be useful! And do you know the worst part? Alive! Yes... you’re useful to me alive! Ha-ha-ha! Because your dear brother... Nikita — is now under my special control. This is a test, a path for both of us! I haven’t killed him or sold him for organs yet. Coincidence? Nonsense! I knew... I knew he was worth much more! Ha-ha-ha-ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_dialog_3">
    <text>You’re insane! Where is he!?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_dialog_33">
    <text>You’re completely mad!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_dialog_4">
    <text>Look there, in that cell. I’ll wait. Admire him, then return quickly, my dear friend! We have matters to discuss! Ha-ha-ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_dialog_44">
    <text>Me? Crazy? Ha-ha-ha... No, psychos are humans, broken humans. But I’m not crazy, my friend. It’s the people around us — they’re wrong. You understand, hermano?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_dialog_5">
    <text>If even one hair on his head... %c[0,140,140,140][...end dialogue...]</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_dialog_55">
    <text>I need to make sure he’s alright! %c[0,140,140,140][...end dialogue...]</text>
</string>

<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_loot_box_dialog_0">
    <text>Where are my things?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_loot_box_dialog_1">
    <text>Your things? Ha-ha-ha... They’re waiting for you! Ha-ha-ha.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_loot_box_dialog_2">
    <text>Stop laughing. I can’t do your tasks without them.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e7_prorok_loot_box_dialog_3">
    <text>You’re right, Voland, you’re absolutely right! Then I permit you to take them. They’re right here, behind me, in this... beautiful container. Go on, take them!</text>
</string>

<string id="nii_avrora_hello_dialog_1_0">
    <text>Need any help, Voland?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_barmen_borya_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Glad to see familiar faces! Ho-ho... How’s life?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_breap_hello_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, well... Look who it is! Voland! Back from vacation already?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_chen_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Ugh, I’m sick of this institute already... Maybe I should head to the Zone. What do you need, Voland?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_deshifr_fobos_dialog_0">
    <text>I came for the decoder.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_deshifr_fobos_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, yes... Here you go, Voland! All yours!</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_deshifr_fobos_dialog_2">
    <text>Don't start with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_deshifr_fobos_dialog_3">
    <text>Ha, alright, alright... everything’s fine.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_fobos_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, Voland. Need repairs or an upgrade? I can handle it—any whim, for the right price!</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_german_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, hello. Business or pleasure?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n10_hirsa_guider_dialog_0">
    <text>I need to get to the Zone. We flying?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n10_hirsa_guider_dialog_1">
    <text>Alright then, to the Zone... let’s go.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n10_hirsa_guider_dialog_2">
    <text>Let’s move out.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n10_hirsa_guider_dialog_22">
    <text>Hold on, I forgot something.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n10_hirsa_guider_dialog_3">
    <text>No problem, but we’ll only fly once the emission passes.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n10_hirsa_guider_dialog_4">
    <text>Got it.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n1_assistent_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>No offense, old man, but I’m not in the mood to talk right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n1_smirnov_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, hello there, old friend.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n1_smirnov_scena_dialog_0">
    <text>Voland?! Old man, good to see you!</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n1_smirnov_scena_dialog_1">
    <text>Cap! Buddy! Look who it is!</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n1_smirnov_scena_dialog_2">
    <text>Heard you ditched your vacation, searching for your brother... How’s that going?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n1_smirnov_scena_dialog_3">
    <text>Mm... Complicated, my friend. He’s a fool—young, naive, green... you get me.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n1_smirnov_scena_dialog_4">
    <text>I get it... but youth can surprise you. I’ve seen it myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n1_smirnov_scena_dialog_5">
    <text>Who’s this rascal? Judging by your face, you mean one of your men, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n1_smirnov_scena_dialog_6">
    <text>Ha, you could say that. We had a kid with us on expedition—an assistant to the professor. "Assistant" became his nickname, heh. But this kid blew us all away—turned into a real monster of a soldier! Saved my life in the lab under Yantar, too. I went in alone, told him to stay put in the bunker, but he came after me... If not for him, I’d still be rotting there as a posthumous captain. And the way he changed since then... Once jumpy and nervous, now probably wrestles mutants barehanded. But his eyes... that stare—chills you to the bone. I saw huge potential in him, but I fear he’ll lose his mind. Maybe I shouldn’t have let him stay in the Zone. He’s dead set on finding that runaway professor... Another madman. So here I sit, waiting for command to greenlight my trip to Limansk to track that bastard down. I just hope I cross paths with Assistant along the way—alive and in one piece. Shouldn’t have left him... Guess I got too attached, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n1_smirnov_scena_dialog_7">
    <text>Going soft, old soldier? Just kidding. We all mellow with age, no matter what life’s thrown at us...</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n1_smirnov_scena_dialog_8">
    <text>That’s true, Voland... So, what are your plans?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n1_smirnov_scena_dialog_9">
    <text>If only I knew, buddy... If only I knew.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n2_bianka_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Voland... What brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n2_prisoner_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Damn... what a mess...</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n2_rogovec_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, soldier! How are you holding up?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n3_morigan_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey there, uncle Voland. How’s life treating you?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n3_valentir_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings!</text>
</string>

  <string id="nii_ozerksie_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Yes? Mr. Voland, do you have some questions for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_scf_sxema_fobos_dialog_0">
    <text>I’ve got a relic from the past—an old blueprint for item No. 62.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_scf_sxema_fobos_dialog_1">
    <text>Whoa! That’s practically a rarity! You brought it to me, I hope?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_scf_sxema_fobos_dialog_2">
    <text>Indeed. To you. From what I know, you’re the one with the most downtime in this institute.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_scf_sxema_fobos_dialog_3">
    <text>Ha! Time ticks, the paycheck’s safe, and I hope they never think of cutting down the tech staff. Otherwise… back to the Zone, and I’d rather not go. Hehe...</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_scf_sxema_fobos_dialog_4">
    <text>Here, take the blueprint—have fun with it.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_scf_sxema_fobos_dialog_5">
    <text>Thanks a lot, Voland. Don’t go yet! Between us... ahem… I’ve got a few interesting suits lying around. Since they’d just gather dust, I want you to have one. Look at this… a Monolith exoskeleton. Not sure what the fanatics were thinking, but their suits were top-notch. Here, take it!</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_scf_sxema_fobos_dialog_6">
    <text>Wow, amazing gift. Where did you get it?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_scf_sxema_fobos_dialog_7">
    <text>Assistant brought it from Chernobyl NPP. He collected a lot of unusual stuff, but I kept this one for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_scfbespilot_ozerskie_dialog_0">
    <text>Could I borrow a decoder?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_scfbespilot_ozerskie_dialog_1">
    <text>For someone like you, of course, Mr. Voland! But tell me—out of curiosity—what’s it for, if you don’t mind sharing?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_scfbespilot_ozerskie_dialog_2">
    <text>A spatial bubble appeared in the settlement, and I need to close it. Ahem… What would I owe you for helping?</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_scfbespilot_ozerskie_dialog_3">
    <text>You owe nothing! A spatial bubble, you say? Dangerous Zone phenomenon, indeed! We studied something similar near Jupiter once. Deactivate it quickly! Go to Phobos’ warehouse—he’ll be expecting you, and he’ll hand over the device.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_scfbespilot_ozerskie_dialog_4">
    <text>Thanks for your help, Professor.</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_scfbespilot_ozerskie_dialog_5">
    <text>Always glad to help!</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_sidorenko_hello_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, soldier. Looking to buy something, or is there business with me?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_2_0">
    <text>I’ve found two fighters for your team.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_2_1">
    <text>Excellent! Now only the small matter remains—we’ll head to the factory soon. Are you coming?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_2_2">
    <text>Yes, it’s safer with me along, hehe.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_2_3">
    <text>Good. Once you’re ready, let me know and we’ll move out.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_start_0">
    <text>Greetings, soldier! Could you lend me a hand?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_start_1">
    <text>What’s the problem?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_start_100">
    <text>Putting together a team for my expedition. Eh.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_start_11">
    <text>I’m on it, madam.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_start_12">
    <text>Good. I’ll wait to hear about the team’s progress.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_start_13">
    <text>Uh-huh.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_start_2">
    <text>Well, spill it—what happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_start_22">
    <text>Busy right now. We’ll talk later.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_start_3">
    <text>I’m assembling a team to explore an underground lab beneath the factory. We just discovered it. I know roughly where the emergency entrance is. I can cover preparation and ammo costs, but no one else wants to go there.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_start_4">
    <text>Hmm… probably scared.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_start_5">
    <text>Most likely…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_start_6">
    <text>Let me help. What do you need from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_start_7">
    <text>Thanks! First, I need a couple more people for reliability. Anyone come to mind?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_quest_dialog_start_8">
    <text>I’ll ask around. Maybe someone will step up.</text>
</string>

  <string id="okr2_afina_to_bunker_dialog_0">
    <text>I'm ready for the expedition.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_to_bunker_dialog_1">
    <text>Are you sure? All set?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_to_bunker_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, quite ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_to_bunker_dialog_22">
    <text>Hold on a second.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_to_bunker_dialog_3">
    <text>Good. Then we’re heading out now. Here, take this—an advance for you!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_afina_to_bunker_dialog_4">
    <text>Excellent. Let’s move.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_docent_afin_task_dialog_0">
    <text>I wanted to ask… Would you join Athena’s team? She’s gathering people for an expedition to an underground lab under the industrial factory.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_docent_afin_task_dialog_1">
    <text>Sounds interesting! I’m in. Where do I go?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_docent_afin_task_dialog_2">
    <text>Just like that? Well, alright. She’s waiting at the stalkers’ camp near the “fish farm” base.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_docent_afin_task_dialog_3">
    <text>Got it. I’ll grab my stuff and head there. See you soon!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_docent_afin_task_dialog_4">
    <text>That was easy…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_expedition_afina_sim_dialog_0">
    <text>Athena is assembling an expedition to explore an underground lab under the industrial factory. She’s covering all costs and paying well for escort and protection. Want to join?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_expedition_afina_sim_dialog_1">
    <text>Nah, I’ll pass.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_expedition_afina_sim_dialog_11">
    <text>No thanks, got my own business. Maybe ask the local adventurers. Stalker Lynx likes these events, you could ask him.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_expedition_afina_sim_dialog_111">
    <text>No thanks, busy with my own stuff. Ask Docent Roma at the scientists’ camp by the gas station—he enjoys these expeditions.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_expedition_afina_sim_dialog_2">
    <text>Sorry friend, not for me. Too scary!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_expedition_afina_sim_dialog_22">
    <text>Uh… no, sorry. Ask someone else.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_expedition_afina_sim_dialog_222">
    <text>I’d join, but busy with my own things. Sorry!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_afin_task_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, want to join Athena’s team? She’s forming a group for an expedition to the underground lab under the industrial factory.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_afin_task_dialog_1">
    <text>Hmm… I’d like to, but there’s a rare mutant bugging me! Shot it in the swamps, but the bastard crawled off… Scientists promised a big reward for this rarity. Can’t leave it like that. Set a trap, but it escaped—no worries, it’ll crawl back!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_afin_task_dialog_11">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_afin_task_dialog_12">
    <text>Excellent.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_afin_task_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes! You found my wonder-fish! Now I’m rich, hehe… I’m ready to help Athena, no problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_rotan_task_end_dialog_0">
    <text>Found your wonder-fish. Didn’t crawl far—belly up, just ten meters from here.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_rotan_task_end_dialog_1">
    <text>Ah? Really? Damn, I’m blind! Thought I checked everything… Thanks, buddy! Here, you earned it!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_self_dialog_0">
    <text>Why the long face? What are you catching?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_self_dialog_1">
    <text>Catching, yeah… a wonder-fish!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_self_dialog_2">
    <text>Tell me more.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_self_dialog_22">
    <text>We’ll talk later.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_fishboy_self_dialog_3">
    <text>Hunting a rare local fish—Rotan. Shot it, but it dashed into the bushes… Can’t find it. Probably escaped. Sitting, waiting for it to come back. Set a trap. They’ll pay well for this one… Eh…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_dialog_0">
    <text>Is there work?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_dialog_1">
    <text>Ho-ho-ho! Of course! Found a mushroom field recently. Not ordinary—anomalous mushrooms! Wonder what they taste like, huh? Hehe…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, tell me, storyteller.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_dialog_22">
    <text>No, I’ll save the details for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_dialog_3">
    <text>Ha! Knew my story would catch your attention… Walked from the trader at night, near the Engineers’ district—saw light far away. Investigated—big glowing mushroom field! Binoculars in hand, it’s a pity it was night… Chickened out alone. Now, thinking… should I check it? Want to come along?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_dialog_4">
    <text>Hmm… Let’s do it! Curious myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_danya_dialog_5">
    <text>Super! Meet here at 2 AM.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_night_danya_dialog_0">
    <text>Shall we check your field?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_night_danya_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, of course! Let’s go!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_night_danya_dialog_11">
    <text>Ah? I said 2 AM! Nothing to see now…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_night_danya_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright, let’s go.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g1_night_danya_dialog_22">
    <text>Okay.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_dialog_0">
    <text>You scared me, Voland! Thought you were done for…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_dialog_1">
    <text>Me? You were in delirium yourself. Woke up before me, I guess?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_dialog_2">
    <text>If only… Woke up here, saw you opposite me. And that’s not all…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_dialog_3">
    <text>I don’t get it. What do you mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_dialog_4">
    <text>We’re trapped. Tried leaving this room… teleport… nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_dialog_5">
    <text>You didn’t drag me here, and we’re locked in this room, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes… Someone locked us in. Connection’s gone. Tried signaling the others… only interference.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_dialog_7">
    <text>Bad! Let me look around.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_self_dialog_0">
    <text>We’re stuck… What happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_self_dialog_1">
    <text>Probably inhaled those mushrooms…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_self_dialog_2">
    <text>Seems so. Now trapped, no connection… What a trap, ugh.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_self_dialog_22">
    <text>Wait, we’ll think of something.</text>
</string>

  <string id="okr2_g4_danik_self_dialog_3">
    <text>We’ll figure something out.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_self_dialog_33">
    <text>Maybe it’s an illusion… maybe we’re still asleep?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_self_dialog_44">
    <text>I’d like to believe that…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_self_dialog_55">
    <text>We’ll figure something out.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_self_dialog_66">
    <text>What mushrooms are these, anyway?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_self_dialog_77">
    <text>Who knows! But scientists will definitely be interested. Main thing is, we need to get out of here.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_self_dialog_88">
    <text>Yeah…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g7_danik_dialog_task_end_0">
    <text>Thanks for the help, Voland. Would’ve been scary alone here. Here’s your share, hehe.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g7_danik_dialog_task_end_1">
    <text>Wait… Doesn’t it bother you that we were trapped in an anomaly and couldn’t get out?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g7_danik_dialog_task_end_2">
    <text>What… I said 2 AM! Nothing to see there now…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g7_danik_dialog_task_end_3">
    <text>Nonsense. Those weren’t hallucinations, I’m sure.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g7_danik_dialog_task_end_4">
    <text>Uh… You look rough. Buddy, let’s head back to camp—who knows what’s going on with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g7_danik_dialog_task_end_5">
    <text>You’re right… Let’s go.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g7_danik_dialog_task_end_55">
    <text>You go ahead, I need to check around here.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_afina_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, soldier. Need something?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_self_art_him_dialog_0">
    <text>Doc, do you know what this "Chemical Clot" is?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_self_art_him_dialog_1">
    <text>Some anomalous formation, apparently… Take it to the scientists at the gas station. They should know what to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_self_bluelamp_dialog_0">
    <text>What are these ultraviolet lamps for in the camp?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_self_bluelamp_dialog_1">
    <text>Ah… Scientists gave them to us. They help preserve the nervous system during emissions. Really works! If you’re near one during an emission, even outside, your chances of survival go up. Scientists even carry them in case of sudden emissions. Really handy.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_self_o_dog_dialog_0">
    <text>Your dog?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_self_o_dog_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes. Came wounded to our camp, I treated her and she stayed.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_self_o_dog_dialog_2">
    <text>Got it.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_self_o_torg_dialog_0">
    <text>I’d like to buy some meds.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_self_o_torg_dialog_1">
    <text>Glad to help, Voland. But trade is tricky at the moment…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_self_o_torg_dialog_2">
    <text>Can I help somehow?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_self_o_torg_dialog_3">
    <text>I need someone to hire a new courier to bring me medications…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_task_dialog_0">
    <text>I’ll help you, Doc.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_task_dialog_1">
    <text>Really? You’d do that, friend? I know some at the local scientific base… Ask if there’s an assistant free to help with medication supply to the base.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_task_dialog_2">
    <text>No problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_task_dialog_22">
    <text>Later then.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_task_dialog_3">
    <text>Thanks, I appreciate it!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_task_end_dialog_0">
    <text>That’s it, Doc. Found you a courier. Have you met?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_medic_task_end_dialog_1">
    <text>Thanks a lot, Voland! Already knew him, good kid. Medication issues solved—if you need something, you’re welcome.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_molag_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, Voland. What brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_sgustok_b10_proff_dialog_0">
    <text>Professor, can you study this "Chemical Clot"?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_sgustok_b10_proff_dialog_1">
    <text>Let me see… I’ll need time. Seems it’s not even an artifact… Leave it with me, I’ll study it and update you once I have results.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_sgustok_b10_proff_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood, Professor. Thanks.</text>
</string>

  <string id="okr_art_himikate_stalkers_self_dialog_0">
    <text>Do you happen to know what this "Chemical Clot" is?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_art_himikate_stalkers_self_dialog_1">
    <text>Uh… no idea, friend. Sorry!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_art_himikate_stalkers_self_dialog_2">
    <text>No clue, bro. Better ask the scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_art_himikate_stalkers_self_dialog_3">
    <text>Artifact or something? Who knows, man. Go ask the ecologists—they might know.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_art_himikate_stalkers_self_dialog_4">
    <text>Don’t know… probably some artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_art_himikate_stalkers_self_dialog_5">
    <text>Take this "thing" to the scientists at the gas station. They should help you out!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_av_1_prisoner_dialog_mess_start_0">
    <text>Thanks for getting me out… I owe you one with my guys at the camp. If not for you, who knows what those sectarians would’ve done… Heard they trade organs, ugh…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_docent_1_hello_dialog_start_0">
    <text>Hello. Any questions? Or need your gear fixed?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_docent_2_hello_dialog_start_0">
    <text>Greetings, comrade Voland. What brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_duplet_hello_dialog_start_0">
    <text>M? What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_ecolog_medic_need_health_care_0">
    <text>%c[0,140,140,140]I need medical help.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_ecolog_medic_need_health_care_1">
    <text>Let me check you now… hmm-hmm, yes…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_ecolog_medic_need_health_care_11">
    <text>%c[0,140,140,140][..next..]</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_ecolog_medic_need_health_care_111">
    <text>All done. You should feel better!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_ecolog_medic_need_health_care_2">
    <text>Hmm… Voland, you’re fine. Maybe just a cold?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_kyriers_proff_dialog_0">
    <text>Heard about Doc? He’s looking for free couriers—short on people for delivering meds.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_kyriers_proff_dialog_1">
    <text>Well… I’m short on staff too. Hmm… Wait! Ask stalker "Rezak"—maybe he’ll agree. But I can’t just let him go… He’s under contract with us and supposed to deliver an artifact. He’s dragging his feet. Talk to him—if he completes it, I could transfer him to your Doc.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_kyriers_proff_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood, Professor.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_proff_dialog_hello_start_0">
    <text>Hello. Any questions for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_proff_self_bluelamp_dialog_0">
    <text>Professor, what exactly do these ultraviolet lamps do?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_proff_self_bluelamp_dialog_1">
    <text>Ah, hehe… We made these with the Research Institute. They protect the nervous system during psi-strikes of emissions. You can survive even in the open during eruptions thanks to these. Useful, though expensive. We hope to make them lighter and more compact soon for easier personal use. Mass production is next.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_rezak_gde_iskat_art_dialog_0">
    <text>Where should I look for that artifact? Any clues?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_rezak_gde_iskat_art_dialog_1">
    <text>Eh… Only thing I know is near electrical anomalies. That’s as far as I got… m-da.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_rezak_hello_dialog_start_0">
    <text>Hello, how can I help?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_rezak_task_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, "Rezak", right?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_rezak_task_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah, that’s me. What’s up?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_rezak_task_dialog_2">
    <text>Doc wants a courier. He’s short on people to deliver medications.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_rezak_task_dialog_3">
    <text>Eh… I’d help Doc. He helped me once. But I’m tied up. Contract with scientists, have to deliver the "Compass" artifact. Don’t even know where to look… Sitting around, wearing out my pants. Ahem…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_rezak_task_dialog_4">
    <text>Got it. I could try helping. If I find it, you settle with the scientists and become Doc’s courier. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_rezak_task_dialog_5">
    <text>Ha! Deal, of course.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_rezak_task_dialog_6">
    <text>Great.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_rezak_task_end_dialog_0">
    <text>Found your "Compass". Terms still stand?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_rezak_task_end_dialog_1">
    <text>Thanks! Of course. I’ll hand it to the professor and head to the Fish Farm base to help Doc!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_rezak_task_end_dialog_2">
    <text>Excellent.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_sgustok_proff_searching_dialog_0">
    <text>What have you learned about this clot?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_sgustok_proff_searching_dialog_1">
    <text>An anomalous formation, hard to call an artifact. Probably a weird chemical reaction. No practical use, but fascinating. If you don’t mind, I’ll keep it in my collection and give you a small reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_sgustok_proff_searching_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright… good.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_0">
    <text>Whoa! And you’re a buddy of this "blue" guy, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_1">
    <text>Who-who?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_100">
    <text>Leaving… leaving.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_111">
    <text>Out of the way, small fry.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_112">
    <text>Are you crazy?! Empty your pockets, now!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_113">
    <text>Sorry, the devil tempted me. Take it—all I got.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_114">
    <text>You’re done, chickens!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_115">
    <text>Watch your mouth, uncle. Alright, leave now!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_116">
    <text>Yes sir.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_2">
    <text>The mercenary hanging here said someone would come to ransom him, ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_222">
    <text>Move, or I’ll lay you all down!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_3">
    <text>Don’t know who you mean.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_333">
    <text>Too brave, huh? Empty pockets and on your knees, girl.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_4">
    <text>Yeah? Whatever. Empty your pockets, bro.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_444">
    <text>You’ll answer for calling me a girl now!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright. Here, take everything.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_55">
    <text>Good, you didn’t start trouble. Now leave.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_555">
    <text>My bad, guys—sorry!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_6">
    <text>Uh-huh.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_66">
    <text>You goats crazy? Move, trash.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_666">
    <text>Too late, uncle. You’re done! Haha… Alright, I’m kind today. Empty your pockets and go.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_77">
    <text>What did you say?! Hey, bros, he doesn’t respect us.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_777">
    <text>Alright, don’t freak out.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_88">
    <text>Calm! Here, take it—all I got.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_888">
    <text>Pray. Face down, snot-noses!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_bandit_robbery_dialog_99">
    <text>Oh, just like that from the start. Fine, now get out of here.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_0">
    <text>Ugh… Got set up… M-m… don’t have long left.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_1">
    <text>Damn… They hit you hard. Need to drag you to a medic. A medkit won’t cut it here.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_2">
    <text>Doesn’t matter… won’t make it to a medic anyway. Listen, I have a dying request… hah… cough-cough…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, tell me.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_4">
    <text>You’re heading to our bar, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_5">
    <text>How did you guess?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_6">
    <text>Hah… Would you be killing those bastards if you didn’t need something here? Cough… Got a pass at least?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_7">
    <text>Pass? No. I’m on trader business with Garrota. Maybe you know him…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_8">
    <text>M-m… Yeah, I know him. Cough… So, since you’re going to us: avenge me, will you? Send the rat who caused this to the other side with me. Cough-cough…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_9">
    <text>Tell me who he is, I’ll handle it.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_10">
    <text>Marcus… His nickname: Marcus… Cough-cough… Get rid of him, he’s probably living it up in the bar off me. Take the reward yourself. He took my loot, led to bandits… and now I’ll die here like a dog… Cough-cough… That’s it… can’t take anymore… Bye.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_11">
    <text>%c[0,140,140,140][..leave..]</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_12">
    <text>I’ll avenge you… don’t worry. Good night, fighter.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_20">
    <text>Give you a medkit? Maybe it’ll ease the pain…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_killer_wounded_dialog_21">
    <text>Joking? Nothing will save me now… Listen, I have a dying request… hah… cough-cough…</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_container_u25_dizel_dialog_0">
    <text>Diesel, can you open this container? %c[255,248,153,26](Closed "Freedom" container)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_dizel_dialog_1">
    <text>Friend… I’d help, but too lazy right now. Ask the ecologist in camp—maybe he’ll do it!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_docent_dialog_0">
    <text>Could you open this container? %c[255,248,153,26](Closed "Freedom" container)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_docent_dialog_1">
    <text>Show me… Haha, nothing complicated. Don’t move, I’ll handle it… Done! Wow, solid arsenal here. You’re lucky, take it all!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_fobos_dialog_0">
    <text>Phobos, could you open this container? %c[255,248,153,26](Closed "Freedom" container)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_fobos_dialog_1">
    <text>Easy! For this, I’ll take 7,000 rubles. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_fobos_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright, go ahead.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_fobos_dialog_22">
    <text>Changed my mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_fobos_dialog_3">
    <text>Excellent! Done! Looks like solid loot—take your goods!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_texnar_dialog_0">
    <text>Technician, open this container? %c[255,248,153,26](Closed "Freedom" container)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_texnar_dialog_1">
    <text>Hmm… Wasting tools is a pity… but for 5,000 I’ll do it.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_texnar_dialog_2">
    <text>Deal. Here.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_texnar_dialog_22">
    <text>Will come back later.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_texnar_dialog_3">
    <text>Don’t go far… Done! Good loot for such a price. Lucky you, heh.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_vint_dialog_0">
    <text>Screw, open this container? %c[255,248,153,26](Closed "Freedom" container)</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_vint_dialog_1">
    <text>Show me. Pff… Piece of cake! I’ll take 2,000 rubles for consumables.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_vint_dialog_2">
    <text>Excellent. Here.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_vint_dialog_22">
    <text>We'll discuss it later.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_container_u25_vint_dialog_3">
    <text>Here we go. Op-pa! Damn, that’s some good loot! Lucky-lucky!</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_e51_actor_rasskazal_o_kvante_dialog_0">
    <text>Prophet, I have information. Your man wants to remove you from your "duties".</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e51_actor_rasskazal_o_kvante_dialog_1">
    <text>Hermano! Surprised! Ha-ha-ha, joke! But… Are you serious? Is it true? And who dares to be insolent?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e51_actor_rasskazal_o_kvante_dialog_2">
    <text>Quantum.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e51_actor_rasskazal_o_kvante_dialog_22">
    <text>Of course, just a joke. Who would dare mess with you in your "community"…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e51_actor_rasskazal_o_kvante_dialog_3">
    <text>M-mm… I suspected this scoundrel… I’ll make sure he sleeps very sweetly. And you’re smart, Voland! High five, ha-ha-ha! Now go, you actually have a very important task, if you haven’t forgotten!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e51_actor_rasskazal_o_kvante_dialog_4">
    <text>Uh-huh.</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_glori_akvapark_dialog2_0">
    <text>Do you hear that too?!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_akvapark_dialog2_1">
    <text>Well, yes…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_akvapark_dialog2_2">
    <text>Suddenly it got scary. What will you do?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_akvapark_dialog2_3">
    <text>And what should I do? Wait for your scanner to record all this.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_akvapark_dialog2_4">
    <text>Maybe check what’s happening there?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_akvapark_dialog2_5">
    <text>Is that really necessary?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_akvapark_dialog2_6">
    <text>I don’t know… But I wouldn’t go there.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_akvapark_dialog2_7">
    <text>Watch the device. I’ll check what’s up there.</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_glori_akvapark_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello! Always glad to see new visitors! Come in-come in, go down the corridor, changing rooms to your right! Quickly put on your swimsuits and go swimming!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_akvapark_dialog_1">
    <text>Is everything giggles and laughs for you?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_akvapark_dialog_2">
    <text>I think I already said you’re a bore, uncle Oleg!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_akvapark_dialog_3">
    <text>Here, take the device. Let’s do the assigned task.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_akvapark_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes-yes-yes. No problem. Starting already…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_akvapark_dialog_5">
    <text>Forward and with a song!</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_glori_wounded_dialog_0">
    <text>Ugh… Who’s here?!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_wounded_dialog_1">
    <text>Quiet-quiet, Gloria. Everything’s fine, it’s me—Oleg. How do you feel?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_wounded_dialog_2">
    <text>They’re here… They’re dangerous!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_wounded_dialog_3">
    <text>Calm down, kid. Get up, we need to get out of here.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_wounded_dialog_4">
    <text>No! It will return! Uncle Oleg, stop it!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_wounded_dialog_5">
    <text>Stop what? Gloria, come on, get up. We need to leave.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_wounded_dialog_6">
    <text>No! I won’t go back! And where’s the device?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_wounded_dialog_7">
    <text>I don’t know. Wanted to ask you. Stop fooling around, come on!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_wounded_dialog_8">
    <text>Get the device back, uncle Oleg! Professor will tear my head off!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_wounded_dialog_9">
    <text>Ugh… Come to your senses. I’ll find the device, I will.</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_gloria_task_end_dialog_0">
    <text>So what? Did you find the device?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_gloria_task_end_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes. Check, is it intact?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_gloria_task_end_dialog_2">
    <text>Let’s see… Lucky, undamaged. Scanning data is fine! Professor Bernada will be calm.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_gloria_task_end_dialog_3">
    <text>Yeah… We really got into a mess.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_gloria_task_end_dialog_4">
    <text>Main thing is everything worked out, uncle Oleg. Thank you so much for not leaving me.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_gloria_task_end_dialog_5">
    <text>Where would I… Do I look like a bad uncle?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_gloria_task_end_dialog_6">
    <text>Well… Nah! You’re one of the few better than you seem! Hehe.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_gloria_task_end_dialog_7">
    <text>Glad for you. Job done—means we can leave?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_gloria_task_end_dialog_8">
    <text>Yes. I’ll head to the complex now. You with me or later?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_gloria_task_end_dialog_9">
    <text>Yes, let’s go.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_gloria_task_end_dialog_99">
    <text>You go, carefully. I’ll drop by the professor later.</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_medalion_sekt_self_dialog_0">
    <text>Do you need this medallion?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_medalion_sekt_self_dialog_1">
    <text>Show me… Nah, that’s sectarian stuff. Hanging on psychos’ necks. No-no-no, put it away.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_medalion_sekt_self_dialog_11">
    <text>Ew, put it away. That’s satanic crap!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_medalion_sekt_self_dialog_111">
    <text>Beh, only Danya Bely from the stalkers' camp might buy such crap from you, I'm sure...</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_medalion_sekt_self_dialog_1111">
    <text>What is it? Ooo… No thanks! That's a sectarian trinket—it won't bring any good. Better throw it away!</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_mod_self_bluelamp_sherif_dialog_0">
    <text>And what are these ultraviolet lamps in the camp for?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_mod_self_bluelamp_sherif_dialog_1">
    <text>These devices help survive the emission, even in the open… Science is awesome, right?</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_molag_sovet_dialog_0">
    <text>Molag, got something to talk about. I made a deal with Garrota. He has the key-card, but in return, I have to do his task.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_molag_sovet_dialog_1">
    <text>Ugh… Better if he took money. But, it is what it is. And what's the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_molag_sovet_dialog_2">
    <text>He asked to deliver a case to a mercenary. Does the nickname "Cleaver" mean anything to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_molag_sovet_dialog_3">
    <text>Hmm… Heard about that thug. He’s like the leader in the local bar. So he’s sending you there?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_molag_sovet_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes. Marked their "VIP entrance" for me. It's not far…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_molag_sovet_dialog_5">
    <text>I don't know what to advise… Heard a lot of bad about this mercenary. Don’t get into trouble! Let me follow, cover your back.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_molag_sovet_dialog_6">
    <text>I don’t recommend it. I think that way we’ll only provoke conflict. I need everything to go quietly. Bring the case, take the envelope, give it to the trader. If things get hot, I’ll send SOS to your PDA. Then save me, hehe.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_molag_sovet_dialog_7">
    <text>As you say, Voland. As you say…</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_n10_hirsa_guider_dialog_0">
    <text>I need to go to the Research Institute. Can you drop me there?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_n10_hirsa_guider_dialog_1">
    <text>Let's fly, no problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_n10_hirsa_guider_dialog_2">
    <text>Forward.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_n10_hirsa_guider_dialog_22">
    <text>I changed my mind. Wait.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_n10_hirsa_guider_dialog_3">
    <text>We'll fly, no problem. But only after the emission.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_n10_hirsa_guider_dialog_4">
    <text>Good.</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_rodjer_hello_dialog_1_0">
    <text>Listen, soldier… Not now. I'm not in the mood to talk, okay.</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_scfbspilot_deshifr_dialog_0">
    <text>Do you happen to have a decoder?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_scfbspilot_deshifr_dialog_1">
    <text>Alas, Mr. Voland. For such equipment, you should contact the Research Institute.</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_sherif_sovet_dialog_0">
    <text>Sheriff. Here's the thing: I made a deal with Garrota. He has the key-card, but in return, I have to work for him.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_sherif_sovet_dialog_1">
    <text>Details? What is he up to now…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_sherif_sovet_dialog_2">
    <text>I need to deliver a case to a local mercenary nicknamed "Cleaver". Know any?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_sherif_sovet_dialog_3">
    <text>Uh-huh. Former soldier, neighboring unit near the Research Institute—served as battalion commander for 20 years. I'm familiar. Haven’t been in contact for a long time since this killer disappeared. Now he’s a “big shot” in the Zone. I smell danger. Let me and Molag go with you?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_sherif_sovet_dialog_4">
    <text>No. Better stay here. If we ruin the deal because of extra staff, I won't get the key-card. If danger comes, I’ll send SOS. Then save me, hehe.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_sherif_sovet_dialog_5">
    <text>You're thinking right, Voland. Good, stay healthy. If anything—we’ll fly in.</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_sim_self_gde_garrota_dialog_0">
    <text>Do you know a trader nicknamed Garrota? Where could he have gone?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_sim_self_gde_garrota_dialog_1">
    <text>Everyone knows this trader. Hmm… Maybe he ditched to the Cordon again, he does that often when pressed. Very slippery type…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_sim_self_gde_garrota_dialog_11">
    <text>I think I saw him recently… Sorry, can’t be sure.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_sim_self_gde_garrota_dialog_111">
    <text>Oh, bro, I don’t even know.</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_standart_danya_new_hello_dialog_1_0">
    <text>Ah, it’s you… If you want to trade, come to my "shop"—my goods are there.</text>
</string>

<string id="okr_task_gloria_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>I feel uneasy here…</text>
</string>

<string id="okrest_pirat_lc_to_scf_dialog_0">
    <text>I need to go to the settlement, to the old church.</text>
</string>
<string id="okrest_pirat_lc_to_scf_dialog_1">
    <text>No problem. Shall we sail?</text>
</string>
<string id="okrest_pirat_lc_to_scf_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes. Let’s sail.</text>
</string>
<string id="okrest_pirat_lc_to_scf_dialog_3">
    <text>Wait a bit.</text>
</string>

<string id="sad_b2_tech_util_1_0">
    <text>Do you happen to need some junk for recycling?</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_tech_util_1_1">
    <text>Yes. See the barrel behind me? Throw unnecessary junk there. But don’t throw weapons, I have enough of those parts! I need pistol, electronic, and rifle parts, disassembled, of course! Armor is useful for fabric, will remove plates from helmets too! Hah, you can even leave artifacts if pockets are tight, and some small parts, might come in handy… But don’t throw guns, they’ll just lie there. I’ll dig through and take what I need. Won’t give much money, but you’ll get rid of junk.</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_tech_util_2_0">
    <text>Well, did you pick something from the junk I left in your barrel?</text>
</string>
<string id="sad_b2_tech_util_2_1">
    <text>Yes, here’s the money.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bes_pb_task_end_dialog_0">
    <text>The spatial bubble is gone.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bes_pb_task_end_dialog_1">
    <text>Good. Thanks for not standing aside and dealing with this phenomenon. Who knows how fast it could have grown and wiped out everything around… Though part of the credit is yours—you fixed it, so you earned the reward! On behalf of all free stalkers, here’s what you deserve! Hehe…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bes_pb_task_end_dialog_2">
    <text>Just wonderful!</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_bespilot_bes_dialog_0">
    <text>Did you see the spatial bubble near the tower?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_bes_dialog_1">
    <text>Of course I saw it! Hard to miss… Something tells me you’re involved, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_bes_dialog_2">
    <text>Apparently. I found an unmanned scout in the river that disappeared before my eyes. But it left a memory module, which thanks to Lyosha we unlocked. Got a couple of bearings leading to local locators. Readings showed some noise… So yeah, I probably triggered this bubble.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_bes_dialog_3">
    <text>I see… Weren’t the strange things in the "uncharted territories" enough? Now this will happen here too.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_bes_dialog_4">
    <text>What do you mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_bes_dialog_5">
    <text>Such bubbles are dangerous. Time stops in them and people disappear… And not just people, they can swallow entire villages! Do you know how many landmarks have vanished because of these things?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_bes_dialog_6">
    <text>I’ve heard bits and pieces…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_bes_dialog_7">
    <text>Exactly. We need to get rid of it before it grows and devours our camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_bes_dialog_8">
    <text>And how do we do that?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_bes_dialog_9">
    <text>With a decoder. Professor Bernada once had a few specimens, but I don’t know if they still exist—or even work…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_bes_dialog_10">
    <text>The institute probably has similar gadgets too.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_bes_dialog_11">
    <text>I hope so. We need to use it quickly. No telling how fast this bubble will grow…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_bes_dialog_12">
    <text>I’ll figure something out.</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_bespilot_module_lexa_dialog_1_0">
    <text>Could you unlock the memory module?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_module_lexa_dialog_1_1">
    <text>Holy crap! I can, definitely. But… where did you find it?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_module_lexa_dialog_1_2">
    <text>It was inside a drone in the river. I tried to examine it, but it vanished before my eyes. In its place was this memory module—the carrier itself.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_module_lexa_dialog_1_3">
    <text>Brr… Creepy stuff. I’ve had enough of such tricks in the uncharted territories. But the memory module is real… We both see it, feel it. Alright, I’ll need a couple of hours to unlock it. I’ll let you know when it’s ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_module_lexa_dialog_2_0">
    <text>So, what’s up with the module?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_module_lexa_dialog_2_1">
    <text>It’s hacked. Here, take it. Check the info yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_module_lexa_dialog_2_2">
    <text>Alright, let me see.</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_citra_medic_need_health_care_0">
    <text>%c[0,140,140,140]I need medical help.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_citra_medic_need_health_care_1">
    <text>Let me see… Not fatal. You’ll live.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_citra_medic_need_health_care_11">
    <text>%c[0,140,140,140][..continue..]</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_citra_medic_need_health_care_111">
    <text>There! All done, good as new.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_citra_medic_need_health_care_2">
    <text>Voland, stop faking ailments, okay? Thoughts are material!</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_lytik_hello_dialog_1_0">
    <text>Hello, traveler!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_lytik_self_dialog_0">
    <text>What are you doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_lytik_self_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, just… Being nostalgic. And you? What brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_lytik_self_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh… You’re sitting up here like a hermit.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_lytik_self_dialog_3">
    <text>Ha! I’m not a hermit, I’m a musician! My ballads bored everyone, so they asked me to "shut up", but I can’t. I’m creative! I climbed up here to not disturb anyone. Eh… maybe tell me about yourself? Your exploits?! I’ll make poems about you!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_lytik_self_dialog_4">
    <text>Mm… Some other time.</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_n1_assistent_quest_dialog_0">
    <text>So, what did you find out about the "Dream Catcher"?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_assistent_quest_dialog_1">
    <text>Your sectarians are indeed responsible for this shard. There were several shards… I don’t know how they got them from under the NPP debris or how they discovered them, but they knew the properties and likely used them as a trap. The second shard is now in Chernobyl, at an industrial plant. Sectarians plan a ritual there.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_assistent_quest_dialog_2">
    <text>As I recall, you told the scientists that these shards possess intelligence? Even though the artifact itself was destroyed…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_assistent_quest_dialog_3">
    <text>Something like that… You can break it into thousands of stones, but the "brain" remains whole. Size only determines power. Now it’s weaker, maybe not aware yet, which is good. We need to destroy the second shard urgently before it grows stronger.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_assistent_quest_dialog_4">
    <text>Need help?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_assistent_quest_dialog_5">
    <text>You'll help, but later. Here are the coordinates. We'll meet at night. Going there during the day is impossible—sectarians will likely be guarding the place. Meanwhile, take care of your business, old man.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_assistent_quest_dialog_6">
    <text>Call me old man again and I'll break your jaw, you little brat.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_assistent_quest_dialog_7">
    <text>Ha! I'm terrified! Don't take it personally, Voland. You can't be offended by the truth. I'll be waiting at the place I indicated, over and out.</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_n1_djinks_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, traveler. Looking for quality goods? You can buy anything you desire from me, just a matter of price!</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_citra_0">
    <text>Why didn't you leave with Kvant?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_citra_1">
    <text>He has his business, I have mine… We won’t see life with the sectarians anymore, so I have nowhere else to go.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_citra_2">
    <text>I could lock you up in prison for this.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_citra_3">
    <text>I know, Voland. That’s a bit unfair. After all, I was looking after your people… And everyone here could be in prison, since almost all in the Zone are unregistered. Are you going to catch them all?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_citra_4">
    <text>So why did you stay? Do you think the stalker community will accept you?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_citra_5">
    <text>I don’t care about their opinion. At least I’m good at making field medicine, extracting bullets, stitching wounds. A new camp here could use a medic. That’s why I’m here.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_citra_6">
    <text>I hope you won’t cause trouble.</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_kolobok_0">
    <text>How are you, Artyom?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_kolobok_1">
    <text>As you can see, I’ve been patched up… She patched me up. That woman… a psychopath, I swear. I wouldn’t want her among the stalkers. Well, we’ll see how she behaves.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_kolobok_2">
    <text>I’m glad you’re okay. Thanks for trusting me and providing compromising info on the sectarians.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_kolobok_3">
    <text>True, but the compromising material is lost. Still, Kvant isn’t stupid—most of what I collected will end up at the research institute. In a way, it worked out. Sectarians are done for; it’s only a matter of time.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_kolobok_4">
    <text>That’s good to hear.</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_sherif_0">
    <text>Sheriff, buddy… glad you’re alive and in one piece.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_sherif_1">
    <text>Thanks to you, Voland. Thank you for pulling me out, Nikita…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_sherif_2">
    <text>It’s a pity about Molag…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_sherif_3">
    <text>Yes. So damn young. He was a great guy… I involved him in this, he died because of me.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_sherif_4">
    <text>I’m no less to blame. Don’t shoulder it all alone, friend. What happened, happened… unfortunately.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_sherif_5">
    <text>Yes. Drop by sometime, we’ll at least commemorate him properly…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n2_dop_dialog_sherif_6">
    <text>Definitely.</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_pirat_dialog_fast_trevel_0">
    <text>My respects, Voland!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_pirat_dialog_fast_trevel_1">
    <text>Do we know each other?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_pirat_dialog_fast_trevel_2">
    <text>By reputation. I’ve already heard about you…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_pirat_dialog_fast_trevel_3">
    <text>What did you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_pirat_dialog_fast_trevel_4">
    <text>I’m a local sailor. If you want to reach the "Rybkhoz" base in Chernobyl, I can give you a ride. I have my own "boat".</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_pirat_dialog_fast_trevel_5">
    <text>What? A working ship?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_pirat_dialog_fast_trevel_6">
    <text>Of course! Want to check? Let’s sail now!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_pirat_dialog_fast_trevel_7">
    <text>Good to know.</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_pirat_dialog_hello_start_0">
    <text>Hey there! Decided to use my "pearl"?</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_pirat_lc_to_okrest_dialog_0">
    <text>I need to get to the "Rybkhoz" base.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_pirat_lc_to_okrest_dialog_1">
    <text>No problem. Shall we sail?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_pirat_lc_to_okrest_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes. Let’s go.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_pirat_lc_to_okrest_dialog_3">
    <text>Wait a bit.</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_v1_kppboy_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, dead man. What the hell are you doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_kppboy_dialog_1">
    <text>I need to see your "boss". I have business with him.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_kppboy_dialog_111">
    <text>I wandered here by accident. I’m leaving. Calm down.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_kppboy_dialog_2">
    <text>What the fuck? You’re confused, bro! And what’s his name, huh? Get out!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_kppboy_dialog_222">
    <text>Shut up, scum!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_kppboy_dialog_3">
    <text>I need to see Jackal. He knows me.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_kppboy_dialog_33">
    <text>Got it, I’m leaving.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_kppboy_dialog_4">
    <text>Huh? How do you know his nickname?! Well, come on, but no funny business. One wrong move and you’re dead. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_kppboy_dialog_5">
    <text>Got it. Understood.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_kppboy_dialog_55">
    <text>Shut up, asshole. You’re screwed!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_kppboy_dialog_hello_0">
    <text>What do you want, dead man?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_shakal_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Blow my eyes out! The prey came to me itself... I can't stop laughing, ha!</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_dialog_0">
    <text>The Prophet ordered my death from you...</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_dialog_1">
    <text>Ha! That's right, Voland. You're either a fool or immortal—coming to me personally, knowing we'll kill you.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_dialog_2">
    <text>No other options available?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_dialog_3">
    <text>Why not? For your head, the Prophet promised us a hundred. You could get ahead and give us two hundred. Business, baby.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_dialog_4">
    <text>Go fuck yourself!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_dialog_44">
    <text>Let's say. Here's 200 pieces. You won't hunt me anymore?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_dialog_444">
    <text>I don't have that kind of money.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_dialog_55">
    <text>Listen, I thought you'd act tough... Hehe. Walk away, soldier. I'll tell the Prophet I didn't see you. Get out of here—I'm feeling kind today.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_dialog_555">
    <text>Yeah? Then I'll have to kill you, sorry! Ha-ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_dialog_666">
    <text>Yeah. Like hell!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_dialog_7">
    <text>Tesak said you're a sellout scum.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_dialog_8">
    <text>Mm... So you know Tesak? Ha! That changes nothing. I don't give a fuck what he told you. Now, get ready to die, Voland.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_dialog_888">
    <text>Ladies first!</text>
</string>

<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_0">
    <text>Blow my eyes out! The prey came to me itself... I can't stop laughing, ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_1">
    <text>The Prophet ordered my death from you... How long have you been working with the sectarians?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_2">
    <text>Ha! A long time, soldier Voland. By the way, I find it amusing to talk to a corpse! You're either a fool or immortal—coming to me personally, knowing we'll kill you.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_3">
    <text>And no other options available?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_4">
    <text>Hmm... Why not? For your head, the Prophet promised us a hundred. You could give us two hundred—business, baby.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_5">
    <text>Here's 200 pieces. Am I free now?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_55">
    <text>I don't have that kind of money.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_555">
    <text>You're finished, Jackal!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_6">
    <text>Oh, excellent! Thought you'd act tough... Hehe. Walk away, soldier. I'll tell the Prophet I didn't see you. Get out—I'm feeling generous today.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_66">
    <text>That's the problem, bro. You could have lived to retirement... Goodbye, soldier!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_666">
    <text>Tesak said you're a sellout scum.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_7">
    <text>Uh-huh...</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_77">
    <text>I won't surrender without a fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_777">
    <text>Mm... So you know Tesak? Ha! Doesn't matter. I don't care what he said. Now, get ready to die, Voland.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_wtf_contract_shakal_new_dialog_888">
    <text>Ladies first!</text>
</string>

<string id="und_kn_a5_contract_tesak_dialog_0">
    <text>Tesak... A mercenary squad attacked me in the canyon. What do you have to say about it?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_kn_a5_contract_tesak_dialog_1">
    <text>Impossible, Voland! My people are under my control. If any gang went after you, it’s Jackal's scum. I'm sure it was his doing. That rat works for the sectarians—their base is at the old military complex near Zalesye. I'd bet my tooth on it.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_kn_a5_contract_tesak_dialog_2">
    <text>They work for the sectarians?!</text>
</string>
<string id="und_kn_a5_contract_tesak_dialog_3">
    <text>You bet. Sectarians are real businessmen, damn them. Jackal gets a cut from some contracts. But why they hunted you… Holy crap… Did you really piss off those fanatics?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_kn_a5_contract_tesak_dialog_4">
    <text>Mm… Got it, thanks for the info.</text>
</string>

<string id="und_markus_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>What, huh? I'm not in the mood.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_markus_quest_dialog_0">
    <text>I have mercenary "Reker's" PDA. Judging by it, you set him up.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_markus_quest_dialog_1">
    <text>Quiet, your fucking… Man, not here. We can make a deal: you give me the PDA, I give you 30 thousand units. Pretty good, hm?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_markus_quest_dialog_2">
    <text>Screw you. You set up your own man. I’ll report everything to your leader.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_markus_quest_dialog_22">
    <text>Deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_markus_quest_dialog_3">
    <text>I have connections, got it!? You won't get away with this!</text>
</string>
<string id="und_markus_quest_dialog_33">
    <text>There, you can see a businessman right away. Hehe… Now let's split up, okay? We don’t need to be seen together. Come on, get going.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_markus_quest_dialog_44">
    <text>I need to think about it.</text>
</string>

<string id="und_predatel_quest_tesak_dialog_0">
    <text>I have proof that your man Markus betrayed his partner.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_predatel_quest_tesak_dialog_1">
    <text>What! What do you mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_predatel_quest_tesak_dialog_2">
    <text>Here's the kid's PDA. His name was Reker.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_predatel_quest_tesak_dialog_3">
    <text>Let me read… Well, Markus turned out to be such scum. Umgh… And we considered him a good fighter! But we don’t need such rats in our squad. Thanks for your help, Voland. Here's your well-earned reward for not siding with that bastard.</text>
</string>

<string id="und_prov_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Hm? Yeah, man. Listening with all my soul… Wanted something?</text>
</string>

<string id="und_rodjer_norm_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Oh, it’s you… How are you? Want something from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_rodjer_zloi_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Get out of my sight, asshole. We'll meet again.</text>
</string>

<string id="und_sab_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>I hope you're here on business… I’m listening.</text>
</string>

<string id="und_u3_bolt_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>What do you want? Need something?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u3_ohrannik_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>I'm not in the mood for talking right now. Go your way.</text>
</string>

<string id="und_u3_rodjer_angry_dialog_0">
    <text>Holy shit! Here you are, asshole. What the hell are you doing here, scum? You're on my territory and I told you we'd meet again. Remember how you punched me in the face!?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u3_rodjer_angry_dialog_1">
    <text>I can do it again.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u3_rodjer_angry_dialog_2">
    <text>You bastard… Well, we’ll meet again—the world is round, remember that.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u3_rodjer_angry_dialog_22">
    <text>Well, sorry, I was heated then…</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u3_rodjer_angry_dialog_23">
    <text>Apologies not accepted, sucker. See you later, watch your back.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u3_rodjer_angry_dialog_24">
    <text>Whatever you say.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u3_rodjer_angry_dialog_3">
    <text>I'll be waiting for our next meeting.</text>
</string>

<string id="und_u3_rodjer_norm_dialog_0">
    <text>Oh… You're here too? How did you end up here?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u3_rodjer_norm_dialog_1">
    <text>Garrota, whom you were guarding, sent me here.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u3_rodjer_norm_dialog_2">
    <text>So that’s how it is… I see. Well, I won’t distract you. Go where you were going. Maybe we’ll see each other at the bar sometime, have a chat. Hehe…</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u3_rodjer_norm_dialog_3">
    <text>Good. No problem.</text>
</string>

<string id="und_u7_girl_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello…</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u7_provodnik_dialog_0">
    <text>Where are we going?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u7_provodnik_dialog_1">
    <text>To Tesak. They let me through.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u7_provodnik_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, I know. Will you find the way yourself or should I escort you?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u7_provodnik_dialog_3">
    <text>I'll find it myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u7_provodnik_dialog_33">
    <text>Well, escort me, I don’t mind.</text>
</string>

<string id="undbar_barmen_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, wanderer! What can I get you? Something to eat or drink?</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_medic_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Can I be of help? If not, I’ll continue… Um, if you need medical supplies, I can sell some.</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_tesak_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Voland, what business brings you here…</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_texnik_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Mm? Need something upgraded or repaired? Or just here to chat…</text>
</string>
<string id="undbar_trader_hello_dialog_0">
    <text>Oh wow… You have business with me? Or maybe want to buy something? That’s fine, my assortment is excellent!</text>
</string>

</string_table>
