<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="mod_sms_error_task_text">
    <text>This quest seems broken or unfinished!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_taxi_open_mess_f_text">
    <text>New fast-travel route unlocked.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_assistent_quest_info_time_sms_txt">
    <text>Voland, I’ve got intel about your sectarians and that artifact. Swing by, we need to talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_cld_sherif_radio_4_txt">
    <text>Looks like things have calmed down… Not sure what’s happening there, but you handled it well.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_cld_sherif_radio_3_txt">
    <text>Voland! What the hell’s happening there?! The ground is shaking! Connection’s messed up! Damn it… Stay safe, buddy!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_cld_sherif_radio_2_txt">
    <text>Your signal’s fading. Did you go deeper? If you stay quiet, I’ll break our pact and come to you. Just give me a sign you’re okay!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_cld_sherif_radio_1_txt">
    <text>Everything alright down there? Do I need to follow? Don’t leave me hanging, old man.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_scf_sherif_n16_sms_say_txt">
    <text>Voland, I just saw Artyom… he’s not doing well, right? Friend, why do you always disappear without a word? This isn’t the first time! I’m here, as always, your loyal mate!</text>
</string>
<string id="cd_p30_prorok">
    <text>Prophet</text>
</string>
<string id="cld_final_boss_prorok_say_1_txt">
    <text>Ah, you... I had hopes for you, hermano. Wanted you among us, yet I showed mercy once. But you, scoundrel Voland! Ha-ha! I gave you another chance… and still… Ha-ha… Hermano, you…</text>
</string>
<string id="cld_p25_megapone_prorok_say_2_txt">
    <text>Hmm… As my father said before killing my mother: “Handle it yourself, son.” Ha-ha… You, brat, dare come to me again, planning my end? You’ll not ruin my plans. Now, quickly, face me! Let’s see who’s in charge here. I’m ready for you, my dear.</text>
</string>
<string id="cld_p25_megapone_prorok_say_1_txt">
    <text>Oh, Hermano! Is that really you?! Thought you were dead! Ha-ha… Or maybe you escaped to the mainland with your little ones! But no, you came! Just in time, the show begins, and before death, you’ll witness my masterpiece! He-he… Now, bring me the head of this warrior! First to do it gets a prize! Or maybe not, we’ll see. Go ahead, brothers! Wonderful we are all here today!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_assistent_cut_say_1_txt">
    <text>Awake now? Sorry, couldn’t save you from the artifact any other way. Had to knock you out. Hope you understand.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_assistent_cut_say_2_txt">
    <text>Lucky you woke up. Almost lost you forever. I don’t get how this artifact returned… Thought I destroyed it.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_assistent_cut_say_3_txt">
    <text>Yes, it was a “Dreamcatcher”. If this isn’t the last, we’re in big trouble.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_assistent_cut_say_4_txt">
    <text>Listen, Voland, don’t tell anyone what you saw. I’ll figure out how this thing reappeared. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_assistent_cut_say_5_txt">
    <text>Sectarians? Ha! I wiped out a whole CNPP of them… Now there are rumors of new fanatics, but they’re not Monolith. Different group. I’ll keep you informed.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_assistent_cut_say_6_txt">
    <text>Yes, old man. Any news, I’ll tell you. Don’t worry, stay safe!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_cd_a1_mercs_name">
    <text>Unknown</text>
</string>
<string id="cld_a1_merc_1_say_1_txt">
    <text>Serge! What are you doing stuck there? Looking for trouble? Ha-ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="cld_a1_merc_1_say_2_txt">
    <text>Get lost, idiot! Damn, need a smoke… Anyone got cigarettes?</text>
</string>
<string id="cld_a1_merc_1_say_3_txt">
    <text>Quiet! Heard something in the second building! Move, follow me!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_voland_cut_say_1_txt">
    <text>What the hell?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_voland_cut_say_2_txt">
    <text>Was that… a Dreamcatcher?!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_voland_cut_say_3_txt">
    <text>We must inform the institute… This thing is dangerous.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_voland_cut_say_4_txt">
    <text>Agreed. Suspect sectarian involvement.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_voland_cut_say_5_txt">
    <text>Alright, Assistant. Keep me posted.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_assistent_art_wtf_txt">
    <text>What the hell… I thought I destroyed the Dreamcatcher. Damn it!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_d2_assistent_im_sorry_txt">
    <text>Don’t take it personally, old man. I’m just saving your life.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_baza_tyda_nelza_txt">
    <text>You shouldn’t be here. You’re finished!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_baza_blizko_txt">
    <text>Hey! What are you doing here, death seeker?! Stay out of this!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_baza_enemy_to_actor_txt">
    <text>Attention! Enemy spotted on base! Neutralize immediately!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_v1_shakal_naebal_txt">
    <text>Did you think I’d let you go?! Ha-ha!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_kolobok_say_1_txt">
    <text>They should be nearby. Let's take a look around.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_kolobok_wound_say_1_txt">
    <text>I'm fine! Focus on taking down these bastards!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_kolobok_say_end_txt">
    <text>Ugh… As I thought. Mercenaries teamed up with the sectarians. What a terrible mix…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_kolobok_fack_say_txt">
    <text>Ouch! Damn! Voland, it's an ambush!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_kolobok_cut_say_2_txt">
    <text>Ugh… Damn it!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_kolobok_cut_say_1_txt">
    <text>You're right, this door wasn’t here before… Maybe someone hanging around installed it.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n16_kolobok_sms_txt">
    <text>Found anything? I'm on my way.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_module_lexa_unblock_time_text">
    <text>Memory module figured out. Come here!</text>
</string>
<string id="m_give_scf_bespilot_name">
    <text>Memory Module</text>
</string>
<string id="m_give_scf_bespilot_coordinati_txt">
    <text>Coordinates of the radio beacon received</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_bespilot_k_spot_txt">
    <text>Radio Beacon</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n15_kolobok_go_sms_me_txt">
    <text>Voland, looks like you decided to stay… Smart move. I think we’re both after the Prophet. Come over, I’ve got some info to share.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_scf_heli_name">
    <text>NII Communicator</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n3_racia_heli_say_txt">
    <text>Connection is clear, Colonel. We hear you perfectly. We'll try to send a helicopter ASAP. Hold on!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n3_racia_heli_say_dva_txt">
    <text>We’ll be there shortly!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n5_heli_army_pribili_text">
    <text>Arrived. Ready for pick-up, over.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n10_radio_pilot_poka_txt">
    <text>Alright… Contact us if needed. Good luck, Colonel!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n3_racia_act_say_1_txt">
    <text>Base, this is Colonel Voland. I need an evac. How’s the reception?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n3_racia_act_say_2_txt">
    <text>Received. Awaiting helicopter, over.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_kvant_say_1_txt">
    <text>Ah, Voland. Did everything go smoothly?</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_n1_nikita_say_1_txt">
    <text>Oleg! Brother, good to see you!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_glori_sms_1_txt">
    <text>Uncle Oleg! Help! Something’s flying around! A-a-a! Please, help!</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_riddik_kroko_say_txt">
    <text>Damn, crocodiles everywhere!</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_riddik_the_end_say_txt">
    <text>Phew… Looks like we handled it!</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_riddik_gotmituns_say_txt">
    <text>Well, thank God.</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_riddik_protect_say_txt">
    <text>Cover me while I examine this anomalous plant!</text>
</string>
<string id="flst_riddik_sms_say_outfit_no_txt">
    <text>Don’t even think about removing your suit here!</text>
</string>
<string id="kn_a5_mercs_attacked_txt">
    <text>You shouldn’t have come here, Stalker. Now you’re in trouble!</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_l1_bes_say_0_text">
    <text>Well…</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_l1_bes_say_1_text">
    <text>Ha-ha, that was easier than expected.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_l1_bes_say_2_text">
    <text>Yew logs… This is the old settlement. They say nobody’s been here for ages.</text>
</string>
<string id="scf_l1_bes_say_3_text">
    <text>Thanks for the backup, Voland. Glad we teamed up… We’ll settle here for now and call the others. The catacombs are worth exploring thoroughly!</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_a1_bes_sms_1_text">
    <text>What are you staring at? Come check this out…</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_a1_bes_sms_2_text">
    <text>Shall we move on?</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_naparnik_bes_say_heh_1_txt">
    <text>Quiet, Lesha. No need to rush…</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_naparnik_bes_say_monsters_txt">
    <text>Damn, real burers! Watch out!</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_naparnik_bes_say_lager_txt">
    <text>Wow, a campfire… Could even set up a temporary camp here.</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_naparnik_bes_say_see_monstrs_txt">
    <text>They keep coming…</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_a1_leha_sms_1_text">
    <text>Such a strange glow… Hope it’s not harmful. Where is it coming from?</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_a1_leha_sms_2_text">
    <text>Incredible view!</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_naparnik_leha_say_heh_1_txt">
    <text>Hmm… Who enjoys dungeons like this? Of course, burers…</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_naparnik_leha_say_monsters_txt">
    <text>Where do all these creatures come from?!</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_naparnik_leha_say_shell_shock_txt">
    <text>Earthquake?!</text>
</string>
<string id="coll_naparnik_leha_say_see_exit_txt">
    <text>Looks like the exit is close!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mod_chu_tutor_svali_txt">
    <text>If someone’s blocking your way, ask them to step aside.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mod_chu_tutor_new_comnd_txt">
    <text>New companion command available: "wait by the campfire".</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_st_sr_changer_to_scf">
    <text>Do you want to go to the surface?</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_k6_sms_cut_kvant_txt">
    <text>Excellent… Looks like you’ve wandered into uncharted territory, Voland! Lucky for us both – we’re heading toward the village of "Zalesye" right now. From what I know, the safest route goes under the old church… Back in the day, the local PRIEST used this path. So it’s safer for both of us to meet there – the Prophet won’t find us immediately. Take these coordinates. I’ll be waiting at the marked spot, grab them.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_k6_sms_cut_actor_txt_1">
    <text>Got it. I’ll be there soon!</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_bes_stop_to_hram_say_txt">
    <text>Don’t go in there! It’s dangerous!</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_bes_stop_to_hram_say_txt_2">
    <text>Damn… We lost him.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a5_bes_say_1_txt">
    <text>Look, Lesha, he’s alive! Phew… We got lucky.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a3_cut_bes_say_1_txt">
    <text>The bell’s stopped ringing… And it feels easier to breathe now, right? Lesha, come over – it seems safer here.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_bes_say_5_txt">
    <text>What the…?! My head’s about to explode…</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_bes_say_4_txt">
    <text>Voland! Watch out, polters!</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_bes_say_3_txt">
    <text>Stay quiet… But don’t relax, anything can happen here!</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_bes_say_2_txt">
    <text>Lesha, rest here. I’ll go with Voland to check the church. Don’t worry – it’s quiet here, like at a resort. No one will touch you.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_bes_say_1_txt">
    <text>You did the right thing avoiding the church… Something paranormal was going on in there, damn it.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_bes_say_1_bad_txt">
    <text>I told you not to enter the church… Lucky you got out alive. But your legs must’ve been fast, ha-ha.</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a1_bes_sms_txt">
    <text>Stalker, help! We’re very close! Don’t enter the church if you want to survive. Come straight to me!</text>
</string>
<string id="chu_a3_cut_lexa_say_1_txt">
    <text>No-no-no, guys… Go ahead without me, okay? I’m not ready yet!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e70_kovalskie_go_to_actor_say_txt">
    <text>Oleg – we’re following you. Lead the way.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_prorok_say_txt">
    <text>Excellent. Very good, Voland. You’re a compliant one…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e60_actor_cut_bad_sound_txt">
    <text>I had a choice, I could have acted differently… But at the cost of my brother and Sheriff friend’s lives, I chose this path. The Prophet has probably already killed them… And now I’m coming for you, sectarian. I’ll finish you fast.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e60_bad_act_say_txt">
    <text>Well then… I had a choice, I could have acted differently… But at what cost? I had to go against the institution to save my brother and friend… Maybe one day I’ll answer for what I’ve done.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtr_e80_actor_cut_say_1_txt">
    <text>At the cost of my loved ones, I stayed loyal to my oath… Yet without them, everything feels meaningless. Am I still just a soldier trained to follow orders? Nonsense… I killed the Prophet, but feel no relief. Maybe I chose the wrong path after all?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtr_e80_actor_cut_say_2_txt">
    <text>Seems like this is the end for me…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e61_prorok_cut_say_1_txt">
    <text>You did the right thing, Voland! Clever as always! Take your brother – you’ve got five minutes, hurry up. Heh-heh-heh!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e61_prorok_cut_say_2_txt">
    <text>Oops… Had to knock off your buddy, sorry, he pissed me off. Enough chatter! Take your kid and get out!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e61_prorok_cut_say_3_txt">
    <text>You know what… Your ignorance angers me! I’ve changed my mind… Kill them!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e65_prorok_natation_bad_final_say_txt">
    <text>There’s a rule… well, not even a rule, hermano. More like a dogma, you see? Trust no one… No one.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e61_actor_cut_say_1_txt">
    <text>You killed the Sheriff! That wasn’t part of the deal!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e62_actor_cut_say_1_txt">
    <text>Everything will be fine, little brother. Take my hand, get up.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtr_e80_kovalskie_cut_sms_text">
    <text>Oleg, we’ve got a problem! It’s a trap! Exit the metro immediately. Attention everyone – run to the exit!</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e56_prorok_angry_sms_text">
    <text>You shouldn’t have done that, Voland… My informant already told me what you did. You’ll regret this. The end for your friends, understand?! Bastard!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e70_prorok_scream_say_1_text">
    <text>We could have been partners, Voland! Best friends… You idiot! You ruined everything!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e70_prorok_scream_say_2_text">
    <text>And you didn’t even save your brother, fool! His blood is on your hands! You ruined everything!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e70_prorok_scream_say_3_text">
    <text>If you were even slightly smarter, you’d have done exactly as I said! But no, too proud, right?!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e70_prorok_scream_say_4_text">
    <text>Ha-ha-ha! You have no idea what I’ve planned for your arrival, hermano… I’ll make you suffer!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e53_show_2_chasa_txt">
    <text>A few hours later</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_e55_rasskazat_vsio_txt">
    <text>Inform someone in the NII about the Prophet’s plans</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e52_actor_racia_say_txt">
    <text>It’s me again. Passage clear, doors open.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e52_prorok_racia_say_1_txt">
    <text>Super! You’re a good boy, heh-heh-heh! Expect guests!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e50_actor_cut_say_1_txt">
    <text>Any issues?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e50_actor_cut_say_2_txt">
    <text>Seriously?! Then tell him himself – the path to his "sacred place" is open!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e50_actor_cut_say_3_txt">
    <text>What do you mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e50_actor_cut_say_4_txt">
    <text>Really? I always thought he was a psychopath from birth.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e50_kvant_cut_say_1_txt">
    <text>Well, the Prophet asked me to keep an eye on you.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e50_kvant_cut_say_2_txt">
    <text>I will, for sure. But I’ve got a counter-offer for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e50_kvant_cut_say_3_txt">
    <text>The Prophet has completely lost it. I doubt he can lead our "community" anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_e50_kvant_cut_say_4_txt">
    <text>Ha-ha… Exactly. Listen, I’m not sure you won’t snitch to the Prophet after hearing this. But if you’re interested in my offer – meet me at the canyon, by the cliff. Choose wisely, Voland. Good luck!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mtrs_e3_kvant_name">
    <text>Kvant</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_av_zahvat_st_text">
    <text>The sectarian outpost has been cleared.</text>
</string>
<string id="m_naiden_av_box_sms_text">
    <text>You’ve opened the sectarians’ ammunition box.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mod_sektant_avanpost">
    <text>"Sectarian Outpost":\n%c[255,1,255,255]According to the data, this is one of the fanatics’ hideouts.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_gribs_spot_text">
    <text>Anomalous location:\n%c[255,1,255,255]«Mushroom Field»</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g7_danik_say_1_text">
    <text>Alright, that’s enough. I’ve gathered plenty of mushrooms, heh-heh! Let’s head back to camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g6_danik_say_1_text">
    <text>What the hell? This house won’t let us out!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g5_danik_see_gribs_say_text">
    <text>Where did this mushroom come from? Strange…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g3_danik_say_task_fail_2_text">
    <text>You left Danny behind! Task desynchronized!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g5_danik_say_1_text">
    <text>Wow, look! The anomaly in the passage is gone!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g4_danik_say_1_text">
    <text>Well, convinced now? We’re trapped in here…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g3_danik_say_task_fail_text">
    <text>Ran off? Too bad! Ai… Alright, I’ll head to base. Too bad, Voland. But it’s your choice…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g3_danik_say_1_text">
    <text>Look at that sparkle… Hmm… I wonder what these mushrooms taste like. Let’s find out, heh-heh…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g3_danik_say_2_text">
    <text>Hmmm… Let me pick a few mushrooms, and you cover me, okay?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_g3_danik_say_3_text">
    <text>Alright, I’ve gathered a few… We could take samples to the scientists for study, heh-heh! Wait… Something’s wrong… Ugh… No-no-nooo, gah!</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_afina_search_1_1_say_txt">
    <text>Interesting… I need to scan everything here.</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_afina_search_1_say_txt">
    <text>So… I need time to take the measurements. Cover me.</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_afina_search_2_say_txt">
    <text>Done with one scanner. Need a few more.</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_afina_search_3_say_txt">
    <text>Almost done… Be patient, guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_afina_search_4_say_txt">
    <text>Great, finished the measurements here. Voland, we need to talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_perehod_open_sms_text">
    <text>You now have access to the passage back. Leaving now will fail the mission.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_st_sr_changer_loc_bunk_closed">
    <text>You just arrived… At least help Afin a little more.</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_no_exit_sms_text">
    <text>Don’t leave the mission yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_afina_say_1_text">
    <text>Big request, guys. Follow my instructions, okay? Let’s go.</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_afina_say_2_text">
    <text>Uh-huh… The door is blocked… Alright, let’s take a detour.</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_afina_say_3_text">
    <text>Stay alert, guys. I have a feeling we’re not alone here…</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_afina_say_4_text">
    <text>At least there’s a control panel here. I’ll hack it now. Cover me!</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_afina_say_5_text">
    <text>Almost there… Hold on!</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_afina_say_6_text">
    <text>Done! Let’s move on.</text>
</string>
<string id="bunk_a1_afina_say_7_text">
    <text>I need to examine everything here. Please wait a moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="m_okr2_afina_primknyl_fishboy_sms_txt">
    <text>Joined Afina’s expedition – "Stalker Lynx"</text>
</string>
<string id="m_okr2_afina_primknyl_docent_sms_txt">
    <text>Joined Afina’s expedition – "Docent «Roman»"</text>
</string>
<string id="m_naiden_okr2_rotan_sms_txt">
    <text>Found the corpse of the "wonder-fish"!</text>
</string>
<string id="m_naiden_zolbox_sms_text">
    <text>Discovered a chest with valuable loot nearby!</text>
</string>
<string id="lx24_volnachzo_sms_assistent_text">
    <text>Hello Stalkers roaming the Zone every day – mercs, Duty members, free anarchists, and bandits alike! Welcome to the show: "On the Wave of CHZO." Good news: the path to the ChNPP is open and safe again. Mutants and anomalies remain, but barriers, psy-installations, and cursed monoliths seem less dangerous now in the Zone’s heart. Grab your backpacks, sober up, take everything you need, and rush to conquer the Northern territories! You deserve it. Signing off, with respect: the channel "On the Wave of CHZO."</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_p3_cutscene_video_sound_txt">
    <text>You know, when I moved from Spain to Belarus, and then to Russia, I was almost immediately drafted into the Second Chechen War. I didn’t even have time to learn Russian properly, and now I speak with you as if it were my native language. Later, I got a contract and ended up in the Zone. To you, my children! Here I finally felt alive – a place where I could be more than I could in the outside world, which had faded, stank, and become boring… and meaningless!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_sub_lx24_cut_remont_gen_name">
    <text>Attention: generator power repair in progress</text>
</string>
<string id="lx24_e41_texnar_say_txt">
    <text>So… in theory, it should work. Come on, try starting it.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx24_e42_texnar_say_txt">
    <text>Ha! It works… Task completed. Now you owe me, Voland.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx24_actor_dymaet_say_txt">
    <text>Need to figure something out. The "Prophet" won’t like my answer. I need to contact Technician; maybe he can suggest something. Damn… the connection is bad here.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx24_e34_tex_rac_say_1_txt">
    <text>Hearing you loud and clear. What happened, old warrior?</text>
</string>
<string id="lx24_e34_tex_rac_say_2_txt">
    <text>Oh… You surprise me. Khm, okay – keep your secrets. I can help. Most likely, we’ll have to fully reassemble your generator, no big deal. We’ll settle up later, hah. Send me your coordinates, I’ll grab some components and come to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="lx24_e34_act_rac_say_1_txt">
    <text>"Technician", come in. This is Voland, can you hear me?</text>
</string>
<string id="lx24_e34_act_rac_say_2_txt">
    <text>I have a request. I ended up in a flooded underground… Don’t ask why, I’ll explain later if I get out! Basically, I need to restore a generator there, but since it was underwater, it got a little wet. Any options?</text>
</string>
<string id="lx24_gen_actor_say_txt">
    <text>What’s there to be surprised about? The generator is fried… What do I tell him now, this finished sectarian?</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mod_okr2_naiden_perehod_v_lx24_txt">
    <text>Found a secret entrance to the "Flooded Underground"</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e16_actor_racia_say_txt">
    <text>I'm in position… The hermetic door’s power is off. What now?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e16_prorok_racia_say_1_txt">
    <text>Listen… Either you’re as crazy as I am, or you’re ignoring my instructions. Clean your ears, Voland! If it were that easy to get there, you’d be messing with me, right? Go to the nearby underground. Restart the power generator – it’s in the flooded section! Experiments there caused the flooding. Your task – neutralize the problem. If the generator got damaged by water… you figure it out yourself, hermano. I need the doors opened. Don’t bother me with trivial stuff – my nerves… Ha-ha-ha… are weak!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_prorok_racia_say_1_txt">
    <text>Crawled out of our burrow? Ha-ha-ha… Listen carefully, soldier. Provide me with a safe and easy path to the "Oasis". Got it? Catch the coordinates of this sacred place! Just like that… Heh-heh-heh.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_prorok_racia_say_2_txt">
    <text>Are you completely stupid, hermano? Imbecile, huh? I told you exactly what to do, damn it! Don’t drag this out or I’ll kill your wards, and then you! Okay? Come on, fuckup. Act!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr2_e15_actor_racia_say_txt">
    <text>Is that all? Will there be more instructions?</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mod_mtrs_give_loot_out_txt">
    <text>You have recovered your personal belongings.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_s2_e3_soldjer_say_txt">
    <text>Get up, animal. The Prophet wants to talk to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mtrs_e1_tolpa_name">
    <text>Crowd of sectarians</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e1_sektants_scream_say_text">
    <text>Attribute! Attribute! Attribute!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_e1_prorok_cut_say_1_txt">
    <text>We came here with one purpose, my brothers! To bring light into the souls of children lost in this world! They don’t yet know that their actions have angered the gods! But we were sent to earth to save it, so tell me, brothers… Who are we!?</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_prorok_say_1_txt">
    <text>Let’s delve deeper into your mind, heh-heh…</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_prorok_say_2_txt">
    <text>Interesting… very interesting…</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_prorok_say_3_txt">
    <text>Don’t miss the details, uncle. I want to know everything about that event…</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_prorok_say_4_txt">
    <text>Ah… So you came for your brother?</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_prorok_say_5_txt">
    <text>Now your motives are clear, Voland. I understand everything about you.</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_o5_voland_say_1_txt">
	<text>Michel? Hello! It's Oleg, hi!</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_o5_voland_say_2_txt">
	<text>Where are you? I went to your place, knocked on the door—silence! Your phones were off. Now I'm at your work… Is anyone there?</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_o5_voland_say_3_txt">
	<text>How are you? Listen… What's going on with Nikita? Did he tell you anything about his plans? Why did he sign that contract? Are there problems? Money issues? What happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_o5_voland_say_4_txt">
	<text>I… Umgh… Ah… Sorry, calm down, Michel! Everything will be fine, hear me? I’ll bring him back, okay? I’m getting my stuff and heading to the Zone! Everything will be fine.</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_o5_voland_say_5_txt">
	<text>I’ll bring him back—definitely. Stay in touch and… send my regards to everyone.</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_o5_mishel_say_0_txt">
	<text>Hello… Oh, hi Oleg. Do you need something important?</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_o5_mishel_say_2_txt">
	<text>Yes… We packed our things and went to my mom's. Just…</text>
</string>
<string id="old_ofc_o5_mishel_say_2_txt">
	<text>Yes… We… Sorry, we’re out of town. I took a vacation. We packed our things and went to my mom's. Just…</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_o5_mishel_say_3_txt">
	<text>I don’t know… He just left us with the fact and went… I really don’t know anything about his contract. He went crazy!</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_o5_mishel_say_4_txt">
	<text>All hope is on you, Oleg… Please bring Nikita back to us!</text>
</string>
<string id="ofc_o1_show_text">
	<text>Memory: A few months ago</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f1_molag_dymaet_lovushka_say_txt">
	<text>Voland, don’t you think this is a trap?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f5_prorok_cut_say_2_txt">
	<text>Let’s look straight into your soul, sinner!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f5_prorok_cut_say_1_txt">
	<text>And who are you? Ha-ha-ha… A lonely sheep or a ferocious wolf? Ah… I know who you are! Yes, I know.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f5_prorok_mudila_say_txt">
	<text>Surprise, mudila!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f2_prorok_rupor_txt">
	<text>They came to destroy us! Demons! Demons sent to drag us to HELL! We won’t tolerate their ignorance. We will destroy them! DESTROY, no matter what! FORWARD!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f5_sherif_krik_txt">
	<text>Voland!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f2_sherif_angry_say_txt">
	<text>He is dead! Bastards… scum… I’ll shoot them all to hell, fuck!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f2_sherif_molag_is_dead_say_txt">
	<text>Voland! Molag… He… N-no!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f2_dead_molag_sound_txt">
	<text>He… help!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f1_sherif_elector_pannel_say_txt">
	<text>There should be a panel somewhere… Power is on, but we need to supply voltage. Look… ah…</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f1_sherif_dark_say_txt">
	<text>Hmm… It’s dark here, like in…</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f1_sherif_door_say_txt">
	<text>Ah… Door. Let’s see… cover me, okay?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f1_sherif_wtf_say_txt">
	<text>Some kind of tricks… Damn it!</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f1_molag_wtf_say_txt">
	<text>What the hell?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f1_molag_say_1_txt">
	<text>Don’t "crow," Sheriff.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f1_sherif_say_1_txt">
	<text>I have a bad feeling.</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs_f1_act_say_1_txt">
	<text>Do you hear that too? We’re not alone here…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_n10_hirsa_sms_say_txt">
	<text>Attention, general channel! I’ve returned from my mission and can now transport everyone in need to the Scientific Institute. My coordinates are already uploaded to your personal digital assistants. Thank you for your attention.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r88_sherif_davai_in_mtrs_txt">
	<text>Come on, friend, insert the card. Time to save your little brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u28_freedom_warn_say_txt_2">
	<text>Whoa… Guys, watch out! Alien!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u28_freedom_warn_say_txt">
	<text>Stalker, get out of here—before they catch you!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u25_sms_0_say_txt">
	<text>Bro, where did you go? Over.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u25_sms_1_say_txt">
	<text>Everything's fine, Sheriff. Had some minor issues with the trader, but we’re good. I have the key card. Heading to the sanatorium. You coming?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u25_sms_2_say_txt">
	<text>Understood. We’re with you—gathering supplies with Molag and moving to the sanatorium.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u25_sms_3_say_txt">
	<text>Alright, see you there. Over and out.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_changer_perehod_okrest_to_mtrs">
	<text>Path to the Metro. Station: "Sanatorium"</text>
</string>

<string id="st_changer_perehod_okrest_to_flst">
	<text>Path to the "Underground Testing Complex"</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_st_sr_changer_okrest_to_flst">
	<text>Go to the "Underground Testing Complex"?</text>
</string>
<string id="fallstation">
	<text>Testing Complex</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u17_dreamcather_o6_radiovolna_txt">
	<text>Greetings to all the living, with you: on the ChZO wave! What a surprise… Recently we learned someone helped liberate the "Forester" camp in… *interference* …the Red Forest! And more—it's the same guy who destroyed the "Burner" under Yantar! Who is he? The hero of the week? We still don’t know, but we’ll find out soon! Stay tuned.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_u17_zapiska_txt">
	<text>Voland, I’m laying low for now. If you have the envelope, hide it at night in the designated spot. In the morning, your key card will be there.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_avtoceh_spot_text">
	<text>Auto Shop</text>
</string>
<string id="kektor_death_sms_1_txt">
	<text>Lethal dead to the cheaters!</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u14_tesak_cutscene_say_txt">
	<text>Thanks again, Voland. My opinion of you has changed for the better. Now we just need to understand how—and most importantly, why—we were attacked.</text>
</string>

<string id="und_u13_tesak_say_1_txt">
	<text>What do these bastards want in my bar!?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u13_tesak_say_2_txt">
	<text>In my bar?! No way! I’ll deal with these scumbags myself!</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u13_tesak_say_3_txt">
	<text>Everyone, stay alert! Keep your eyes on the elevator!</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u13_tesak_say_4_txt">
	<text>Forward—move!</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u13_tesak_say_5_txt">
	<text>Call the elevator, warrior. Let’s finish off these bums!</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u13_tesak_say_6_txt">
	<text>We made it… What a day, damn it.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u13_welcome_sherif_say_txt">
	<text>Glad you’re okay, buddy!</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u13_welcome_molag_say_txt">
	<text>Looks like we’re on time, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u10_ketrin_ghost_txt">
	<text>Get up! Don’t lose consciousness, Voland!</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u10_ketrin_ghost_txt2">
	<text>Please… don’t die. I need you!</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u10_ketrin_ghost_txt3">
	<text>Don’t you dare leave me, do you hear!?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u11_sherif_sms_txt">
	<text>Hold on, Voland! Molag and I are following your trail.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u11_molag_sms_txt">
	<text>Voland, it’s Molag. How are you? Did you already break into the mercenary bar? Damn… signal is weak… Are you underground or what? I’m on your trail, buddy. Hang in there—I’ll be there soon!</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u9_tesak_warning_say_1_txt">
	<text>What the… Listen! Give me one good reason not to kill you right here and now! Did you bring a tail? Answer quickly!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_p2_cutscene_video_sound_txt">
	<text>And the voice in my head called me—the Apostle. It keeps telling me the path, the right path. Righteous! Free! Without filth and garbage… This is purification, my brother. And you… you will be free.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_st_sr_changer_loc_undbar_closed">
	<text>You just arrived… Better do what you came here for first.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u2_ohrannik_cut_say_1_txt">
	<text>Stop! Who are you? What are you doing here!?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u2_ohrannik_cut_say_2_txt">
	<text>Aha. Right… look over there, I see you.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u2_ohrannik_cut_say_3_txt">
	<text>Why so silent?! Who are you? Do you have a pass?</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u2_ohrannik_cut_say_4_txt">
	<text>Hmm… To "Tesak"? I’ll check… Wait by the door.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u2_ohrannik_prohodi_say_txt">
	<text>Proceed. Tesak is in the "Chamber Section"—waiting for you. Walk straight down the corridor to the elevator. You’ll go down to the bar, but no nonsense, got it? I’m watching you!</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u2_actor_cut_say_1_txt">
	<text>Ah? What the…</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u2_actor_cut_say_2_txt">
	<text>Yeah, I’m here to see "Tesak"—from the trader, Garrota. I have an appointment.</text>
</string>
<string id="und_u2_actor_cut_say_3_txt">
	<text>Understood. Received.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_modmaker_4ector_name">
	<text>4ECTOR</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_modmaker_maylay_name">
	<text>MayLay</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_rofl_sms_1_txt">
	<text>Yeah, go ahead and kill them. They deserve it!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_rofl_sms_2_txt">
	<text>Why act like a punching bag? Kill the jerks!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_rofl_sms_3_txt">
	<text>Seriously, you’ll give them your hard-earned money and take it!?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b54_rofl_sms_4_txt">
	<text>Hmm… I would have killed them the moment I saw them.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_p1_cutscene_video_sound_txt">
	<text>You know, before my mother killed my father, she said: "Son, you’re not like everyone else. You were born for greater things!" And then she lunged at me with a knife, slashing my back, arms, legs… head. Ha-ha… again and again.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_garrota_angry_rodjera_pobili_say_txt">
	<text>Hey, I don’t get it! Who beat up Roger!? Damn it, I’ll find the idiot and kill him.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_cut_vagon_actor_say_1_txt">
    <text>I heard a little birdie say you can get a key card from the secret entrance under the sanatorium.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_cut_vagon_garrota_say_1_txt">
    <text>Well… if you know the password, then you’re not just some random dude, right? What do you have?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_garrota_password_actor_txt">
    <text>Wait… I know the password. Uhm… "Kitchen a la Espanola." I think that’s it…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_cut_vagon_actor_say_2_txt">
    <text>No matter. Just name your price.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_cut_vagon_garrota_say_2_txt">
    <text>Key card? Ha-ha-ha… Who told you I have it?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_cut_vagon_actor_say_3_txt">
    <text>Hey! I really need that key card! What do you want for it? Let’s negotiate.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_cut_vagon_garrota_say_3_txt">
    <text>Hmm… here’s the thing—whoever told you I have it was wrong. Get lost.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_cut_vagon_actor_say_4_txt">
    <text>What—what? More details…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_cut_vagon_garrota_say_4_txt">
    <text>That’s a different story. A favor for a favor, it turns out. So listen, it’s simple: you complete my task—I give you the key card.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_cut_vagon_actor_say_5_txt">
    <text>Somehow this all sounds very dubious.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_cut_vagon_garrota_say_5_txt">
    <text>You don’t need the details. You need to meet an influential guy. He’s a mercenary, nickname: Tesak. He has his own base. I’ll give you the entrance coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_cut_vagon_actor_say_6_txt">
    <text>Damn, I don’t have time for this. I urgently need that card—get it already!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_cut_vagon_garrota_say_6_txt">
    <text>Don’t interrupt. Upon arrival, say you’re from Garrota—they’ll let you through. Give the case to Tesak, he’ll hand you an envelope. Better not look inside if you want the key card. Deliver the envelope intact to me and we’re even, got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_cut_vagon_actor_say_7_txt">
    <text>Umgh… okay. Give me your case.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_cut_vagon_garrota_say_7_txt">
    <text>Listen, I have enough of my own business. If you need the card urgently—don’t whine, go to my client.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r6_molag_o_door_say_txt">
    <text>Damn fanatics… They still communicate using notes? Hmm, yes. They have their own base under this sanatorium… I suspected as much.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_garrota_rupor_text_scene">
    <text>Closed.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_garrota_rupor_text_open">
    <text>Umgh… Come in.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_garrota_rupor_text_closed">
    <text>Closed! Not accepting clients.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_r4_dead_zona_out_timer">
    <text>Return to the combat zone!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_m1_act_ogo_molag_see_say_text">
    <text>Come on… is that Molag?</text>
</string>
<string id="mtrs">
    <text>Metro - Station "Sanatorium"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nii_perehod_to_inst_spot">
    <text>Entrance to the "NII" Institute</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nii_perehod_to_office_spot">
    <text>Entrance to the main office "NII"</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_st_sr_changer_nii_ofc_closed">
    <text>You cannot enter at this time.</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_st_sr_changer_in_institut">
    <text>Main building of the Scientific Research Institute.</text>
</string>
<string id="sub_niichaz">
    <text>Scientific Research Institute</text>
</string>
<string id="sub_okrest">
    <text>Outskirts of Chernobyl</text>
</string>
<string id="nii_n1_hirsy_about_inst_say_text">
    <text>Here we are. If you suddenly want to go back to the Zone, you’re welcome—come here.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nii_n1_zona_out_timer">
    <text>You cannot leave the «NII» on your own</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mod_actor_open_lager_3">
    <text>Scientists' Base</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mod_actor_open_lager_2">
    <text>Scientists' Camp</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mod_actor_open_lager_1">
    <text>Stalkers' Camp</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nii_vert_spot_text">
    <text>Helicopter Pad</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nii_ofc_spot_text">
    <text>Old «NII» Office</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nii_sklad_spot_text">
    <text>Warehouses</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nii_stolovka_spot_text">
    <text>«Battery» Canteen</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nii_kpp_spot_text">
    <text>Checkpoint</text>
</string>
<string id="st_nii_glav_zdanie_spot_text">
    <text>Main «NII» Building</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_st_sr_changer_na_poverhnost">
    <text>Return to the surface?</text>
</string>
<string id="st_changer_perehod_okrest_to_lab_24">
    <text>Path to the Flooded Dungeon</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_st_sr_changer_okrest_to_lab_24">
    <text>Go to the Flooded Dungeon?</text>
</string>
<string id="st_changer_perehod_okrest_to_undbar">
    <text>Descent to the Lucky Ones Bar</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_st_sr_changer_okrest_to_undbar">
    <text>Descend to the Lucky Ones Bar?</text>
</string>
<string id="st_changer_perehod_okrest_to_bunker">
    <text>Descent to the Underground Laboratory</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_st_sr_changer_okrest_to_bunker">
    <text>Descend to the Underground Laboratory?</text>
</string>
<string id="ui_st_sr_changer_locations_closed">
    <text>Path closed!</text>
</string>    
<string id="bunker">
    <text>Underground Laboratory</text>
</string>
<string id="niichaz">
    <text>Scientific Institute</text>
</string>
<string id="und_bar">
    <text>Lucky One’s Bar</text>
</string>
<string id="lab_24">
    <text>Flooded Bunker</text>
</string>
<string id="office">
    <text>Main Office Building, NII Branch</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_b10_docent_2_name">
    <text>Associate Professor Roman</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_b10_docent_1_name">
    <text>Associate Professor Alexey</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_proff_sgust_sms_txt">
    <text>I have studied what you brought.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_taxiboy_hello_fitst_see_txt">
    <text>Come on over! Local taxi has arrived… I can give you a ride.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_b10_taxiboy_first_see_txt">
    <text>Whoa, what brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_taxiboy_2_go_road_txt">
    <text>Start up, baby… And… well, let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_taxiboy_2_end_road_txt">
    <text>We've arrived, Voland. You're on your own from here…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_taxiboy_1_go_road_txt">
    <text>We'll get there in a flash, buckle up. Heh-heh!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_taxiboy_1_end_road_txt">
    <text>Here we are. Good luck!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_a5_taxi_bag_sms">
    <text>Oops, I broke the script… Let's take a look and fix it.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_sub_okr_taxi_perehod1_name">
    <text>Attention: Fast transition through the location</text>
</string>
<string id="st_sub_okr_prolog_mod_name">
    <text>A couple of weeks later…</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_prlg_prorok_say_txt">
    <text>And who are you? Heh-heh-heh.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_v1_news_chzo_dc_snd_sms">
    <text>Hello everyone, this is the ChZO wave channel! Some daredevil turned off the "Brain scorcher" under Yantar. Who could it be? Unknown for now, but communication in the Zone is restored, and that’s great news! Stay tuned for more.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_prlg_radio_surge_say_txt">
    <text>Stalkers, attention! The emission will start any minute. Find a deep hole if you want to survive.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_prlg_act_mother_fack_say_txt">
    <text>Damn it! What's going on here?!</text>
</string>      
<string id="okr_prlg_act_hide_surge_say_txt">
    <text>Damn. I need to find shelter quickly!</text>
</string>    
<string id="okr_prlg_actor_surge_say_txt">
    <text>Emission? Are you kidding?!</text>
</string>    
<string id="okr_prlg_actor_say_3_txt">
    <text>Hm… Maybe climb higher? Worth a try.</text>
</string>    
<string id="okr_prlg_actor_say_2_txt">
    <text>Damn, the connection is glitchy here too… Where can I climb to get a signal?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_prlg_actor_say_1_txt">
    <text>It's peaceful here… like on a resort.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_radio_surge_name">
    <text>General Channel</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_prlg_radio_hehe_say_txt">
    <text>Brr... What weather today! Don't feel like going anywhere, but I really wanted to take a little walk in the forest. Collect some radioactive mushrooms. Heh-heh...</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_radio_ved_name">
    <text>ChZO News</text>
</string>
<string id="st_golos_okr_a5_tutorial_name">
    <text>VIVIENT-MODS</text>
</string>
<string id="st_upgr_okr_mod_cherteji">
    <text>The technician needs blueprints.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_p1_actor_say_1_txt">
    <text>Sheriff. Greetings! Heh-heh... I heard you're in the Chernobyl area now, and I'm here "passing through". There's something to discuss, but better in person. Shall we talk?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_p1_sherif_say_1_txt">
    <text>What people... Buddy! Glad to hear from you, Voland. Something wrong? Okay, let's discuss. Catch the coordinates, we'll meet there!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_p1_actor_say_2_txt">
    <text>Received. I'll be there soon, over.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_sub_okr_present_mod_name">
    <text>A few weeks before that...</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c4_sherif_go_to_base_say_txt">
    <text>Well... There's nothing more for us here. Let's go to the local camp, it's the only safe place now.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_c3_sherif_svistit_say_txt">
    <text>Don't fall behind, Voland!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_a5_sherif_sms_pda_txt">
    <text>Voland. I figured out the PDA. Come over, we'll think it through.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_d1_cutscene_video_snd_prorok_say">
    <text>Are you filming him? Oh... Idiota! Hold the camera steady. Steady, damn it! Do you have tremors? Ha-ha, ah... Hey soldier, don't piss yourself. Just smile for the camera, hermano. People should know their heroes by face, ha-ha... Eh, isn't that right? Let them watch, closely.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_okr_r2_cuts_act_say_1_txt">
    <text>"Observer"... "Comet"... Are you serious? You said it's our mutual acquaintance. Who is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r2_cuts_act_di_sher_say_1_txt">
    <text>You'll find out on site, remember the old times... Heh-heh! When you're ready - come over, we'll head to the meeting place. You'll definitely like the meeting, I don't want to spoil the intrigue!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r2_sherif_say_1_txt">
    <text>Roger-roger, this is "Observer". "Comet", how do you read?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r2_molog_say_1_txt">
    <text>Sheriff, is that you? Hah... "Comet" on the line. Let's skip the military stuff.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r2_sherif_say_2_txt">
    <text>Ha-ha! I knew you'd like it.. Listen friend, I need your help. Our mutual acquaintance is back. Ahem... You're our scout after all, do you know anything about the "Sectarians" - who attacked the military squad at the school a week ago.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_r2_molog_say_2_txt">
    <text>Ah... So that's what interests you? I have some leads on that. I got onto the "Sect"... Let's discuss this in person, okay? We'll meet at the "Nest" - I'll be there soon, hope you remember where it is. Over and out.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_attribute_intro_story_subtitres_text">
    <text>In the Zone, things are still restless... Literally every day, it throws new surprises, and the number of daredevils uncovering the veils of secrets inside it is getting fewer. In the last few years, our operational command has been actively participating in raids to the center of the Zone. As for me, I've been resting from service on the mainland for almost a month now. After all, even military personnel deserve a vacation, right? But recent news forced me to end my tranquility ahead of schedule... I won't drag it out... My younger brother, Nikita, decided after his mandatory service to follow in my footsteps and become a military man. But I didn't wish that kind of "happiness" for him. As if life on the civilian side was bad for him... He became a volunteer in escorting a scientific expedition, at the request of the "Institute for the Study of the ChZO" - without even telling me, probably because he knew what I thought about it... And so, together with a squad of military prepared for such operations, he set off in search of adventures on his ass! Now communication with them is lost. I also learned that the squad of my old comrade, Captain Smirnov, also went on an expedition with scientists to search for some artifact, I think it was called... "Dream Catcher". Hmm, communication with them was cut off too. As far as I knew, the reason was the installation under Yantar. I'm worried about Nikita, so I'm heading out to search for him right now. What will I tell his son and wife, that I left everything as is? Hell no, I'm not going to sit on my ass... I feel guilty for how it turned out and worry about him. Hah... He always looked at me kind of from below-up. Saw me as his idol or something? Damn, there's nothing in me to see... I had to argue hard with the superiors so they would give in - but I must find my brother! I hope I can contact my friend "Sheriff" in the Zone - I think he won't refuse to help with the search, after all, I've bailed him out more than once in tough times for both of us. I'm heading deep into the Zone. Nikita, just please, don't get into any mess. I'll take you home soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_welcome_tutor_1_txt">
    <text>This camp is the only safe place in the vicinity.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_welcome_tutor_2_txt">
    <text>Here you can rest or listen to the news.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_welcome_tutor_3_txt">
    <text>And here you could store your personal belongings.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_welcome_tutor_4_txt">
    <text>And if you get bored - on this receiver, you can turn on and listen to music!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_welcome_tutor_5_txt">
    <text>You can also get to know the locals, work for them.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_welcome_tutor_6_txt">
    <text>Welcome. After all, this is where you will begin your journey...</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_cut_walk_actor_say_1_txt">
    <text>Do we know each other?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_cut_walk_ilay_say_1_txt">
    <text>Come on, did you forget? It's me, Ilay! You bailed me out from the military on the Cordon a year ago, remember? Ha-ha... I didn't expect to meet you here, what brings you?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_ilay_hello_cut_say_txt">
    <text>Hey, Voland... Long time no see!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_cut_walk_actor_say_2_txt">
    <text>A long story.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_cut_walk_ilay_say_2_txt">
    <text>Oh well... Alright, I won't bother you then. When you have a free minute - come by, we'll chat. We have things to talk about!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_a5_cut_walk_actor_say_3_txt">
    <text>Understood... Well, okay. When I have time - I'll come by.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_venera_spot_text">
    <text>Abandoned complex «Venus»</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_zapravka_spot_text">
    <text>Gas station</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_aviabaza_spot_text">
    <text>Airbase</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_derevnya_spot_text">
    <text>Village</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_electro_anom_spot_text">
    <text>Transformer booth</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_sanator_spot_text">
    <text>Old sanatorium</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_akvapart_spot_text">
    <text>Swimming pool</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_dom_ghosts_spot_text">
    <text>House with ghosts</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_izba_spot_text">
    <text>Anomaly «Air Hut»</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_old_heli_spot_text">
    <text>Old helicopter</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_garage_spot_text">
    <text>Garages</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_starcity_spot_text">
    <text>District «Engineers»</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_stroiplate_spot_text">
    <text>Construction site</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_izbas_spot_text">
    <text>Anomalous place:\n%c[255,1,255,255]«Air Hut»</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_krater_spot_text">
    <text>Anomalous place:\n%c[255,1,255,255]«Crater»</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_labirint_spot_text">
    <text>Anomalous place:\n%c[255,1,255,255]«Minotaur's Labyrinth»</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_samolet_spot_text">
    <text>Anomalous place:\n%c[255,1,255,255]«Flight Loop»</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_vodalol_spot_text">
    <text>Anomalous place:\n%c[255,1,255,255]«Water Polo»</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mod_okr_new_loc_txt">
    <text>A new anomalous phenomenon has been discovered.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mod_okr_new_loc_name">
    <text>Marker added</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_syhles_spot_name">
    <text>«Dry» forest</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_krater_spot_name">
    <text>Anomaly «Crater»</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_zavod_prom_spot_name">
    <text>Industrial plant</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_sr_c4_spot_name">
    <text>Old school</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_spot_fish_hoz_name">
    <text>«Fish farm» base</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_c3_dead_zona_out_timer">
    <text>Do not leave the story mission!</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_s1_off_mine">
    <text>%c[255,248,153,26]Disarm the trap ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
</string>
<string id="st_sub_okr_d1_name">
    <text>Video file found</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mod_scfhouses_name">
    <text>Inspected</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mod_search_houses_name">
    <text>Clue</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mod_warning_name">
    <text>Attention</text>
</string>
<string id="st_mod_okr_a5_no_sleep_txt">
    <text>Sleep is not available to you now.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_tip_radio_on">
    <text>%c[255,248,153,26]Turn on music ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_tip_radio_off">
    <text>%c[255,248,153,26]Turn off music ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
</string>
<string id="st_okr_c4_sherif_cut_say_text">
    <text>I was told that the attack on the military was here. But... This doesn't look like an ambush, let's take a look around.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_sub_okr_c3_mod_name">
    <text>STALKER - «Attribute»</text>
</string>
<string id="st_sub_okr_c1_name">
    <text>VIVIENT-MODS present.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_ui_pda_legend_vip">
    <text>Important character</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c3_cut_actor_say_1_txt">
    <text>Yes... Some strange dream.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c3_cut_actor_say_2_txt">
    <text>What... Ah... Where are you from?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c3_cut_actor_say_3_txt">
    <text>Umgh... I honestly don't know myself. Okay, let's not talk about it.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c3_cut_actor_say_4_txt">
    <text>Yes, you're right.</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c3_cut_sherif_say_1_txt">
    <text>What-what, having nightmares?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c3_cut_sherif_say_2_txt">
    <text>So... Well, who is this "Katherine"?</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c3_cut_sherif_say_3_txt">
    <text>You were talking in your sleep!</text>
</string>
<string id="okr_c3_cut_sherif_say_4_txt">
    <text>No problem. Well, it's already morning - and we still have a long way to go. Let's wrap it up. And also... Find your brother sooner.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_golos_okr_c1_name">
    <text>Unknown voice</text>
</string>
<string id="st_golos_okr_c1_text1">
    <text>Once, someone told you that God did not create people - one better than the other. But this quote had a continuation...</text>
</string>
<string id="st_golos_okr_c1_text2">
    <text>We were only born equal... And then - everything depended only on us.</text>
</string>
<string id="okrest">
    <text>Vicinity of Chernobyl</text>
</string>
</string_table>
